<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="1.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="1.03" rain:generator="/iati/iatiactivities_v22" rain:version="1.01" version="1.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:rain="http://data.rainfoundation.org" xmlns:version="2.0">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-34200988_DWDG_NP13_514</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org rain:organisationtype="international NGO" rain:url="http://rainfoundation.org" ref="NL-KVK-34200988" type="21">RAIN foundation</reporting-org>
  <title>Piloting the 3R approach</title>
  <description rain:description="General (short) project description" rain:type="description" type="3">- Implementing 3R + WUMP approach in 2 sub catchments. 
- Construction of household rwh systems (jars) in additional localities
- collaboration with Simavi and with Engineers Without Borders
- multi-year project</description>
  <description akvo:type="7" rain:type="d_activities" type="1">1.	High Catchment Intervention (Decentralised Household Scale)
2013 and 2014&#x2013; Stage I:	Implementation of RWH jars for household use and at 	community level (Masel, Phinam, Nareswor, Gorkha Municipality, Tanglichowk)
2014 &#x2013; Stage II:	MUS Expansion of RWH for livelihood uses (3R Catchments only)
2015 &#x2013; Stage III:	Monitoring and evaluation of optimised RWH systems

2.	Mid-Low Catchment Intervention (Centralised Community-Scale) &#x2013;  Tanglichok 3R Catchments
2013 &#x2013; Stage I:	Implementation of Gravity-flow systems/springs (Simavi)
2014 &#x2013; Stage II:	Upstream MUS expansion of RWH through sub-surface 
		storage and decentralised 3R catchment initiatives (RAIN Foundation)
2015 &#x2013; Stage III:	Monitoring and evaluation of community-scale systems

3.	Catchment-Scale Intervention (Decentralised Catchment-scale): piloting the 3R-WUMP module in Tanglichok 3R Catchments
2013 &#x2013; Stage I:	Hydrologic Monitoring and Modelling, 3R Opportunity mapping
2014 &#x2013; Stage II:	Implementation of catchment-wide recharge and retention 
2015 &#x2013; Stage III:	Monitoring and Evaluation of project and development of Draft 3R Catchment Methodology.</description>
  <description rain:type="d_duration_months" type="3">34</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability combined" type="1">Financial sustainability : Financial sustainability will be promoted at the VDC level through establishing or linking with existing savings and credit cooperatives if available. NEWAH shall promote the use of micro-finance for within the intervention area and conduct workshops with the community to promote it&apos;s use. 
Throughout the project, NEWAH will facilitate and provide linkages between the community and micro-finance institutions as well as biogas providers. Due to the potential for income generating activities, NEWAH will conduct training on micro-finance within the target community and link with local savings and credit groups. Initial &apos;seed&apos; capital of RS 100,000 has been reflected in the budget to &apos;kick-start&apos; existing savings and credit groups within the target catchment area.
Institutional sustainability : Within the target catchments the VDC V-WASH CC will be the main WASH governing Institutional body to plan and manage the project. NEWAH will also facilitate linkages between the WSUC and the district level Federation of Drinking water and sanitation users Network (FEDWASUN) so that beneficiaries have a sustainable institutional mechanism for raising future concerns. Institutional training is provided to the WSUC through NEWAHs existing processes in addition to biannual support visits for a period of two (2) years post-construction. This visit also develops the capacity of the community and provides refresher training to WSUCs if required.

NEWAH will work in partnership with Water and Sanitation Users Committee (WSUC) and local government WASH structures such as Village Water Supply Sanitation and Hygiene Coordination Committee (V-WASH CC) to provide and promote drinking water services as well as facilitate awareness and education programs. The WSUC will be responsible to mobilise the local communities during the training. They will be involved in managing the local materials like sand, aggregate and stone collection for water supply structure construction and keeping records of all the construction materials received at project site and expenditure made at the project level.
Environmental sustainability : Through the retention and recharge of peak flow runoff, anthropogenic erosion will be decreased reducing impacts on downstream aquatic ecosystems. Revegetation, if proposed, will be conducted in a manner conducive to promoting ecosystem biodiversity. Through proposed education the community will have a greater understanding of natural catchment processes contributing to improved community management practices and improved environmental health.

An initial site visit to the intervention catchment will be conducted and catchment areas delineated. The purpose of the initial investigation will be to gather context and scope potential locations for runoff monitoring equipment and rainfall gauges. NEWAH will liaise with BSP to apply their developed Area Selection Tool to the catchment to confirm the catchment is appropriate for a 3R pilot.

Specific 3R intervention measures will not be known until a catchment assessment and hydrologic modelling is complete but may include decentralised measures such as:
&#x2022;	Erosion prevention and slope stabilization
&#x2022;	Revegetation to improve infiltration and/or soil water retention
&#x2022;	Terracing, bunds or eyebrow pits construction to promote infiltration.
&#x2022;	Sub-surface infiltration measures
Technical sustainability : Proposed technical solutions will be context-appropriate and utilise sustainable, locally available materials wherever possible. The use of nominated community members for hydrologic monitoring ensures a level of sustainable technical knowledge is retained within the community. The use of local community labour in construction ensures that beneficiaries have not only an understanding of system construction but take ownership in their asset. Training in system operation and maintenance ensures that infrastructure will be sustainable and managed effectively by the intervention community. However, as 3R approach is new for NEWAH and communities, NEWAH staff may face challenges on applying the suitable technologies in the field which shall be communicated to BSP Nepal and RAIN and support and suggestions will be sought. 

Rainfall/Runoff Monitoring: Daily rainfall and runoff data will be monitored from April 2013 until September 2015, rainfall guage/s will be located as close to the catchment centroid as possible and runoff monitoring locations will be selected based on a compromise of optimum locations for both data collection for model validation, and post-construction quantitive comparison. Sub-daily runoff and rainfall measurements will be collected for a number of storm events to allow model calibration and validation. A monitoring database and internal NEWAH processes for data collection and storage will be developed to ensure accurate and regular collection of data by regional office staff. Runoff monitoring will occur at both catchment outfalls, as well as small (1 &#x2013; 2 ha) agricultural and forested catchments within both intervention catchment to aid in model calibration. It has been assumed that runoff measurement at outfall will occur through the construction of concrete flumes, and runoff measurements of small catchments by rectangular or v-notch weirs, and this has been reflected in the budget.

Detailed Catchment and Agricultural Survey: A detailed catchment and socio-economic survey will be conducted in order to provide hydrogeologic data, a demographic and agricultural profile and to ground-truth land-use/vegetation data and catchment topography. On site constraints and landowner boundaries will be mapped in addition to on-site soil infiltration testing.

Hydrologic Model Selection, Setup, Calibration and Validation: An appropriate hydrologic model for the catchments will be selected and a model constructed. Following final wet-season precipitation in October, modelling calibration and validation will occur and a coarse water-balance model will be developed to provide temporal context on water surplus and deficit.

Social sustainability : The standard NEWAH approach actively includes groups disadvantaged by gender, caste and religion, and a Gender and Social Inclusion (GESI) approach during planning, capacity building and paid job opportunities will be used. An accessible and equitable water supply systems increases social well-being as less time is spent on water collection by girls and women, resulting in an increased enrollment in schools. A safe water supply system reduces instances of easily preventable disease reducing the financial burden of sickness and improving social harmony.

In order to ensure community participation and to build trust, monitoring will be undertaken by intervention community and recorded manually for monthly entry by NEWAH&apos;s PME team. Monitoring equipment will also be installed in a participatory manner utilizing local labour and materials when possible.</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (financial)" type="1">Financial sustainability will be promoted at the VDC level through establishing or linking with existing savings and credit cooperatives if available. NEWAH shall promote the use of micro-finance for within the intervention area and conduct workshops with the community to promote it&apos;s use. 
Throughout the project, NEWAH will facilitate and provide linkages between the community and micro-finance institutions as well as biogas providers. Due to the potential for income generating activities, NEWAH will conduct training on micro-finance within the target community and link with local savings and credit groups. Initial &apos;seed&apos; capital of RS 100,000 has been reflected in the budget to &apos;kick-start&apos; existing savings and credit groups within the target catchment area.</description>
  <description rain:coding="(F,I,E,T,S),(Financial, Institutional, Environmental, Technical, Social)" rain:description="Subjects: main sustainability elements, considering content and results and not main budget allocation" rain:type="d_subjects" type="3">I,E,T</description>
  <description rain:coding="(ADV,INT,IMP),(Advice, Intelligence, Implementation)" rain:description="RAIN Services offered" rain:type="services" type="3">IMP</description>
  <description akvo:type="6" rain:type="d_context" type="1">Most of the project communities are situated in the rural and remote locations. Majority of land area is covered with rocky hills. The altitude of these VDCs ranges from 1000m to 1700m meters. The settlement of the community is scattered with sloppy terrains. Most of the houses are made of mud mortar with slate roofing and very few with dry grasses. The community is inhabited by various castes and ethnicity with lower castes. Nepali is the main language of the community for communication. Agriculture is the main occupation for majority of people in the project areas. Some male people use to go India for labor because their own production from agriculture is not enough for them for the whole year. In Nareswor, Tanglichok and Masel VDCs the proposed interventions are all located high in the catchment along ridge lines. The water sources below these areas are currently unprotected traditional sources and as such there is also considerable potential for contamination.</description>
  <description akvo:type="8" rain:type="d_objectives" type="2">Piloting the 3R approach/ Supporting local government mechanisms for effective 3R approach to WASH planning and delivery/ Strengthening the community capacity to manage, operate and maintain WASH systems in a sustainable way/ Improving knowledge and basic understanding of catchment processes within the target community/Enhancing community realisation of their potential to undertake other development opportunities/ Creating a stronger research position to refine 3R approach in a Nepali context.</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (technical)" type="1">Proposed technical solutions will be context-appropriate and utilise sustainable, locally available materials wherever possible. The use of nominated community members for hydrologic monitoring ensures a level of sustainable technical knowledge is retained within the community. The use of local community labour in construction ensures that beneficiaries have not only an understanding of system construction but take ownership in their asset. Training in system operation and maintenance ensures that infrastructure will be sustainable and managed effectively by the intervention community. However, as 3R approach is new for NEWAH and communities, NEWAH staff may face challenges on applying the suitable technologies in the field which shall be communicated to BSP Nepal and RAIN and support and suggestions will be sought. 

Rainfall/Runoff Monitoring: Daily rainfall and runoff data will be monitored from April 2013 until September 2015, rainfall guage/s will be located as close to the catchment centroid as possible and runoff monitoring locations will be selected based on a compromise of optimum locations for both data collection for model validation, and post-construction quantitive comparison. Sub-daily runoff and rainfall measurements will be collected for a number of storm events to allow model calibration and validation. A monitoring database and internal NEWAH processes for data collection and storage will be developed to ensure accurate and regular collection of data by regional office staff. Runoff monitoring will occur at both catchment outfalls, as well as small (1 &#x2013; 2 ha) agricultural and forested catchments within both intervention catchment to aid in model calibration. It has been assumed that runoff measurement at outfall will occur through the construction of concrete flumes, and runoff measurements of small catchments by rectangular or v-notch weirs, and this has been reflected in the budget.

Detailed Catchment and Agricultural Survey: A detailed catchment and socio-economic survey will be conducted in order to provide hydrogeologic data, a demographic and agricultural profile and to ground-truth land-use/vegetation data and catchment topography. On site constraints and landowner boundaries will be mapped in addition to on-site soil infiltration testing.

Hydrologic Model Selection, Setup, Calibration and Validation: An appropriate hydrologic model for the catchments will be selected and a model constructed. Following final wet-season precipitation in October, modelling calibration and validation will occur and a coarse water-balance model will be developed to provide temporal context on water surplus and deficit.</description>
  <description rain:coding="(CAP,R-D,L-P,INF),(Capacity Development,Research and Development,Lobby and Promotion,Infrastructure)" rain:description="RAIN project typology" rain:type="type" type="3">R-D</description>
  <description akvo:type="5" rain:type="d_summary" type="1">The proposed 3R projects will be implemented in Tanglichowk Village Development Committee (VDC). In addition to a complete catchment and hydrologic assessment of these catchments Rainwater Jars have been previously surveyed and are proposed by NEWAH to be constructed. Additionally the community has requested rainwater harvesting jars in additional VDC&apos;s outside the proposed 3R catchments: in Phinam, Masel and Nareswor VDCs as well as some parts of Gorkha Municipality.</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (social)" type="1">The standard NEWAH approach actively includes groups disadvantaged by gender, caste and religion, and a Gender and Social Inclusion (GESI) approach during planning, capacity building and paid job opportunities will be used. An accessible and equitable water supply systems increases social well-being as less time is spent on water collection by girls and women, resulting in an increased enrollment in schools. A safe water supply system reduces instances of easily preventable disease reducing the financial burden of sickness and improving social harmony.

In order to ensure community participation and to build trust, monitoring will be undertaken by intervention community and recorded manually for monthly entry by NEWAH&apos;s PME team. Monitoring equipment will also be installed in a participatory manner utilizing local labour and materials when possible.</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (environmental)" type="1">Through the retention and recharge of peak flow runoff, anthropogenic erosion will be decreased reducing impacts on downstream aquatic ecosystems. Revegetation, if proposed, will be conducted in a manner conducive to promoting ecosystem biodiversity. Through proposed education the community will have a greater understanding of natural catchment processes contributing to improved community management practices and improved environmental health.

An initial site visit to the intervention catchment will be conducted and catchment areas delineated. The purpose of the initial investigation will be to gather context and scope potential locations for runoff monitoring equipment and rainfall gauges. NEWAH will liaise with BSP to apply their developed Area Selection Tool to the catchment to confirm the catchment is appropriate for a 3R pilot.

Specific 3R intervention measures will not be known until a catchment assessment and hydrologic modelling is complete but may include decentralised measures such as:
&#x2022;	Erosion prevention and slope stabilization
&#x2022;	Revegetation to improve infiltration and/or soil water retention
&#x2022;	Terracing, bunds or eyebrow pits construction to promote infiltration.
&#x2022;	Sub-surface infiltration measures</description>
  <description rain:coding="(WASH,3R,MUS,BDEV,FSEC,OTH),(WASH,3R,MUS,Business Development,Food Security,Other)" rain:description="Themes: main thematic areas, considering content and results and not main budget allocation" rain:type="d_themes" type="3">WASH,3R,MUS</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (institutional)" type="1">Within the target catchments the VDC V-WASH CC will be the main WASH governing Institutional body to plan and manage the project. NEWAH will also facilitate linkages between the WSUC and the district level Federation of Drinking water and sanitation users Network (FEDWASUN) so that beneficiaries have a sustainable institutional mechanism for raising future concerns. Institutional training is provided to the WSUC through NEWAHs existing processes in addition to biannual support visits for a period of two (2) years post-construction. This visit also develops the capacity of the community and provides refresher training to WSUCs if required.

NEWAH will work in partnership with Water and Sanitation Users Committee (WSUC) and local government WASH structures such as Village Water Supply Sanitation and Hygiene Coordination Committee (V-WASH CC) to provide and promote drinking water services as well as facilitate awareness and education programs. The WSUC will be responsible to mobilise the local communities during the training. They will be involved in managing the local materials like sand, aggregate and stone collection for water supply structure construction and keeping records of all the construction materials received at project site and expenditure made at the project level.</description>
  <description akvo:type="9" rain:type="current_phase" type="1">finished</description>
  <description akvo:type="4" rain:type="subtitle" type="1">in disadvantaged areas of Gorkha district, Nepal</description>
  <description akvo:type="3" rain:type="d_targetgroup" type="3">infra | Local |  households | rural | 
infra | Local |  schools | rural | 
infra | Local |  health centers | rural | 
capdev | District |  government officials | rural |</description>
  <participating-org akvo:ref="464" rain:internal-org-ref="186" rain:organizationcode="Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs" rain:remark="Owner of main programme (DWDG) that funded this project" rain:website="www.rijksoverheid.nl/ministeries/bz" ref="NL-1" role="FUNDING">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs</participating-org>
  <participating-org akvo:ref="518" rain:abbreviation="NEWAH" rain:internal-org-ref="18" rain:website="www.newah.org.np/index.php" role="ACCOUNTABLE">Nepal Water for Health</participating-org>
  <participating-org akvo:ref="35" ref="NL-KVK-34200988" role="ACCOUNTABLE" type="21">RAIN foundation</participating-org>
  <other-identifier owner-name="akvorsr" owner-ref="2289"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier owner-name="rainpms" owner-ref="514" rain:type="id"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier owner-name="rainpms" owner-ref="DWDG_NP13_514" rain:type="abbreviation"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4" rain:activity-status="finished" rain:remark="activity status mapping from IATI to RSR done by RSR import API" xml:lang="EN">finished</activity-status>
  <activity-date rain:date-type="startdate" rain:date-type-remark="changes when contract is signed" type="START-ACTUAL">2013-02-01</activity-date>
  <activity-date rain:date-type="enddate" type="END-PLANNED">2015-12-31</activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>RAIN foundation</organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)20 58 18 250</telephone>
   <email>info@rainfoundation.org</email>
   <website>http://rainfoundation.org</website>
   <mailing-address>Barentszplein 7, 1013 NJ Amsterdam, The Netherlands</mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name rain:type="loc_name">Tanglichowk VDC, Nareswor VDC, Masel VDCs, Gorkha Municipality</name>
   <description rain:type="loc_free">Two subcatchments of Tanglichowk VDC and household interventions in Nareswor and Masel VDCs</description>
   <administrative country="NP" rain:continent="Asia" vocabulary="1">Nepal</administrative>
   <coordinates latitude="27.908272" longitude="84.686737" rain:explanation="centre of project area"></coordinates>
   <location-type code="PPL">populated place</location-type>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name rain:encoding="ISO 3166-2" rain:type="loc_iso31662">NP-DH</name>
   <location-type code="ADM1"></location-type>
   <rain:geojson rain:encoding="geoJSON" rain:status="no geoJSON data available yet" rain:type="loc_geojson"></rain:geojson>
   <rain:subdivision rain:encoding="none" rain:type="subdivision">Baglung</rain:subdivision>
  </location>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="100" vocabulary="DAC">agricultural production / food security</sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="DAC-3">wash projects</sector>
  <budget rain:budgettype="contracted" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Other" akvo:type="2" currency="EUR" rain:type="other" value-date="2015-12-31">169857</value>
   <rain:value currency="EUR" type="total contracted" value-date="2015-12-31">169857</rain:value>
  </budget>
  <document-link akvo:photo-id="DWDG_NP13_514_20140411_130749.jpg" format="APPLICATION/JPG" url="https://data.rainfoundation.org/pmspicture/DWDG_NP13_514_20140411_130749.jpg">
   <title>Piloting the 3R approach</title>
   <category code="A08">Image link</category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" rain:description="infrastructure data" rain:infradata_id="20" type="1">
   <title rain:systemlevel="Health" rain:systemstorage="tan.ferr.rt" rain:systemtype="rooftop">type :rooftop | level : health | storage: tan.ferr.rt</title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="systems" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of systems</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="men" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of women reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="m3domestic" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Volume for domestic use in m3</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" rain:description="infrastructure data" rain:infradata_id="19" type="1">
   <title rain:systemlevel="School" rain:systemstorage="tan.ferr.rt" rain:systemtype="rooftop">type :rooftop | level : school | storage: tan.ferr.rt</title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="girls" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of girls reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="women" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of women reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="men" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of women reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="systems" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of systems</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="m3domestic" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Volume for domestic use in m3</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="boys" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of boys reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="850"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" rain:description="infrastructure data" rain:infradata_id="18" type="1">
   <title rain:systemlevel="Household" rain:systemstorage="tan.jar.rt" rain:systemtype="rooftop">type :rooftop | level : household | storage: tan.jar.rt</title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="men" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of women reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="172"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="women" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of women reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="186"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="m3domestic" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Volume for domestic use in m3</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="m3productive" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Volume for productive use in m3</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="255"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="girls" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of girls reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="59"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="boys" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of boys reached</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="66"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1" rain:field="systems" rain:measure="Unit">
    <title>Number of systems</title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output2" type="1">
   <title>122 household level RWH infra of 6m3</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output1" type="1">
   <title>8 community level RWH infra of 20m3</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output5" type="1">
   <title>Formation + training of 61 people in 3 water user commiteesc</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output3" type="1">
   <title>Hydrologic Monitoring and Modelling, 3R Opportunity mapping</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output4" type="1">
   <title>Upstream MUS expansion of RWH through sub-surface storage</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" rain:description="infrastructure data" rain:infradata_id="21" type="1">
   <title rain:systemlevel="Community" rain:systemstorage="pon.cem.sr" rain:systemtype="surface runoff">type :surface runoff | level : community | storage: pon.cem.sr</title>
  </result>
  <activity-website>http://rsr.akvo.org/project/2289/</activity-website>
  <rain:budget budgettype="actual" type="2">
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
  </rain:budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
