<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-34200988_DWDG_NP14_615</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-34200988" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RAIN foundation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boosting RWH entrepreneurship</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F,I,T</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nepal&#x2019;s access to water and sanitation is improving, access to improved water sources (80%+) is on target to meet the MDGs by 2015. Sanitation (48%) however is lagging behind, and even the &#x201C;improved&#x201D; water sources are not adequate as nearly half (43%) are not functioning properly (WASH Status Report 2011). Many systems installed, drinking or sanitation related, are not properly maintained and because of many reasons maintenance service is not reliable. In many projects to address these issues, the approach to date has been single solution approach based, often focused on installing the equipment (drinking water system, toilet, treatment plant) without assessing long-term maintenance. Many times, civil contractors or masons are hired to build the system designed by project-based NGOs, so when the project finishes the civil contractor/mason has no incentive or liability for longer-term maintenance. What we have seen is this resulting in broken down systems over time.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the course of 2014 to mid-2015, SmartPaani plans to setup of 11 urban nodes across Nepal, centered in municipalities with a high potential demand for rainwater harvesting and other water conservation technologies. This will expand SmartPaani services across Nepal and along with it rainwater harvesting and other water conservation technologies; it will create a network of independent entrepreneurs (or increase the capacity of existing entrepreneurs).</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SmartPaani Pvt. Ltd is expanding to 11 Urban Nodal Points across Nepal using a model similar to the franchise model used globally. This proposal outlines our request for support from the RAIN Foundation for 5 out of 11 of the UNPs. This is in-line with RAIN&#x2019;s goal to work more with the private sector to expand rainwater harvesting and also a way to support some of the trained masons that RAIN has set up across Nepal with its other partners, by giving them long-term legitimacy</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SmartPaani Pvt. Ltd is proposing collaboration with RAIN Foundation to increase the adoption of rainwater harvesting across Nepal by setting up SmartPaani Urban Nodal Points across the country. SmartPaani is looking at collaborating with RAIN for the expansion into 5 of the UNPs. This proposal outlines the key investments and activities required to bring this to fruition and establishing a path-breaking collaboration between a foundation (RAIN) and the private sector (SmartPaani) to promote RWH</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SmartPaani will develop a conceptual business plan, conduct market research and collect data on household and institutional level, they identify entrepreneurs and develop business plans. They will also establish UNP&#x2019;s by providing technical/business support and trainings, installations and exchange trips and learning experiences, and advertising on the UNP&#x2019;s nationally and regionally.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The beneficiaries from establishing three entrepreneurs in municipalities across Nepal are 3 types; a) value-chain beneficiaries (entrepreneur, employee, suppliers, etc) and b) direct beneficiaries from each installation (household, school, institution).

a)	Value-Chain Beneficiaries: After almost 3 years of operation, SmartPaani has 15 full-time employees in Kathmandu along with several part-time interns and consultants. Since we are targeting medium-sized municipalities, we expect the nodes to employ between 5-10 people over a similar time period. 
Additional benefits will be distributed down the value-chain, as this is a business that uses raw materials like pipes, tanks, sand, and gravel, to create systems including large biosand filters and greywater recycling systems. 

b)	 Direct beneficiaries: SmartPaani has installed more than 220 systems in under 3-years of operation. While this is in the capital, the nodes in medium-sized municipalities will target generating similar numbers around 150 for each node over a 3-year period.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This information will soon be available</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH,BDEV</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">finished</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">through a decentralised network of franchise takers</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34200988" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RAIN foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Simavi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smart Paani</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="2371">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">akvorsr</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2014-09-01</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2015-09-30</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RAIN foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)20 58 18 250</telephone>
   <email>info@rainfoundation.org</email>
   <website>http://rainfoundation.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Barentszplein 7, 1013 NJ Amsterdam, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </description>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>27.70000185.333328</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
  </location>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">agricultural production / food security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">wash projects</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2015-09-30">21781</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/JPG" url="https://data.rainfoundation.org/pmspicture/DWDG_NP14_615_20141113_150000.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://rainfoundation.org/project/NL-KVK-34200988_DWDG_NP14_615">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activity website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial report on the funds invested by RAIN and the predicted ROI of the investment</narrative>
   </title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding plan to seek venture capital for SmartPaani to expand and support an increased network of</narrative>
   </title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Market Research Summary</narrative>
   </title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Set up of 6 UNPs</narrative>
   </title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Simple business plans for 6 UNPs</narrative>
   </title>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
