<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="1.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="1.03" rain:generator="/iati/iatiactivities_v22" rain:version="1.01" version="1.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:rain="http://data.rainfoundation.org" xmlns:version="2.0">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-34200988_DWDG_ET12_465</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org rain:organisationtype="international NGO" rain:url="http://rainfoundation.org" ref="NL-KVK-34200988" type="21">RAIN foundation</reporting-org>
  <title>GLOW-Guided learning on Water and Sanitation</title>
  <description rain:coding="(CAP,R-D,L-P,INF),(Capacity Development,Research and Development,Lobby and Promotion,Infrastructure)" rain:description="RAIN project typology" rain:type="type" type="3">-</description>
  <description akvo:type="7" rain:type="d_activities" type="1">Add text:</description>
  <description akvo:type="4" rain:type="subtitle" type="1">Capacity building for sustainable WASH</description>
  <description akvo:type="5" rain:type="d_summary" type="1">Ethiopia faces problems in terms of rural water supply and sanitation coverage aggravated by a high percentage of non-functioning systems. The Woreda water and Health Desks are the crucial factor in supporting the development and operation of water supply and sanitation systems. The difficulty is that the training staff working at this level received does not allow them to provide the necessary support to WASH committees responsible for the day to day management of water system. Most of them have received training at a Technical and Vocational Training Centre (TVETC) which unfortunately is more focused on theory. Therefore, this project focuses on building the capacity of the Wereda staffs to reduce the WASH related problems through Guided Learning on Water and Sanitation (GLOW).</description>
  <description akvo:type="6" rain:type="d_context" type="1">Ethiopia is one the eight countries where the Dutch WASH Alliance Program is working. The program works on water, sanitation and hygiene components working in the two regions of Oromia and Afar. In these regions, it mainly focuses on pastoralist and communities where access to WASH service is relatively difficult creating more burden to women and children. The program will run until 2015 targeting the marginalized.
Currently it is working with its alliance member NGOs composed of AMREF-Ethiopia, HCS-RiPPLE, HOAREC, WaterAid and MetaMeta.</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability combined" type="1">Financial sustainability : Sustainability is at the core of the WASH Alliance programme. One of the key learnings from past decades, confirmed and strengthened in our contextual analyses, is that many attempts to make WASH programmes more sustainable have not been successful. Remedial actions changed over time, but attempts had in common that they were input-based, donor driven and mono-sectoral, focussing on just one aspect of sustainability. The WASH Alliance aims at creating a paradigm shift, with the full commitment of all Southern and Northern partner organisations to integrate five strategic principles that cover and connect Financial, Institutional, Environmental, Technical and Social aspects of sustainability. These principles, together given the acronym &#x2018;FIETS&#x2019;, were discussed with Southern stakeholders, who welcomed the principles as a departure from the conventional donor driven-approach. 

Financial Sustainability:
Financial Sustainability refers to the establishment of local financial potential for the strengthening of water, sanitation and hygiene initiatives. Financing is available to provide and sustain WASH investments at household, community and business level.

Institutional Sustainability:
Institutional sustainability in the WASH sector means interventions that ensure systems and procedures at the local level are functional and meet the demand of users of water and sanitation services. Households and other water users, authorities and service providers at the local and the national level are clear on their own roles, tasks and responsibilities and are capable of fulfilling these roles effectively, while working together with other stakeholders in the WASH chain. 

Environmental Sustainability:
A systematic approach to environmental sustainability is required in order to ensure the management of water and sanitation resources for current and future generations, in response to increased water scarcity and pollution of water sources.

Technological sustainability:
Technologies in the WASH sector, also called watsan technologies, concern hardware facilities for safe water collection (such as hand pumps, rainwater harvesting, water stand post and kiosks) and safe sanitation (such as toilets, collection, treatment, re-use).

Social Sustainability:
Social Sustainability encompasses social, cultural, political and religious beliefs, attitudes, practices, relations and last but not least: rights. As such we define social sustainability in the context of the WASH alliance as &#xB4;the realization and sustaining of the social conditions or prerequisites that are essential in order to be able to realize the right to water and sanitation, both from the perspective of rights holders and duty bearers&#xB4;.</description>
  <description rain:coding="(ADV,INT,IMP),(Advice, Intelligence, Implementation)" rain:description="RAIN Services offered" rain:type="services" type="3">IMP</description>
  <description akvo:type="8" rain:type="d_objectives" type="2">It is essential, also in the context of the Dutch WASH Alliance, to strengthen the capacity at Woreda level to better support the communities and to ensure that some very practical training is provided to WASH committees that truly helps them to manage their systems. 

The capacity building problem has been the reason for MetaMeta in collaboration with RiPPLE, SNV, the TVETC and the university in Hawassa to establish a refresher course for Woreda level staff.</description>
  <description rain:description="General (short) project description" rain:type="description" type="3">It is proposed that the GLOWS training will be used as a key ingredient to build the capacity of crucial partners for the Dutch WASH Alliance including trainers and Woreda level staff and the reap the additional benefits of obtaining good insight in the problems at hand in different Kebeles. The emphasis in 2011 will be on Oromiya but a similar approach can be envisaged for Afar in 2012.

The GLOWS training will be led by MetaMeta in collaboration with RiPPLE and trainers from local training institutions (TVETC, University) and the Water Bureau. An important advantage is that the modular self-learning approach makes it feasible to combine the Training of Trainers (TOT) is and the training of Woreda staff. This implies that the trainers and the trainees all start with the programme at the same time, with the trainers being in close contact with MetaMeta and RiPPLE. 

In this way we can train at least some 16 Woreda staff and some 8 trainers and resource persons in the first training, and this may leave a few slots for some others.  

Training programme
Trainees will be selected in consultation with Woreda management and based on the concept that in each participating Woreda a group of 4 trainees will be selected who will go to the training together and doing several of the activities in their own office and in communities in their Woredas. Trainers and resource persons will come twice to the trainees to review and support their work. 

The overall course requires an input from the trainees of some 160 hours distributed over a period of some 4 months, but in the last month already a start can be made with practical improvements. Also experienced trainees can do the training faster as it is based on guided self-learning.

Learning and review workshop    
In the third month of the training a very important workshop will take place where the first WASH assessment and action plans are being reviewed by the team leaders from MetaMeta and RiPPLE and specific (technical, financial and organizational) problems will be identified. The review includes the training results, the WASH assessments and the action plans.  It will be explored if some of the other Dutch WASH Alliance partners and particularly WASTE and Practica can participate as well as this will give a good opportunity to identify possible concrete problems that they can help solve. As part of this workshop more detailed implementation plans will be made including the development of WASH action plans for other Kebeles and the organization of a training approach of WASH committees. 

After the workshop the trainers and trainees will go back to the communities and Kebeles to jointly with the communities complete the action plans and develop specific proposals for interventions that would require external support including the rehabilitation of existing facilities and the development of new facilities. It is envisaged that several of these interventions can be taken up under the Dutch WASH Alliance early in 2012. 

Parallel activities
In parallel with the training other activities will be initiated including: 
&#x2022; The development of specific support materials including some information on the use of water ponds and some video materials that can support training and advocacy
&#x2022; The development of a concept note on local financing and possibilities for micro credit
&#x2022; The development of a concept note on possible private sector support for construction, maintenance and repairs 
&#x2022; The preparation of a training package for WASH committees</description>
  <description rain:coding="(F,I,E,T,S),(Financial, Institutional, Environmental, Technical, Social)" rain:description="Subjects: main sustainability elements, considering content and results and not main budget allocation" rain:type="d_subjects" type="3">S</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (financial)" type="1">Sustainability is at the core of the WASH Alliance programme. One of the key learnings from past decades, confirmed and strengthened in our contextual analyses, is that many attempts to make WASH programmes more sustainable have not been successful. Remedial actions changed over time, but attempts had in common that they were input-based, donor driven and mono-sectoral, focussing on just one aspect of sustainability. The WASH Alliance aims at creating a paradigm shift, with the full commitment of all Southern and Northern partner organisations to integrate five strategic principles that cover and connect Financial, Institutional, Environmental, Technical and Social aspects of sustainability. These principles, together given the acronym &#x2018;FIETS&#x2019;, were discussed with Southern stakeholders, who welcomed the principles as a departure from the conventional donor driven-approach. 

Financial Sustainability:
Financial Sustainability refers to the establishment of local financial potential for the strengthening of water, sanitation and hygiene initiatives. Financing is available to provide and sustain WASH investments at household, community and business level.

Institutional Sustainability:
Institutional sustainability in the WASH sector means interventions that ensure systems and procedures at the local level are functional and meet the demand of users of water and sanitation services. Households and other water users, authorities and service providers at the local and the national level are clear on their own roles, tasks and responsibilities and are capable of fulfilling these roles effectively, while working together with other stakeholders in the WASH chain. 

Environmental Sustainability:
A systematic approach to environmental sustainability is required in order to ensure the management of water and sanitation resources for current and future generations, in response to increased water scarcity and pollution of water sources.

Technological sustainability:
Technologies in the WASH sector, also called watsan technologies, concern hardware facilities for safe water collection (such as hand pumps, rainwater harvesting, water stand post and kiosks) and safe sanitation (such as toilets, collection, treatment, re-use).

Social Sustainability:
Social Sustainability encompasses social, cultural, political and religious beliefs, attitudes, practices, relations and last but not least: rights. As such we define social sustainability in the context of the WASH alliance as &#xB4;the realization and sustaining of the social conditions or prerequisites that are essential in order to be able to realize the right to water and sanitation, both from the perspective of rights holders and duty bearers&#xB4;.</description>
  <description rain:coding="(WASH,3R,MUS,BDEV,FSEC,OTH),(WASH,3R,MUS,Business Development,Food Security,Other)" rain:description="Themes: main thematic areas, considering content and results and not main budget allocation" rain:type="d_themes" type="3">WASH</description>
  <description akvo:type="9" rain:type="current_phase" type="1">finished</description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (environmental)" type="1"></description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (institutional)" type="1"></description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (social)" type="1"></description>
  <description akvo:type="10" rain:type="sustainability (technical)" type="1"></description>
  <description akvo:type="3" rain:type="d_targetgroup" type="3"></description>
  <description rain:type="d_duration_months" type="3"></description>
  <participating-org akvo:ref="464" rain:internal-org-ref="186" rain:organizationcode="Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs" rain:remark="Owner of main programme (DWDG) that funded this project" rain:website="www.rijksoverheid.nl/ministeries/bz" ref="NL-1" role="FUNDING">Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs</participating-org>
  <participating-org akvo:ref="35" ref="NL-KVK-34200988" role="ACCOUNTABLE" type="21">RAIN foundation</participating-org>
  <participating-org akvo:ref="730" rain:abbreviation="RIPPLE" rain:internal-org-ref="132" rain:website="www.rippleethiopia.org" role="ACCOUNTABLE">RIPPLE</participating-org>
  <other-identifier owner-name="akvorsr" owner-ref="392"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier owner-name="rainpms" owner-ref="465" rain:type="id"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier owner-name="rainpms" owner-ref="DWDG_ET12_465" rain:type="abbreviation"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4" rain:activity-status="finished" rain:remark="activity status mapping from IATI to RSR done by RSR import API" xml:lang="EN">finished</activity-status>
  <activity-date rain:date-type="startdate" rain:date-type-remark="changes when contract is signed" type="START-ACTUAL">2012-01-27</activity-date>
  <activity-date rain:date-type="enddate" type="END-PLANNED">2012-12-31</activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>RAIN foundation</organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)20 58 18 250</telephone>
   <email>info@rainfoundation.org</email>
   <website>http://rainfoundation.org</website>
   <mailing-address>Barentszplein 7, 1013 NJ Amsterdam, The Netherlands</mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <name rain:type="loc_name">Gelemso, Meiso, Meta, Chinakson</name>
   <administrative country="ET" rain:continent="Africa" vocabulary="1">Ethiopia</administrative>
   <coordinates latitude="8.816000" longitude="40.515999" rain:explanation="centre of project area"></coordinates>
   <description rain:type="loc_free"></description>
   <location-type code="PPL">populated place</location-type>
  </location>
  <location>
   <location-type code="ADM1"></location-type>
   <name rain:encoding="ISO 3166-2" rain:type="loc_iso31662"></name>
   <rain:geojson rain:encoding="geoJSON" rain:status="no geoJSON data available yet" rain:type="loc_geojson"></rain:geojson>
   <rain:subdivision rain:encoding="none" rain:type="subdivision">West and East Hararghe in Oromiya</rain:subdivision>
  </location>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="100" vocabulary="DAC">agricultural production / food security</sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="DAC-3">wash projects</sector>
  <budget rain:budgettype="contracted" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
  </budget>
  <document-link akvo:photo-id="DWDG_ET12_465_20140505_102337.jpg" format="APPLICATION/JPG" url="https://data.rainfoundation.org/pmspicture/DWDG_ET12_465_20140505_102337.jpg">
   <title>Bore hole drilling</title>
   <category code="A08">Image link</category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output1" type="1">
   <title>25-30 trainers, resource persons and Woreda staff trained</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output2" type="1">
   <title>Concrete proposals for WASH improvements</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output3" type="1">
   <title>Intervention plans for 4 Woredas</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output4" type="1">
   <title>Proposal for capacity building activities</title>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" rain:type="d_output5" type="1">
   <title>Proposal for rehabilitation and new constructions</title>
  </result>
  <activity-website>http://rsr.akvo.org/project/392/</activity-website>
  <rain:budget budgettype="actual" type="2">
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-31"></period-end>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-27"></period-start>
  </rain:budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
