<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IT-CF-97091470589-35-100</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IT-CF-97091470589" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS onlus</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen protective environment for women and girls in Yemen</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Yemeni Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs), Returnees and Host Communities in Yemen &#x2013; all ages, males and females &lt;BR&gt;- Women and girls at risk of violence and abuse provided with quality services &lt;BR&gt;- Community members, Leaders and Youth for awareness &lt;BR&gt;- Local associations engaged in social-economic empowerment of women, including women protection activities. &lt;BR&gt;- Staff and volunteers from the services providers (including MoSAL) in the South trained, aimed to strengthen their capacities on women protection service delivery. &lt;BR&gt;- Police officers and local authorities in the South trained in women protection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1: To strengthen the capacity of 216 staff/volunteers of local actors to offer quality women protection services for conflict affected communities in 8 governorates in Yemen &lt;BR&gt;Objective 2: To assure availability of local quality services for 2.688 women protection cases (1.080 per year) by supporting 16 local associations in service delivery &lt;BR&gt;Objective 3: To strengthening the self-esteem and self-reliance for 1.440 women protection cases (480 per year). &lt;BR&gt;Objective 4: To enhance community awareness on women protection - prevention and response targeting annually 1.750 beneficiaries, focussing on community leaders and youth</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main purpose of this project will be to strengthen prevention and response to women protection issues in Yemen.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Ferdous Association of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al-Usra Seeda Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Atta Foundation for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baqis Association for Women and Child care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basma Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection and Care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daoud Al-Jilani Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eiwa Social Foundation for Relief and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="IT-CF-97091470589" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS onlus</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mawada Foundation for Child care</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozn Charity Social Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Foundation for Health Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000000592" crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands - Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Orphans&apos; Development Foundation O.D.F.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wama Organization for Development and Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Scouts Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS Humanitarian Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Mission</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evelyn Lernout</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>yemen@intersos.org</email>
   <website>http://www.intersos.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social-economic empowerment for women and girls Women protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="35100-02">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USS" value-date="2020-08-13">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000000592" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="IT-CF-97091470589-35-100" ref="IT-CF-97091470589" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="35100-03">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USS" value-date="2021-01-28">404750</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000000592" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="IT-CF-97091470589-35-100" ref="IT-CF-97091470589" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="35100-01">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USS" value-date="2018-12-13">550000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000000592" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="IT-CF-97091470589-35-100" ref="IT-CF-97091470589" type="21"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Objective 4: Community awareness on GBV prevention and response">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">1194</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Objective 3: Strengthening self-esteem and self-reliance for vulnerable women and girls">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">127667.8</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Objective 2: Availability of local quality services for women protection">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">13028.17</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Objective 1: Capacity building local actors in women protection">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">64469.45</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Operational support cost">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">89848.31</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="[interim #2] Objective 1: Capacity building local actors in women protection">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">144002.13</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="[interim #2] Objective 3: Strengthening self-esteem and self-reliance for vulnerable women and girls">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">239747.4</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="[interim #2] Objective 4: Community awareness on GBV prevention and response">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">3474.97</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="[interim #2] Objective 2: Availability of local quality services for women protection">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">71159.41</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="[interim #2] Operational support cost">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">90700.94</value>
  </transaction>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1: To strengthen the capacity of 216 staff/volunteers of local actors to offer quality women protection services for conflict-affected communities in 8 governorates in Yemen</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[YEAR 1] Capacity building for CBOs INTERSOS held coordination and kick-off meeting with CBOs in South and North to explain project&#x2019;s activities. During the meeting, INTERSOS further assessed the capacity of the CBOs, and reconfirmed the need to further develop their technical skills in the protection fieldwith specific focus on women protection. During September 2019, INTERSOS worked with the selected CBOs, to identify gaps in individual case management (ICM),to plan livelihood courses and to schedule the trainings to be conducted in October 2019. Referral pathways and mechanisms were established within the CBOs, to ensure a comprehensive response to the needs of cases through the available services. Capacity building for national CBOs: INTERSOS conducted 4 capacity building programs for local actors/MoSAL and INTERSOS protection staff aiming to strengthen their capacities on GBV prevention and response. - Planned activity: 4-day training on individual case management (ICM) and Information Management System (IMS) for local actors/MOSAL in South for 48 individuals (3 participants from each of the 8 CBOs (including the head of CBO) and 2 people from MoSAL for 8 governorates). - Revised activity: The number of trainings days and the targeted participants was reduced due to the impossibility of conducting trainings in the North. The overall number of training days and beneficiaries targeted in the CM and IMS training in South were 3 training days for 32 beneficiaries (3 people of CBOs X 8 CBOs + 2 people of MoSAL X 4 location) - Implemented activity: During October 2019, INTERSOS conducted training on ICM and IMS for 3 days from 27 to 29 of October 2019 for 8 CBOs partners from Aden, Hadramout North, and Hadramout South) &#x2013; 24 participants (3 men and 21 women). Also, 6 participants from MoSAL Aden and Hadramout (1 man and 5 women) attended the training. The training aimed at building CBOs&apos; and stakeholders&#x2019; capacity to design and implement structured individual case management activities, to bolster a network of service providers and permit the functioning of the referral system, and to develop a solid reporting mechanism for women and child protection. In total 30 participants (4 men and 26 women) attended the training in Aden. Based on the pre-test done at the beginning of the training, 38% of the participants were aware of CM and IMS topics and understood the importance case management in the delivery of protection services. Post-training test was conducted to measure the impact of the training, and 80% showed knowledge and understating of CM and IMS system and general women protection. The participants at the end of the training were more familiar with Case Management steps, SGBV typologies, Child Protection principles, case management tools and information management system. - Planned activity: 2-day Training on PSS for 36 social workers (1 x 36 participants per training x 2 days per training) - Achieved activity: During October, INTERSOS conducted training for Case Management Supervisor, Socal workers, SGBV SW, PwSN CMS, and ASR Social workers on PSS for 2 days from 29 to 30 of October for 30 INTERSOS staff (12 men and 18 women) from (Aden, Lahj, and Hadramout governments). Based on the pre-test done at the beginning of the training a percentage of (42%) were aware of PSS topic and understand the stander procedures to deliver PSS during the CM and providing protection services. At the end of the training, a post-test was done for the participants to measure the impact of the training, the test indicates a percentage of (92%) gained more knowledge and understating PSS standard procedures as well delivering PSS for cases correctly and smoothly following all the protection standers and policies during providing support for affected people. - Planned activity: 2-day Training on International human rights law for 18 lawyers. - Achieved activity: During October 2019, INTERSOS conducted training on International human rights law for 18 lawyers for 2 days from 20 to 21 of October for 18 INTERSOS lawyers (12 men and 6 women) from (Aden, Lahj and Hadramout governments). The training focused on the Human rights concepts, International and regional human rights protection mechanisms, Legal protection of women in accordance with Yemeni laws, and Sexual violence and Yemeni law attitude. During the training participants done some exercise and working group to study more about the best practice of international human rights law and the methods to apply in the field. Based on the pre-test done at the beginning of the training a percentage of (50%) were aware of the International human rights law topic and understand the importance of applying the international law in the Yemeni context. At the end of the training, a post-test was done for the participants to measure the impact of the training, the test indicates a percentage of (68%) gained more knowledge and understating of International human rights law and the best method to implement the exercise during providing protection services. - Planned activity: 2-day Training on PSFA for 18 psychosocial counselors/psychologists - Achieved actitivty: During October 2019, INTERSOS conducted training for Protection Monitors and outreach Volunteers on PSFA for 2 days from 27 to 28 of October for 19 INTERSOS staff (9 men and 10 women) from (Aden, Lahj, and Hadramout governments). Based on the pre-test done at the beginning of the training a percentage of (35%) were aware of PSFA topic and understand the importance of delivering PSFA during providing protection services. At the end of the training, a post-test was done for the participants to measure the impact of the training, the test indicates a percentage of (93%) gained more knowledge and understating of PASF and the best method to implement the exercise during conducting the CM for cases. Activity 1.2: Training for police officers and local authorities on women protection &gt; 168 police officers and local authorities (10 police officers and 4 authority figures per governorate) (min 25% women) annually gained improved skills and knowledge in women protection case management. The number of participants was reduced from 168 to 56 due to the impossibility of conducting trainings in North. The 56 participants (10 police officers and 4 authority representatives per governorate per 4 location) were divided into 2 groups due to the security situation in the South and impossibility of participants from Hadramout to attend the training in Aden. &#x2022; Training for police officers and local authorities on women protection in Aden for 2 days from 22 to 23 October 2019 for 30 participants (22 men and 8 women) from 3 districts in Aden (Al Buraiqa, Dar Sa&#x2019;ad and Basateen). &#x2022; Training for police officers and local authorities on women protection in Mukalla for 2 days from 30 to 31 October 2019 for 30 participants (22 men and 8 women). The trainings focused on Human Rights, human rights protection mechanisms, women legal protection in Yemeni law, and Sexual violence and Yemeni law point of view to women protection, in addition to the importance of applying women protection concept during providing legal services. Here are the results of the Pre-test (55%) vs post-test (70%).
&lt;HR&gt;
[YEAR 2]
Year 2 kick-off meetings were conducted with CBOs in South and North to explain the project objectives and targets for 2020. Project manager and activity coordinators are providing continuous technical guidance on case management, livelihood courses&#x2019; proposals, and implementation planning. 
INTERSOS had to postpone the 4 capacity building programs planned to be conducted for CBOs within the end of 2020 due to COVID-19 pandemic. 
In December 2020, INTERSOS conducted 4 capacity building trainings for partner CBOs, local actors/MoSAL and INTERSOS protection staff, aiming to strengthen their capacities on GBV prevention and response. All trainings were conducted in respect of social distancing .
-	Taining on Individual Case Management (ICM) and GBV Information Management System (IMS)
Original proposal planned activity: 4-days training on individual case management (ICM) and Gender Based Violence Information Management System (IMS) for local actors/MOSAL for 48 individuals (3 participants from each of the CBOs (including the head of CBO) and 2 people from MoSAL for 8 governorates). 
Revised activity: The number of trainings days and the targeted participants was reduced  (due to the impossibility of conducting trainings in the North): 3 days training days for 38 participants (3 people from CBOs X 10 CBOs + 2 people from MoSAL X 4 location)
Implemented activity: From 15 to 17 December 2020, INTERSOS conducted a 3-days training on ICM and GBV IMS for 34 participants (3 men and 31 women) from Aden, Lahj, and Wadi Hadramout and Hadramout Sahel:
- 30 participants from the 10 CBOs in the South (3 men and 27 women). 
- 2 participants from MoSAL Aden (2 women), while MoSAL Lahj and Hadramout apologized for not attending. 
- 2 CMS from INTERSOS (2 women).
The training focused on CBOs&apos; and stakeholders&#x2019; capacity to design and implement structured individual case management. In particular on the introduction to GBV (survivor &#x2013; centered approach), guiding principles, chronological case management steps, response to intimate partner violence for women and girls, response to GBV child survivors, GBV intake form, GBV information management system.
Based on the pre-test conducted at the beginning of the training, only 18% of the participants were aware of ICM and IMS and understood the importance case management in the delivery of protection services. The low result could be linked to CBOs&#x2019; focal points turn over. A post-training test was also conducted to measure the impact of the training, and 91% of the participants showed knowledge and understating of ICM and its tools, SGBV typologies, CP principles, and IMS.

-	PSS training
Original proposal planned activity: 2-days Training on PSS for 36 social workers (1 x 36 participants per training x 2 days per training)
Revised activity: The number of the targeted participants was reduced  (due to the impossibility of conducting trainings in the North): 2-days training for 30 beneficiaries (2 people from CBOs X 10 CBOs + 10 INTERSOS staff)
Implemented activity: on 20 and 21 December 2020, INTERSOS conducted a PSS training for a total of 30 Social workers (from Aden, Lahj, Hadramout): 20 SWs from CBOs (20 women) and 10 SWs from INTERSOS (5 men and 5 women). 
Based on the pre-test, only 13% of the participants knew the standard procedures of PSS in CM and the provision of protection services, which emphasizes the importance of on job coaching, and of the regular follow up on the services provided by CBO staff. The low result could be linked to CBOs&#x2019; focal points turn over. At the end of the training, a post-test was conducted to measure the impact of the training, and 90% gained more knowledge and understanding of PSS standard procedures as well delivering correctly PSS for cases and smoothly following all the protection standards and policies while providing support to affected people. 

-	PSFA Training
Original porposal planned activity: 2-day Training on PSFA for 18 psychosocial counsellors/psychologists.
Revised activity: The number and typology of participants targeted was modified to give the opportunity to attend to CBOs social workers (2 people from CBOs X 10 CBOs)
Implemented activity: On 22 and 23 December 2020, INTERSOS conducted a 2-days PSFA training for 20 CBOs&#x2019; social workers (20 women) from Aden, Lahj, and Hadramout governorates. 
Based on the pre-test, 25% of the participants were aware of PSFA and understood the importance of PSFA when providing protection services, which also emphasizes the importance of on job coaching, and of the regular follow up on the services provided by CBO staff. The low result could be linked to CBOs&#x2019; focal points turn over. At the end of the training, a post-test was done for the participants to measure the impact of the training; the test indicates that 85% gained knowledge and understating of PSFA and the best methods to apply it during ICM and protection services in general.

-	Training on International Human Rights Law (IHRL) and CRM
Planned activity: 2-days Training on International Human Rights Law (IHRL) and CRM for 18 lawyers (1  x 18 participants per training x 2 days per training) &gt; No revision of the activity done.
Implemented activity: On 23 and 24 December 2020, INTERSOS conducted a 2-days training on IHRL for 18 lawyers (13 men and 5 women) from Aden, Lahj and Hadramout governorates. 
The training focused on the International Human Rights Law, Yemeni civil law (personal act law): focused on women and girls protection, procedures and gaps. In addition, a session dedicated to INTERSOS CRM SoPs, and feedback and complaint mechanisms available for staff, beneficiaries, partners and stakeholders, was given to the lawyers. During the training, participants used cases studies and working groups to understand the application of IHRL in their daily work. Based on the pre-test 62% were aware of IHRL and understood the importance of applying it in the Yemeni context. At the end of the training, a post-test was conducted to measure the impact of the training, and of (87%) gained knowledge and understating of IHRL and the best methods to apply it during the provision of legal services.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff/volunteers of local CBOs and MoSAL gain improved skills and knowledge in GBV case management (75% women and 25% men), with refresher annually.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="32"></target>
     <actual value="30"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="38">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">BLA BLA BLA</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="34"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Police officers and local authorities (min 25% women) annually gained improved skills and knowledge in GBV case management.</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="56"></target>
     <actual value="60"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="56"></target>
     <actual value="61"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 2: To assure availability of local quality services for 2.688 women protection cases (1.080 per year) by supporting 16 local associations in service delivery</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[YEAR 1] Continuously monitor and audit case management services of 16 local CBOs In September 2019, INTERSOS established 11 community centers (out of the 16 planned to be established in year 1) in collaboration with the selected CBOs. The aim of establishing a safe space inside every CBO was to ensure a private place to conduct case management and to extend women protection services through a community-based approach. During December 2019, added/established 3 more community centers. INTERSOS signed MoUs with 10 CBOs in the South and 4 CBOs in the North on 31 December 2019, reaching 14 community centers (out of the 16 planned for Year 1). Further assessment was conducted in South and North during year 1, to reach the targeted number of CBOs planned in the project proposal, during the second year of implementation. The evaluation was based on the following criteria: &#x2022; CBOs capacity &#x2022; CBOs previous experience in livelihood programs &#x2022; CBOs experience in protection, particularly in women protection (ICM, awareness and livelihood) &#x2022; CBOs access to vulnerable &#x2013; affect people &#x2022; CBOs structure and space to establish a community center to receive cases 9 CBOs in South and North were already partners during September and October 2019 and 5 CBOs were assessed as possible project partners for impelemnting activities as follow: &#x2022; 2 CBOs in Hajja governorate were assessed as project partners to extend project geographical coverage and upon request of SCAMCHA to fill the gap in Hajja governorate with project activities especially livelihood. &#x2022; 1 CBO was added to cover Amant Al-Asmah governorate. &#x2022; 2 CBOs were added in Lahj governorate to extended project geographical coverage in the South. In Ibb governorate INTERSOS put 2 CBOs on hold as there is no ongoing project in the governorate, by the time INTERSOS will start a project in Ibb, the activities will be easy to pick-up/resume.
&lt;HR&gt;
[YEAR2]
During year 2, INTERSOS continued to work with 14 safe spaces established from year 1. The aim of establishing a safe space inside every CBO is to extend women protection services, through a community-based approach, and to ensure that organizations selected can provide quality case management for women.
INTERSOS renewed MoUs with 28 dedicated volunteers in the CBOs for the second year of the project, 20 volunteers in South CBOs, and 8 volunteers in North. Meanwhile suspended 2 CBOs and 4 volunteers in North, Ibb location, for future action after having a project in the governorate.

The Community Centre Focal Point and Supervisor (Volunteers) are responsible for the efficient and correct implementation of referral mechanisms for protection cases in the CC among IDPs and host communities. 
Although collective activities were suspended due to the COVID-19, individual case management was ongoing ensuring social distancing between client and counselor. During the suspension period, project team was working in rotation according to INTERSOS preventive measures but ensured full coverage and support to CBOs volunteers.
In December 2020, INTERSOS team provided support on case management to CBO for the closure of 2020 and the transfer of cases to 2021.
INTERSOS project&#x2019;s team coordinated with other INTERSOS protection projects (DG ECHO-funded (35117) project (protection team) in the South and North, to provide legal support to project partners/CBOs.
Project Manager had missions to North and South to monitor and supervise the implementation of the activities of the project, prepared work plans with the team, and discussed specific cases to agree on the action plan.

South:
PM provided support for the project team during meetings and field visits to CBOs. The activity Coordinator and Reporting officer conducted regular visits and meetings with project partners / CBOs in Aden, Lahj, and Hadramout to provide technical support on case management, follow up, referral pathway system, closure procedures, data management, sessions awareness, and livelihood courses to CBOs and all volunteers. During the suspension of collective activities due to the COVID-19, INTERSOS team maintained regular communication with the CBOs via phone calls and emails to ensure individual case management was ongoing.
Aprail 2020, in Hadramout a curfew was imposed in all the Government, however, CBO staff was available to guarantee assistance to cases in need. 

North:
PM and AC conducted a field visits to the CBOs in Sana&apos;a and Amant Al-Asmah, to provide technical guidance and support to the CBOs&#x2019; focal point and supervisor to deliver good CM for cases following case management procedures and to use referral pathway system. As well as to support the CBOs within the implementation of livelihood courses and the ,management of database of the cases. During the suspension of collective activities due to the COVID-19, INTERSOS team maintained regular communication with the CBOs via phone calls and emails to ensure individual case management was ongoing.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&gt; % of GBV survivors supported with emergency cash support for protection</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="23.5"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local associations provide quality case management services for GBV survivors and individuals at risk</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="13"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16"></target>
     <actual value="14"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local associations report on monthly basis on GBV cases received into the GBV IMS through INTERSOS</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="13"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="16"></target>
     <actual value="14"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBV survivors receive quality case management services provided by local associations</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1100"></target>
     <actual value="1693"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="448"></target>
     <actual value="286"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 4: To enhance community awareness on GBV prevention and response, focusing on community leaders, authorities and youth</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[YEAR 1] INTERSOS focused on the awareness sessions conducted by project partners on protection related issues in general (rights-based approach &#x2013; the right to education, right to basic social services, right to identity and documentation, incl. (but not exclusively) GBV and reproductive health and rights): 1. Gender roles and gender equality basic principles 2. Good parenting &amp; child protection 3. Importance of Girls Education 4. Intimate partner violence &amp; GBV 5. Family Planning and basic RHRs 6. Early marriage (risk and consequences, including consequences related to early pregnancy) 7. Conflict mitigation techniques will be addressed as a cross-cutting issue. Activity 4.1: Community awareness sessions &gt; October 2019: INTERSOS conducted through its partners&#x2019; CBOs in South 8 awareness sessions: - 3 awareness sessions in Hadramout Al-Sahel at CBOs - 1 awareness sessions in Hadramout Al-Wadi at CBOs - 4 awareness sessions in Aden at CBOs Total: 175 attendants, 125 HC (11 girls, 114 women, 0 boys, 0 men) 50 IDPs (0 girls, 50 women, 0 boys, 0 men). Note that general awareness sessions in the North were cut from the proposal, due to reasons explained before. Activity 4.2: Awareness raising for community leaders (focus on men) &gt; October 2019: INTERSOS conducted through its partners&#x2019; CBOs in South 8 awareness sessions: - 3 awareness sessions in Hadramout Al-Sahel at CBOs - 1 awareness sessions in Hadramout Al-Wadi at CBOs - 4 awareness sessions in Aden at CBOs Total: 166 attendants, 155 HC (0 girls, 24 women, 0 boys, 131 men) 11 IDPs (0 girls, 0 women, 0 boys, 11 men). Note that awareness raising for community leaders in the North were cut from the proposal, due to reasons explained before. Activity 4.3: Awareness raising for youth (separate sessions for girls and boys) and active participation by main women protection actors in organization of events &gt; October 2019: INTERSOS conducted through its partners&#x2019; CBOs in South 8 awareness sessions: - 3 awareness sessions in Hadramout Al-Sahel at CBOs - 1 awareness sessions in Hadramout Al-Wadi at CBOs - 4 awareness sessions in Aden at CBOs Total: 173 attendants, 119 HC (27 girls, 64 women, 15 boys, 13 men) 54 IDPs (6 girls, 44 women, 0 boys, 4 men). Note that awareness raising for youth in the North were cut from the proposal, due to reasons explained before. INTERSOS CBO partners in South Yemen organized a total of 24 awareness sessions for a total of 514 beneficiaries (159 men, 296 women, 15 boys, 44 girls).399(78%) HC and 115 (22%) IDPs. (66% Female, 34% Male).
&lt;HR&gt;
[YEAR 2]
Between January and July 2020, INTERSOS conducted through project partners a total of 24 awareness sessions on protection related issues, such as rights-based approach &#x2013; the right to education, right to basic social services, right to identity, and documentation, incl. (but not exclusively) GBV and reproductive health and rights . 
Awareness sessions were attended by a total of 602 beneficiaries (150 men, 401 women, 0 boys, 51 girls). Out of the 602 participants, 81% were HC members (485) and 19% IDPs (117), 66% were female and 34% male.
In August and September 2020, INTERSOS resumed the awareness sessions on protection related issues, conducting through project partners a total of 29 awareness sessions and reaching a total of 707 beneficiaries (128 men, 304 women, 95 boys, 180 girls). Out of the 707 participants, 84% were HC members (593) and 16% IDPs (114), 68% were female and 32% male.
In October 2020, INTERSOS conducted through project partners 5 awareness sessions reaching 131 beneficiaries (63 men, 68 women, 0 boys, 0 girls). Out of the 131 participants, 75% were HC members and 25% IDPs, 52% were female and 48% male.
In November 2020 no awareness sessions were conducted as partners were busy in the closure of livelihood trainings (in addition except Lahj, all other partners achieved the targeted awareness sessions).
In December 2020, the 2 remaining awareness sessions were conducted by Lahj CBO for 44 beneficiaries (0 men, 26 women, 0 boys, 18 girls). All participants were HC members and all were female.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Persons (25% men- 75% women) participate in community awareness sessions and increase their awareness about GBV prevention and response organized by local associations</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1920"></target>
     <actual value="1509"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1440"></target>
     <actual value="514"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 3: To strengthening the self-esteem and self-reliance for 1.440 women protection cases (480 per year).</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">[YEAR 1] Organize informal skills trainings (IDP, returnees and host community) for women and girls to enhance their self-reliance and reduce vulnerability Based on previous livelihood courses and FGDs conducted during INTERSOS projects in 2019 and the experience that INTERSOS got from the implementation of livelihood activities under projects funded by other donors, INTERSOS shared with the selected CBOs the most successful (in terms of impact on the beneficiaries&#x2019;) livelihood programs&apos; topics, as follow: &#x2022; Solar system maintenance &#x2022; Smartphone maintenance &#x2022; Photography, Photoshop, and Video &#x2022; Creative writing, Journalism &#x2022; Livestock breeding, Beekeeping, and Fishermen &#x2022; Beauty Salon, Henna, Coiffeur &#x2022; Bakery &#x2022; First Aid &#x2022; Dressmaking and Tailor &#x2022; Enterprise/Business Management &#x2022; Perfume and incense making During last week of September and the beginning of October 2019, INTERSOS received, from the selected CBOs, the proposals of livelihood courses selected by beneficiaries according to the outcomes of the FGD and the shared list of most successful livelihood topics, and started to do the review of the proposal content and budget. In the second week of October 2019, all CBO / project partners both in the South and North started livelihood courses, 14 livelihood courses through CBOs for 210 beneficiaries, at the same time, INTERSOS, through its&#x2019; community centers in Dar Sa&#x2019;ad &#x2013; Aden and Ras Al-Ara &#x2013; Lahj conducted 4 livelihood courses, 2 in each center, for 60 beneficiaries. Each livelihood course targeted 15 beneficiaries. South: 12 livelihood courses for 180 beneficiaries (114 HC and 66 IDPs; 180 Female) North: 6 livelihood courses for 90 beneficiaries (84 HC and 6 IDPs; 90 Female) The total beneficiaries of 18 Livelihood course were 270 beneficiaries (198 HC and 72 IDPs; 270 female and 0 Male) All CBOs conducted FGDs to identify the subject of livelihood trainings according to the beneficiaries&apos; needs. 15 FGDs were conducted for 170 participants (106 HC and 64 IDPs; 170 female and 0 Male). - In the South, 8 FGDs were conducted through 8 CBO/project partners for 80 participants (55 HC and 25 IDPs; 80 female and 196 Male) - In South 4 FGD through INTERSOS (2 in Aden and 2 in Lahj) for 60 participants (28 HC and 32 IDPs; 60 female and 0 Male). - In the North, 3 FGDs were conducted for 30 participants (23 HC and 7 IDPs; 30 female and 0 Male) Livelihood trainings were only accepted/could only start once they were presented to INTERSOS with full cost breakdown and training outline and upon final acceptance by INTERSOS. All livelihood courses conducted by CBOs and INTERSOS were designed to have life skills components aiming to build the beneficiaries&apos; life skills and strengthen their personality for the market. For South and North, by the end of October 2019, all CBOs successfully completed all livelihood courses. CBOs closed the training period and completed the livelihood training with a graduation ceremony for the participants and distributed the livelihood kits.
&lt;HR&gt;
[YEAR 2]  Organize informal skills training (IDP, returnees and host community) for women and girls to enhance their self-reliance and reduce vulnerability 
 	Based on previous livelihood courses conducted during 2019 and the experience that INTERSOS got from the implementation of livelihood activities, INTERSOS project team shared with the selected CBOs the most successful (in terms of impact on the beneficiaries&#x2019;) livelihood programs&apos; topics: beauty salon, henna, coiffeur - bakery - first aid - dressmaking and tailoring - perfume and incense making.

All project partners/CBOs in South and North submitted the proposed livelihood courses selected by beneficiaries, according to the outcomes of the FGDs.
All CBOs conducted FGDs to identify the subject of livelihood trainings according to the beneficiaries&apos; needs.
25 FGDs were conducted for 325 participants (246 HC and 79 IDPs; 319 females and 6 males).
-	South, 20 FGDs were conducted through 10 CBO/project partners for 283 participants (213 HC and 70 IDPs; 277 females and 6 males)
-	North, 5 FGDs were conducted through 4 CBO/project partners for 42 participants (33 HC and 9 IDPs; 42 females and 0 males)
Livelihood trainings were only accepted/could only start once they were presented to INTERSOS with full cost breakdown and training outline and upon final acceptance by INTERSOS and ensuring livelihood courses are designed to have life skills components aiming to build the beneficiaries&apos; life skills and strengthen their personality for the market.
In March 2020, all project partners in South and North started the implementation of livelihood courses but due to the outbreak of COVID-19, all to the trainings were suspended. INTERSOS shared with all CBOs a revised Arabic version of the guidelines for the safe distribution of livelihood kits during COVID-19, based on Food Security Cluster &#x2013; Emergency Livelihood Response Program (RLRP).

70 adolescents were involved in livelihood courses as measure for GBV risk prevention. 4 livelihood courses were conducted and completed successfully, applying COVID-19 preventive measures as follows:
-	2 livelihood courses in the South for 40 adolescents.
-	2 livelihood courses in the North for 30 adolescents</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of beneficiaries in informal skills training report the ability to have adopted positive coping mechanism following the courses and kits distribution</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="80">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">80% reported ability to adopt positive coping mechanisms - thorough PDM</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="56"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and girls (GBV survivors and/or women/girls at risk of GBV) participate in informal skills trainings (IDP and host community)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="270"></target>
     <actual value="270"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="585"></target>
     <actual value="490"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
