<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="168" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/11219" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-ARCIS-HT-14-11219</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Canaan Social Engagement Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Canaan is a rapidly emerging city north of Port-au-Prince in the West Department, now estimated to be between 100,000 and 150,000 residents. Canaan developed after the 2010 earthquake in response to the establishment and operation of a relocation settlement as well as a Haitian government declaration of eminent domain of the surrounding area. The city has received little external assistance from Haitian authorities or the international community. However, Canaan continues to grow with grassroots investments by local households; these investments were estimated at US$100 million as of July 2013.

The lack of government oversight has caused Canaan to grow similarly to informal settlements of Port-au- Prince, with poor access to basic services, construction and urbanization in areas at high exposure to natural hazard, and inadequate waste management systems. Furthermore, social cohesion in Canaan is only in nascent stages, given that most of the residents have been there for approximately two years or less.

This program proposes to build community cohesion by establishing fair community representation structures and engaging the community in common concerns surrounding Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR) and the environment. This work will provide a foundation for future implementing actors in the city to begin work. The program therefore proposes to start in December 2014 and continue for 18 months until May 2016. As this program is one of the first interventions in Canaan, it aims to target the entire population, an estimated 100,000 to 150,000 people. In particular, marginalized groups (including women and youth) will receive greater emphasis to ensure they are fairly represented in community structures.

The overall program goal is to mobilize and organize the communities within Canaan to improve their resilience. This will be accomplished through three programmatic pillars: 

- Social engagement

- Disaster risk reduction

- Environmental engagement

These three pillars correspond to three program objectives:

-Increase community cohesion, representation and capacity to engage national and local government, as well as international organizations

-Communities are better prepared against natural disasters with increased understanding of natural hazards and risks

-Increase community understanding of local environmental concerns and engagement for improving the environmental status.

These objectives will be accomplished by coordinating with the Haitian government and other implementing actors to define a common social engagement approach and to establish community platforms that are representative of the communities. These platforms will engage Haitian authorities and support community assessments in DRR and environmental concerns, as well as the establishment of long-term entities responsible for follow up activities (e.g. establishing Community Intervention Teams with Department of Civil Protection).

The program will be directly implemented by ARC in close coordination with the Haitian Red Cross (HRC). Consultants will be engaged on a punctual basis for surge capacity or technical expertise. The HRC will play a vital role in mobilizing their volunteer network in Canaan to build community cohesion and buy in as well as conduct household level messaging on key messages related to DRR and the environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-53-0196605" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">American Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haitian Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="ARCIS-HT-14-11219" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">American Red Cross</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonathan Garro</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Information Analyst</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>jonathan.garro@redcross.org</email>
   <website>http://www.redcross.org</website>
   <website>http://www.redcross.org/haiti</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="osm_393329">
   <location-id code="393329" vocabulary="G2"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Croix des Bouquets</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Croix des Bouquets, Haiti (admin level 2)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="393329" level="2" vocabulary="G2"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.53577542 -72.05066773</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM2"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Prevention and Preparedness</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.redcross.org/haiti">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
