<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3117" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-MX-11-3117</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building Our Future II: Towards Improving Campesino Families Livelihood from the Sierra Madre of Chiapas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will improve food security and income generation for 1000 smallholder coffee&#x2010;growing families in four cooperatives in the El Triunfo reserve, Sierra Madre of Chiapas. The project will promote alternative sources of food and diversified sources of income in order to reduce dependence on income from coffee production. Activities will promote backyard vegetable gardening, beekeeping, and reactivation of milk, meat, and egg production, both for consumption and for supplementary income. Participants will also be provided
with draft horses to help haul their products to towns and markets. All production components will be strongly supported by appropriate, timely training.
The project is considered an expansion of the current project with partner Campesinos Ecol&#xF3;gicos de la Sierra Madre de Chiapas (CESMACH), launched in 2008 with the support of Green Mountain Coffee Roasters (GMCR).
Heifer will apply the experiences and best practices gained from working with CESMACH communities to address issues of seasonal food insecurity on a larger and more impactful scale &#x2010; covering a significantly larger number of communities to the west of the current area of intervention (Cuxtepeques). Heifer&#x2019;s agricultural,
environmental and values&#x2010;based organizational initiatives also seek to strengthen these communities&#x2019; capacity, access and connection to Green Mountain Coffee Roasters and fellow stakeholders in the fair trade / organic supply chain, strengthening critical long&#x2010;term trade relationships towards sustainable income.
Heifer will lead the development and implementation of activities to achieve these key results:
Result 1: Increased food security and improved nutrition by diversifying farm production and consumption of highly nutritious foods.
Result 2: Increased income by linking farmers to local markets for the sale of surplus produce and byproducts from promoted activities.
Result 3: Strengthened organizational capacity and community service through establishment of Farmer Field Schools and utilization of regional promoters.
The main inputs will include small and medium&#x2010;sized livestock including hogs, hens, rabbits, sheep, beehives, fish, draft horses, vegetable seeds and trees, as well as training to improve organic production of milk, meat, eggs, vegetables and honey. The cattle, horses and poultry will be sourced from local ranchers, so stock will be well adapted to the zone.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Campesinos Ecol&#xF3;gicos de la Sierra Madre de Chiapas (CESMACH)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="22-2270-60" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-MX-11-3117" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Americas Program</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>americas@list.heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_3531011">
   <location-id code="3531011" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chiapas</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chiapas, Mexico (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="3531011" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.5 -92.5</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
