<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3817" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-PE-11-3817</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security Enhancement and Entrepreneurial Development (FEED) Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the Food Security Enhancement and Entrepreneurial Development (FEED) Project, Heifer aims to increase the income and food security of 700 Peruvian women and their families&#x2014;320 original participants and 380 through Heifer&#x2019;s Pass on the Gift (POG) process. FEED will work with eight associations in the Puno region of Peru to support women&#x2019;s economic activities and promote a greater role for women in family and community decision-making.
Puno is one of the poorest departments in Peru. According to the National Institute of Statistics and Information , 41.6 percent of the population of Puno faces extreme poverty, defined as the inability to purchase essential food items. Diets in the communities targeted by this project are nutritionally poor, with food intake limited to noodles, sugar, vegetable oil, drinks and crackers, resulting in severe nutritional deficiencies. According to the United Nations&#x2019; Children&#x2019;s Fund, 30 percent of Puno&#x2019;s children ages 0 to 5 face chronic malnutrition.
Currently, women in the area lack the training and access to key inputs for improved agricultural and livestock production that would strengthen their capacities as &#x201C;bread makers&#x201D; and position them to be &#x201C;bread winners,&#x201D; thus empowering them to take on a greater role in family decision-making. In particular, women need to know how to recognize early warning signs of agricultural issues and practice risk-reducing techniques to minimize their families&#x2019; vulnerability to the annual onset of extreme weather, drought and frost that often result in losses in crops, grains and animals. Women in the target project area are primarily rural Quechua and Aymara&#x2014;groups that are highly vulnerable to poverty due to the ethnic and gender discrimination they face, causing them to have less access to education than their male counterparts, less legal and political representation, less access to professional training and fewer income-earning opportunities. As these women&#x2019;s labor is mostly unpaid, it is undervalued in Peru&#x2019;s patriarchal society, leading women to have little say in household decision-making, particularly regarding household finances.
FEED is a continuation of an existing Heifer project, Departmental Association of Campesina Women of Puno (ADEMUCP) for Food Security in Puno, which has provided initial technical assistance to women&#x2019;s productive associations in Puno since July 1, 2008. Through this project, Heifer has increased women&#x2019;s technical capacities in agriculture and animal husbandry to help them increase and diversify their income and improve family food security and nutrition. FEED will build upon the previous project&#x2019;s success in increasing productivity levels by strengthening the institutional and marketing capacities of eight key associations. These associations will help the women achieve higher production volumes attractive to buyers, lower production costs and allow the women to collectively market their products, thereby integrating the women into agriculturally based value chains. FEED will also increase rural revenues by supporting crafts production&#x2014;a non-farm economic activity with strong marketing potential in the highly touristic project area.
During a project period of three years, Heifer will lead the development and implementation of activities to meet the following three principle objectives by June 30, 2014:
&#x2022; At least 70 percent of women in eight associations will have increased their income by 20 percent through the production and marketing of local agricultural products and handicrafts.
&#x2022; At least 80 percent of women in eight associations will have improved their nutrition and that of their families through the consumption of highly nutritious, locally produced food.
&#x2022; At least 70 percent of women in eight associations will have increased their participation in family decision-making, particularly in relation to household income expenditures.
The beneficiaries of the project will be 700 women organized in eight producer groups belonging to ADEMUCP, which is part of the Farm Confederation of Peru. Heifer Peru has worked with women organized in ADEMUCP in other projects since 2003. Founded in 1947, ADEMUCP includes more than nine provincial associations of women farmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation(s)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer Peru</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="23-1743-02" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-PE-11-3817" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Americas program</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Americas program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>americas@list.heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_3931275">
   <location-id code="3931275" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puno</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Puno, Peru (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="3931275" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-15.0 -70.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
