<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/2969" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-GH-10-2969</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TUNA Women&apos;s Empowerment and Sustainable Livelihoods Development Project (TUWELDEP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Tuna Women&#x2019;s Empowerment and Sustainable Livelihoods Development Project will target women in six partner solidarity groups and will assist a total of 18,792 families. Out of this number, about 17,600 women&#x2014;12,000 original and 5,600 through Heifer&#x2019;s Pass on the Gift (POG) process&#x2014;will have regular access to shea butter extraction equipment, while a total of 1,192 families (260 original and 932 POG) will also be assisted with livestock and poultry. The project will be implemented in the six communities of Naafa, Bombalanyuro, Korapuo, Kukunya, Nahayizire and Nyanyama. These communities are located in the newly
created district of Sawla-Tuna-Kalba of the Northern Region of Ghana. The primary goal of this project is to enhance the livelihoods of people in the targeted communities through the creation of sustainable food production systems. To do this, the project will focus on a) human capital development by honing the knowledge and skills of the project participants; b) rejuvenation of the degraded vegetative cover through tree planting and bushfire-awareness creation, alongside the adoption of appropriate and sustainable agricultural practices; and c) wealth creation through a process whereby participating families are given living loans of livestock and resources that will help them build tangible and financial assets. Heifer will distribute 500 meat sheep and goats to 100 families (five sheep/goats per family in a ratio of one male to four females), 90 local pigs to 30 households (three pigs per family in a ratio of one male to two females), and 1,300 local chickens to 130 families (10 chickens per family in a ratio of nine hens to one cock). A total of 6,660 seedlings of various tree species will also be distributed. Some of these, such as mangoes, will provide food and income; others will serve as windbreaks, shade trees and sources of fuel. Shea butter extraction is a common occupation in this area and has been identified as an enterprise opportunity for women in the project. It is labor-intensive and can be time consuming. This project, therefore, will partner with the Ecumenical Church Loan Fund (ECLOF) to connect participants with microenterprise opportunities. Heifer will also work to ease the drudgery associated with shea butter extraction by providing three shea nut roasters and three shea nut crushers to the project participants. It is estimated that a total of 17,600 women in more than 10 communities, including the targeted communities, will be served by this equipment during the five-year project period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Theoretical and hands-on training in small ruminant and poultry production. Training in project management and record keeping. Training in compost preparation. Training on modern shea butter extraction methods. Training on the 12 HPI cornerstones. Training on gender equity. HIV/AIDS awareness creation. Farmer to farmer visitation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women-headed households, Youth</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecumenical Church Loan Fund (ECLOF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tuna Women Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="21-1040-01" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-GH-10-2969" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elizabeth Bintliff</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interim Vice President for Africa Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>elizabeth.bintliff@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_2297169">
   <location-id code="2297169" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern, Ghana (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2297169" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.5 -1.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
