<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/4777" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-NI-13-4777</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Income And Food Security For Small Farmers Affected By Climate Change in Northern Nicaragua.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will take place in the departments of Estel&#xED; Madriz and Le&#xF3;n. In this area 88% of the population is rural and the main economic activity is the production of basic grains (corn beans) coffee and some dual-purpose livestock. Most families rely primarily on seasonal agricultural work complemented by off-farm labor particularly during the lean season from February to April. These productive systems are exposed to natural disasters such as drought hurricanes flooding landslides and earthquakes that seriously affect agricultural production and food security. Climate change has exacerbated the frequency and intensity of these climate shocks with harvest losses due to natural disasters and irregular rainfall patterns predicted to worsen[1]. The Nicaraguan Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry (MAGFOR) has identified the loss of 386 400 hectares of basic grains (corn beans rice sorghum) in the period 2005-2010 due to climate change. [2] The UNDP&apos;s Nicaragua climate change profile states that the country&apos;s annual temperature has increased by 0.9&#xB0;C since 1960[3] and CIAT predicts a 2.2&#xB0;C increase in temperature and an average drop in rainfall of 7.4 percent by 2050.[4] In addition to poverty in terms of resources due to the small size of their farms and depletion of their soil they lack access to agricultural and business development services such as technology credit and the inputs to incorporate new technologies (whether due to economic resources or lack of availability of inputs on the local market). They are also paid low prices for their produce and lack management capacities information and organization to take better advantage of their relationships with the market. How will the target population benefit? Population goal 470 families will benefit from the activities of reforestation and agroforestry systems to achieve higher resistance to climate change including the protection and fertilization of the soil and the introduction of plant species adapted to the conditions of the zones to increase the coverage of soil to protect and restore the soil water and forests. Of this population a group of 160 low-income households will be The project will take place in the departments of Estel&#xED; Madriz and Le&#xF3;n. In this area 88% of the population is rural and the main economic activity is the production of basic grains (corn beans) coffee and some dual-purpose livestock. Most families rely primarily on seasonal agricultural work complemented by off-farm labor particularly during the lean season from February to April. A population goal of 470 families will benefit from the activities of reforestation and agroforestry systems to achieve higher resistance to climate change including the protection and fertilization of the soil and the introduction of plant species adapted to the conditions of the zones to increase the coverage of soil to protect and restore the soil water and forests. Of this population a group of 160 low-income households will be selected to improve its food through the development of home gardens (100 in Madriz) and 60 families in Achuapa. 60 families of Achuapa will participate in beekeeping activities it will equip them beehives and equipment for the production of honey. To improve income help to 250 families to participate more competitively in the value chain of bean and corn. This activity will be coordinated with institutions such as the INTA (Nicaraguan Agricultural Technology Institute) and MAGFOR (Ministry of agriculture livestock and forestry).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="23-1623-17" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-NI-13-4777" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-21" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Americas program</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Americas program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>americas@list.heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_3617796">
   <location-id code="3617796" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Madriz</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Madriz, Nicaragua (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="3617796" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.5 -86.41667</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_3618029">
   <location-id code="3618029" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leon</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leon, Nicaragua (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="3618029" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.58333 -86.58333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_3619193">
   <location-id code="3619193" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Esteli</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Esteli, Nicaragua (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="3619193" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.16667 -86.33333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
