<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3269" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-PH-10-3269</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protecting and Enhancing the Environment and Natural Resources for Community Resilience (PEER) Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Protecting and Enhancing the Environment and Natural Resources for Community Resilience (PEER) Project will help protect and nurture the coastal, lowland and upland ecosystem, which are the primary sources of livelihood and income of the local people of Macabari and Layug barangays (villages) of Barcelona, Sorsogon in the Philippines.  Through the Heifer&#x2019;s Pass on the Gift process and Values-based holistic community approach, the project will benefit 120 original families and 480 pass on families. Macabari is a coastal village along the Pacific Ocean, and fishing and farming are the primary livelihoods. Like most other rural, coastal communities in the Philippines, most of its families are socio-politically and economically disadvantaged. This situation is aggravated by the deteriorating state of the environment in the area. The mangrove forest are diminishing, illegal fishing are rampant, and disposal of wastes in the coast are common problems. In the adjoining upland area, the watershed and forest are deteriorating, there is no systematic solid waste management and people generally lack awareness on environmental management. Poor housing, health and sanitation and inadequate potable water are major issues faced by families.  Typhoons and storm surges frequently devastate fishing boats, farms and homes, further aggravating the already poor conditions. Farming productivity is low here because of poor farming practices and  that affects farming seasons.This project will improve awareness of the participants on natural resource management, facilitate passage of environmental local laws in the village, improve fish sanctuary through mangrove reforestation and cleaning of the coastal area.  Families in the upland vicinity will establish  agro-forestry and organic farms and improve solid waste management systems. NRM monitoring committees will be established in the villages. Heifer will also provide 58 families each with one heifer and five chickens, 10 families each with one carabao heifer and five chickens, 18 families each with one non-motorized boat and fishing net, 16 families each with one pig and five chickens, 14 families each with one pig and one fishing net, and four families each with one pig and one fishing net. All 120 original families will also be helped to improve productivity and diversify income through sustainable crop and livestock production; they will be provided with 26 pounds of vegetable seeds, 240 bundles of cassava and sweet potato cuttings, 1,200 fruit tree seedlings, 120 sets of farm and garden tools, and worms for vermi-composting and some inputs on handicrafts for the women.. In addition to technical trainings, participants will receive training on Heifer&#x2019;s 12 Cornerstones, leadership and group management and disaster risk reduction (DRR) to increase their resilience in times of disasters.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coastal Community Resources and Livelihoods Development, Inc. (Coastal CORE)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="22-0220-14" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-PH-10-3269" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dilip Bhandari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Asia Program Desk</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>dilip.bhandari@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
