<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/2995" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-SL-11-2995</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Koinadugu Smallholder Crop-Livestock Integration Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Farmer households, Women, Youth</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Placement of animals, training in Cornerstones, Leadership, Crop and Livestock Integration, Animal Wellbeing, Provision of seeds (Rice and Groundnut), Veterinary Support,</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Koinadugu Smallholder Crop-Livestock Integration Project is a five-year project, with initial funding from the German International Cooperation (GIZ), formerly GTZ.  The project is aimed at improving the standard of living among resource poor households in Folosaba-Dembelia and Dembelia-Sinkunia Chiefdoms in Koinadugu District, Northern Sierra Leone. The project outcomes include: improved household incomes
&#x2022; improved household food security and nutrition
&#x2022; improved access to clean and safe drinking water
&#x2022; Enhanced capacity to identify needs and implement project activities 
&#x2022; Sound environmental practices 
&#x2022; Sustained peace between crop and livestock farmers . The project will provide a total of 3,946 resource-poor smallholder families with goats and sheep (2,732 original + 1,214 pass on families), establish community seed banks for increased crop production and distribute high yielding local varieties of rice/groundnut and jute bags to minimize post-harvest losses to l farm families.  Through a partnership with the International Institute of Agricultural Agriculture (IITA), original families will each receive 32 bundles of improved cassava cuttings to cultivate two acres of land to boost food security. 
Also the entire project communities will benefit from environmental conservation and have unrestricted access to clean and safe drinking water through the construction of ten wells in the project communities. 
All original families of the project will receive training in improved livestock husbandry/crop and livestock integration. Veterinary drugs, equipment and community-based veterinary support services will be provided for each group. The project will also work towards greater understanding of rights and obligation issues.  Issues especially relating to conflict between crop farmers and livestock owners, principal protection issues (including gender-based violence); and the capacity to address these through community actions, while linking up with government authorities and other relevant stakeholders in the district. The project will organize community tree planting programs and conduct monthly education and sensitization sessions on sound soil conservation and environmental practices in all target communities. Advocacy forum to be created will include chiefs, councilors, members of parliament, crop farmers and livestock owners particularly cattle owners and other relevant stakeholders.  The goal will be to address destructive conservation practices such as indiscriminate burning; uncontrolled grazing as a result of free range livestock rearing that is responsible for the increased conflict between crop farmers and livestock owners.  
Through partnership with other NGOs engaged in providing clean and safe drinking water, the project will help to improve access to clean and safe drinking water for all community members and their animals through the construction of ten wells in the project communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">German International Cooperation (GIZ)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sierra Leone Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry, and Food Security (MAFFS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Westerville Community United Church of Christ</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="21-1806-01" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-SL-11-2995" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Program</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interim Vice President for Africa Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>africa@list.heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_2407650">
   <location-id code="2407650" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Koinadugu</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Koinadugu, Sierra Leone (admin level 2)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="2407650" level="2" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.50991 -11.34601</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM2"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
