<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3294" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-UG-08-3294</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HPI-Millennium Villages Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The five-year project will be implemented in three Millennium Villages referred to as MVs: MV I (Ruhiira Parish), MV II (10 villages surroundings of Ruhiira) in Isigngiro district, Western Uganda and MV III (Kaberamaido district Eastern Uganda). In Kaberamaido district (MV III) the project will be implemented in three parishes of Acanpi, Anyara and Abururu in Kaberamaido district in Eastern Uganda, located about 70 km North West of Soroti Town. Like other villages, the Ruhiira Millennium Project is a partnership between the United Nations Development Programmed (UNDP), the Earth Institute at Colombia University, the UN Millenuim Project and Millenuim Promise. Activities started in March 2006 in the Ruhiira in Isingiro district. The total population in the project area is 43,056, comprising 8,133 households. The project aims to empower communities with knowledge and skills to use the resources they have to come out of poverty in all its manifestations. This is done through participatory processes that enhance local ownership and sustainability of the overall program. Agriculture and related activities are the main occupation of the area, involving over 95% of the population. The agriculture system is predominantly mixed farming where livestock and cultivation of annual and perennial crops is done. Major crops grown are millet, sorghum, sesame, pigeon peas and ground nuts. Small proportion of the populations keep local cows that are communally grazed, goats and local chicken. Food and livestock production is primarily for subsistence.  The average land holding per household is 0.4 hectares. Household average income of about $250 per year is derived mainly from the sale of bananas, Irish potatoes, maize and beans. A significant proportion of the community, which is estimated at between 40-50% still live below the poverty line. Kaberamaido district (MV III), is characterized by population density of 93 persons per km2 compared to the national average of 85. most of the land is not cultivated, covered by thick bush, shrubs and native trees. It covers an approximate total area of 1646 sq Km. Kaberamaido district has a total population of 160,278 in 2008 of which 78,458 (48.8%) are males and 81,820 (51.2%) are females. The over-dependence of traditional housing on natural environment for building materials is taking its toll on the environment. Afforestation programmes may reduce the pressure on forests for building materials. About 3500 households are directly involved in the fishery industry as boat owners, fishmongers, fish transporters, boat repairers and makers and support service such as eating houses owner, bar owners, shop owners drug shop operators etc. This does not include the dependent people on them hence the total number of people whose living is directly related to fishing might be well over 21,000.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives in helping Ruhiira and Keberamaindo achieve the Millennium  Development Goals and transition from extreme poverty to self-sustaining growth include: Increasing agricultural productivity through soil fertility improvement; Diversifying agriculture into livestock, fruits and vegetables, and high value crops; Improving water and sanitation through rainwater harvesting and other water supply technologies, such as de-mineralization and water filtration with charcoal and sand; and Improving education standards at primary and secondary level and reducing the drop-out rates. Other objectives are Improving health standards by tackling common causes of ailments in the village - high rates of maternal and child mortality, malaria, diarrhea, upper respiratory infection, HIV/AIDS, and tuberculosis, all exacerbated by malnutrition; and Improving rural incomes through knowledge and skills transfer and off-farm employment in carpentry, bricklaying, agro-processing, input supply, and financial services. A number of Government and other development organizations are providing services in these millennium villages as collaborators during implementation of the project. Residents of the MV are faced with chronic food and income insecurity due mainly to poor labor and agricultural productivity, related to lack of skills in improved integrated crop and livestock farming, poor soil fertility, shortage of land, and lack of access to credit facilities.   Other population and development indicators are: Infant Mortality Rate at 126 and Maternal Mortality Rate is 505/100,000, mainly due to serious malnutrition and diarrhea-related illnesses; Also the literacy Rate is 47% of which Adult Literacy rate is 23.7%.; Households with Safe water is 16.4%; Sanitation Coverage is 48%. The overall goal of this project is to reduce poverty in this community by increasing agricultural productivity that ensures food security, improved household incomes and improved livelihoods of the farming communities by the end of the five year project cycle. During this period, it is hoped that the beneficiary communities will also have improved their nutritional status through consumption of balanced food items. The surplus income will be used to purchase some of the other essential food stuffs and other basic necessities of life.  In order to achieve the project goal, which is in line with HPI mission, the project will directly assist 2,000 families (1,000 original and 1,0000 pass ons) in the five year project implementation period with exotic meat goats and draft animals and related implements after related training in livestock management. Of the original families 300 families in MV I and 200 families in MV II will receive each a Boer nanny and 500 families in MV III will receive oxen (four oxen for a set of five families). The project will allow expanded membership in order to assist more people in the community. 50 Boer bucks will be conveniently placed in the communities so that a cluster of 10 families benefit from the services of one buck for breeding purposes. In addition, the clustering will be used to avoid inbreeding. The 50 buck keepers will also receive a nanny each. The bucks will be rotated once a year to avoid inbreeding. Therefore, training and other services related to crop and livestock production will be accessed by beneficiaries of the project. There is a big market and hence high demand for goat products within and without Millennium Villages. HPI-Uganda is a major market for the goats produced by the farmers after passing on gifts. Millennium Villages Project has mobilized and organized farmers into Producer Marketing Groups (PMGs) and Market Service Centres (MSCs). The former group assists farmers to market their farm produce and the latter to provide farmers with loans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="21-0655-01" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-UG-08-3294" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kelly Doppelhammer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kelly.doppelhammer@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_448215">
   <location-id code="448215" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kaberamaido</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kaberamaido, Uganda (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="448215" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.75732 33.22576</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_7056285">
   <location-id code="7056285" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Isingiro</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Isingiro, Uganda (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="7056285" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.83354 30.87175</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2008-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="2000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
