<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3035" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-UG-10-3035</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HPI/BTC/KDLG Project for Improving Livelihoods of Vulnerable Communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The four-year Project for Improving Livelihoods of Vulnerable Communities will be implemented in the communities of Nyakatonzi, Busunga, Nyakakindo/Mubuku, Ibuga/Hima, Karusandara and Kitshwamba in the Kasese district of Western Uganda. The project is co-funded by Belgium Technical Corporation (BTC), Heifer International and the Kasese District Poverty Reduction Program (KDPRP).This project will strengthen the ability of 4,604 vulnerable families&#x2014;1,825 original and 2,729 through Heifer&#x2019;s Pass on the Gift (POG) process&#x2014;in the six communities to use appropriate technologies to cope with threats from natural disasters, limited livestock and land productivity, and rangeleand degradation. In addition, families will improve their household nutrition, income and rangeland management through training in integrated livestock farming and rangeland management by the year 2015. The domestic market for products from livestock and households in the district will be strengthened through the increased production of milk, meat, other farm products and value-addition technologies through bulking and group marketing.To achieve its goals, the project will enable 3,440 families to have access to and use of artificial insemination (AI) services, extension services and veterinary inputs through hiring, training and equipping two extension workers in addition to training and equipping three AI technicians. The project will strengthen the communities&#x2019; capacities to market their milk and related products through bulking and group marketing. A total of 1,174 families will benefit from 453 meat goats and 806 dairy goats, which will be distributed by the project and raised in zero-grazing systems.To maximize productivity, 25 meat and 50 dairy bucks will be conveniently placed in the communities so that a cluster of about 10 families will benefit from the services of one buck for breeding purposes. The 85 buck-keepers will also receive a nanny each. The bucks will be rotated once a year to avoid inbreeding. In addition, the bucks will be used to crossbreed with the indigenous nannies within the communities. Project participants will receive training and other services related to livestock production. Areas of training include group formation and organizational development animal husbandry and health, including AI; clean milk production, handling and marketing; rangeland management; gender equity; HIV/AIDS awareness; family planning; human nutrition and home hygiene; drought preparedness; and enterprise development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation(s)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="21-0663-01" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-UG-10-3035" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-10-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kelly Doppelhammer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kelly.doppelhammer@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_443342">
   <location-id code="443342" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasese</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasese, Uganda (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="443342" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.121 30.00777</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
