<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3026" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-KE-09-3026</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homa Bay Orphans Livelihood Project (HOLP) Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caregivers, Orphans and vulnerable children (OVC), People living with HIV/AIDS (PLWHA)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will integrate and strengthen business support services and enterprise development to help poor families in the region to upgrade indigenous goats for the purpose of increasing milk and meat production as well as introduction of dual purpose poultry for eggs and poultry-meat production. The strategy to be adopted in this project will involve the following;
1. Facilitating the families to cross-breed the local goats with pure breed goats, enabling them to realize two kinds of benefits; increased production of goat offspring for meat as well as increased milk production for home consumption and sale.
2. Integrating poultry rearing with the original families by facilitating them to own dual purpose chickens and breed them with improved breeding cockerels for increased eggs and chicken production for home consumption and sale.
3. Support the Nyanza Dairy Goats Farmers Association (NDGFA), to strengthen their capacity in corporate governance and project management so that they can participate effectively in implementing HOLP II together with HPI/K.
4. Strengthening community-based animal health service delivery with an aim of turning it in to profit making enterprises.  The 2,500 participating families will be drawn from the four districts but the project is expected to reach beyond this number because the wider community will also benefit from upgrading of their local goats from the project pure breed bucks. The project will be implemented by the HPI/K and its team based in the region, in close collaboration with the government departments of livestock production, veterinary services and the regional dairy goat farmers institution &#x2013; Nyanza Dairy Goat Farmers Association (NDGFA), formed by HPI/K out of HOLP to cater for dairy goat farmer&#x2019;s interest in marketing, lobbying and advocacy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This Homa Bay Orphans Livelihood Project (HOLP) Phase II seeks to address the high poverty level among 5,000 family (2,500 original and 2500 POG) family caregivers of an estimated 30,000 HIV/AIDS orphans who have lost one or both of their parents to the HIV/AIDS pandemic. The project area will be implemented in four districts of Nyanza Region namely Homa Bay, Suba, Migori and Rachuonyo districts. The districts are characterized by high levels of poverty manifested in the form of food shortage, malnutrition, unemployment and under employment and high level of age dependency due to the ever increasing orphan population.  The majority of these orphans have lost both parents are being cared for by close or distant relatives who themselves struggle with poverty.  According to data collected during the mid-term review of HOLP phase I, the average number of orphans per family was found to be 7, with some extreme cases as high as 15 orphans per family. Most of these families are food and income insecure for most part of the year and addition of the orphans has further strained the meager family resources exacerbating the poverty situation. Currently, the caregivers cannot cater for the nutritional, health and educational needs of the orphans. The main goal of this project is to introduce sustainable survival mechanisms for the orphans and their caregivers through development of sustainable livestock and crop agriculture. The objectives are to increase capacities of identified families caring for orphans and vulnerable children in improved livestock husbandry, sustainable organic agriculture, family nutrition, livestock products and vegetable marketing. Two local goats and five poultry (4 hens and 1 cockerel) will be placed with the families in the name of the orphans to help them develop a sense of making contributions to the family&#x2019;s wellbeing. The local goats will be upgraded to dairy goats through crossbreeding with bucks. Both the livestock and vegetables will provide the families with a sustainable source of income and nutrition. These interventions will enable many orphans and vulnerable children (OVCs) to attend schools as most of them fail to get an education due to various reasons including general ill health, lack of money to purchase books and uniforms and lack of parental care. Through training on psycho-social care, the OVCs will have a sense of belonging to and integration with the host families.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="21-0354-01" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-KE-09-3026" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-07-02" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kelly Doppelhammer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kelly.doppelhammer@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="osm_880037">
   <location-id code="880037" vocabulary="G2"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homa Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homa Bay, Kenya (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="880037" level="1" vocabulary="G2"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.543002609 34.36293925</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
