<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3042" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-ZM-10-3042</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Livelihood Women Empowerment Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">High poverty levels, unemployment, HIV/AIDS and poor governance are Zambia&#x2019;s key development challenges. The target project areas, Kabwe and KapiriMposhi in Central province of Zambia were once characterized by mining, textiles and railway industries as major economic activity for many years. Unfortunately, these companies were liquidated in the early 1990&apos;s leaving a huge number of people without gainful employment leading to increased poverty of urbanites and proximal rural communities. These affected communities moved to the rural areas and are now surviving on subsistence agriculture. In the face of these socio-economic hardships, these Smallholder farm families are facing persistent food and income insecurity exacerbated by poor extension services, shortage of agricultural inputs, poor marketing linkages, deteriorating environment due to deforestation and an increase in the spread of HIV/AIDS. HIV/AIDS has contributed to family labor constraints, increased number of women&#x2013;headed households (mostly widows), orphans and vulnerable people with limited adaptive and coping strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will provide high quality inputs and training to improve agricultural production. The action also introduces livestock farming in target communities to diversify production and income and further increase resilience to shocks. The action emphasizes the community as the focus of the intervention and thus will work with community leaders to transform attitudes and promote a new mind-set of empowerment.
As a result of Heifer Zambia&#x2019;s work with these communities, the project participants will receive Heifer value-based training for sustainable agriculture development to improve food security, participants will become more resilient in terms of diversifies income-generating opportunities, improved animal health management and productivity, increased crop and vegetables production from their land. Women will be empowered to take on leadership and management of their activities and to change negative cultural attitudes to women and girls so that gender equity is enhanced. Further, the training and awareness raising programs will significantly increase knowledge in environmental management and HIV/AIDS mitigation in all target communities.
Heifer Zambia will implement this project in collaboration with its major partners in the Central province which include: the government Ministry of Agriculture &amp;amp; Cooperatives, Zambia National Farmers Union, Ministry of Health, Community Development &amp;amp; Social Welfare and other private service providers to promote enterprise development for smallholder farmers.
Overtime, this project will have a multiplier effect on the community through the &#x2018;passing on the gift&#x2019; of animals and practical skills and knowledge in integrated agriculture development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation(s)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer Zambia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia Ministries of Community Development and Social Welfare</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia Ministry of Agriculture and Co-Operatives (MACO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia Ministry of Health</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia National Farmers Union (ZNFU)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="21-0153-01" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-ZM-10-3042" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-06" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lisa Dixon</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>lisa.dixon@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_921064">
   <location-id code="921064" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central, Zambia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="921064" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-14.0 29.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
