<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3033" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-UG-10-3033</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hoima Integrated Livestock Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 4-year project &#x201C;Hoima Integrated Livestock Project&#x201D; proposes to alleviate the problem of abuse of watersheds and riparian ecosystems in the subcounties of Kiziranfumbi, Buseruka and Kabwoya in Hoima District thereby reducing the rate of biodiversity loss. The project targets 481 households that live in the vicinity of the protected areas of Wambabya, Kanywabarogo and kasoma rivers as well as Bugoma and wambabya central forest reserves in Hoima District. The project is planned for five years targeting the communities above. There is a weaned Heifer Dairy cattle Projects in Hoima District (Bunyoro Kitara COU Heifer Project) from which the targeted community has gained significant experiential learning. The community has also gained some skills in animal husbandry, animal feed production, animal breeding, milk marketing and Business Development Services through networking with the District through the NAADS Programme. In this project, 278 needy families will receive 204 original Boer goats, 55 improved pigs and 120 Kenya Top Bar bee hives. An additional 278 needy families will benefit through the pass on the gift process by receiving 108 off spring Boer goats, 70 improved offspring pigs and 25 bee hives. Furthermore, all original beneficiary families will be supplied with assorted improved high yielding, early maturing, drought and disease resistant food crop seeds/planting materials. Vegetable seeds such as; Cabbages, tomatoes, carrots, indigenous vegetables and fruit tree seedlings that mature early like paw paws and passion fruits will also be supplied. These will serve to supply essential nutrients and boost the immunity of the beneficiary families. At the same time the surplus will be sold to the community for additional income.  Families will be expected to choose only one of the above three options. A family will receive either one Boer nanny or one gilt or three bee hives. In addition, 10 families will come together to share one boar which will be kept by one of them. 12 families will share one buck which again will be kept by one of them. The family keeping the buck or boar will be expected to pass on a buck or boar as well. All participating families will be expected to plant and maintain at least 500 multipurpose tree species compatible with the ecosystem.
All beneficiaries will receive related training on animal husbandry, environmental protection and sustainable use of natural resources. Other initiatives will include training on values based planning, cornerstones, Gender equity and family planning, HIV/AIDS awareness, organizational strengthening, cooperative bulking and marketing of surplus produce. The project aims to increase food and nutritional security of 481 needy households by at least 25% and household income by at least 50% over the four-year period.  Furthermore, the project will promote community oriented environmental protection activities to reduce the rate of biodiversity loss.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation(s)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="21-0661-01" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-UG-10-3033" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kelly Doppelhammer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>kelly.doppelhammer@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_443332">
   <location-id code="443332" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hoima</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hoima, Uganda (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="443332" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.393 31.11</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environment</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
