<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/4789" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-AM-13-4789</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting Innovative Rural Tourism in Black Sea Basin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will build effective and replicable networks of capable local service providers in rural tourism, as well as will help travel agencies to co-develop, market and sell a new unique touristic product that encourages interflows of visitors intra-regionally. It will and contribute to unprecedented cooperation between national authorities in the region aimed ultimately to sustaining the cross-border impacts of rural tourism.
In particular local hospitality service (B&amp;amp;B) providers will build their capacities through provision of new quality product by utilizing their natural, agricultural and human resources as well as from networking with their counterparts.
Travel agencies will design innovative customized strategies via extensive training courses with acknowledged business professionals and consultants. As a result they will introduce innovative single cross boarder visitor package. They will build their capacity in marketing and sales and learn to utilize strategic knowledge. It is also expected that the travel agencies will further develop cross boarder professional associations and effective networks to exchange best practices intra-regionally and enhance product standards and service delivery.
On the government level national and local authorities will collaborate with their counterparts in other countries and will synergize their approaches for rural, eco-, agro- and culinary tourism development in their respective regions and focus on the further development of industry as a whole. The initiative will further encourage the national/local authorities to focus on rural tourism in more tangible terms and with greater regional focus.
Together with the mentioned target groups prospective tourists/visitors who are particularly interested in various types of rural tourism in the Black Sea Basin region will directly benefit from the project. Also certain benefits are estimated for the populations at-large in participating countries to benefit from improved infrastructure in select localities and increased income base. We estimate 40-50% increase in income and living standards in the target rural communities; 30%increase of tourist flows intra-regionally and most importantly enhanced standards of product and service delivery by 50% as direct and indirect outcomes of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="27-0256-13" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-AM-13-4789" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-05" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe Program</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Associate</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>europe@list.heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
