<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3866" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-AM-11-3866</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Animal Health Management in Cross-Border Areas of Armenia and Georgia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Animal Health Management in Cross-Border Areas of Armenia and Georgia

This project perfectly merges with the Armenian and Georgian government strategies on strengthening of cross-border economic links and creation of private veterinary services that will complement government action on prevention of animal diseases.

The project will ultimately benefit the rural population in the target areas, through improvement of animal husbandry and health control practices and, therefore providing better conditions for their economic activities.

The direct benefits expected from this project are:

1. 60 veterinarians in rural communities in the bordering villages of northern Armenia and southern Georgia effectively advocate on the prevention and control of animal infection diseases.

2. Rural communities of Shirak and Lori marzes in Armenia and Samtskhe-Javakheti and Kvemo-Kartli provinces in Georgia effectively prevent and control animal diseases and promote livestock sector development practices through application of new techniques and establishment of veterinary health care services through Service Centres (two Centres to be established in Armenia; two health care units within existing Centres to be established in Georgia).

The core concept of making new models replicable is to demonstrate their veterinary applicability that attracts veterinary business interests to the project beneficiaries and also stakeholders.

We believe that the proposed project is commercially applicable as there is a market demand in high quality vet services and for consistent access to farm output markets. However, under the current underdeveloped farm management system, with limited financial inflows and lack of trained vets in the regions, this demand is currently impossible to fulfill.

Successful implementation of Animal Health (AH) demonstrations will open opportunities and attract business incentives of the private sector to invest in similar business models in Armenia and Georgia, which will ensure continues action in this field.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target areas of the present project cover Armenian and Georgian bordering regions, namely, Shirak and Lori marzes in Armenia and Samtskhe-Javakheti and Kvemo-Kartli regions in Georgia. 

There are direct and indirect beneficiaries identified for the project: the direct or immediate target groups are Community veterinarians; and the indirect or secondary target groups are Community members and farmers. 

The direct target groups, i.e. those who will get Training of Trainers (ToT) training, will be 15 veterinarians from each region. The trained 60 veterinarians will train small and medium farmers. The secondary beneficiaries will be identified with the help of trained veterinarians. This group will be composed of 100 farmers per region, i.e. indirect target group will be formed by 400 farmers both in Armenia and Georgia. 
Within the frames of the project two Farm Service Centres will be established in Armenia and two veterinary service units will be set-up on the basis of already existing Farmer Service Centers in Georgia, through which sustainable veterinary health care services will be provided in the bordering regions of Armenia and Georgia (see details section A 2.1). Location of the veterinary health care services will be identified considering their geographic position towards neighbouring villages. This means, one veterinary health service will be established in every target region serving several surrounding communities/settlements.

Gender issues: Women play a very significant role in the rural economies of Armenia and Georgia, providing 40% of the workforce and heading a third of rural households. The project will encourage participation of women farmers that are actively involved in animal husbandry activities (animal care, milking, feeding, etc.). Accordingly, the project will systematically take gender considerations into account as a matter of priority. Particularly, the project will: (a) assure that eligible poor rural women will be made fully aware of and fully access the benefits available under the project: (b) at least a third of farm households to be targeted will be woman-headed; (c) mainstream gender into the project management; (d) identify the best development methods to support poor rural women. 
Within the project CARD Foundation will cooperate with Georgian organizations engaged or interested in animal health protection activities, Ministries of Agriculture of Armenia and Georgia, regional and local governments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Agribusiness and Rural Development (CARD), Armenia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer Georgia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="27-0525-12" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-AM-11-3866" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-05-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Europe Program</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Associate, Central Eastern Europe</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>europe@list.heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AM" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="50"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_828263">
   <location-id code="828263" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lori</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lori, Armenia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="828263" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.0 44.5</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_828264">
   <location-id code="828264" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shirak</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shirak, Armenia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="828264" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>40.75 43.83333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_865536">
   <location-id code="865536" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvemo Kartli</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvemo Kartli, Georgia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="865536" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.51667 44.51667</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_865544">
   <location-id code="865544" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samtskhe-Javakheti</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samtskhe-Javakheti, Georgia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="865544" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.58333 43.26667</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
