<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="534" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3298" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HEFI-GE-11-3298</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value-Added Poultry Production Market Chain Establishment in Georgia&#x2019;s Post-Conflict Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local farmers traditionally target sales of turkey meat for New Year and Easter holidays. During the rest of the year, however, there is an unsatisfied demand for locally produced turkey meat, which is compensated for by imports from Brazil and Argentina. Market research shows that chain retailers are ready to substitute imports for locally produced, cooled, cut and packed fresh meat. Local farmers using local breeds and techniques, however, are not able to meet this demand. To improve the livelihoods of participant farmers, Heifer will help establish and strengthen the five major blocks of the poultry market chain: inputs (hatching eggs, veterinary medicines), hatching and raising of poults, poult finishing, slaughtering and primary processing, and marketing. 

The first element of this project is the construction and equipping of a poultry hatchery. The second element is the finishing of the poults by project participants at their family farms. The project will provide turkey, chicken and duck poults to 750 original families who will Pass on the Gift to another 1,250 families. Participants will receive training in Heifer&#x2019;s 12 Cornerstones for Just and Sustainable Development, gender equity, poultry farming, women-led enterprise development, slaughterhouse operation and value-added market chains.  The third element of the project is the construction and equipping of a poultry slaughterhouse where poults raised by project participants will be slaughtered and will receive primary processing before being delivered to the retail market. Finally, Heifer Georgia will assist farmers in linking to the retail markets. The sustainability of the project is ensured by this third element. It is estimated that, after the processing (value adding) of the poults, farmers will be able to get a 30 percent increase in sale price.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Value-Added Poultry Market Chain Establishment in Georgia&#x2019;s Post Conflict Region Project will establish functional links between suppliers, producers and final markets. The project will define a roadmap for moving 2,000 project participants from subsistence to self-reliance along the poverty continuum. This project is centered in Georgia&#x2019;s Gori municipality, which was affected by the 2008 conflict with Russia. The conflict resulted in hardships that have persisted, drastically reducing agricultural production and shattering local industry and infrastructure. According to Georgian authorities, 118,500 people have been directly affected, including both those living in the conflict area and those who were displaced. Heifer will employ its holistic community development approach to contribute to the overall building of social capital. The best possible outcome for highly vulnerable groups is integration into mainstream economic activity, as this maximizes both income generation and sustainability. In the conflict-affected area, many farmers&#x2013;especially internally displaced people living in settlements&#x2013; have limited access to arable land and, therefore, face difficulties generating income from farming activities.

Poultry raising is a promising industry for the proposed project participants, as it can be conducted in small areas in backyard gardens. In Georgia, there is currently no commercial production of goose, duck or turkey poults; participant farmers can capitalize on this niche market. Small-scale poultry farming is profitable for families, as it has rapid turnover and does not require large capital investments. Heifer has a history of success helping farmers in Georgia raise turkeys for meat and profit through previous projects. However, to achieve maximum positive benefit on the participants&#x2019; livelihoods, it is clearly necessary to establish a complete value-added poultry market chain, which will allow the farmer to gain maximum returns from this business.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dzevera 2009</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation(s)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="27-0524-12" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-35-1019477">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HEFI-GE-11-3298" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-10-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heifer International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greta Grishanova</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director of Programs CEE</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>Greta.Grishanova@heifer.org</email>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
   <website>http://www.heifer.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_865540">
   <location-id code="865540" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shida Kartli</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shida Kartli, Georgia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="865540" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>42.32 44.14</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.heifer.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Website</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
