<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="64" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/18821" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-HLA-MX-15-18821</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No M&#xE1;sExplotaci&#xF3;n Sexual de Ni&#xF1;as, Ni&#xF1;os y Adolescentes (No M&#xE1;s ESNNA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the five years that HAI has implemented the project No M&#xE1;s Explotaci&#xF3;n Sexual de Ni&#xF1;as, Ni&#xF1;os y Adolescentes (No M&#xE1;s ESNNA, No More Sexual Exploitation of Children and Youth), its design has evolved from direct service delivery to more sustainable efforts to build the capacity of frontline personnel working with youth to better address issues of sexual violence and protect victims. Through the experience of implementing No M&#xE1;s ESSNA in Jalisco to combat commercial sexual exploitation of children (CSEC), HAI has identified that CSEC is part of a broader threat of sexual violence against children and youth. HAI has, therefore, tailored the next phase of No M&#xE1;s ESSNA to focus specifically on addressing sexual violence as an urgent threat impacting the children and youth in the project&#x2019;s target community in Jalisco. 

Local researchers have identified several risk factors that influence the likelihood that a child will become a victim of sexual violence, including: poverty, social exclusion, rural-to-urban migration, lack of support networks, violence, corruption and consumerism. No M&#xE1;s ESNNA will work with school administrators and staff, as well as public officials from DIF, JHO, and the AG, to increase their awareness of sexual violence and how to best address the cases of sexual violence against children and youth that they encounter in their work. 

SEXUAL VIOLENCE TRAINING IN MIDDLE AND HIGH SCHOOLS

No M&#xE1;s ESNNA will work in four schools to increase the knowledge and capacity of 90 school administrators and staff on sexual violence and how to identify risk factors through a year-long training program. Content of the training program will focus on the following themes: 
(1)	Human Rights Approach to Working with Children and Adolescents,
(2)	Applying a Gender and Human Rights Perspective to Understanding Sexual Violence, and
(3)	Prevention of Sexual Violence and Exploitation of Children and Adolescents.

These three themes together represent a holistic approach to understanding and preventing sexual violence motivated by cultural factors like machismo and a lack of recognition of the rights of children and youth. The training program will include a reflection process for school administrators and staff to trace back to the sexual education that they received, and how this could impact their understanding of sexual violence as adults. In addition to learning practices for preventing and addressing sexual violence through their roles in schools as frontline personnel, training participants will gain a deeper understanding of how to incorporate a rights-based approach and gender sensitive perspective into their work. 

The project will work with school leaders to revise protection policies to ensure that existing policies are in line with child and youth protection standards outlined in the General Law on Children and Youth passed in December 2014. HAI will use resources such as the &#x201C;Guide for Best Practices for Working with Children and Youth Victims or Witnesses of Sexual Abuse and Other Crimes&#x201D; (3) developed by UNICEF to ensure that target schools are applying best practices for prevention of sexual violence in their internal child protection policies. HAI will work to support these groups of school leaders in each school to design sexual violence prevention activities based on the needs of their respective schools, and could include awareness campaigns, arts-based educational events, or developing expanded protection clauses and response protocols.

CRIMINAL JUSTICE SYSTEM

HAI will work with duty bearers responsible for ensuring the protection of children and youth from sexual violence to improve inter-agency coordination for addressing sexual violence, including DIF, JHO, and the AG, as well as representatives from other NGOs that work with children and youth or address issues of violence. Professional profiles of training participants will include psychologists, social workers, teachers, attorneys, and law enforcement personnel, as they are often the first people to whom children and youth reach out when they have experienced acts of violence.  A total of 120 public officials and social service providers will be trained in improving protection mechanisms and inter-agency coordination to respond to the needs of children and youth that report sexual violence. Of these, 80 will complete a more in-depth training on methods for designing victim-centered services within their agencies. These trainings will highlight the expanded federal regulations for child protection under the new General Law on Children and Youth, and will focus on applying a holistic approach to working with child victims of sexual violence using concepts of human rights, gender, and self-care.

The project will support DIF, JHO, and the AG in adapting their service approach for child and youth victims of sexual violence with a victim-centered approach that encourages inter-agency coordination and reduces the likelihood that children will be re-traumatized through the case investigation and management process. The adaptation process towards a more victim-centered approach will culminate in the development of a case management protocol for working with victims of sexual violence. 

EVIDENCE-BASED MODEL DEVELOPMENT

HAI aims to accurately document, replicate, and scale up best practices in combatting sexual violence against youth. As part of a sustainability strategy, HAI will invest in the development and documentation of models that effectively combat sexual violence in a school setting. These models will be informed by the analysis of data from five years of No M&#xE1;s ESNNA programming, including baseline diagnostics, pre and post surveys, and other data gathered over the course of the past five years. These models will provide general frameworks for addressing sexual violence against youth in a school setting, while also providing guidance on how the models can be tailored to address the specific realities within any given school or locality.   The development of these models will also fulfill the secondary purpose of this project, which is to effectively transition the No M&#xE1;s ESNNA project away from Boeing funding towards other viable sources of support, including but not limited to fee-for-service models, government, and private grants. HAI will be able to assess, refine, package, and market its years of experience addressing sexual violence against youth that is has cultivated, thanks to Boeing&#x2019;s generous support, to continue to combat this ongoing challenge in Mexico. 

In addition, HAI will convene a Sexual Violence Working group. This working group will be comprised of 15 high-level stakeholders including lawyers, government, and civil society groups that are already working on the issue of sexual violence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-36-1877640" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heartland Alliance International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="CC7519" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-36-1877640">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heartland Alliance International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HLA-MX-15-18821" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heartland Alliance International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.heartlandalliance.org/international/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
