<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://data.mcc.gov/" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:mcc="https://data.mcc.gov/ns#" xmlns:usg="http://foreignassistance.gov/iati#">
  <iati-identifier>US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-18" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy Sector Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia - Energy Sector Project: The Project is comprised of four interlinked activities aimed at enhancing power generation, strengthening the capacity of key sector institutions, and supporting the development of foundational policies as the sector modernizes and becomes more commercially viable.  The Mt. Coffee Rehabilitation Activity aims to increase the amount of electricity generated in Liberia, facilitate a decrease in the overall electricity tariff, and contribute to increased reliability and adequacy of electricity. This activity addresses the overarching problem in the energy sector, i.e., lack of access to affordable and reliable electricity, by targeting the insufficient supply of electricity in Liberia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-8" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Account - Liberia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-18" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Millennium Challenge Corporation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United States of America</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/evalbrief-092120-lbr-electricity-access">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing Access to Electricity in Liberia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/news-and-events/feature/liberia-closeout">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia Compact Closeout Feature</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="http://www.mcc.gov/where-we-work/program/liberia-compact">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia Compact Closeout</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.mcc.gov/resources/doc/liberia-compact-kpi">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liberia Compact Key Performance Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A08"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD" type="1"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR-0086" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR-0369" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR-0462" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR-0464" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR-0465" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR-0482" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ENRGY SCTR-0508" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-MON &amp; EVAL" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-NA" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-PGM ADMIN" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="US-18-LBR-2750BXCOMD-ROAD" type="3"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By February 1, 2016, and prior to any Disbursement of MCC Funding under the Energy Project on or after such date, the Government must have communicated in writing to MCC, a selected management arrangement for LEC, and MCC and the Government will have agreed on such arrangement.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By March 15, 2016, and prior to any Disbursement of MCC Funding under the Energy Project on or after such date, the Government must have submitted to MCC a management implementation plan approved and adopted by the board of directors of LEC with a schedule of milestones for the implementation of the selected management arrangement, including any required interim arrangement for the management of LEC prior to the implementation of the selected management arrangement, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Further details on conditions precedent affecting this activity can be found in the top-level parent activities.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to any Disbursement of MCC Funding that includes funding for the Energy Project, MCC must be satisfied that: (i) the LEC board is providing timely oversight for, and otherwise in compliance with the terms and conditions of, the management services contract, including, without limitation (1) timely review and approval of all applicable contract deliverables and (2) granting the management services contractor the exclusive, day-to-day authority to manage all of the operational, commercial, and financial affairs of LEC in accordance with the management services contract, including without limitation Section 10.1 thereof, (ii) LEC has developed, and is complying with, workplace codes of conduct and related procedures, in each case satisfactory to MCC, governing standards for employee behavior and misconduct, and (ii) the Government and LEC are facilitating the timely assessment and adjudication of any specific cases or issues related to LEC&apos;s activities, in each case in accordance with applicable law.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to any Disbursement of MCC Funding that includes funding for the Energy Project, the Government shall have: (i) appointed two LEC board members representing the private sector with the technical and managerial qualifications to provide substantive oversight and governance to LEC and the management services contractor (and if such position(s) become vacant, the Government is actively engaged, to MCC&apos;s satisfaction, in nominating a replacement(s)), and (ii) established a payment plan acceptable to MCC to liquidate all Government payables to LEC, and be in substantial compliance with such plan as of the date of such Disbursement</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each Disbursement of MCC Funding under the Energy Project following the adoption of the management implementation plan, the Government must have submitted evidence, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC, that LEC is implementing such plan and is in compliance with the requirements of the plan.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to each subsequent Disbursement of MCC Funding that includes funding for LERC, such chair and each commissioner noted in (f) above remain in place, or if such position has become vacant, the Government has nominated a replacement candidate acceptable to MCC;</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the initial Disbursement of MCC Funding after September 30, 2018 that includes funding for the Liberia Electricity Regulatory Commission (&quot;LERC&quot;), the Government shall have nominated candidates acceptable to MCC, and such candidates shall have been confirmed, as the chair and commissioners of LERC pursuant to Section 13.1 of the 2015 Electricity Law of Liberia</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prior to the initial Disbursement of MCC Funding under the Energy Project the Government will have passed the 2015 Electricity Law of Liberia, in form and substance satisfactory to MCC.</narrative>
   </condition>
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Government will have provided evidence of LEC&apos;s commitment to absorb the funding of the additional LEC full time permanent staff positions funded under the Mt. Coffee Support Activity so that prior to the commencement of the fourth year of the Compact, LEC will be responsible for solely funding such positions.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy Sector Project Results</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Electricity tariff</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Average tariff per kilowatt-hour</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0.52" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Average tariff per kilowatt-hour Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Average tariff per kilowatt-hour Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Average tariff per kilowatt-hour Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generation capacity added</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of Generation capacity added, measured in megawatts, resulting from construction of new generating capacity or reconstruction, rehabilitation, or upgrading of existing generating capacity funded with MCC support.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generation capacity added, measured in megawatts, resulting from construction of new generating capacity or reconstruction, rehabilitation, or upgrading of existing generating capacity funded with MCC support. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="88">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generation capacity added, measured in megawatts, resulting from construction of new generating capacity or reconstruction, rehabilitation, or upgrading of existing generating capacity funded with MCC support. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="88">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generation capacity added, measured in megawatts, resulting from construction of new generating capacity or reconstruction, rehabilitation, or upgrading of existing generating capacity funded with MCC support. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Customers connected to the grid</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Number of customers that have a legal connection to electricity service from LEC</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="36964" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of customers that have a legal connection to electricity service from LEC Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="105101">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of customers that have a legal connection to electricity service from LEC Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="85371">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of customers that have a legal connection to electricity service from LEC Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Date Output of Number of people trained on leak detection equipment use</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="N/a - Date Indicator" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained on leak detection equipment use Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained on leak detection equipment use Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10/28/2020">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people trained on leak detection equipment use Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">System Average Interruption Frequency Index (SAIFI)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Sum of all customer interruption durations / Total number of customers</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="NULL" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of all customer interruption durations / Total number of customers Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of all customer interruption durations / Total number of customers Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="44.2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of all customer interruption durations / Total number of customers Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">System Average Interruption Duration Index (SAIDI)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Sum of durations, in customer-hours, of all customer interruptions in a year / Total number of customers connected to network in the same year</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="NULL" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of durations, in customer-hours, of all customer interruptions in a year / Total number of customers connected to network in the same year Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of durations, in customer-hours, of all customer interruptions in a year / Total number of customers connected to network in the same year Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="46.54">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sum of durations, in customer-hours, of all customer interruptions in a year / Total number of customers connected to network in the same year Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value disbursed for Mt. Coffee Hydropower Plant rehabilitation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of The amount disbursed for MCHPP rehabilitation, including costs associated with construction, oversight, environmental and social mitigation, initial operations and maintenance, and contingencies</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="137924885" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The amount disbursed for MCHPP rehabilitation, including costs associated with construction, oversight, environmental and social mitigation, initial operations and maintenance, and contingencies Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="356762257">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The amount disbursed for MCHPP rehabilitation, including costs associated with construction, oversight, environmental and social mitigation, initial operations and maintenance, and contingencies Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="337891616.7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The amount disbursed for MCHPP rehabilitation, including costs associated with construction, oversight, environmental and social mitigation, initial operations and maintenance, and contingencies Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value disbursed of power infrastructure construction contracts</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Process of The amount disbursed of all signed construction contracts for power infrastructure investments using compact funds.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The amount disbursed of all signed construction contracts for power infrastructure investments using compact funds. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="146800000">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The amount disbursed of all signed construction contracts for power infrastructure investments using compact funds. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="144858722">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The amount disbursed of all signed construction contracts for power infrastructure investments using compact funds. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instructors trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="65">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Instructors trained (Unspecified)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="NULL" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="35">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of classroom instructors who complete MCC-supported training focused on instructional quality as defined by the compact training activity. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individual staff trained (Female)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;amp;M plan</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individual staff trained (Male)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;amp;M plan</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Individual staff trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Outcome of The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;amp;M plan</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="16">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of people trained to implement the O&amp;M plan Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Students participating in MCC-supported education activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="75">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="319">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Students participating in MCC-supported education activities (Unspecified)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="NULL" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling  Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="NULL">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling  Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="319">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of students enrolled or participating in MCC-supported educational schooling  Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kilometers of transmission lines upgraded or built</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded transmission lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded transmission lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="51">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded transmission lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="51">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sum of linear kilometers of new, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or upgraded transmission lines that have been energized, tested and commissioned with MCC support Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transmission substation capacity added</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cumulative Output of The total added transmission substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substati</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total added transmission substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substati Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="122">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total added transmission substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substati Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="84">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total added transmission substation capacity, measured in megavolt amperes, that is energized, commissioned and accompanied by a test report and supervising engineer?s certification resulting from new construction or refurbishment of existing substati Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity sold</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level (cumulative) Outcome of The total megawatt hours of electricity sales to all customer types.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="37464" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total megawatt hours of electricity sales to all customer types. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="198460">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total megawatt hours of electricity sales to all customer types. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="87435.41">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The total megawatt hours of electricity sales to all customer types. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Percentage of electricity supplied by Mt. Coffee Hydropower Plant</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level Outcome of Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced by MCHPP in a quarter / Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a quarter for supply to the grid</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced by MCHPP in a quarter / Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a quarter for supply to the grid Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="57">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced by MCHPP in a quarter / Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a quarter for supply to the grid Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="98.73">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced by MCHPP in a quarter / Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a quarter for supply to the grid Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity supply</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level (cumulative) Outcome of Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a year.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="62039" year="2015">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a year. Baseline</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-20"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-01-19"></period-end>
     <target value="319070">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a year. Target</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="242168.96">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total electricity, in megawatt hours, produced or imported in a year. Actual</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
