<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-30933</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Persianas Group</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Persianas Group (the Company or Persianas) is the developer of the first, internationally specified, purpose-built mall (The Palms Shopping Mall) in Nigeria. The Companys existing portfolio comprises the Palms Shopping Mall and Polo Park Mall in Lagos and Enugu State respectively which are in operation and two other malls in Kwara and Oyo States that are under development. The Companys vision is to develop and list Nigerias first investment grade real estate portfolio. The Nigerian real estate sector is expected to produce high growth in the medium term driven by the recovering economy, and other high growth sectors of commerce, construction, telecommunications, and a recovery in the financial services sector. This is expected to lead to demand for real estate product in all sectors in an environment where there is a dearth of quality stock of real estate and the market is undersupplied. To address Nigerias vastly underserved commercial property, Persianas is undertaking a restructuring and expansion of its operations which involves the: i) building and development of new retail and mixed used centres; ii) establishment and development of a professional asset management company; and iii) restructuring of the Companys balance sheet (The Project). At completion, the new Project is expected to provide at least approximately 140,000 square meters of business infrastructure.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is expected to have the following impacts:  i) Improvement of food security - rollout of modern food retailing as planned anchor for every development. ii) Direct and indirect employment - retail and service jobs; possibility for linkages.  iii) Tax revenues will accrue to the government. iv) Development of critical business infrastructure in Africa&apos;&apos;s second largest market, and most populous nation. v) Elevation of commercial real estate standards - throughout the country. vi) Better aesthetic environment, particularly states outside Lagos undergoing redevelopment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Persianas Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-30933" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Adetayo Amusan Persianas Investment Limited Plot 999A, Danmole Street, Victoria Island, Lagos, Nigeria.  Telephone: +234 1 741 9100 Email:  mailto:tayoa@persianasgroup.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG-Nigeria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project will be implemented in different states within Nigeria. Some project sites have been identified and are in various stages of development and operation. These include:  Lagos Sate: The Project will be located on approximately 69,000 square meters of land at the Oniru Chieftaincy Family Private Layout, Victoria Island Annex, Lekki-Pennisula, Eti-Osa Local Government Area. Oyo State: The Project will be located on approximately 77,210 square meters of land along M.K.O Abiola Road, Ibadan in Ibadan South West Local Government Area of Oyo State. Enugu State: The Project is located on approximately 83,000 square meters of land at Polo Park grounds in GRA, Enugu, along the Abakaliki Expressway, Enugu State. Kwara State: The Project will be located on approximately 32,240 square meters of land at Fate Road/ Alhaji Tunde Mohammed Road, by Nigeria Television Authority Station, Ilorin, Kwara State.  Persianas expects to develop additional mall projects during the lifetime of IFCs proposed investment, and may also acquire existing buildings for redevelopment and subsequent letting.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.0000000000 8.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Construction and Real Estate</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $87.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-06-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-26">37000000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-06-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-26">50000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-26">50000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Persianas Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-26">37000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Persianas Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/30933/persianas-group">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
