<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9202</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEF Global Fabrics Manufacturers Limited</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY OF PROJECT INFORMATION (SPI)    Project Name	NIGERIA: Global Fabrics Manufacturers Limited    Region		Sub-Saharan Africa    Sector		Manufacturing    Project No		009202    Projected   Board Date 		February 7, 1999    Company Name	Global Fabrics Manufacturers Limited    Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    There is no technical partner.  The project is sponsored by Messrs. M.C. Nwoba, F. Amobi and M.A. Afunugo.  Mr. M.C. Nwoba is the Chairman of the Company.  Equity is held equally (33.33% each) among the three Directors. Global is affiliated to MAFFACO Group (West Africa) Limited.  The Group comprises six companies involved in engineering and agro-business including production and export of rubber.    Project Cost including Proposed IFC Investment     Project cost including proposed IFC investment:  US$1,083,000 equivalent of which IFC has been requested to provide a loan of US$320,000.    Location of Project and Description of Site    The factory is presently located at No. 1 Uba Street, Nkpor, Idemili North L.G.A of Anambra State.  The project is to relocate the existing factory to a new, previously undeveloped, 3-hectare site in the industrial estate of Azu Village, Ogbunike Industrial layout along Enugu/Onitsha expressway. The new buildings will comprise the administrative block and staff quarters.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    The Company will acquire additional machines and equipment from Taiwan in order to expand its production of narrow fabrics and wicks.  The narrow fabrics are used for making mattress tapes, ribbon tapes, waist bands, elastic tapes, bag tapes and winding tapes.  Upon project completion, the Company will be one of the largest domestic manufacturers of these products in Nigeria.    The Company employs 30 regular workers of and some temporary workers. The project will employ an additional 53 regular workers. This import substitution project will help in the industrialization of the area.    IFC will provide a loan a long-term loan, which is currently unavailable in Nigeria.  It will also help three dynamic entrepreneurs to further develop their business activities.    Environmental Category and Issues    This is a category B project according to IFCs environmental and social review procedure.  The key environmental and health and safety issues include: sewage and solid waste management; fire prevention and emergency response; and employee health and safety, including training.  Employee sanitary sewage will be separately discharged to the local sewerage network.  Solid waste will be collected periodically by the municipality and disposed of in the local dump.  Adequate fire prevention systems have been incorporated into building design and operation.  All employees will be trained in fire prevention and response.  The facility is appropriately registered with the local fire department for provision of emergency services in case of a fire.  Global will address all aspects of employee health and safety including workplace noise, and general health and safety and training.    IFC will monitor the sponsors ongoing compliance with World Bank policies, and environmental, health and safety guidelines during the life of the project by evaluating monitoring reports submitted annually to IFC.    The Environmental Review Summary is available from the Public Information Center.    Host country location of		Federal Environmental Protection Agency Environmental documents 		(FEPA)    Date SPI sent to InfoShop		January 8, 1999    This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose to enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit   Telephone:  (202) 473-7711   Facsimile:  (202) 971-4384    \\StreetTalk\Shared Data@CAFNET@IFC\CAF\AEF\NIR\Globalspi.doc   December 17, 1998 5:05 PM  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL FABRICS MANUFACTURERS LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9202" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-07-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-01-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG-Nigeria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.0000000000 8.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BA - Household Textile Products (Including Drapes, Mattress Covers, Carpets, Towels, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.32 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-07-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-07-29">320000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-07-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-07-29">320000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GLOBAL FABRICS MANUFACTURERS LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9202/aef-global-fabrics-manufacturers-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
