<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-10090</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEF Oha Motors (Nigeria) Limited</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)    Project NameNigeria - AEF-Oha Motors (Nigeria) Limited    RegionSub-Saharan Africa   Sector   Project No010090   Projected Board DateMay 18, 2000   Company NameOha Motors (Nigeria) Limited   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    Major Shareholders: The project is sponsored by Oha Motors Nigeria Limited, a private limited liability company established in 1994. The shareholding is as follows:    		Chief Iloanusi Ohamadike		25%   		Mrs. Roseline Ohamadike		      25%   		Mr. Uche Ohamadike			25%   		Mr. Anthony Ohamadike			25%   							     100%   The major sponsor, Mr. Uche Ohamadike, 37, a chemical engineer and businessman. He was educated at the College of Technology, Enugu, Nigeria. Before venturing into motor business, he worked for his father, Chief Iloanusi Ohamadike in his motor spare parts retail outlets from where he developed the bus operations. Oha Motors is an offshoot of Oha Nigeria Limited, a spare parts trading Company managed by his father.   	The project has no technical partner.    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	The total project cost is estimated at US$2.4 million equivalent. The proposed IFC investment is a loan of US$900,000.    Location of project and Description of site    	The project consists of bus transportation between two bus stations, Lagos and Abuja, buses plying between them. The bus stations will have normal facilities for passengers and administrative offices.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    The project entails the purchase of six 55-Seater buses to start the Lagos/Abuja route.    	The company operated as Oha Nigeria Limited, a motor spare parts retail trading company until July 1999 when the transport business was separated from the trading company. The companies are family owned. The company plans to acquire six (6) new 55-seater buses to expand the company&apos;&apos;s inter-state transportation business by starting the Lagos-Abuja route. Oha buses currently ply between Lagos and Onitsha, Enugu, Owerri, Aba and Port Harcourt.    IFC will be providing a loan with long-term maturity, which is currently unavailable in the Nigerian market. Public transportation in Nigeria is presently under-served. Attempt by the Federal Government through the Federal Urban Mass Transit Authority (FUMTA) has failed. IFC will help develop a sector dominated by the private sector and vital to the economy. About 35 additional jobs will be created. The project will provide a service that will contribute to infrastructure development in Nigeria.    Environmental Category and Issues    	 This is a Category B project. Key environmental, health and safety issues include: Site location and potential pre-existing contamination; Water supply and sustainability; CFC free equipment; Fuel and other chemicals storage (including secondary containment and leak detection)Waste management including sewage, liquid, solid and hazardous waste; Control of vehicles air emissions and maintenance.   General occupational health and safety; Equipment safeguarding; Fire prevention and emergency response preparedness; and Employee exposure to noise and chemical substance.    Based on its review of the environmental information provided by Oha Motors, IFC concludes this project will be operated in a manner that meets all pertinent Government of Nigeria requirements and all relevant World Bank Group policies and environmental, health and safety guidelines.     The Environmental Review Summary is available from the InfoShop.   Host country location of environmental documentsFederal Environmental Protection Agency (FEPA)    1.    FEPA Abuja Office        Airport Road,       Abuja, FCT.        Phone:  090-802-479,        Fax:        09-5235510    2.    FEPA Lagos Office        Federal Ministry of Environment       Bishop Powell Street       Games Village       Opposite Ministry of Works       Off Bode Thomas/Eric Moore       Surulere, Lagos        Phone: 5851570-1, 5850120, 5850122-4    Date SPI sent to InfoShop April 18, 2000        This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oha Motors (Nigeria) Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-10090" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-11-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2001-08-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG-Nigeria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.0000000000 8.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AD - Transit and Ground Passenger Transporation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.90 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-11-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2001-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-11-17">900000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-11-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-11-17">900000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oha Motors (Nigeria) Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/10090/aef-oha-motors-nigeria-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
