<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9628</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEF Hygeia Nigeria Limited</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information (SPI)    Project Name		NIGERIA:  Hygeia Nigeria Limited    Region			Sub-Saharan Africa    Sector			Social Services (Health Care, Education)    Project No.		009628    Projected Board	June 25, 1999   Date    Company Name	Hygeia Nigeria Limited    Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	There is no technical partner.  The company has a technical agreement with Health Partners, a health management organization based in Minneapolis, USA to provide training and advice.  The principal sponsors of the project are Professor E.A. Elebute and his wife Professor O.W. Elebute, a husband and wife team who were founding members of the leading University Teaching Hospital in Lagos in the early 1960s.  The two principal promoters own 55% of the shares.  Other major shareholders are three leading insurance companies, UNIC Insurance Plc (12%), African Alliance Insurance Company (8.3%) and Lion of Africa Insurance Plc (8.3%).    Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    	Project cost including proposed IFC investment:  US$2,186,000 equivalent including a proposed IFC investment of US$581,000.    Location of Project and Description of Site    	Project Location:  The project will be located in Lagos, Nigeria.  Lagoon Hospital is located Apapa, Lagos and proposed model clinics will all be located in Lagos.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project   (include IFCs Role and Development Impact)    	Hygeia Nigeria Limited was established in 1984.  It owns and operates Lagoon hospital, a 40 bed hospital in Apapa, Lagos which opened in 1986.  The hospital provides tertiary health care services and preventive health screening facilities to a high end niche  and care in various medical specializations.  It also operates satellite clinics for its corporate clients within the clients premises.  The company offers a managed care scheme which provides primary and secondary level health care services to large corporate clients in the Lagos metropolis at a fixed cost.  The project is intended to upgrade existing tertiary health care services at Lagoon Hospital and expand the companys managed care business.  The managed care product satisfies customers current buying criteria of low cost and quality service while eliminating the problem of fraud and abuse.  IFC will be providing a loan with longer maturities than presently available in Nigeria.  The managed care scheme will ensure the maintenance of quality while reducing the cost of healthcare delivery.     Environmental Category and Issues    This is a category B project according to IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental and social review procedure.  Environmental issues associated with this project include: Site location, prior use and land acquisition process; handling and storage of medical material; storage, handling and final disposal of chemicals; source of water and power supply; hygiene and implementation of good medical management practices; waste management; CFC free air conditioning and cold storage equipment; provision of employee protective clothing and equipment; exposure of employees to radioactive material; employees health and safety training; and fire prevention.    The sponsor has presented plans to address these issues and demonstrate that the proposed project will comply with applicable governmental and World Bank requirements. In particular, the fuel storage area is to be protected by retention bunds; medical supplies and chemicals will be locked in the Pharmacy Store and handled by regularly trained staff.    At IFCs request, the sponsor has commissioned a consultant to undertake the development and implementation of a comprehensive waste management plan.  Hazardous and biomedical wastes are collected separately and will be incinerated in situ in a specifically built incinerator that the sponsor has undertaken to install.  The Lagos Municipal Incinerator represents another facility, which could be used if it is adequately licensed to accept these types of waste and deemed adequate after a site visit by the IFC environment department.   Sharp objects such as needles and blades are currently being secured in refuse cans before being disposed, together with other hazardous and bio-medical waste by the Waste Disposal Authority, to an authorized landfill together with other solid waste.   Sanitary waste is disposed of in septic tanks incorporating filter soakaway and are regularly emptied.  The sludges are discharged to an authorized landfill. Other wastewater, essentially kitchen wastewater and laundry waste water, is treated in separate soakaway pits.  All treated effluents from the septic tanks and soakaway pits percolate into the ground.       The sponsor has developed an adequate health and safety plan including an emergency response and evacuation plan and fire safety is ensured by an alarm, fire extinguishers and reels of hoses on each floor. Plans have been made to install smoke detectors and automatic water sprinklers    The Environmental Review Summary is available from the Public Information Center     Host country location of		Federal Environmental Protection Agency (FEPA)   environmental documents		Apapa local government Headquarters    Date SPI sent to InfoShop		May 25, 1999    This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit   telephone:	(202) 473-7711   facsimile:	(202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HYGEIA NIGERIA LIMITED</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9628" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-09-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-03-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG-Nigeria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.0000000000 8.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Hospitals and Clinics</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.58 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-09-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-09">200000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-09-09"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-09">380000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-09">380000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HYGEIA NIGERIA LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-09-09">200000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HYGEIA NIGERIA LIMITED</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9628/aef-hygeia-nigeria-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
