<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-42187</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indorama Eleme Fertilizer and Chemicals Limited</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Indorama Group (Indorama or the Sponsor) a long-standing IFC client in several countries, is one of the worlds fastest growing groups in the petrochemical and fibres business, with global business presence in 35 countries in Asia, Africa, Europe and the Americas and more than 37,000 employees.&#xA0;   In August 2006, Indorama International Finance Plc, UK (Indorama International) purchased a 75% equity stake in what was formerly known as Eleme Petrochemicals Company Limited (now known as Indorama Eleme Petrochemicals Limited  IEPL) under the Nigerian federal governments privatization plan, to which IFC had acted as advisor. IFC also invested in Indorama to implement a turnaround program for Elemes olefins, polyethylene and polypropylene plants (IFC Project # 24802).&#xA0;   In June 2016, Indorama successfully commissioned a 1.4 million metric tons per annum (MMtpa) urea fertilizer facility (including a captive ammonia facility) in Nigeria under its Indorama Eleme Fertilizer &amp; Chemicals Limited (IEFCL or the Company) subsidiary, with investment from IFCs own account, IFC-mobilized parallel lenders and other commercial lenders (IFC Project #30967).   In March 2016 IFC made an additional investment in IEFCL to support construction of a jetty in the nearby Onne port for the export of fertilizer (IFC Project #38096).   Having successfully commissioned the Line I Ammonia Urea fertilizer facility, Indorama also approved the construction of Line II, the second ammonia / urea fertilizer line, to expand the current capacity to 2.8 MMtpa; IFC provided a loan to this project as well (Project # 40420). Line II is currently under construction and is expected to be operational by 3rd quarter of 2021.&#xA0;   IFC is considering a further investment in IEFCL of up to US$35 million (MM) for its own account and up to US$115MM in parallel loans to be mobilized from commercial banks and other DFIs, for construction of a feed conditioning unit (FCU), an add-on gas processing facility to Line II with capacity of 160 MM standard cubic feet per day (the Project). The FCU will recover carbon dioxide in the gas and shall also separate heavier by-products. This will ensure the supply of gas having consistent composition to Line II, and the heavier by-product will help increase polymer production in IEPL .   The Project will essentially replicate, at a larger size, the recently completed FCU unit, located next to the IFC-supported Eleme Fertilizer I urea plant (project #30967) and used for the recovery of heavier by-products from feedstock supplied by a gas supplier. The first FCU, which was completed in 2018, was installed as part of the construction of Line I and is operating satisfactorily.   FCU II will be located next to the existing FCU; the two units will share several facilities including the control room and flare systems. The Project is expected to be started up in April 2022, about a year after expected Line II start-up.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project will promote (i) Economic diversification in Nigeria by increasing supply of raw materials converted to higher value products; (ii) Direct and indirect employment; (iii) Environmental impact through savings in feed usage and the reduction in CO2/GHG emissions; (iv) Integration of smaller downstream companies in the value chain, and possible development of additional plastic processors in Nigeria with the increase in polymer product availability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INDORAMA ELEME FERTILIZER AND CHEMICALS LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-42187" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  Location: Rivers State    Address:     Headquarters, Eleme Local Government Area,    Eleme, Rivers State, Nigeria</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indorama Eleme Fertilizer &amp; Chemicals Limited (IEFCL)  Mr. Rahul Moondra  Senior Manager - Finance  +234 -8129130097  infoprojectsii@indorama.com.ng  P.M.B. 5151, Port Harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria  www.iefcl.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="NG-Nigeria">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Port Harcourt, Nigeria</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.0000000000 8.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="3251" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">G-BE - Petrochemical</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $35.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">35000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-30">35000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INDORAMA ELEME FERTILIZER AND CHEMICALS LTD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/42187">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/42187">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
