<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14207" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-AF-12-14207</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helmand Agriculture Sector Programme (HASP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HASP adopts an integrated approach to agricultural development by tackling the chosen value chains through customer demand stimulation and an improved supply-side provision by the private sector. In order to stimulate economic growth, improve agricultural skills and livelihoods, and create jobs, Mercy Corps&#x2019; programme will include this range of interventions, which would be implemented in target communities using a systemic approach. 

This programme will strengthen the market mechanisms that support self-determined options that farmers can select to build their livelihoods that depend on agriculture.  HASP will conduct this dialogue between the private sector and the government to clarify roles and responsibilities and to build capacity in each along those lines.

The Theory of Change is that by improving the quality of goods and services at a competitive price and with an extended market distribution channel to new locations, all farmers in the industry will stand to benefit.   This hypothesis is challenged by the continued presence of development actors who persist with giving away free inputs.

Poor access to electricity is a critical constraint to the sustainability and expansion of businesses.  Businesses that operate in the agricultural processing sector have great capacity to add value to local produce, supply reasonably priced foodstuffs, and to create employment. HASP will undertake a small energy related project to develop a viable business model for promoting decentralized electricity supply to commercial enterprises in Lashkar Gah.

The focus on HASP will be to support the input supply industries that are critical to improve farming production and to strengthen market linkages for selling and or processing this produce.  The indirect goal is to improve farmers&#x2019; incomes by increasing the competitiveness and quality of service among the input suppliers in Helmand, and extending these services to districts outside of Lashkar Gah.  The key value chains under HASP are:

a) Meat Value Chain &#x2013; with a specific focus on increasing the availability and accessibility of improved ruminant feed, which is critical to the health of animals.
b) Fruit and vegetables &#x2013; increase the capacity of agricultural retailers to provide value added inputs and services at a competitive market prices.
c) Work with DAIL to clarify and strengthen an appropriate oversight role for regulating the market
d) Pilot test a private sector management structure to support commercial provision of biomass electricity &#x2013; to develop the availability of commercially available and cheaper electricity to supply power to agricultural processors and secondary support businesses that are connected with the agricultural industry</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps&#x2019; goal within the HASP programme is Improved agricultural market systems supporting small farmer livelihoods.  The purpose is to increase transactional relationships between target farmers and vendors to improve the availability of market inputs and technical advice, promote off-season production for improved prices, and improved postharvest handing and processing to open up new sales avenues. 

HASP has the following outcomes:

1. Improvement in the capacity and marketing orientation of vendors supplying to the agricultural sector &#x2013; Livestock farmers have sustainable access to improved quality animal feed and fruit and vegetables farmers have access to affordable inputs, both leading to reduced cost of production per unit sold.

2. Improved capacity and institutionalised role of DAIL for oversight of the private sector and consumer protection. 

3. Support to farmers and agri-businesses through consolidating farmer aggregation and cooperation through semi-formal groups, linkages to markets and increased access to financial services and inputs.  This will promote the viability and efficiency for access to sales markets.

 
4. Business model for providing biomass powered affordable electricity for commercial customers &#x2013; This will be a platform for primarily seeking investment capital with possible donor start-up support capital to provide private sector electricity supply to agri-business and related firms and potentially additional income to farmers supplying the biomass fuel.

- in the NCE to March: HASP will provide a sustainable electric supply to the existing but non-operational cold storage units in Helmand, and potentially other secondary agricultural processing businesses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-AF-12-14207" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="4652.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1140043">
   <location-id code="1140043" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helmand</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helmand, Afghanistan (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1140043" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.0 64.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-10-01">1482557.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Department for International Development (DFID)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
