<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14177" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-TL-13-14177</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combatting malnutrition and reducing poverty in Timor-Leste through inland fish farming</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OVERALL OBJECTIVE:
To decrease malnutrition and poverty in Timor-Leste by promoting inland fish farming and integrated agri-aquaculture systems (IAAS)

SPECIFIC OBJECTIVE:
To improve inland aquaculture production systems, enhance dietary diversity and increase income among 1500 vulnerable households in Timor-Leste

RESULTS:
Result 1- Increased production of and access to nutritious foods from fish farming and integrated agri-aquaculture systems (IAAS) in target communities

Result 2- Enhanced consumption of balanced diet through increased intake of fish and nutritious crops by target household members

Result 3- Established linkages between aquaculture activities and markets</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposed intervention rationale:

Mercy Corps, and partner Hivos, jointly propose Combatting Malnutrition and Poverty through Aquaculture in Timor-Leste, which is based on the successful work of both agencies in aquaculture and nutrition over the past three (3) years in diverse rural areas of Timor-Leste, primarily working with resource poor farmers. WorldFish will join the Programme as a technical and research partner and to compliment the in-country experience of Mercy Corps and Hivos. Together the three agencies will comprise a Consortium, to be led by Mercy Corps in the implementation of the Programme. In preparation for this proposal, the Consortium consulted extensively with the National Directorate of Fisheries and Aquaculture (NDFA) of the Ministry of Agriculture and Fisheries (MAF), and the National Center for Fisheries and Aquaculture (NIWA) of New Zealand.1
Addressing poverty and malnutrition in Timor-Leste is critical as it remains one of the least-developed countries in the world with almost 70% of the population living on less than $2 a day and 40% living on less than a $1 a day2. According to figures published by the United Nation&#x2019;s Children Fund (UNICEF) in 2011, Timor-Leste has the third highest rate globally of chronically malnourished children under 5 at 54%.

The Combatting Malnutrition and Poverty through Aquaculture programme will promote inland fish farming, and where feasible integrated aqua-agriculture systems (IAAS), as a viable means to increase both access to nutritious food as well as income for an estimated 2,000 resource poor farming households in nine rural Districts of Timor-Leste. An additional 30,000 community members will benefit from the programme through awareness raising and behavior change programming around good nutritional practices, increased availability of fish and other nutritious foods such as orange-fleshed sweet potatoes, leafy greens and legumes in the local markets, economic linkages through fish traders, input providers, and, where feasible, through the promotion of local fish in school feeding programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Centre for Fisheries and Aquaculture (NIWA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Zealand Ministry of Agriculture and Fisheries (MAF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Zealand National Directorate of Fisheries and Aquaculture (NDFA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Norwegian Embassy in Jakarta</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WorldFish</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-TL-13-14177" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="5217.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">2076265</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Norwegian Embassy in Jakarta</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2013-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="32000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
