<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14152" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-ID-14-14152</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Services for Infrastructure and Sanitation Technology (INSIST) II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal: To develop an affordable, sustainable, and context appropriate waste management system in poverty affected high-density communities of Jakarta

Objectives:
1- Refined, newly developed sanitation technologies are user friendly, context appropriate and can be sold at affordable price points
2- Demand and access to affordable sanitation services is increased in one poverty affected Kelurahan of North Jakarta
3- A sustainable and vibrant market for affordable sanitation services is developed by facilitating the role of stakeholders (market, government and community actors) to enable sanitation solutions for the urban and peri-urban poor in Jakarta</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia&apos;s rapidly urbanizing population, along with an existing lack of sanitation and water services for many, mean that there is a need for enhanced infrastructure which supports the health and hygiene of the urban poor. INSIST II will build on the research of INSIST, RW Siaga Plus+ and PUSH to provide market-based sustainable solutions for households in the Kelurahan (Village) Penjaringan, in Kecamatan (Sub-District) Penjaringan in North Jakarta.

In particular, activities will include a market research and feasibility study to determine the sanitation and fiscal needs of households in the target area; the development of a sanitation value chain analysis and report to highlight key stakeholders and market constraints which will determine design interventions; the development and refinement of a Sanitation Management Plan in partnership with the Department of Public Works and other government administrations; Identifying of community stakeholders and establishing a community Sanitation Task Force to manage sanitation systems implementation; Construction of household and communal septic tanks as well as sludge removal carts and storage facilities; Developing a community fecal removal model; Creating a social marketing campaign with key players to facilitate behavior change and knowledge dissemination around sanitation products; partnering with local SMEs to install and operate sanitation products; and working with local MFIs to create sanitation related financial services for households.

This will improve the access of urban poor households to sanitation products and facilitate a market for low-cost, sustainable sanitation solutions which will be replicable in other areas. INSIST II will also instill partnerships between community stakeholders, government actors, and private sector players to ensure buy-in.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-ID-14-14152" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="5908.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1642907">
   <location-id code="1642907" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jakarta Raya</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jakarta Raya, Indonesia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1642907" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-6.2182 106.8584</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="13" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-06-01">303663</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IKEA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
