<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3360" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-MN-12-3360</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Productive Agribusiness Chains Support (PACS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Local, regional, and international market research:
During the first year of project implementation, the PACS partners will undertake detailed assessments of the beef, pork and dairy value chains, identifying the constraints that limit their productivity as well as opportunities for growth both within Mongolia and for export markets. These assessments, completed in both Mongolian and English language versions, will build on the PACS partners&#x2019; current understanding of the agriculture sector in Mongolia generally, while providing some baseline information and guidance for project activities. However, the main target of the assessment conclusions will be the project beneficiaries themselves, highlighting for them the specific opportunities that exist within the meat and dairy markets in Mongolia for growth, informing the business they take at each step of the value chain. The findings will also be disseminated widely to other market stakeholders, such as business service providers (see activity below) and microfinance institutions, as well as the Ministry of Food, Agriculture, and Light Industry (MoFALI) so as to directly inform their own decisions on accessing technical assistance in areas most relevant to their own enterprises. Business associations will also be able to use the information to increase their advocacy to government on all levels to inform on-going policy development. Government agencies will use the information to identify priorities for reform or budgeting, or to ensure that initiatives are at least not harmful to the meat and dairy value chains. Each assessment report will take into account the context specific to each targeted aimag, identifying where respective opportunities for beef, pork and dairy are strongest. This activity will directly benefit 29,520 agribusinesses, in this case including livestock producers, input suppliers, business service providers and processors. The budget for this activity is $75,910.

(2) Intensive training on improved on-farm practices:
To meet the need for more and better quality meat and dairy production at the farm level, the PACS project will facilitate access to intensive training and technical assistance for livestock producers and their employees. First, during the first two years of implementation, PACS will work with aimag-level, state-run Vocational Training Centers (VTCs), building on Mercy Corps&#x2019; recent development work with these partners to develop new winter school curricula focused on increasing on-farm capacity to intensify dairy, pig and beef production. These courses will last up to 45 days and will focus on the context-specific needs identified as critical constraints. Education and training opportunities are traditionally highly valued in Mongolia, but where necessary, PACS will provide up to 50 percent of training costs to facilitate the participation of producers and/or their employees during the first two years of the project. The training courses will remain available for attendance at the VTCs beyond the life of the project. Second, the PACS partners will facilitate the access to the services provided by the strengthened business service provider network (see activity below) by providing cost share to cover part of the cost of acquiring such services for the first time. Maximum cost share value for livestock producers will be 50 percent and this will only be available once per participating individual. VTC participation in value chain linkage activities (see activity below) will promote recognition of the value of the training and will foster continued attendance at the course beyond the PACS implementation period. Budget amount: $455,466.

(3) Improved capacity to provide training and technical assistance:
As noted in the Strategic Analysis, a nascent business service provider sector exists in Mongolia with the potential to provide local expertise to strengthen agricultural value chains. This sector has been growing through the efforts of Mercy Corps, Development Solutions, and the Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation (SDC), which have been building the capacity of individuals and enterprises in Mongolia with specific technical expertise to deliver technical assistance to a variety of businesses in a variety of sectors. This service enables entrepreneurs to identify the factors that limit productivity and sales and helps them develop and enact strategies for overcoming them. PACS will focus considerable effort on improving and expanding this sector, particularly those consultants and business services providers (BSPs) who focus on agriculture, with the expectation of establishing a sound source of technical expertise that will be available beyond the life of project activities. This will be linked closely to USAID&#x2019;s Business Plus Initiative, which is developing a Center of Excellence aimed at supporting the same beneficiaries with the same capacities. Direct beneficiaries will be the local consultants and other BSPs, while the livestock producers, processors and input suppliers who make use of the improved technical services will be indirect beneficiaries. Capacity will be built in subjects relevant to improving each step of the meat and dairy value chains. At the on-farm level, BSPs will be able to address (1) dairy specific needs for improved post production milk handling and quality assurance, (2) improved on-farm technologies and inputs, such as improved feed, milking equipment, breeding and animal health, and (3) improved farm management and business planning to maximize local operations according to the local context. Farther up the value chain, BSPs will work with suppliers and processors to (1) facilitate the adoption of international food safety assurance systems such as Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points (HACCP), Good Manufacturing Practices, and Good Hygiene Practices; (2) improve veterinarian inspection services; (3) introduce better processing technologies; and (4) improve marketing of final products. In all cases, the PACS project will facilitate BSP participation in capacity building activities by providing a cost share to help defray initial costs to participation. It is expected that the increased use of their services will result greater incomes, thus providing continued economic incentive to continue improving their services. It is also expected that through increased linkages among value chain actors, other, non-participant producers and agribusinesses will also become interested in obtaining training and technical assistance from consultants and BSPs. These activities will take place all three years of implementation in all targeted aimags. Direct beneficiaries will include livestock producers, BSPs and processors. BSPs, processors and there employees are all referred to as Agribusiness Owners in the beneficiary section, given limited selection of beneficiary types. Budget amount: $393,028.

(4) Increase and improve animal feed production and preservation:
During the first year of implementation, Mercy Corps will identify up to five producers, who, having availed themselves of training and/or technical assistance regarding improved fodder production and use, are interested in pursuing a specialized and intensified fodder mineral supplements and fortified feed production and/or preservation component to their enterprise. Mercy Corps will facilitate partnerships between these producers and Government of Mongolia&#x2019;s Institute for Animal Husbandry. Researchers from that Institute will guide the introduction of fodder production and/or preservation on the targeted producers&#x2019; farms during the remainder of the implementation period, encouraging new and innovative approaches to producing and marketing this critical input. Through activities to strengthen market linkages among value chain actors (see activity below), animal feed producers will be able to interact with other livestock producers and market their activities through direct contact or through demonstration of their own animals. As their enterprises grow, these feed producers will also be able to advertize their product in input supplier &#x201C;yellow pages&#x201D; (again, see activity below). Other producers will be able to uptake feed-related activities through the increased ability of the Institute for Animal Husbandry to provide technical assistance. Other business service providers will be available through the training and technical assistance activities to support business planning and implementation. For initial animal feed producers, PACS will provide a one-time grant amounting to about 20 percent of the initial costs of instigating fodder production activities, while the remainder of the cost will be the responsibility of the producer. This activity will take place in no more than five targeted aimags, but the specific geographic targeting will depend on where the most appropriate recipients emerge. Budget amount: $145,193.

(5) Strengthen market linkages among value chain actors:
During all three years of implementation and throughout the targeted aimags, PACS will facilitate and/or organize local, regional and national business relationships among livestock producers, input suppliers, processors and business service providers (BSPs). These events will include market days, where livestock producers can learn from each other&#x2019;s successful practices, access information about input and service providers available in the area, and connect with potential buyers of their meat and dairy products. Market days have already been established in the aimags where Mercy Corps has implemented economic development activities in the past, and the new phase of funding will introduce new ones in new geographic areas, becoming sustainable as their organization becomes a viable economic opportunity. The project will also conduct 10 study tours annually highlighting the most promising developments in livestock-based livelihoods, producer-to-business and business-to-business meetings, animal health demonstrations, elite animal shows, and other relevant gatherings. To facilitate participation in these events and to drive the growth of the network of value chain-related relationships, the PACS project will provide cost share to cover a portion of the cost of attending such events. Cost share will primarily benefit livestock producers, but also smaller agribusiness entrepreneurs, especially those located in more remote areas. In addition to these events, PACS will work with the government&#x2019;s National Extension Service Center and local organization Media for Business to build on a successful pilot activity that regularly collects and consolidates input supplier and BSP information into an annual &#x201C;yellow pages&#x201D; publication for use by producers and other agribusinesses. The information will be available in printed format and Mercy Corps will explore information delivery on individual requests via SMS. This information will be available for purchase in all target aimags as well as the rest of Mongolia. The direct beneficiaries include both livestock producers and input suppliers (referred to as Agribusiness owners in the beneficiary information). Budget amount: $523,220.

(6) Adoption of international safety and quality standards:
To accommodate the growing demand for minimum standards by Mongolian consumers, as well as to meet export requirements, PACS will facilitate the meat and dairy processing industries to adopt internationally recognized standards. PACS will work with the Government of Mongolia&#x2019;s General Agency for Specialized Inspection and the Center for Excellence funded through USAID&#x2019;s Business Plus Initiative, to develop specialized training courses for business service providers on Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points (HACCP), Good Manufacturing Practices (GMP), and Good Hygiene Practices (GHP), and ISO 22000 certification. These will be medium-term trainings, lasting up to 45 days, from which consultants will be able to advise processors on implementing HACCP or other recognized standards for processing and potentially earn auditor or lead auditor certification on ISO 22000. The resulting cadre of certified consultants will be available to assist processing businesses in incorporating these practices. As international standards, government licensing of these services will not be required. PACS will facilitate this initial access by cost sharing 50 percent of initial services while the business owner covers the other 50 percent. To further encourage the adoption of improved practices in processing, PACS will also provide a limited cost share to processors who want to introduce safety assurance systems in rural areas, amounting to 20 percent of the required investment cost. Each component of this activity will take place during all three years of project implementation. Consultant training will likely be set in Ulaanbaatar. Mercy Corps expects agribusinesses from all targeted aimags to adopt improved safety and quality standards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary: The markets for meat and dairy products in Mongolia have tremendous potential to reduce poverty in the country because of both the capacity for expansion of the livestock sector and the growing demand for quality products in urban markets. In response to this opportunity, Mercy Corps plans to monetize 2,500 metric tons (MT) of refined vegetable oil and use the proceeds to increase the productivity of meat and dairy value chains and expand trade of those goods. In this program, Mercy Corps and its partners, USDA legacy organization Development Solutions and livestock and dairy development specialists Land O&#x2019;Lakes, will initiate the three-year Productive Agribusiness Chains Support (PACS) project, which will focus activities on overcoming key challenges that specifically constrain the meat and dairy markets in eleven aimags (provinces). Reaching a total of 29,670 direct and 30,540 indirect beneficiaries, the proposed PACS project will build on Mercy Corps&#x2019; previous activities with USDA funding which created the foundation of a dynamic and lucrative agricultural sector in Mongolia by increasing access to financial services, building capacity in basic production and handling techniques, nurturing a new business services sector, and improving animal health services delivery. The aim of the project is to translate the individual achievements of earlier programs into a substantial step forward in productivity that accelerates improvements in the agribusiness sector. By the end of the PACS project, participating livestock producers will experience a 15 percent growth in productivity, while value chain actors will achieve a 20 percent growth in sales and a 25 percent growth in production volume.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-MN-12-3360" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Recovery and Development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-01">4588265</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
