<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14011" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-GE-14-14011</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Market Alliances in the Lesser Caucasus Region of Georgia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Goal of the ALCP is to contribute to poverty alleviation and the transition to a durable market economy for the livestock sector in the Kvemo-Kartli, Samstkhe Javakheti and Ajara regions of Georgia.

Purpose: To enable the livestock market system to function more efficiently for &amp;amp; inclusively of small-scale livestock producers in Kvemo-Kartli, Samstkhe Javakheti and Ajara regions of Georgia resulting in improved productivity, incomes and resilience to livelihood shocks.

Outcome 1: SSLP&#x2019;s as Customers. Supporting Functions: SSLP&#x2019;s can access target services veterinary, breeding, nutrition, access to information and access to finance which will enable them to make informed decisions for improving their productivity.

Outcome 2: SSLP&#x2019;s as Suppliers. Core Related Supporting Functions &amp;amp; Core Related Rules. Market Access and Terms of Trade are improved by facilitating key market players in the form of enterprises producing or reliant on the supply of milk, meat, wool and to enable increased opportunities for SSLP&#x2019;s to supply products to market. A market, which will in Ajara include the supply of products to the mass and rural tourist markets. Support to enterprises in the form of business related consultancy services is a key component under this outcome the importance of which has been made apparent in the programming to date. These services will range from those focussed on FS&amp;amp;H to BDS, technical consultancy, environmental consultancy, training consultancy etc. FS&amp;amp;H forms the core related rule which forms the key driver for change.

Outcome 3: Rules: SSLP&#x2019;s as Citizens Dependent on Livestock Production. Improved rules relating to the local governance of SSLP&#x2019;s operating environment. Working with gender, governance and DRR and in aspects of these issues that are directly relevant and high priority for SSLP&#x2019;s means generating support for the efficient, and pro-SSLP, functioning of the market system in which the farmers are market actors</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to expound and detail the agreed Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation (SDC) and Mercy Corps (MCS) merger, expansion and scale up of the exiting Alliances livestock development programmes in Samstkhe Javakheti and Kvemo Kartli into three new municipalities of Kevmo Kartli and the Autonomous Republic of Adjara, in a new rural economic development programme the Alliances Lesser Caucasus Programme6(ALCP).

The ALCP will be launched from February 15th 2014 running until February 14th 2019 and will target small scale livestock producers in the mountainous and lower land regions of Kvemo Kartli (KK), Samtskhe-Javakheti (SJ) and Ajara (Aj) where since the collapse of the Soviet Union very little governmental support and no major development assistance has reached or been focussed on the agricultural sector. The ALCP programme will scale up the existing Alliances programmes and their interventions in the beef, dairy and wool sectors of the livestock market system to the new Kvemo Kartli municipalities of Bolnisi, Gardabani and Marneuli and the region of Ajara, targeting the municipalities of Khulo, Shuakhevi and Keda in particular but not excluding the rest of Ajara. In the existing programme areas it will focus on deepening supporting functions, maximizing scale and copying and crowding in around existing interventions and players facilitated by the programme. In Ajara, the demand for dairy and meat products from the tourism market will be harnessed to offer considerable pro poor opportunities for growth to small scale livestock producers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-52-0846183" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Communities (formerly CHF International)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation (SDC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-GE-14-14011" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="5723.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-28" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_615929">
   <location-id code="615929" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ajaria</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ajaria, Georgia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="615929" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.66667 42.0</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <location ref="gn_865536">
   <location-id code="865536" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvemo Kartli</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvemo Kartli, Georgia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="865536" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.51667 44.51667</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-03-01">7771898</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation (SDC)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="30000"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
