<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14176" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-NP-15-14176</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Responding to Earthquake-Affected Communities and Households in Nepal (REACH)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goal: Affected populations in Nepal are able to meet their basic needs and recover from the effects of the 2015 earthquakes 

Objective: Earthquake-affected households access temporary shelter materials to help meet their immediate needs

Objective: Earthquake-affected communities regain their access to clean water and safe sanitation</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps requests $1 million from OFDA to reach an estimated 17,500 women, men, girls and boys affected by the April 25 and May 12, 2015 earthquakes and subsequent aftershocks and landslides. Our proposed program focuses on emergency response interventions in the sectors of Shelter and
Settlements and Water, Sanitation and Hygiene to help affected households, and communities recover from the effects of the earthquakes, while also working to stimulate local-level businesses and markets. Mercy Corps will provide necessary temporary shelter materials to affected households, as well as a one-time $75 cash transfer to enable households to meet their individually prioritized needs. Mercy Corps will only provide a one-time cash transfer as UNICEF and the government anticipate providing additional cash transfers. 4 UNICEF has stated that it will supplement the government&#x2019;s social protection payments across 11 districts for an estimated 255,000 people, with two cashtransfers of $30 for eligible households scheduled for June and September. The government&#x2019;s social protection transfers are approximately $5 to $10 per household with priority given to the elderly, people with disabilities and women-headed or single mother households. Mercy Corps will deliver cash transfers through local wholesale and retail networks, thereby also supporting the economic
recovery of affected businesses. Mercy Corps and our implementing partner will raise awareness about proper hygiene through the distribution of Information, Education and Communication (IEC) materials, combined with improved access to sanitation facilities where appropriate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-NP-15-14176" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-05" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-05" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="18" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12" percentage="33.333333333333336" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter and Housing</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13" percentage="33.33333333333333" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation and Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
