<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14195" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-US-10-14195</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical and Operational Performance Support (TOPS) Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The TOPS Program aims to identify, synthesize, adapt, and share the highest quality information and tools to build capacity and establish best practices among USAID&#x2019;s development food assistance program partners. The TOPS Program is a five-year Leader with Associates (LWA) Cooperative Agreement (August 13, 2010 - August 12, 2015) with a global mandate to enhance opportunities for sharing knowledge and best practices among practitioners in the multifaceted food security community. 

In implementing TOPS, Save the Children (SC) leads a strong consortium of experienced food security grantees that brings specialized knowledge to the TOPS Program. The five principal consortium partners are the CORE Group (knowledge management), Food for the Hungry (social and behavioral change), Mercy Corps (agriculture and natural resources), and TANGO International (monitoring and evaluation). SC manages and directs TOPS, and provides technical support for nutrition and food technology. The TOPS Program brings together an experienced and capable program management team, an engaged membership with participation by the majority of Food for Peace grantees, a commitment to efficient, inclusive and transparent processes, and respected collaborating and resource partners that bring new thinking and new networks to food security and nutrition programming. 

TOPS builds a network of food security practitioners around the world to identify, analyze, improve, and share information, tools, and promising practices to improve program performance. 

The Program uses four fundamental approaches to address the food security community&#x2019;s needs: 

&#x2022; A directed program of capacity-building activities for USAID&#x2019;s development food assistance partners, led by TOPS technical staff; 

&#x2022; An inclusive community of practice through the Food Security and Nutrition (FSN) Network and technical task forces and interest groups with open membership to all USAID grantees and other food security stakeholders; 

&#x2022; A food security and nutrition web portal (www.fsnnetwork.org), the foundation of the TOPS knowledge sharing system; and 

&#x2022; A small grants program promoting the creation, use, and adaptation of capacity-building tools and encouraging evaluation and documentation to build the evidence base as part of TOPS&#x2019; strategies for the dissemination of best practices to food security and nutrition stakeholders (grantees, local NGOs and other partners, as appropriate), with a focus on field-led and collaborative initiatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The TOPS Strategic Objective is highest quality information, knowledge, and best practices for improved methodologies in Title II food assistance commodity program performance identified, established, shared, and adapted. 

The theory of change for the TOPS program follows a knowledge management results chain which outlines the four project results that are hypothesized contributors to the program strategic objective. 

PR1: Knowledge capture: Knowledge and skill needs of audiences identified.  

PR2: Knowledge generation: Reliable, high-quality information synthesized and produced in user-friendly, appropriate formats.

PR3: Knowledge application: Effective and appropriate traditional and non-traditional skill delivery approaches and systems / applications used. And

PR4: Knowledge sharing: Information, skill and knowledge exchange supported and expanded.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of Food for Peace (USAID/FFP)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-US-10-14195" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="4953.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-08-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="US" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-08-01">1995140</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Office of Food for Peace (USAID/FFP)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
