<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/3359" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-KG-12-3359</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food for Education 2012 (FFE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">30,000</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program&#x2019;s goal is to empower communities and government to achieve sustained, improved educational achievement in schools in the most underserved educational institutions in 40 regions of the country, through the provision of commodities for warm, nutritious in-school meals for 30,000 students.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the McGovern-Dole Food for Education (FFE) program, Mercy Corps will implement a 36-month school feeding program in all 40 rural regions of the Kyrgyz Republic.  The FFE program will support schools through the current complexities and reforms initiated by a new government following 2010&#x2019;s revolution and inter-ethnic violence and subsequent economic hardships, exacerbating an already high 60% rural poverty rate and a 48.5% country-wide child poverty rate.

The learning environment will be improved through approximately 300 infrastructure and equipment grants to improve kitchen facilities, energy efficiency and sanitation benefiting at least 160,000 school children, with the intent of decreasing absences, and working with the Ministry of Education to pilot a modified primary school feeding program.  Intensive training of school administrators, parents, cooks and dietitians, and especially government representatives with influence over school feeding program policies and regulations will be a critical component of the FFE program to ensure increased government support for improved child literacy and increased use of health and dietary practices.  The FFE feeding component, school grants, and capacity-building activities will act as a stimuli for involvement on behalf of schools and local governments in mobilization and sustainability planning projects with Mercy Corps and FFE for continued provision of healthy school lunches, and maintenance and implementation of school infrastructure projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-KG-12-3359" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-09-21" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="5" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
