<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/4558" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-GT-12-4558</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Nutrition and Health Care Project (Nutri Salud)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CNHC is a health and nutrition improvement program that builds support for Guatemalan policies and structures that facilitate the dual focus on municipalities and civil society, such as the national policy mandating government entities and local NGOs to implement interventions designed to eradicate malnutrition and reduce resulting diseases related to hunger. To synergistically improve capacities in both municipalities and civil society, CNHC assists local entities to improve inter-sectoral coordination and strengthen links among themselves. The program emphasizes better use of data to create a culture of sharing of information and results as well as a system of accountability to communities.

To strengthen the ability of COMUDEs (Municipal Development Councils) to implement their plans and also to promote institutionalization and long-term sustainability, CNHC administers a robust competitive grants program for awards to NGOs and other  civil society organizations integrated into COMUDEs&#x2019; work plans and current US Government programs in the CNHC areas. The grants program selects and supports groups that  prioritize vastly underserved groups, remote rural areas, and/or innovative approaches to engaging communities in monitoring health and nutrition status. All grantees benefit from financial  and management support and training, through our partner SHARE. 

CNHC also supports municipalities to embrace their role in coordination and monitoring, bringing together public and private-sector resources, linking nutrition and health actions with other sectors, and reporting  results.  

In Municipal Health Districts (DMS), the program expands and consolidates quality practices for Promotion of Essential Obstetrical and Neonatal Care (ProCONE), covering the continuum of care from community health workers and NGOs in the PEC and other models to health posts, health centers, and secondary level Permanent Health Centers (CAP) and Integrated Maternal and Child Health Care Centers (CAIMI).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University Research Center</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-GT-12-4558" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Democracy and Governance</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
