<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14147" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-ID-14-14147</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of Pest Control and GAP Services for Cashew Farmers in Bima and Dompu (PRISMA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Currently Indonesia accounts for only 4% of the global raw cashew nut market, yet it is an increasingly important export commodity for Indonesia. National earnings from cashew exports increased substantially from US$ 44 million in 2011 to US$ 97 million in 2012. The main cashew producing provinces in the country are East and West Java, South Sulawesi, Nusa Tenggara Timur, and Nusa Tenggara Barat. The major cashew processing countries globally are Vietnam and India, which account for more than 70% of the market. However, due to decreasing ability to meet importers&#x2019; demands around delivery time, quantity and quality, supplies from these two countries have declined since 2009. The decline from Vietnam and India as primary exporters has provided opportunity for Indonesia to tap into the market.

The intervention development of pest control and GAP services was selected because it is expected to increase yield productivity by 30% and net additional income for farmers 63% (depending on yield productivity increase and the market price of cashew). The intervention requires relatively low investment as there are existing input suppliers and service providers who have strong incentives to engage as inputs and service providers for good farming practices, particularly in pest control services.  

In the two-year testing phase of the intervention, it is anticipated that six service providers will be established and able to provide services and supplies to 3,760 farmers.  At the end of this two-year phase, these identified farmers are expected to increase yield productivity by at least 30%.

The intervention area focuses on sustainably raising productivity in the cashew sector in Bima and Dompu districts, where there are a number of problems related to productivity.Small-holders typically realize lower yields than in comparable areas of Indonesia.  Local farms are susceptible to pests, such as Hemopalis and Lavanna (White Butterfly), which reduces productivity, and do not demonstrate good practices that could minimize these issues. 

To address the underlying causes in the sector, the program will facilitate the delivery of three different services to the farmers: (1) supplies for effective pest control and good farming practice solutions, tools and technology; (2) pest control services; and, (3) knowledge and skills on good farming practices, including trimming, effective planting distance, and fertilization.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The PRISMA program will provide support to farmers in cashew-producing provinces to increase yields by at least 30% and provide services and supplies to 3,760 farmers. 

This will be accomplished through:

1) Delivering supplies for pest control, in conjunction with education surrounding successful farming practices, tools, and new technologies

2) Providing pest control services where needed

3) Enhancing the knowledge and skills of farmers on good farming practices, such as trimming, planting distances and fertilization techniques.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palladium (formerly GRM International)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-ID-14-14147" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="5793.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-28" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1633792">
   <location-id code="1633792" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Nusa Tenggara</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Nusa Tenggara, Indonesia (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1633792" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-8.74 117.5333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-03-01">372425</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palladium (formerly GRM International)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2014-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-02-28"></period-end>
     <target value="3760"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
