<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="296" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/14092" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-MC-IQ-12-14092</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Broadening Participation through Civil Society Project (BPCS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps and consortium partners propose the Building Participation through Civil Society (BPCS) program, with the goal that Iraq&#x2019;s democratic systems become more participatory and dynamic as a result of civil society sustainably deepening citizens&#x2019; social and political engagement; and the program objective to foster an increasingly professional, interactive and interconnected Iraqi civil society that offers greater opportunities for citizens to contribute to and benefit from the country&#x2019;s development.

 
 Three foundational approaches underpin the program: 1. Semi-annual civic attitudes and behaviors surveys will capture citizen, government and civil society attitudes toward each other. 2. A CSO coach development project will create a cohort of coaches/mentors with the capacity to continue facilitating the development of Iraqi organizations and a professional network to support each other as trailblazers in the Iraqi civil society development arena. 3. An integrated subgrant fund will support initiatives under multiple IRs, linking capacity development to concrete outcomes and providing flexibility to support
 efforts in response to the known and emerging priorities of organizations and their constituents.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National citizens</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the BPCS program, Mercy Corps aims to achieve five main results:
 1. Democratic engagement of citizens will be increased.
 2. Institutional capacity of CSOs/NGOs will be increased.
 3. Impact of civil society on public policy will be increased.
 4. Enabling environment for CSOs will be improved, and
 5. Special projects will be implemented, such as assistance for civilian war victims.

 
To achieve these results, BPCS will engage and mobilize diverse and marginalized groups to broaden democratic participation at community, sub-national and national levels. The program will target organizations with the greatest potential to contribute to Iraq&apos;s development through effective constituent-focused service delivery and policy impact, engaging organizations at all levels of capacity and scale. 

 
 BPCS will also facilitate opportunities for civil society to directly influence decision-making that affects the whole society and will strengthen mechanisms for collective voice and constructive collaboration. Strengthening these mechanisms with the general public, government actors and the private sector will ensure civil society leadership in Iraq&apos;s consolidation of democracy.

 
 Finally, BPCS will build on over nine years of collective experience assisting Iraqi civilians who have suffered losses as a result of U.S. Forces-Iraq activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="MC-IQ-12-14092" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="4471.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-15" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.mercycorps.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Democracy and Governance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-10-01">54988991</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-91-1148123">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2015-10-15"></period-end>
     <target value="17500"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
