<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5204043601-PSE-72040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Koop utan gr&#xE4;nser OPT CAP 2013</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sw Cooperative Centre OPT CAP 2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka livsmedelss&#xE4;kerheten f&#xF6;r utsatta       hush&#xE5;ll i omr&#xE5;de C. F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntat resultat &#xE4;r att &#xF6;ka tillg&#xE5;ngen till     sm&#xE5;skaligt jordbruk och inkomster f&#xF6;r s&#xE4;rskilt utsatta grupper.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The outcome objective is improving food security and self-reliance of 473 women-headed and vulnerable households and of 215 threatened      small-scale farming families who are directly affected by the Israeli Separation Barrier and or Israeli settlements. The expected results   is an increase access to small scale agriculture and income, restore  agriculture production, and increase access to water resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor Country NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We Effect</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine, State of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency food assistance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">921206.1659399373</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">874648.3184886078</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">921206.1659399373</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">874648.3184886078</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">-7372.0237742161</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-01">1842412.331879</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-28">921206.1659399373</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-07-28">874648.3184886078</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-28">-7372.0237742161</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: This project aimed at enhancing the livelihood of the poor, marginalized and female headed families on one hand and the small scale farming families on the other hand to mitigate their migration flow and support their existence in the marginalized localities affected by the Israeli occupation. It is believed that the project&#x2019;s Overall Goal has been achieved through enhancing the food security and resilience capacities of its Rights holders/Beneficiaries.

Reaching the final results was challenging due to the target groups (female headed and poorest families), target locations (politically instable sensitive areas that need special permissions and can be obstructed by the Israeli army), type of conducted activities (agro-production activities that need certain circumstances to be implemented).
The project outcome objective is improving food security and self-reliance of 473 women headed and poor HHs and 215 threatened small scale farming families. However, the actual achievement of this objective exceeded what was planned, where the total number of Rights holders/Beneficiaries is 997 HHs, which represents 145% of the total planned number of 688 Rights holders/Beneficiaries HHs. The project targeted communities affected by the separation wall and seam zone and Jerusalem Governorates. Originally 38 localities were proposed, but the project expanded the targeted areas to include new localities in the seam zone of Qalqilya governorate increasing the number of target localities into 42. Most activities were conducted in sensitive locations, Area C, and East Jerusalem.

550 female headed and poor families benefited from food security and income generating interventions increasing their food intake quantitatively and qualitatively. About 773,300 $ is the worth amount of consumed and sold food from chicken farms&#x2019; eggs, sheep newborns, produced milk (even the though the quantities are consumed by the newborns) and food baskets. (The target was 600,000$, this represents 129% achievement)

541 out of 550 families indicated increase and in their daily food intake (they have more than 2 meals/day) which forms 97% of the total number, while  only 2 families out of the surveyed sample still have 2 meals/ day. Additionally, 671 HHs have increased access to small scale agriculture for self-consumption and income.

447 Rights holders/Beneficiaries were small scale farming families benefited from land and water rehabilitation interventions increasing their persistence position to live in their sensitive areas. All of the 447 farmers have resumed and maintained their farming after rehabilitating their agricultural asset or improving the availability of water resources they need. This result represents 208% achievement of the whole project target. In addition to that, the project decreased the challenges faced by the targeted farmers; none of them face water scarcity (decreased from 54%) and only 10% of them have limited services (decreased from 31%).

Many factors have affected the implementation of the different interventions, this includes the unstable political/security situation in many of the target localities specially Qusra, Jaloud, Qaryout, and Twayyel in Nablus governorate. This situation had set many constraints on the freedom of movement for the project team, ability to delivering the equipment needed to implement the activities and risk on the sustainability of implemented interventions. This was overcome as it was part of the project&#x2019;s mitigation plan.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52040436" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
