<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5211007501-PSE-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kvinna till Kvinna 2014-2016</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">support to Kvinna till Kvinna 14-16 strengthening women&apos;s organizing to improve</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestinian women&apos;s rights are protected by law and women&apos;s needs, interests and rights reflected in public discourse, policies, procedures, (Sharia) Court rulings and budgets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den svenska organisationen Kvinna till Kvinna, KtK, har ans&#xF6;kt om fortsatt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r sin verksamhet i oPt i form av finansering om 27 386 481 SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra sitt program &quot;St&#xE4;rkande av kvinnors organisering f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra palestinska kvinnors status&quot;, under perioden 2014-2016. 

Det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let med insatsen &#xE4;r att civila samh&#xE4;llets organisationer bidrar till en milj&#xF6; d&#xE4;r kvinnor kan vara f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringsakt&#xF6;rer. Programmet avser finansiellt och tekniskt st&#xF6;d till ett 10-tal palestinska kvinnor&#xE4;ttsorganisationer som arbetar i V&#xE4;stbanken (inklusive Area C och &#xD6;stra Jerusalem) och Gaza. Det finansiella st&#xF6;det till organisationerna st&#xF6;der aktiviteter inom (i) kvinnors politiska deltagande och (ii) kvinnor, fred och s&#xE4;kerhet, inklusive v&#xE5;ld mot kvinnor. En annan del av insatsen utg&#xF6;rs av administrativ och tematisk kapacitetsutveckling av organisationerna f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka deras l&#xE5;ngsiktighet och p&#xE5;verkansm&#xF6;jligheter. Insatsen bidrar &#xE4;ven till att underl&#xE4;tta n&#xE4;tverkande och utbyte mellan de palestinska organisationerna.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Swedish organisation Kvinna till Kvinna, KtK, has applied for continued support to its&apos; activities in the oPt in the form of financing of 27 386 481 SEK for the implementation of its&apos; program &quot;Strengthening women&apos;s organisations to improve the status Palestinian women&quot;, during the period 2014 -2016.

The overall aim of the contibution is that civil society organisations contribute to an environment in which women are agents of change in their communities. The program covers financial and technical support to around 10 Palestinian women&apos;s rights organisations working in the West Bank (including Area C and East Jerusalem ) and Gaza. The financial support to the organisations is directed to activities in the areas of ( i) women&apos;s political participation and ( ii) women, peace and security, including violence against women. Another part of the program consists of administrative and thematic capacity development of participating organisations in order to enhance their sustainability and advocacy capacities. Further, the program facilitates networking and exchange between the Palestinian organisations and with other relevant actors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donor Country NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kvinna till Kvinna</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palestine, State of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1331244.770331929</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1080322.5653375725</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1456225.3257757262</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1331244.7703319292</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1065720.2851956864</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1467259.042832934</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">4475103.281388</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-05-28">1331244.7703319292</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">852573.4046717996</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-28">213146.8805238869</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-05-28">1080152.1650207445</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">387106.8778121896</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">KtK&apos;s Development Objective was: Palestinian women&#x2019;s rights are protected by law and women&#x2019;s needs, interests and rights reflected in public discourse, policies, procedures, (Shar&apos;ia) court rulings and budgets.
The programme included the following areas:
&#xA0;1: Collective Agency for Change which refers to women&apos;s agency within the context they operate in; family members, members of the local communities and relevant stakeholders.
&#xA0;2: Individual Agency for Change which refers to the individual agency of marginalized women.
Main results achieved as a result of this programme include the following:
- There was limited progress regarding amending criminal law. Article 99 which the majority of perpetrators benefit from, is still in force. Violence against women is not criminalized by law and most discriminatory articles violating women&#x2019;s rights have been suspended by Presidential decree, not repealed, which means that they can be reinstated in the future. Culture of impunity continues. However, several of Kvinna till Kvinna partners were part of amending the criminal law. Women&apos;s Studies Center and Women&apos;s Affairs Center were appointed on a working group by the Ministry of Justice. New laws have not yet been introduced by Presidential decree as law (PLC not functioning since 2007).
-&#xA0;Women&apos;s Affairs Center (WAC) Collected around 7300 signatures for a petition against early marriage from representatives of women organizations and CBOs, lawyers, activists, judges, mukhtars and religious leaders. All PLC members in Gaza received SMS on stopping early marriage. PLC member Huda Nai&#x2019;m in her capacity as the chair of women affairs in PLC supports raising the age of marriage to above 18 years. Khailda Jarar the PLC member as well as judges showed their willingness to raise the age of marriage. A committee representing women NGOs/CBOs shared the draft petition on early marriage with Huda Naiem, the chair of the status of women in the PLC. A committee represented by the General Union of Palestinian Women, Ministry of women&apos;s Affairs and Women CSOs communicated a draft amended family law to president Mahmoud Abbas for approval. Decision Makers, Judges, Mukhtars, and community committees considered the amendments to the family law in their actions.&#xA0;WAC: Judges working in Shari&apos;a Courts changed attitude and indicated that they will convince families not to marry off their girl children 18 years old. Examples to this: &#x2022; An underage girl came with her parents to Shar&apos;ia court in Jabalia to undertake a marriage contract. The judge stopped the marriage contract procedure as the girl was below legal age according to the birth certificate. The Judge had advised the parents and girls about the health and psychosocial impacts of early marriage. &#x2022; A parent performed the marriage contract of his underage daughter in collaboration with a Mazon (religious official) and violating the law. The court judge stopped the registration of the marriage contract as well as terminating Mazon who was involved in this violation. The Judge asked CSOs to raise the awareness of girls and parents on stopping early marriage for girl child.
- 23462 court rulings in favour of women
- 520 consultations related to personal status and panel laws.
- Women submitting lawsuits to courts; 261 cases with 237 cases of divorce, alimony, custody, dues and discord and conflict.
- 106 women were referred from courts.
- 57 women were referred internally within Palestinian Working Women&apos;s Society for Development (PWWSD) to benefit from its services.
- 20 women were referred from the Women&apos;s Affairs Technical Committee (WATC) to receive protection and legal services.
-&#xA0;New Family (Personal Status) Law has not entered into force yet, despite the mobilisation of Women&apos;s Rights Organisations (WRO) and civil society calling for new family law and penal law, leaving it with no other choice but to continue to appeal to the President to issue a decree to ensure CEDAW compliance.
- PWWSD partnered with the Sharia Court to increase the impact of change in view of governmental institutions. PWWSD received arbitration sessions between the spouses once a week, and the work of the lawyer was received in the court in support of women, in addition to referrals from and to the court. PWWSD: a Sharia Judge was invited to the Center to discuss the Personal Status Law and he talked about women&apos;s rights and how the Tulkarem community centre contributes to raising the awareness of judges and sensitizing them to women&apos;s rights, which is reflected in their referrals to the Center. PCHR: Training at PCHR&#x2019;s Women&#x2019;s Rights Unit, the training aims at qualifying newly-graduated lawyers to defend women&#x2019;s rights in Shari&#x2019;a courts and help women reach justice.&#xA0;
In Summation, when it comes to collective agency for change, KtK&apos;s partner organizations gathered together in joint campaigns and initiatives to address common relevant issues for them like early marriage and protection legislation in Palestine. Little change has been achieved on structural level.
On individual agency for change, many examples of the work that was done show individual actions motivated by increased agency, in addition to clear indications and commitments towards behavioural change with key stakeholders. This however remains on local and grass root level and less so on government level.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="52110075" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1110102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1500000000" strategy-end-date="2019-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>Palestine 2015-2019</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Palestina 2015-2019</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
