<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-136031</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental Sector Programme Support (ESPS) Phase I</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Environment Natural Resources Management and Mainstreaming Programme is an initiative of the Government of Zambia that aims to bring improved coordination and implementation capacity to the Environment Natural Resources Management sector. The programme comprises of two Components namely, 1) Capacity Development and 2) establishment of an Interim Environment Fund. In addition Denmark has taken the initiative to establish a fund which will provide support for activities carried out by Civil Society Organisations. The activity is seen as a 3rd component in the Danish support to the environment sector.

The programme will work through the Ministry of Tourism, Environment and Natural Resources. The intention is firstly, to build the Ministry&#xBF;s capacity both to coordinate national policy making and provide environmental information that is required for evidence based policy development in the ministry. Secondly, sector ministries and local government will be assisted to utilise information and environmental management tools produced by the programme to mainstream environment into their planning and operations. Thirdly the programme will support the establishment of a permanent environmental fund for investments in the environment and natural resources sector to complement the policy shift towards sustainability. The fund will finance projects that benefit the livelihoods of poor people by remedying previous degradation or promoting the sustainable use of resources. And last but not least a fund will also be established with the aim to support local civil society organisations working in the environment sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.Zambia.806-100">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-136031-22160" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-136031-22162" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-136031-22163" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-136031-22165" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
