<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-160780</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Service Delivery and Good Governance Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program supports decentralization reform in Ghana. The intention of supporting the national decentralization process is to involve citizens in the decision-making processes related to public services such as water supply, road maintenance and buildings for schools and hospitals. Involvement of the citizens will ensure greater local ownership and strengthening democracy at the district level. Furthermore, the objective is to improve the quality of public services and to increase accountability and effectiveness of public employees at district level.
The program consists of the following three components:

1. Support for key institutions responsible for the implementation of the decentralization reform. One of the major tasks is to transfer employees from the central authorities out to the districts. In this regard, it must be ensured that there is capacity to implement the development plans that concerns investment in infrastructure and social services, which is developed for each district.

2. Support for investment in development. The support is provided through a District Development Facility based on a principle that the districts which can best document compliance with the formal requirements for district administration receives most funding for their development plans. This is determined by an annual inspection of all 216 districts where the minimum requirements shall be met to receive investment funds. Since 2011 earmarked support to water supply, sanitation and road maintenance in selected rural areas with special needs is phased out in favour of support for the nationwide District Development Facility. This facility is financed by the Government of Ghana with Canada, Germany, France, Switzerland and Denmark.

3. Support for an annual audit of districts&apos; accounting.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.Ghana.53">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-21690" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-21691" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-21692" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-21693" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-21694" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-21885" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-30789" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-30790" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-160780-30791" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
