<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-165109</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme for Access to Justice</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three components have been identified for the Danish support, prioritising interventions enhancing access to justice for the poor: i) strengthening the performance of key institutions of the sector; ii) strengthening voice, accountability and empowerment through the Ombudsman and civil society; and iii) the provision of formal, alternative and community justice services to poor and vulnerable groups, in particular women and indigenous persons, through Integrated Justice Centres (ICJs). The programme may be extended after the first 3 years, based on the experience gained in this first phase.
Considering the present state of the sector and the changes to come, there is not at present a basis for a full-fledged sector programme. Denmark will promote, and if possible support during this phase, enhanced coordination between the state institutions on one hand, and development of a sector perspective among the donors on the other, as a basis for a possible broader future sector approach. 
The areas for support have been selected with a view to making justice accessible to the poor. In the short term this will happen through support to the government&#xBF;s &#xBF;Access to Justice Programme&#xBF;, that aims at setting up IJCs in poor and conflictive semi-urban areas as an accessible alternative for conflict resolution to the formal judicial system. Due to the accessibility of the centres and their integration with the neighbourhood, most cases presented are related to family issues. The Centres also support people in penal cases through the formal system and provide training on legal issues in the neighbourhood. Also the Ombudsman and civil society will provide training and information on Human and legal rights. The support to the IJCs is expected also to provide experience and &#xBF;good practice&#xBF; to the development of an overall justice sector reform with a focus on the poor. Seen to the government&#xBF;s commitment to the IJCs, they are expected to continue in the medium term.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Bolivia.45.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2009002228</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-165109</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-22583" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-27136" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-27137" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-27138" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-27139" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-27140" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-27141" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-165109-30921" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
