<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-122979</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Road Sector Programme Support, phase 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The third phase of the Danish Road Sector Programme Support (RSPS 3) is aligned to Tanzania&apos;s strategy for growth and poverty reduction which focus on road infrastructure both as a prerequisite for economic growth through access to markets and financial centres as well as improved welfare by access to social services. The overall objective is to contribute to poverty reduction through the development of a sound transport infrastructure as a basis for broad social and economic development in Tanzania. RSPS 3 support is improving accessibility of local roads in rural areas, contributing to the stabilization of the overall road network through support for the rehabilitation of main and regional roads; promoting a sustainable road administration at central and local level; promoting maintenance, and contributing to improved road safety.

RSPS 3 has three components reflecting the institutional linkages: 1) National roads through the national highway authorities; 2) Local roads through the Ministry of Regional Administration and Local Government; 3) Institutional development and support for sector reforms through the Ministry of Infrastructure. 
The focus is on promoting sustainable maintenance as a prerequisite for maintaining service levels at both large and small roads and to protect the investment in road infrastructure. Thus, the program&apos;s investments complement and relieve the road fund for some of the most urgent expenses. Progressive alignment with national systems is taking place. Strengthening administrative systems form part of the grant and road safety has a prominent place in RSPS 3.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2005-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-122979-17760" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-122979-17761" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-122979-17762" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-122979-17763" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
