<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-161687</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Assistance to Refugee Hosting Areas, Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following 20 years of insurgency, Northern Uganda is lagging behind the rest of the country in the main socio-economic development indicators. Consequently, the Government of Uganda (GoU) has developed the Peace, Recovery and Development Plan for Northern Uganda (PRDP). The DAR2 programme is aligned with and anchored to the PRDP. The programme covers six districts in the West-Nile sub region, and has the following objectives: 1) Strengthen the capacity of the District Local Government and communities in refugee hosting areas to plan, implement and sustain development activities; and 2) Improve the livelihoods of the population by promoting agricultural production and marketing. A similar programme is implemented in the Acholi sub region in Northern Uganda, focussing on the restoration the agricultural livelihoods, which had been disrupted by the prolonged conflict. 

The DAR2 programme targets small scale, low income farmers in areas which earlier hosted refugees from South Sudan. The support is based on a &apos;voucher-for-work&apos; model, which was successfully applied during the first phase of the programme. After participating in agricultural training for one season, small scale farmers are given the opportunity to work on small, labour intensive infrastructure projects and earn vouchers, which they can then exchange for agricultural inputs. In effect, the programme increases purchasing power of the local population, enabling them to invest in their agricultural production. The programme thus promotes improved farming methods and supports the reconstruction of important agricultural related rural infrastructures. It also supports and builds the capacity of private input dealers in order to improve the availability of improved inputs in the rural areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2009002062</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">46.Uganda.5.B.1-5.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-161687</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-161687-21796" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
