<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-136727</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Global Partnership for Education former Fast Track Initiative</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Partnership for Education-GPE was established in 2002 with the objective of promoting the MDG on universal access to education. GPEs vision is ensuring universal access to quality education in order for them to realize their full potential and contribute to society. GPE supports global efforts for education with a focus on the poorest and most marginalized children. All LDC are eligible and GPE provides financial and technical support to the development of national education plans. The national education plans are endorsed by donors active in the education sector in the country. Indicators established by GPE is increasingly being used as a reference for the evaluation of national education sector plans and GPE cooperates closely with partner countries concerning the development of the national sector plan. Elements such as girl&#xBF;s access to education, quality and capacity development are included in the evaluation process. The GPE-support is monitored in close cooperation between the GPE-Secretariat, the local education group and national authorities responsible for education. GPE provides an important contribution to harmonization and alignment in the education sector. Focus is on support to primary education with the option to support the broad &#xBF;education for all&#xBF; agenda. Institutionally the GPE is located in the World Bank with it&#xBF;s own board and secretariat. The board includes members of both partner countries/recipients and donor countries, CSO representatives, private sector and multilateral partners (EC, UNESCO, UNICEF and the World Bank). Members of the board are organised in constituencies, Denmark participates in the constituency with Sweden, Norway and Ireland. Norway is the current member of the board with Denmark as alternate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-18886" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-21732" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-22555" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-22988" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-23571" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-24773" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-25039" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-25259" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-25614" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-26339" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-27195" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-28511" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-30362" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-30724" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-31258" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-136727-31489" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
