<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR-21/UKR_CBPF/SA3/P-WASH-E-H-N/NGO/19927</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durable solutions for targeted conflict affected communities to ensure access to essential services</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is aimed at empowering the targeted conflict-affected communities to ensure access to essential services by improving community centers, improving or providing internet and phone connection, providing access to water and proper hygiene, education, health service for targeted communities in an inclusive manner. 

NGO &quot;Proliska&quot; plans to improve access to essential services for people living in targeted conflict-affected communities or settlements where healthcare, psychosocial support, education, water and sanitation and social services are hard-to-reach, through the mobilization of communities, strengthening their ability to access these services and through the improvement of communication with authorities and service providers. Community centers in 16 targeted communities will be supported and capacity building for community mobilization agents will be conducted to improve the resilience of conflict-affected people and system of service provision. The community centers will be used as hubs for community mobilization, community-based protection projects, and community-based services provision, including education, health and protection services. Proliska will improve sanitation and the availability of clean water at the community centers. Also, Proliska plans to directly provide essential services (MHPSS, including psychological support to pre-identified SGBV survivors
in these communities, case management) to the most vulnerable PoCs in 16 targeted communities.
Advocacy interventions will be conducted to ensure the eventual handover of responsibility for services provided and community spaces to amalgamated territorial communities. 

Totally, almost 4.5 thousand people will directly benefit from improved access to services, including 330 children, over 2 thousand women, and over 2 thousand elderly people.

NGO &quot;Proliska&quot; has been operating in Luhanska and Donetska oblasts since July 2014. Our organization has got many years of experience in implementing projects in the conflict zone: from 2016 to the present, we are the executive partners of UNHCR in 2016-2018 we were the executive partners of UNICEF, since 2019 we are the partners of the Ministry of Temporary Occupied Territories and Internally Displaced People. and 2019-2020 successfully implemented 2 UHF projects and now are in the process of implementing 2 more UHF projects within the standard and the reserve allocation. Currently, the organization has more than 130 employees who are members of the communities along the &#x2018;contact line&#x2019;. Our employees are qualified specialists, having mainly 5 years of experience of work in the conflict zone. We have experience in community-based protection and assistance close to the contact line in complex approach which entails provision of services to people, community mobilization, and restoration of the ability of communities to develop and to become more self-sufficient.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proliska</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proliska</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yevhen Kaplin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of organization</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+380973225225</telephone>
   <email>yevhenkaplin@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="UA14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donetska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.04731497 37.67411990</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="UA44">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luhanska</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>48.98551927 39.01773003</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="7" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="7" percentage="18" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="25" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-09">497406</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="UKR81-19927">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-09">497406</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proliska</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-UKR81-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
