<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-21-CR-CR-341</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. To develop low-impact, community- managed tourism in the area extending from the Monteverde cloud forest to the Gulf of Nicoya.. To develop low- impact, community- managed tourism in the area extending from the Monteverde cloud forest to the Gulf of Nicoya.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assist special populations which may be vulnerable or at-risk on a temporary or chronic basis whose needs are not addressed under emergency humanitarian assistance or other programs. These include groups such as the disabled; orphans, children and at-risk youth; victims of trafficking; victims of gender-based violence; refugees, returnees, ethnic minorities, internally displaced or other socially excluded groups; the elderly; and female heads of household. Depending on circumstances, services may intend to protect groups; mitigate adverse conditions they face, or to remove barriers to help integrate them into society. Components may include measures to increase the capacity of local service and advocacy NGOs and/or professional social workers; to establish public/private service delivery partnerships as well as family and community focused service models; to establish effective referral networks; to develop appropriate service protocols and methods for screening prospective recipients; or to improve public understanding and sensitivity to the needs of the vulnerable.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation is the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of programs and projects as a basis for judgments, to improve effectiveness and inform decisions about current and future programming. Evaluations are distinct from (a) needs assessments, which are designed to examine country or sector context to inform project design, (b) internal informal reviews of projects and (c) audits (conducted either internally or by an external audience). This program area should include all evaluations designed and funded with foreign assistance funding, including the components of contracts with task orders for evaluations (regardless of the mechanism). It should also include all independent contractors hired solely to produce an evaluation(s).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to assist special populations which may be vulnerable or at-risk on a temporary or chronic basis whose needs are not addressed under emergency humanitarian assistance or other programs. More specifically, this includes Fundaci&#xF3;n Neotropica in Costa Rica (FN) will work with seven community associations in the Corredor Biol&#xF3;gico P&#xE1;jaro Campana(CBPC) to develop a plan for low-impact, community- managed tourism in the area extending from the Monteverde cloud forest to the Gulf of Nicoya. Approximately 50 community residents will participate.. Fundaci&#xF3;n Neotropica in Costa Rica, $49,450 over one year and six months; counterpart committed, $32,650 FN will work with seven community associations in the Corredor Biol&#xF3;gico P&#xE1;jaro Campana(CBPC) to develop a plan for low-impact, community- managed tourism in the area extending from the Monteverde cloud forest to the Gulf of Nicoya. Approximately 50 community residents will participate. 1. Fundaci&#xF3;n Neotropica in Costa Rica, $49,450 over one year and six months; counterpart committed, $32,650 FN will work with seven community associations in the Corredor Biol&#xF3;gico P&#xE1;jaro Campana(CBPC) to develop a plan for low- impact, community-managed tourism in the area extending from the Monteverde cloud forest to the Gulf of Nicoya. Approximately 50 community residents will participate..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fundaci&#xF3;n Neotr&#xF3;pica</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Inter-American Foundation</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-21" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-American Foundation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lesley Duncan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+1 202-360-4530</telephone>
   <email>lduncan@iaf.gov</email>
   <website>http://www.iaf.gov</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1331 Pennsylvania Ave. NW, Suite 1200 North&#xC2;&#xA0;Washington, DC 20004</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CR">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Costa Rica</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Costa Rica&apos;s relatively limited land and sea border-patrolling capabilities make it vulnerable to the rising violence threatening other Central American countries. U.S. foreign assistance seeks to equip and train Costa Rican security authorities to secure national borders and create safe communities. U.S. assistance focuses on blocking transnational criminal organizations from penetrating Costa Rican society, reducing the tide of drugs transiting the country en route to the United States, and protecting the hundreds of thousands of U.S. citizens who annually visit or reside there. The U.S. Strategy for Engagement in Central America (Strategy) focuses on three overarching lines of action: 1) promoting prosperity and regional economic integration; 2) enhancing security through continued and expanded Central America Regional Security Initiative (CARSI) activities; and 3) promoting improved governance. The FY 2017 request of $750.0 million in bilateral and regional assistance for Central America - a part of the Administration&apos;s $1.0 billion whole-of-government request for appropriations and financing assistance to support the Strategy - includes and aligns the resources necessary to comprehensively increase economic opportunity, reduce extreme violence, strengthen the effectiveness of state institutions, address climate change and food insecurity, and challenges resulting in increased migration.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-10-22">16295</value>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Administrative costs (non-sector allocable)</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="8002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring and Evaluation</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2013" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-22">22255</value>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="4004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Services</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2014" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-13">10900</value>
   <sector code="16010" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Protection</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="4004" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Services</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:fiscal-funding-year begin="2015" end="2015"></usg:fiscal-funding-year>
    <usg:main-account code="3100">Inter-American Foundation</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="11"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
