<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5111009701-KEN-15151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDEA - Electoral Support</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">IDEA - Electoral Support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: IEBC and ORPP increase their capacities to review and enforce the electoral legal framework, including provisions for sound political finance, democratic standards and gender equality in candidate nomination.Outcome 2: IEBC enhances the electoral risk management capacity for Kenya&apos;s 2017 elections and beyond</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projekt syftar till att st&#xF6;dja Kenyas demokratiska institutioner att fullg&#xF6;ra sina uppdrag samt att garantera en fredlig och r&#xE4;ttvis spelplan f&#xF6;r politiskt opinionsbildande. Projektet fokuserar p&#xE5; tre akt&#xF6;rer, n&#xE4;mligen registratorkontoret f&#xF6;r politiska partier (Office of the Registrar of Political Parties, ORPP), den oberoende valkommissionen (Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission, IEBC) samt de olika politiska partierna. Det planerade st&#xF6;det kommer fr&#xE4;mst att fokusera p&#xE5; tre grundl&#xE4;ggande tematiska omr&#xE5;den: valregelverket, i synnerhet f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r en sund politisk ekonomi; demokratiska standarder och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lld kandidatnominering samt ett &#xF6;vergripande ramverk f&#xF6;r riskhantering i samband med val. De tematiska omr&#xE5;den som identifierats f&#xF6;r detta st&#xF6;df&#xF6;rslag &#xE4;r i linje med de prioriteringar f&#xF6;r val och politiska processer som beskrivs i Kenya Vision 2030. M&#xE5;let i Vision 2030 &#xE4;r att anta och genomf&#xF6;ra n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndiga policyer samt juridiska och institutionella ramverk i syfte att befr&#xE4;mja de politiska processerna bl.a. genom att inf&#xF6;ra nya lagar och best&#xE4;mmelser g&#xE4;llande politiska partier; att st&#xE4;rka det juridiska regelverket kring valprocessen; och att st&#xE4;rka de lagar som befr&#xE4;mjar att kvinnor och andra marginaliserade grupper inkluderas i valprocessen. Den st&#xF6;dmodell som f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s f&#xF6;r resultatuppn&#xE5;else och aktiviteter g&#xE5;r ut p&#xE5; att sprida kunskap, skapa dialogm&#xF6;jligheter, st&#xE4;rka organisatoriska strukturer och den operativa kapaciteten, utforma modeller f&#xF6;r samarbete mellan institutioner, samt att utforma ett juridiskt ramverk enligt vilket ORPP, IEBC och de olika politiska partierna ska verka.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to support key Kenyan democratic institutions in fulfilling their mandates to guarantee a peaceful and levelled playing field in political contestation. The project focuses on three actors, namely the Office of the Registrar of Political Parties (ORPP), the Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission&#x2019;s (IEBC) and the com-peting political parties. The intended support will focus primarily on three essential thematic areas: the electoral legal framework, particularly provisions for sound political finance, both democratic standards and gender equality in candidate nomination; and the overall electoral risk-management framework. The thematic areas identified for support under this proposal are consistent with the Electoral and Political Processes priorities outlined in the Kenya Vision 2030&#x2019;s political pillar. The 2030 Vision aims at enacting and operationalizing the necessary policy, legal and institutional framework to support the development of issue-based political processes through, inter alia:  the introduction of new laws and regulations covering politi-cal parties; the enhancement of the legal and regulatory framework covering the electoral process; and the strengthening of laws to promote the inclusion of women and other marginalized groups in the electoral process . The modalities of support proposed in the project&#x2019;s outputs and activities consist of providing comparative knowledge, creation of dialogue opportunities, strengthening organisational structures, operational capacities, modes of inter-institutional cooperation, and the legislative framework under which the ORPP, the IEBC and competing political parties operate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="47058" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International IDEA/International Institute for Democracy and Electoral Assistance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="47058" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International IDEA/International Institute for Democracy and Electoral Assistance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elections</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">355901.4390281518</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766435</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.351000351</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-53137.1398324588</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">355901.4390281518</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766434</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">351000.3510003509</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-53137.1398324588</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-01">1012921.239011</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">355901.4390281518</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">350610.6468766435</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">351000.351000351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">-53137.1340789837</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project &apos;Supporting Electoral and Political Processes in Kenya Phase II&apos;, was carried out during 33 months (originally 30 months), had as its objective to support key democratic institutions&#xB4; role in enabling a peaceful and levelled playing field in electoral contestation. Two outcome areas had been identified:&#xA0;
The Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (IEBC) and the Office of the Registrar of Political Parties (ORPP) increase their capacities to review and enforce the electoral legal framework, including providions for sound political finance, democratic standards and gender equality in candidate nomination,; and The IEBC enhances its electoral risk-management capacity for Kenya&#xB4;s 2017 elections and beyond.
It is important to note that it is not possible to state with certainty what the level of impact this project had in reaching some of the goals, given that many other actors were also actively working with both key institutions of the project. One of the larger partners were the UNDP Basket fund, still active in the post-election evaluation of the IEBC performance during the 2017 general elections and fresh presidential election. The type of contribution is also difficult to assess in the short term, and the full impacts may be more reasonably assessed in the medium long term.&#xA0;
Under outcome 1, one of the most important activities were to address the gender gap in terms of political party candidates - contributing to adherence of the constitutional 2/3 gender rule of parliament. Although some progress were noted, in the form of recommendations from IDEA, there still remain quite a lot of work (and especially change of mindsets) before this is a reality. Another equally important target was the implementation of the Campaign Finance Act, through improved coordination mechanisms between IEBC and ORPP. Despite progress on clarity and coordination the implementation of the act was tabled by parliament ahead of the intensified election campaigning beginning of 2017. Lack of political will among parliamentarians is deemed to be the determining factor.&#xA0;
The project&#xB4;s outcome 2 focused on enhanced risk-management capacity by the IEBC in preparation for the 2017 elections. International IDEA has developed its own tool, the Electoral Risk Management (ERM) tool, which was used already during Kenya&#xB4;s elections 2013. This time IDEA strengthened the use of the tool, something that the completion report (confirmed in the evaluation) was successful and was used to inform parts of the IEBC&#xB4;s and Police&#xB4;s electoral security plan. Data from the ERM tool also informed decisions taken by the IEBC including cancellation of elections in conflict areas after the boycott of fresh elections ordered by the Supreme Court. The ERM component was the project&#xB4;s most successful part, although more staff and earlier project start could have increased effectiveness - not least in the number of ERM champions trained (only one champion per county was trained).&#xA0;
Two unintended impacts are highlighted in the evaluation report:&#xA0;
- The IEBC risk officers and department of Audit and risk compliance became an integral part of the intelligence system, credited the accuracy of the risk maps developed by using the ERM tool.&#xA0;
- The ERM tool drew attention as they engaged other stakeholders and some universities invited IEBC staffs to give public lectures on the same. Some of the universities asked if the tool could be integrated into their peace and security studies curriculums.&#xA0;
In terms of sustainability it is likely that the use of the ERM tool will continue to be used and developed, based on the buy in from the IEBC. However, the evaluation advises that the momentum should be sustained by continued encouragement and information to various stakeholders.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51110097" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
