<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11798A0101-KEN-43060</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFP Capacity Strengthening for DRR and resilience</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">WFP kapacitetsutveckling f&#xF6;r katastrofriskreducering och motst&#xE5;ndskraft</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet &#xE4;r att se till att nationella och l&#xE4;nsinstitutioner i Kenya har st&#xE4;rkt kapacitet och system f&#xF6;r att hj&#xE4;lpa livsmedelsotrygga kvinnor och att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att s&#xE5;rbara kvinnor och m&#xE4;n kan dra nytta av h&#xE5;llbara, inkluderande livsmedelssystem och d&#xE4;rigenom f&#xE5;r &#xF6;kad motst&#xE5;ndskraft mot klimatchocker f&#xF6;r att m&#xF6;ta livsmedelsbehov.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim is to ensure that national and county institutions in Kenya have strengthened capacity and systems for assisting food-insecure and nutritionally vulnerable populations and that targeted food-insecure and vulnerable populations benefit from sustainable, inclusive food systems and increased resilience to climate shocks to meet food and nutrition needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme&#xA0;is expected to strengthen capacity of National and county institutions in Kenya to assist food-insecure&#xA0;and nutritionally vulnerable populations.&#xA0;The expected programme outputs are as follows:
1. National and county government institutions develop a well-functioning institutional arrangement that is effective in inter-sectorial coordination and has enhanced sustainable financing and leadership for resilient livelihoods programming and emergency preparedness and response, anchored in relevant policy and legislation.
2. National and county government institutions develop technical capacities, know-how and experience for evidence based design and planning of resilient livelihoods and Emergency Preparedness and Response programmes.
3. National and county government institutions develop systems that improve delivery efficiency, foster greater accountability and responsiveness in implementation of resilient livelihoods and emergency preparedness and response programmes.
4. Communities vulnerable to and affected by climatic shocks have strengthened productive capacities to withstand and recover their livelihoods.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41140" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFP/World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41140" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Food Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43060" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2267627.1517996867</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1305064.5515054779</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2267627.151799688</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1305064.551505483</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">5e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">3650676.608671</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">2267627.1517996867</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">1305064.5515054779</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/agreement-11798-wfp-capacity-strengthening-for-drr-and-resilience.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement 11798 WFP Capacity Strengthening for DRR and Resilience</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/MSWORD" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/wfp-capacity-strengthening-for-drr-and-resilience-agreement.docx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFP Capacity Strengthening for DRR and resilience</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kenya/wfp-capacity-strengthening-for-drr-and-resilience-decision--11798-.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFP Capacity Strengthening for DRR and resilience-Decision</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From a total of 62 planned activities in 2019, 35 activities were fully completed within the planned timeline, furthermore 16 activities were partially achieved and 11 activities were rescheduled to 2020 (see Workplan and budget). Key reasons for delays include sequencing of activities at county level, alignment of planning cycle with county counterparts, onboarding of technical support staff, prolonged process of policy write-shops and training workshops. Strategic Objective 2: Climate-Resilient Livelihoods Activity 3:  Create assets and transfer knowledge, skills and climate risk management tools to food-insecure households Output 3.1: Communities in food insecure areas (including young people and communities hosting refugees), benefit from enhanced organisation enabling them to determine, create and utilize productive assets and improved access to innovative risk management tools for increased, diversified and sustainable food production systems. In 2019, WFP and county governments jointly completed targeting and electronic registration of 390,000 beneficiaries across nine arid counties (Turkana, Marsabit, Mandera, Wajir, Garissa, Isiolo, Samburu, Baringo and Tana River), with 348,000 residing in the priority counties (which excludes Mandera county) of this project. The beneficiaries were registered in WFP&#x2019;s corporate beneficiary management system, SCOPE, which is linked to the national social protection database, the Single Registry, containing the details of recipients for all national social protection programmes. This enables county governments to coordinate and have accurate data on the social protection beneficiaries and minimize the risk of one family unintentionally receiving support from multiple programmes. Targeted beneficiaries (348,000) received capacity strengthening support including training and non-food items (NFIs). Training along different value chains (beekeeping, poultry production, horticulture, pasture production) and other capacity-building activities including extension services and procurement of NFIs continued across all counties in the arid and semi-arid lands (ASAL) and is forecasted to continue in the next years. Output 3.2: Establish and implement a rigorous and independent monitoring, evaluation and learning framework for WFP&#x2019;s work on sustainable food systems. During 2019, WFP invested in the establishment of a baseline for the food systems programme. This was undertaken by a contracted third party to increase the independence, quality and timeliness of outcome data. The same company will undertake annual outcome data collection and reporting as well as a mid-term and end-line evaluation. Analysis of the 2019 baseline data endorsed the relevance of the food systems targeting, intervention design and focus, and recognised the important preparatory work conducted at the county level in terms of planning, mobilization and awareness building. Based on recommendations and findings presented in the baseline, WFP developed a technical response to ensure timely and structured follow up. Findings from the outcome monitoring planned for July 2020 will further determine the achievements towards building sustainable, inclusive food systems and resilience to climate shocks. Strategic Objective 3: Capacity Strengthening for Disaster Risk Reduction In 2019, WFP invested greatly in strengthening evidence-based design and implementation of programmes, review and development of policies, strategies and legislative frameworks, strategic coordination and programme linkages and roll-out and enhancement of systems. Output 5.1: Technical Assistance to strengthening capacity of Government (national and county) for coordination and policy WFP engaged the government through the State Department for Devolution on advocacy for a multisectoral policy that provides a framework for coordination and accountability for relief assistance in humanitarian emergencies. The policy and framework development are underway and a concept note articulating required evidence has been developed. A multisectoral technical working group for steering the policy, comprised of relevant government ministries, departments and agencies, has been constituted and a costed roadmap and a list of stakeholders to be solicited for discussions has been established. The technical working group started their meetings and prioritised critical activities that are to be undertaken to deliver the national relief management policy. However, owing to the government reprioritizing and requesting WFP to support the establishment of a digital platform for provision of relief assistance, the pending steps (desk and literature review, stakeholder mapping, consultation, public participation, policy validation and policy launch) for the policy work were delayed/deferred as key government officers were re-deployed. Laying a foundation for the upcoming national relief assistance policy, the Government of Kenya through the Ministry of Devolution and the ASALs constituted and gazetted a multi-agency taskforce to advise the transition from food and non-food items relief assistance to cash transfers using a digital platform. On the Government&#x2019;s request for support, WFP nominated two officers to be part of the taskforce. The intention of the Kenya Government was to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of relief assistance during emergencies by leveraging on technology and with the help of the taskforce to implement a policy change to facilitate the transition. WFP supported the taskforce in a comprehensive review of existing policies, legal frameworks and systems for provision of relief assistance including cash transfers. In addition, WFP provided technical and financial support towards stakeholder engagement, write shops, and public participation. The finalized report is awaiting approval by the Cabinet for adoption and policy shift that would allow for the law-making process to commence. The report also serves as a useful resource for the planned national relief assistance policy development. WFP has engaged in advocacy and dialogue with other stakeholders, such as National Disaster Operation Centre (NDOC), government ministries, departments and agencies and other UN and non-governmental agencies through the National DRR platform. Through these efforts and bearing in mind the lessons learnt and the existing international, regional and national frameworks, Kenya formulated the National Disaster Risk Reduction Action Plan (NAP) 2019-2022. The purpose of NAP 2019-2022 is to serve as a guideline for all stakeholders involved in DRR in Kenya to undertake their DRR activities in a systematic, coordinated and harmonized manner, with all actors at national and county level expected to align their activities to the prioritized interventions in NAP 2019-2022. The NAP was submitted to the Ministry of Interior and Coordination of the national government for approval in March 2019. The Action Plan will support the strengthening of DRR coordination mechanisms by enhancing collaboration and accountability by institutions engaged in DRR activities in Kenya. At the county level, WFP supported the Isiolo and Wajir county governments through Disaster Risk Management (DRM) departments to establish Disaster Risk Management Committees at county and sub-county levels. These committees have a role to review the Disaster Risk Management Policy and legislation and to develop instruments and institutional frameworks. Through WFP&#x2019;s support Wajir county government trained Disaster Risk Management committees. The committees were formed at county, sub county and ward levels through meetings with the community to select representatives to the DRM committee. The committee members underwent a two-day basic training on DRM and their roles and responsibilities. The committees are now set up to enhance the capacity of the county government to effectively prepare for and respond to the impacts of disasters and emergencies as well as ensure actions are in place to prevent or minimize threats to life, health and the environment from natural disasters and other emergencies. In addition, the County Executive Committee Members were also sensitized through a one-day workshop about the importance of the formation of the County Disaster Management Fund for the county. The Disaster Management Fund (DMF) is a mechanism that enables the county to channel grants and loans from the national government or national and international organisations towards meeting county expenses for emergency preparedness, response, mitigation, relief and reconstruction. DMF as expressed in the Wajir County Disaster Management Bill (2014), will enhance the capacity of the county government as first line responders to finance emergency preparedness, response, mitigation, relief and reconstruction in the event of a disaster in the county. Additionally, 23 staff in the DRM department were trained on various aspects of DRM and EPR. As a result, the department is now responsible for coordinating humanitarian affairs and have strengthened its coordination function. The four counties that have benefited from SIDA support since 2015 (Baringo, Marsabit, Samburu, Wajir) have been able to mainstream Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR) in their County Integrated Development Plans (CIDP), which has significantly strengthened their departmental workplans by allocating budgets for DRR during the reporting year. Moreover, Wajir county has a Climate Change Adaptation Act that was spearheaded with support from Sweden. The linkages with the DRR and resilience building activities are elevated under the overall coordination by the County Steering Group. Wajir county government staff, who benefited from the capacity strengthening, gained skills and know-how in evidence generation and policy formulation which enabled them to develop a livestock disease control framework and in turn mobilised ten Frontier Development Counties (FDCs) to come up with a regional framework. Through WFP and other development partners&#x2019; technical and financial support, the Garissa and Tana River county governments initiated the development of a policy and bill for DRM. The team of renowned facilitators (from KIPPRA, KLRC, NDOC) inducted select technical officers on policy formulation process and supported them through a policy drafting process. The DRM policy and bill for Tana River County were finalized and it is anticipated that the policy formulation for Garissa County will be completed in 2020. The policy and bill will provide the counties with effective and efficient framework for disaster management focusing on preparedness and response to disasters as part of county planning mechanisms and facilitate effective and timely response. In addition, through WFP&#x2019;s support, Isiolo county government developed and validated their Gender and Enterprise development policy. This policy establishes the institutional mechanism by which all agencies involved in gender issues and the society consciously recognize gender differences to ensure that the needs, requirements and rights of both sexes in society &#x2013; men and women, are taken care of, so that there is no discrimination. Through WFP&#x2019;s support the County government of Tana River, officers undertook a learning mission to Baringo to familiarise with the work done in the county on disaster risk reduction and emergency preparedness and response. The mission comprised of technical officers from the departments of Education, Health, Water, Agriculture and Irrigation, Special Programs, Trade and Industry and Administration. The team was hosted by a multisectoral team of senior county officers including the Deputy Governor and County executive committee members, chief officers and directors as well as Community leaders and farmer representatives. WFP committed to support four counties (Turkana, Garissa, Isiolo and Tana River) to align their DRM policy implementation plan with CIDP M&amp;amp;E Framework for monitoring results. The need for M&amp;amp;E system support was also expressed by other four counties (Marsabit, Baringo, Wajir, Samburu) as reflected in the joint AWP with WFP. Owing to the overwhelming requests, WFP discussed the M&amp;amp;E support with UN partners and the Government&#x2019;s Monitoring and Evaluation Directorate (MED3 in National Treasury) and reached an agreement on an integrated approach to enhancing the county-level M&amp;amp;E capacity, including the support to County Integrated Monitoring &amp;amp; Evaluation System (CIMES). During the reporting period, one MED team diagnostic/M&amp;amp;E backstopping mission was carried out to assess the status of CIMES implementation in Marsabit County. The team met with various departments (Finance and Economic Planning, Governor&#x2019;s Delivery unit, Agriculture, Livestock and Fisheries, Education, Lands, Environment, ICT, Transport, and Trade) to introduce and apply the CIMES Diagnostic tool. A capacity development strategy that will guide M&amp;amp;E capacity development was developed and included development of an indicator handbook for the CIDP and an M&amp;amp;E policy that is aligned to the national M&amp;amp;E policy as well as a short course on M&amp;amp;E</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="11798" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000.0" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Kenya 2016-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Kenya 2016-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
