<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5111009801-KEN-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Capacity Building for Devolution through UNDP</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building for Devolution through UNDP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Programmet syftar till att st&#xF6;dja genomf&#xF6;randet av en decentraliserad stat och d&#xE4;rigenom &#xE5;stadkomma en b&#xE4;ttre samh&#xE4;llsstyrning och en f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad socioekonomisk utveckling i Kenya. Det baseras p&#xE5; FN:s initiativ &apos;Delivering as One&apos; och FN:s strategi f&#xF6;r decentralisering, samt &#xE4;ven p&#xE5; Kenyas medell&#xE5;nga plan II och det &#xF6;vergripande ramverk f&#xF6;r kapacitetsutbyggande i samband med decentralisering som ministeriet f&#xF6;r decentralisering och planering utformat. Programmet kommer att bidra till att det n&#xE5;s resultat enligt FN:s ramverk f&#xF6;r utvecklingssamarbete (UNDAF), resultat 1.3, samt enligt landsprogramdokumentet, resultat 2, g&#xE4;llande decentralisering och ansvarighet. I programmet ing&#xE5;r fem resultatomr&#xE5;den, vilka ska genomf&#xF6;ras enligt &#xE5;rsarbetsplaner som utg&#xE5;r fr&#xE5;n vilken sorts kapacitetsuppbyggande som beh&#xF6;vs allteftersom genomf&#xF6;randet fortskrider. Arbetet bygger ofta vidare p&#xE5; tidigare aktiviteter. Den modell f&#xF6;r &#xE5;rlig arbetsplanering och budgetering som anv&#xE4;nds vid genomf&#xF6;randet av det vidare resultatramverket medger flexibilitet. Detta f&#xF6;r att det ska g&#xE5; att svara mot olika behov av kapacitetsuppbyggande och f&#xF6;r att man stegvis ska kunna bygga vidare p&#xE5; det som redan &#xE5;stadkommits. Varje &#xE5;r kommer prioriteringar som g&#xE4;ller insatsens &#xF6;vergripande syfte gemensamt att identifieras och beslutas av implementerande parter och UNDP f&#xF6;r att sedan sammanfattas i ett resultatramverk med tydliga delresultat. &#xC5;rsarbetsplanen ska ligga</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2010 constitution established a two level governance, comprising a national government and 47 County governments. The constitution also established other institutions critical to the success of devolution. The new structure of governance came into place after the 2013 general elections. Most of the institutions created are new and starting off from scratch and their capacity needs to be strengthened in order for them to play their rightful role of ensuring devolution becomes a reality. The government of Kenya has since put in place the policy, legal and institutional framework for the implementation of devolution. Through MTP 2, the government has prioritized the full implementation of the constitution to ensure rapid set up of Counties without disruption of service delivery. At the same time, the GOK has prioritized capacity development and alignment at both County and National levels. 
This intervention will be contributing to efforts by the governemnt of Kenya to enhance the capacity of County Governments and other related institutions to play their part in ensuring devolution succeeeds. It will be implemnted through UNDP with funding from several partners including USAID, DFID, Norway, Demark and Sweden. The EU and Finaland are also considering joining. Its objective will be to support the implementation of devolved government to achieve improved governance and socio economic development. Its approach will be capacity building which is often used as an overall concept for the conditions that must be in place, for example knowledge, competent, effective, and oriented organisational and institutional frameworks, neccesary to make development possible. The intervention will be implemented over a period of five years..</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The projet objective is to support the implementation of devolved government to achieve improved governance and socio- economic development in Kenya.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1749296.6369772155</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766435</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">865800.8658008657</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">563840.5596980576</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1749296.6369772155</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">350610.6468766434</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">865800.8658008658</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">563840.5596980576</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-01">5437397.046604</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">1749296.6369772155</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">350610.6468766435</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">865800.8658008657</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">563840.5596980576</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida supported this program with SEK 37.3 million for activities which took place December 2014 &#x2013; March 2019.&#xA0;&#xA0;
Kenya envisioned counties in the 2010 constitution, and they were established in 2013.&#xA0; In 2014, UNDP developed a four-year Kenya Integrated Support Programme to the Devolution Process in Kenya (2014 &#x2013; 2018); it was expanded in November 2015. The programme was designed to support devolution with an aim of achieving improved governance and socio-economic development in the country. The integrated programme involved UN Women, other national implementing partners and 27 county governments.
The ex post evaluation of the previous devolution program (End Term Evaluation for the Integrated Support Project to the Devolution Process in Kenya (Infotrak and UNDP, 2018)) concluded that the program was quite successful, giving the program: 5 out of 5 for project relevance; 4 out of 5 for project sustainability and national ownership, project effectiveness, project social and environmental standards, project efficiency, and project management and monitoring; and 3.5 out of 5 for project impact. These scores reflect well on UNDP&#x2019;s capacity to implement the program.
The programme has contributed to Kenya&#x2019;s national priorities by aligning its interventions along the UNDAF and UNDP-Kenya CPD 2014-2018, Kenya Vision 2030, and Medium Term Plan II.
The project&#x2019;s theory of change framework was flexible, allowing UNDP and other implementing partners to adjust their programmes to respond to the continuously identified needs from the counties. The project proactively took advantage of new opportunities.
The project design enhanced interaction between the counties and the national government institutions.
The programme has contributed &#x201C;immensely&#x201D; to improving the quality of governance, socio-economic development, gender equality and women empowerment, climate change adaptation and mitigation, and disaster risk reduction in the country and in the counties.
County staff interviewed reported that their respective county governments were now able to do budgets in a better way after benefiting from the project capacity building programmes. Through monitoring and evaluation, they were able to track the progress of different projects and activities.
The introduction and establishment of Performance Management Systems (PMS) in the counties re-engineered innovation and a new culture of service delivery.
Peer to peer learning among county governments has enabled them to pick up best practices that can be replicated across board.
Review of the County Integrated Development Plans (CIDPS) gave the supported counties a better focus and understanding of their mandates.
As at the time of the evaluation, the project had managed to mobilise USD 21.6 million, of which Sweden contributed SEK 37.3 million.&#xA0; The mobilized amount translates to 62 per cent of the entire envisaged project resources. Further, the project had utilised USD 17.8 million of the mobilised resources, which translates to 82.4 per cent absorption rate.
The end of term evaluation noted that most of the supported county governments have adopted performance management systems for improved public service delivery. The beneficiary counties have also come up with M &amp; E policies and systems which, if operationalized, will assist in collecting and monitoring of periodic data on all county project activities and outputs.
Capacity building of both national implementing partners and county governments has created ownership and will ensure sustainability over time. Mainstreaming of project activities and cross-cutting issues of gender, climate change, disaster risk reduction and HIV into county plans, budgets, CIDPs, policies and laws will also ensure sustainability of the project results over time.
The most effective anchor for engendering county activities was inclusion of gender indicators in performance contracting as well as county monitoring and evaluation frameworks. Gender mainstreaming was included in county plans and activities. The second generation CIDPs have demonstrably integrated more gender concerns than before. It was also noted that the supported county budgets are aligned to the CIDPs, meaning they are more engendered.
The county governments have included climate change mitigation and adaptation measures into their activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51110098" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
