<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5111003801-KEN-15112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank Devolution TF</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">World Bank Devolution TF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen &#xE4;r mycket relevant och kommer vid r&#xE4;tt tid &#x2013; den &#xE4;r ocks&#xE5; i linje med Kenyas, Sveriges och V&#xE4;rldsbankens prioriteringar. Kenyas regering har uppvisat n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndigt &#xE4;garskap och ledarskap, riskerna som analyserats &#xE4;r generellt klassificerade som l&#xE5;ga till mellanh&#xF6;ga och olika risk&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder finns p&#xE5; plats. Det &#xE4;r d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r h&#xF6;gst sannolikt att projektm&#xE5;len kommer att uppn&#xE5;s och att insatsen blir ett betydande bidrag till genomf&#xF6;randet av decentraliseringsreformen i enlighet med 2010 &#xE5;rs konstitution. Det f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r att Sverige st&#xF6;djer programmet med 17 miljoner kr under perioden januari 2015 &#x2013; december 2017.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2010 constitution established a two level governance system, comprising a national government and 47 county governments. The constitution also established other institutions critical to the success of devolution. The new structure of governance came into place after the 2013 general elections. Most of the institutions created are new and starting off from scratch and their capacity needs to be strengthened in order for them to play their rightful role of ensuring devolution becomes a reality. The government of Kenya has since put in place the policy, legal and institutional framework for the implementation of devolution. Through MTP 2, the government has prioritized the full implementation of the constitution to ensure rapid set up of Counties without disruption of service delivery. At the same time, the GOK has prioritized capacity development and alignment at both county and national levels. 
This intervention will be contributing to efforts by the governemnt of Kenya to enhance the capacity of county governments and other related institutions to play their part in ensuring devolution succeeeds. It will be implemnted through the World Bank&apos;s Multi Donor Devolution Partnership Facility with funding from several partners including USAID, EU, UKaid, Finland and Sweden.  The overall objective of the facility is strengthened core devolved governance systems at both national and county level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KADP&#x2019;s specific objectives are to improve knowledge and capacity of national and county level stakeholders to implement a successful devolution process, and to help build the accountability relationship between the new county governments and Kenyan citizens for improved efficiency and development results.
Components:
*Fiscal Knowledge Program: Understanding and addressing the fiscal implications of revenue sharing and intergovernmental finances
*Public Financial Management and Human Resource Management: Strengthening public financial management and public sector capacity at county level
*Monitoring and Evaluation, Performance Management Systems and Open Data: Strengthening sub-national performance monitoring, county level data quality and access to information
*Social Accountability and Citizen Engagement: Strengthening public participation, oversight and social accountability mechanisms in county systems and service delivery sectors
*Developed Sector Support: Enhanced service delivery in devolved sectors
*Knowledge and Learning, Communications and Outreach, Monitoring and Evaluation, and Program Management: Supporting peer learning and sharing of knowledge among counties
Cross Cutting Themes:
*Citizen engagement
*Climate change
*Gender
*Conflict and violence prevention and marginalized county support
KADP Outcomes
*KADP impact statement: Improved capacity of core county governance systems
*KADP outcome statements: Improved county performance and leveraging World Bank portfolio
*KADP inter-outcome statement: Core devolved governance systems are strengthened at both national and county levels</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation and support to subnational government</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">979772.6976142741</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">522353.0649214048</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">474935.6499356499</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">979772.697614274</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">522353.0649214049</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">474935.6499356499</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-04-01">1991575.457036</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">979772.6976142741</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">522353.0064862969</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">474935.6499356499</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Component 1: fiscal impacts of devolution
KADP met or exceeded all the set targets. The key component deliverables were:
*The first ever County Gross Domestic Product report which is now a useful resource to understand county economies
*An Enterprise Survey in conducted in ten counties to provide information on investment climate
*The development of BOOST &#x2013; an online budget portal - to increase budget transparency through provision of granular budget execution data interlinked with both IFMIS and the Controller of Budget (CoB) systems
*County Public Expenditure Reviews (PER) in ten counties
*The Own Source Revenue (OSR) study which deepened understanding of the status of revenues in the counties
*County Credit Worthiness Reports for four counties
Component 2: public financial management and human resource management 
KADP made good progress towards the targets set for Component 2, nearly all met or exceeded.
*Public Expenditure and Financial Assessment undertaken in six counties to form the basis for strengthening their PFM systems
*In partnership with the National Treasury, supported the development of the Public Finance Management Reforms Strategy (PFMRS). The PFMRS is the umbrella strategy for the coordination and implementation of PFM and HR reforms in Kenya at both levels of government (2018-2023)
*Led in the development of the World Bank USD200m GESDEK Program for Results operation supporting key PFM and HR reforms in Kenya
*In partnership with the Salaries and Remuneration Commission, developed the Wage Bill Management Study Report. The report provided analysis and information on the extent of the public sector wage bill report and ways to strengthen its management
*Technical Papers for the Kenya National Wage Bill management Conference which provided an opportunity for experts and stakeholders to share their experiences on wage bill management.
*In partnership with the National Treasury, provided technical assistance to the development of user requirements and road map for E-GP.
*County Assets and Liabilities Management Study developed. The study presents detailed institutional, functional, and financial analysis of the state of asset-liability management in Kenya and makes recommendations to stakeholders for implementation.
*In collaboration with component 4, supported the Office of the Auditor General in the development of the Citizen Engagement Framework on Social Audit
*In collaboration with component 1, provided technical contributions to the County Public Expenditure Report 2018
Component 3: monitoring and evaluation, performance management systems and open data 
Component 3 met or exceeded all the set targets.
*County Integrated M&amp;E System Guidelines produced and rolled out to all 47 counties through the Kenya Devolution Support Program
*The component supported the establishment of effective Service Delivery Units in 12 counties that are contributing to problem-solving and improved service delivery
*Support to the development of the Open County Portal &#x2013; an online platform for key county data - which has been integrated in the Maarifa Centre portal and is available to both county citizens and county government staff
*Support to the County Data Visualization page which is embedded in website of the Kenya National Bureau of Statistics
*Piloting of two rapid evaluations in Kilifi and Kericho counties to strengthen the evaluation function in Kenya
Component 4: Social Accountability and Citizen Engagement
Component 4 KADP made good implementation progress and met or exceeded nearly all the set targets.
*Technical assistance to the Ministry of Devolution and Planning for the development of Public Participation Guidelines and subsequent roll out to all 47 counties through the Kenya Devolution Support Program
*Development of a model for Participatory Budgeting and roll out to 10 counties that are undertaking extensive consultations with citizens in their planning and budgeting processes
*Analytical report on county Grievance Redress Mechanisms
*Support to the Council of Governors in the development of the Devolution Hub &#x2013; an online library/repository for devolution related documents
*Braille version of the Public Participation Guidelines
Component 5: devolved sector support and cross cutting themes 
Component 5 met most of its development targets while others were exceeded.
*Technical assistance and analytical support to define intergovernmental relations in the water sector contributed to the Water Act of Kenya (2016)
*Development of a model for water provision in Kiambu county intended to inform similar models across counties
*Technical assistance to develop Kenya Environmental Sanitation and Hygiene Policy; Kenya Environmental Sanitation and Hygiene Strategic Framework; Prototype County Environmental Health and Sanitation Bill and the National ODF Campaign Framework as well as support to Kisii, Migori and Makueni Counties on county-level legislation and strategies
*Institutional Analysis for Urban Development and Fiscal Framework for Secondary Urban Areas
*Support to the Commission on Revenue Allocation for the Integrated Devolution Policy and Investment Data Portal and the development of the third-generation revenue sharing formula
*Web-based application for Results-Based Financing in the health sector
*Support to Bomet and Kitui Counties on identifying and addressing gaps in Gender-Based Violence prevention and response
*Social Risk Management policy dialogue and support to the establishment of University of Nairobi Center of Land Acquisition and Resettlement
*Capacity development support to the establishment of the Frontier Counties Development Council (FCDC), including the development of its Socio-Economic Blueprint
*Support to counties to build capacity to address conflict and violence, including Isiolo county, and development of the Conflict and violence mitigation reports
*Piloting of approaches to strengthen county capacity to address climate risk management and resilience that are now being scaled up through the Financing Locally-Led Climate Action Program
Component 6: knowledge exchange and program management 
KADP met or exceeded all the set targets under Component 6.
*Support to the Council of Governors to develop the Maarifa Centre - which is now the leading mechanism for knowledge sharing and county peer learning on devolved service delivery - with an online platform that features a range of documented experiences and key documents.
*Support to peer learning events under the Maarifa Centre that enabled counties to learn from each other in areas such as social risk management, agriculture, water and sanitation and health.
*Development of a first set of partnerships between CoG/Maarifa Centre and selected Kenyan universities to build a sustainable mechanism for systematic county experience documentation by students as part of field assignments and internships.
*Support to KSG to formulate a new Strategic Learning Strategy which updates the school&#x2019;s approach from more lecture-based learning towards practical participatory peer learning methodologies. As part of this work, over 150 faculty and associated faculty have been trained on the new methodology. This has led to a significant change in the classroom experience of public servants taking courses at KSG. (pp. 44-50)</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51110038" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
