<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5111003801-KEN-15112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank Devolution TF</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">World Bank Devolution TF</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KADP&#x2019;s specific objectives are to improve knowledge and capacity of national and county level stakeholders to implement a successful devolution process, and to help build the accountability relationship between the new county governments and Kenyan citizens for improved efficiency and development results.
Components:
*Fiscal Knowledge Program: Understanding and addressing the fiscal implications of revenue sharing and intergovernmental finances
*Public Financial Management and Human Resource Management: Strengthening public financial management and public sector capacity at county level
*Monitoring and Evaluation, Performance Management Systems and Open Data: Strengthening sub-national performance monitoring, county level data quality and access to information
*Social Accountability and Citizen Engagement: Strengthening public participation, oversight and social accountability mechanisms in county systems and service delivery sectors
*Developed Sector Support: Enhanced service delivery in devolved sectors
*Knowledge and Learning, Communications and Outreach, Monitoring and Evaluation, and Program Management: Supporting peer learning and sharing of knowledge among counties
Cross Cutting Themes:
*Citizen engagement
*Climate change
*Gender
*Conflict and violence prevention and marginalized county support
KADP Outcomes
*KADP impact statement: Improved capacity of core county governance systems
*KADP outcome statements: Improved county performance and leveraging World Bank portfolio
*KADP inter-outcome statement: Core devolved governance systems are strengthened at both national and county levels</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen &#xE4;r mycket relevant och kommer vid r&#xE4;tt tid &#x2013; den &#xE4;r ocks&#xE5; i linje med Kenyas, Sveriges och V&#xE4;rldsbankens prioriteringar. Kenyas regering har uppvisat n&#xF6;dv&#xE4;ndigt &#xE4;garskap och ledarskap, riskerna som analyserats &#xE4;r generellt klassificerade som l&#xE5;ga till mellanh&#xF6;ga och olika risk&#xE5;tg&#xE4;rder finns p&#xE5; plats. Det &#xE4;r d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r h&#xF6;gst sannolikt att projektm&#xE5;len kommer att uppn&#xE5;s och att insatsen blir ett betydande bidrag till genomf&#xF6;randet av decentraliseringsreformen i enlighet med 2010 &#xE5;rs konstitution. Det f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r att Sverige st&#xF6;djer programmet med 17 miljoner kr under perioden januari 2015 &#x2013; december 2017.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2010 constitution established a two level governance system, comprising a national government and 47 county governments. The constitution also established other institutions critical to the success of devolution. The new structure of governance came into place after the 2013 general elections. Most of the institutions created are new and starting off from scratch and their capacity needs to be strengthened in order for them to play their rightful role of ensuring devolution becomes a reality. The government of Kenya has since put in place the policy, legal and institutional framework for the implementation of devolution. Through MTP 2, the government has prioritized the full implementation of the constitution to ensure rapid set up of Counties without disruption of service delivery. At the same time, the GOK has prioritized capacity development and alignment at both county and national levels. 
This intervention will be contributing to efforts by the governemnt of Kenya to enhance the capacity of county governments and other related institutions to play their part in ensuring devolution succeeeds. It will be implemnted through the World Bank&apos;s Multi Donor Devolution Partnership Facility with funding from several partners including USAID, EU, UKaid, Finland and Sweden.  The overall objective of the facility is strengthened core devolved governance systems at both national and county level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decentralisation and support to subnational government</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">979772.6976142741</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">522353.0649214048</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">474935.6499356499</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">979772.6976142739</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">522353.0649214047</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">474935.6499356499</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1991575.457036</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">979772.6976142741</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">522353.0064862969</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">474935.6499356499</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">These conclusions are primarily based on&#xA0;Kenya Accountable Devolution Program (KADP): Annual Report 2018 (World Bank, 2019). Progress towards KADP impact statement: improved capacity of core county governance systems In the new Annual Capacity and Performance Assessment published in 2018, the average county score was 41.8 of out 100, suggesting a modest level of capacity and performance. According to the report, &#x201C;the number of counties with functional public participation systems and processes improved in 2018,&#x201D; with a corresponding score of 2 out of a possible 3. However, this has not been measured before, so I cannot see the basis for concluding that there has been improvement. Counties did not perform well on the production of County Annual Progress Reports. The average score was 1.5 out of 5. More than half of the counties did not produce the reports at all, and only 6 out of the 47 counties got the top score of 5. Generally there was significant variation in the county scores, a reminder that not all counties have the same needs.&#xA0; the often low scores are a remender that many counties have a long way to go. Progress towards KADP outcome statement: improved county performance The quality of audit reports is an important measure of transparency and accountability. There has been a marked improvement in the quality of the counties&#x2019; annual audit reports, judged by the Kenyan Office of the Auditor General&#x2019;s audit of these reports. In fiscal year 2014/2015, *5 of 47 counties&#x2019; annual reports were qualified &#x2013; there are some material misstatements or misrepresentations but no evidence of systemic non-compliance with audit standards *17 were adverse &#x2013; financial statements are misrepresented, misstated, and do not accurately reflect its financial performance *25 received a disclaimer &#x2013; it could not be determined whether standards were followed due to a lack of sufficient evidence In fiscal year 2017/2018, *For the first time, two counties &#x2013; Nyandarua and Makueni &#x2013; got unqualified &#x2013; &#x201C;clean&#x201D; &#x2013; opinions. *35 of 47 counties&#x2019; annual reports were qualified *Only 5 were adverse *Only 5 received a disclaimer (p. 7) This represents a significant, strategically important important improvement, albeit from a very low level.&#xA0; Results Framework A results framework is the tool used in large programs to measure progress.&#xA0; There is no other practical way to measure progress in such a large program; it&apos;s impossible to get an overview of activities, sub-goals and targets without one. There is an extensive results framework (pp. 34-39) which demonstrates that the program is meeting many of its output goals. &#xA0; Finances Public financial management and human resource management was budgeted about 25% of program resources and developed sector support an additional about 20%. Fiscal Knowledge Program 3 600 000 17% Public Financial Management and Human Resource Management 5 470 000 26% Monitoring and Evaluation, Performance Management Systems and Open Data 2 800 000 13% Social Accountability and Citizen Engagement 3 200 000 15% Developed Sector Support 4 305 000 21% Knowledge and Learning, Communications and Outreach, Monitoring and Evaluation, and Program Management 1 605 000 8% Total 20 980 000 100% Program management was 9.6% of total disbursements, which is not unreasonable compared with other multilateral programs. As of the end of 2018, USD 15.8 million of USD 21.0 million granted to the program or 75% of the available funds had been used. (p. 32) Sweden&#x2019;s last disbursement to the program was SEK 4.1 million in October 2017.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <contribution contributionid="51110038" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1060403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000.0" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <title>Kenya 2016-2020</title>
    <titleSV>Kenya 2016-2020</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
