<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5111009302-KEN-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum Syd - Wajibu Wetu 2015-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Forum Syd - Wajibu Wetu 2015-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Det demokratiska utrymmet i Kenya har kontinuerligt minskat sedan den nuvarande regeringen kom till makten 2013. Det har blivit sv&#xE5;rare att arbeta med demokrati och m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttighetsfr&#xE5;gor, speciellt f&#xF6;r civilsamh&#xE4;lles organisationer, j&#xE4;mf&#xF6;rt med det mer &#xF6;ppna och till&#xE5;tande klimat som r&#xE5;dde mellan 2003 och 2013.

Forum Syd har inkommit med programf&#xF6;rslaget Wajibu Wetu (v&#xE5;rt ansvar) 2015-2019 om 92 500 000 kronor. De utmaningar som programmet avser adressera kan sammanfattas i tre &#xF6;vergripande kategorier: 1) Den demokratiska kulturen: Politiska  stela maktstrukturer, korruption, brist p&#xE5; ansvarstagande, straffrihet, marginalisering av stor del av befolkningen, brist p&#xE5; nationell sammanh&#xE5;llning. 2) M&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter: begr&#xE4;nsat deltagande i beslutsprocesser s&#xE4;rskilt f&#xF6;r kvinnor och ungdomar, &#xF6;vergrepp p&#xE5; politiska och civila r&#xE4;ttigheter (yttrandefrihet, hot och trakasserier, anti-terrorlagstiftning, ouppfyllda sociala och ekonomiska r&#xE4;ttigheter. 3) J&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet: brist p&#xE5; kvinnliga f&#xF6;rtroendevalda / politiker och tj&#xE4;nstem&#xE4;n, oj&#xE4;mlika maktstrukturer, traditionella k&#xF6;nsroller, diskriminering, GBV, sexuella och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter och h&#xE4;lsa, diskriminering och utanf&#xF6;rskap. Programmets &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r &#x201C;Improved democratic culture, accountability and gender equality in Kenya&#x201D;, medan det specifika m&#xE5;let &#xE4;r &#x201C;Strengthened demand for democratic culture, human rights and gender equality through the media and CSOs&#x201D;. F&#xF6;r att n&#xE5; dessa m&#xE5;l kommer Forum Syd arbeta med en rad olika civilsamh&#xE4;lles akt&#xF6;rer, allt fr&#xE5;n etablerade organisationer till lokala initiativ.

Redan i slutet av 2014 inkom Forum Syd med ett konceptpapper, efter att de deltagit i konsultationsprocessen kring framtagandet av Kenyasektionens nya strategi. Koncept pappret diskuterades med ambassaden och n&#xE5;gra m&#xE5;nader senare inkom f&#xF6;rsta ans&#xF6;kan fr&#xE5;n Forum Syd, i vilken en f&#xF6;rberedande fas var inkluderad. En beredning gjordes och diskuterades p&#xE5; ambassadens kvalitetss&#xE4;krings kommittee. Kommitt&#xE9;en rekommenderade att den f&#xF6;rberedande fasen skulle genomf&#xF6;ras f&#xF6;r att kunna f&#xE5; ett mer detaljerat och genomarbetat programdokument, innan kommittee kunde rekommendera det fullst&#xE4;ndiga programmet f&#xF6;r beslut. En ans&#xF6;kan fr&#xE5;n Forum Syd f&#xF6;r att kunna genomf&#xF6;ra den f&#xF6;rberedande fasen inkom i juni och beviljades i samma m&#xE5;nad med 500 000 SEK. Under den f&#xF6;rberedande fasen har Forum Syd f&#xE4;rdigst&#xE4;llt resultat ramverket och arbetsplaner, f&#xE5;tt in ans&#xF6;kningar fr&#xE5;n samarbetsorganisationer, bed&#xF6;mt dessa f&#xF6;rslag och genomf&#xF6;rt kapacitetsbed&#xF6;mningar av dessa organisationer, samt kartlagt kapacitet och kompetensutvecklingsbehov hos samarbetspartnerna. I september inkom Forum Syd med ett nytt mer detaljerat och genomarbetat programf&#xF6;rslag som denna beredning behandlar.

Forum Syd blir avtalspartner till Ambassaden. Forum Syd kommer d&#xE4;refter att ing&#xE5; avtal med initialt 13 civilsamh&#xE4;lles organisationer f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rmedla sub-grants (7) och seed-grants (6).  Ambitionen &#xE4;r att knyta till sig nya organisationer och/eller projekt under avtalsperioden f&#xF6;r att snabbt kunna respondera eller ta tillf&#xE4;llet i akt om m&#xF6;jlighet ges f&#xF6;r bra och relevanta initiativ. Budgeten ger utrymme f&#xF6;r upp till nya 1-2 sub-grants (ca 1 MSEK per organisation)  och 15 eller fler seed-grants (max 100 000 SEK) per &#xE5;r. Sverige kommer att ha en n&#xE4;ra dialog med Forum Syd vad det g&#xE4;ller anslutandet av nya organisationer och/eller initiativ.

Eftersom Sverige befinner sig mellan tv&#xE5; strategiperioder kommer ambassaden endast kunna ing&#xE5; ett avtal som st&#xF6;der verksamhet till slutet av 2017 (det vill s&#xE4;ga 2015-2017 - 45 000 000 kronor). Intentionen &#xE4;r dock att st&#xF6;dja hela programperioden, avh&#xE4;ngigt den mid-term review som kommer att genomf&#xF6;ras av programmet och att medel finns tillg&#xE4;ngliga.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya&#x2019;s Constitution (2010) heralds a new era for Kenya particularly in relation to the advancement of democratic culture, human rights and accountability. It has strengthened opportunities for women such as the commitment to affirmative action, more devolved structures and the repealing of discriminatory laws and practices. The Bill of Rights has enshrined freedoms of expression, opinion and assembly, together with the provisions of a minimum of gender representation in key decision-making organs of the government. These include civil service, parliament, cabinet and County Governments where women have previously been under-represented. However, there exist key challenges to the realisation of a sustained democratic culture ranging from deeply rooted impunity particularly in relation to the conduct of duty bearers, corruption and rampant misuse of public resources. The democratic space in Kenya has continuously been shrinking, since the current government came into power after the elections in 2013. The environment for governance and human rights work, in particularly for civil society, is compared to the years between 2003 and 2013 much more cumbersome.Forum Syd has submitted a program proposal Wajibu Wetu (our responsibility) Programme 2015-2019 for 92 500 000 SEK. The challenges that this programme proposes to address can be summarised in the following three overarching categories: 1) Democratic Culture: rigid heretical power structures, corruption, lack of accountability, impunity, marginalised and excluded populace, lack of national cohesion 2) Human Rights: limited participation in decision making processes especially woman and youth, political and civil rights abuse (freedom of expression/ threats, the proposed anti-terror law Dec 2014), unfulfilled social and economic rights 3) Gender Equality: lack of female elected representatives/officials, unequal power structures and traditional gender roles, discrimination, GBV, sexual and reproductive rights and health, discrimination and exclusion. The programme&#x2019;s overall objective is improved democratic culture, accountability and gender equality in Kenya. The specific objective is strengthened demand and mechanisms for accountability, inclusion and democratic culture through proactive right holders, media, cultural and gender focussed CSOs. These objectives will be achieved through sub granting projects to national media and cultural actors, to support activities around civil society collaboration initiatives including national cohesion, and to provide seed grants for Kenyan grassroots media and cultural actors at their early stages of development.Already late 2014 Forum Syd submitted a concept paper after being part of the consultative process for the development of a new Strategy for Kenya, which was discussed with the Embassy. InA few months later Forum Syd submitted a programme document which included an inception phase. An appraisal was conducted and presented in the Embassy&#x2019;s quality assurance committee. The committee recommended the inception phase to be implemented, in order to get more detailed programme documents, prior to be able to recommend the contribution for decision. In June Forum Syd submitted an inception phase proposal which was approved with 500 000 SEK. During the inception period Forum Syd developed a comprehensive results framework, work plans, received applications from partner organizations and evaluated these proposals. Forum Syd also conducted organisational capacity assessments of the applicants, identified their capacity gaps and skills development needs. In September Forum Syd submitted a new more detailed and thorough program proposal which is the base for this decision and appraisal.The intention is that Sweden will support the whole program period, pending the availability of funds and the mid-term review.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme&apos;s overall development objective is improved democratic culture, accountability and gender equality in Kenya, while the specific objective of the contribution is is strengthened demand for democratic culture, human rights and gender equality through the media and CSOs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ForumCiv (f d Forum Syd)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ForumCiv (f d Forum Syd)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">-87448.9617460854</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-28">-87448.9617460854</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme has during the activity period achieved a wide range of results below is a small selection.&#xA0;The programme objective was to strengthen demand for democratic culture, human rights and gender equality through the media and CSOs in Kenya. Through the programme&apos;s partners, this objective was to be achieved through influencing of public policies and legislation, dialogues between right holders and duty bearers, awareness raising and reporting on cases of abuse of power and human rights and finally the agitation for women&#x2019;s representation in leadership processes. For example, The Nest Collective intensely lobbied against the passing of the Film, Stage Plays and Publications (Draft) Bill 2016. The bill presented one of the most dangerous attacks on freedom of expression with serious implications on film, publishing, advertising, theatre, games, artistic creativity and online expression. Article 33 of the Constitution of Kenya enshrines freedom of expression and ensures that Kenyans have the right to seek, receive and impart information including freedom of artistic creativity. The Nest Collective, along with other film and art sector stakeholders, attended a public meeting called by the board on 12th October 2016 to engage the sector on the draft bill. From the plenary submissions of creative sector associations and practitioners, there was unanimity on the potential harmful effects of the bill: a clear breach of constitutional guarantees to freedoms of expression and association, as well as constraints on freedom of the media and the right to privacy. The draft bill was seen to criminalize filmmaking, increase the costs of doing business and introduce new bureaucratic hurdles and constraints. This strong sector response opened public discussion on the proposals and created an opportunity for stakeholders&#x2019; engagement with the process. As a result, on the 18th of December 2016, the Ministry of Sports, Culture and Arts and the Executive Office of the President convened a meeting of creative sector umbrella organizations and associations, and subsequently oversaw the formation of a sectoral team to engage with the state to resolve the issues raised around the proposed bill. The committee submitted its report and the finalized film draft policy (2017) to the Ministry of Sports, Culture and Art on the 9th of June 2017, and its recommendations are currently under consideration. Another significant result from the programme is the development of the first county countering violent extremism strategy (CVE) in the country by Kwale County in 2017 through the efforts by Msambweni Human Rights Watch and the Council of Imams and Preachers of Kenya. The impact and cost of insecurity resulting from violent extremism is enormous and is a risk to Kenya&#x2019;s development agenda. The radicalisation and violent extremist phenomena are disproportionately impacting youth and women from marginalised areas. This strategy aims at building the resilience of at-risk communities against extremist narratives that can lead to violent extremism within the county.
A rights-based approach means giving people greater opportunities to participate in shaping the decisions that impact on their human rights. It also means increasing the ability of those with responsibility for fulfilling rights to recognise and respect human rights. The relationship between rights-holder and duty-bearer is a crucial part of the human rights-based approach. The programme sought to do this by stimulating dialogues between the duty bearers and the right holders. Youth form much of the population in Kenya and their involvement in the shaping of the development agenda is key. It is key to note that the programme supported dialogues between them and various state actors with regards to governance processes. This took place in Mombasa, Kisumu, West Pokot and Turkana counties. An example is Turkana County, youth participated in the vetting of the gubernatorial candidates during their gubernatorial debates ahead of the 2017 general election questioning them mostly on their development priorities for youth and women. The youth also questioned the incumbent governor to explain why fishery projects had not worked despite over Kes. 40 million allocated for the project. The partners working in the creative industries like PAWA 254, The Godown and The Nest Collective also engaged in dialogues with different duty bearers. The Godown through its project aimed to improve the quality of urban living and urban spaces, using people-centred, participatory methodologies and approaches. Of note is the physical development of public space. This component of the project successfully included officers from Nairobi City County and other important collaborating partners such as the UN-Habitat and tertiary institutions. Beyond the partnership between the architects, the design process successfully used a multi-sectoral approach through workshops that included various relevant sectoral actors &#x2013; big corporations, city planners, UN-Habitat, students of architecture and urban planning. The results of this process are that beneficiaries are beginning to see how they can have &#x2018;ownership&#x2019; in the project; their buy-in in it is also increasing, making it also easier for The GoDown to invite them to support the fundraising campaign for the newly designed development. Furthermore, the participatory, multi-stakeholder approach has received goodwill from the Nairobi City County duty bearers and generated interest from scholars and urbanists in Africa and beyond. Another example is the inclusion of women in traditional leadership forums in highly patriarchal societies, this was one of the results of the programme in Isiolo County through the work of Isiolo County Gender Watch. Women had been looked at as a gender that cannot lead or participate in any decision making. The work of Isiolo County Gender Watch addressed this marginalisation through their advocacy efforts. A result of this was the nomination of the first female senator from Isiolo County and the addition of women to the Njuri Ncheke council of elders for that particular county.
The use of innovative advocacy mechanisms in addition to the traditional advocacy methods was a hallmark of this programme. The utilisation of social media, satire, animation, short films, poetry and investigative journalism was significant in the achievement of results within the programme. Non-traditional actors such as The Nest Collective, Africa Uncensored, Dandora Hip Hop City, Kwacha Africa, Buni Media, Creatives Garage and Creative Spills utilized these innovative modalities to create awareness, inform and expose human rights and accountability issues. Africa Uncensored&#x2019;s work is notable via their investigative series that highlighted corruption and human rights violations. One series named the Kanjo Kingdom resulted in the sacking of corrupt individuals within the Nairobi City&#x2019;s inspectorate and a vastly improved appreciation for the perils faced by informal street vendors in Kenya including reparations for the victims of the corrupt staff at the county council. Wajir Community Radio enlightened the pastoralists community by exposing issues of extrajudicial killings conducted by the military in Wajir East and forced disappearances carried out by the police were also highlighted. Women were also empowered to take part in political processes as a result by debunking women in leadership myths and promoting a fairer image of women aspirants as illustrated by the work of Wajir Community Radio and Kalya FM who utilised community radio as a platform for awareness creation. The efforts of Akira Chix are also worth mentioning, through their work in training computer programming skills to young girls they have transformed their lives as a result of the training.
In terms of gender equality, the programme managed to support several women to vie for leadership positions in government. 47 women candidates targeted in the programme vied for various seats in the 2017 elections, 2 for senatorial positions, 6 as members of parliament, 3 for women representatives, 34 for the post of MCA. Out of them, 1 was elected as a senator in Isiolo county, 5 elected MCAs, 2 nominated as MCAs. While this may seem insignificant in relation to the number of women voted in, the result, in essence, is the fact that the women actually vied for these positions in a male-dominated field.
The programme has also seen an increased number of women non-political leadership positions at the grassroots leadership spaces and thus demystified the fact that there is more offer in leadership that is provided for in the political leadership spaces only. In Nyeri and Meru Counties, women that contested and captured the seats and those that were nominated at the MCA level have formed a structured women MCA caucus with governance structures and accountability mechanism. This has seen them develop and launch the caucus and a strategic plan in Nyeri and it was clear that Meru County was preparing to do their caucus launch and a strategic plan unveiling reportedly by mid-December 2018.
Further, the programme has triggered an impetus amongst the trained women to advocate for rights issues within their households and communities, which should be encouraged and sustained. As a women leadership advocacy project, basic pathways have been laid that should be enhanced by follow up interventions. Nyeri Sauti Ya Mama a registered organization which was formed in Nyeri after the 2017 elections has stood out as a prime example of the impact of this project &#x2013; it is comprised of women from all sub-counties of Nyeri County and has made a mark as a champion for women&#x2019;s leadership rights but also fights for inclusion of children and persons with disabilities. The Self Help Groups (SHGs) and caucuses associated with the trained women were also experiencing renewal through registration, improved book-keeping as well as membership recruitments. While tangible alliances and networks had not started to naturally form by the end of the project, the external evaluation observed that what existed among the SHGs and trained women was commendable for a project of such short time-frame.
Capacity development was a commendable achievement of the programme. Partners had onsite coaching on financial management, project management, results harvesting and quality assurance. The capacity of all the 29 partners was strengthened through onsite training, coaching and support, which included budgeting, record keeping, cost-effectiveness, reporting, auditing; and project management. This led to an overall improvement in an organisational capacity not only in areas of grant compliance but also in the strengthening of internal organisational systems.
The joint democracy and human rights festivals in 2016 and 2018 gathered practitioners and key stakeholders in Kenya to share experiences, knowledge, lessons and explore best practices in pursuit of gender equality, democratic culture and human rights. Participants ranged from grassroots to national CSOs, faith-based organisations, private sector, cultural art and media actors as well as a good representation of state actors ranging from Cabinet Secretaries to permanent secretaries to political actors. The 2018 festival saw the participation of over 1000 persons in two days of interactive engagement and learnings. Bi-annual CEO forums targeting the various leaders of organisations within the Wajibu Wetu Programme have enhanced the capacities of the current leaders to be more creative and effective moulding the next generation of leaders through co-learning, exchanges and mentorships. The programme also catalysed the collaborations amongst the CSOs in thematic areas such as women mentorship, advocacy to name a few. The Nation Leadership Forum in July 2017, a platform to spotlight issues affecting Kenyans by provoking national discussions, shaping opinions and policy directions critical to the development and economic growth of Kenya. Wajibu Wetu partners CREAW, The NEST, Akili Dada and select partners from the Diakonia basket engaged in a series of national conversations focusing on elections management and preparedness; economies of elections, the role of actors in attaining peaceful and credible elections, and voters&#x2019; civic responsibilities. The Forums broadcasted live on NTV to an audience of about 10 million according to Geopoll as well as seeing over 47 million engagements on social media.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51110093" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060404" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000" strategy-end-date="2025-12-31" strategy-start-date="2021-01-01">
    <sida:title>Kenya 2021-2025</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kenya 2021-2025</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
