<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5111007301-KEN-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women Strategy 2014-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UN Women Strategy 2014-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Constitutionally mandated policy and institutional framework is fully operationalized; National laws meet international standards particularly with regard to the protection of human rights; the judiciary &amp; justice system are responsive, effective, accessible &amp; independent; &amp; law enforcement system is reformed, people-oriented &amp; anchored on integrity</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Denna bed&#xF6;mning g&#xE4;ller m&#xF6;jligheten till ett nytt svenskt st&#xF6;d till UNW:s strategi f&#xF6;r att &#xF6;ka j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldheten mellan k&#xF6;nen och st&#xE4;rka kvinnors st&#xE4;llning i Kenya. Strategin utg&#xE5;r fr&#xE5;n FN:s bist&#xE5;ndsplattform (UNDAF) och Kenyas Vision 2030 samt den medell&#xE5;nga planen (MTP II). 

Den totala kostnaden f&#xF6;r strategiprogrammet &#xE4;r 42 miljoner USD, cirka 318,8 miljoner SEK.  Enligt bed&#xF6;mningen f&#xF6;resl&#xE5;s att Sverige under en tre&#xE5;rsperiod (2015-2017) bidrar med 45 MSEK till insatsen (25%).  Det &#xE4;r b&#xE5;de ett k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d och ett programst&#xF6;d. 

I programmets strategier ing&#xE5;r bidragsgivande, kapacitetsutveckling, policyutformning och teknisk assistans. UNW kommer &#xE4;ven forts&#xE4;ttningsvis att ansvara f&#xF6;r koordination samt att verksamheten bedrivs i enlighet med FN:s system f&#xF6;r st&#xF6;d till nationella prioriteringar g&#xE4;llande j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och kvinnors egenmakt (gender equality and women&apos;s empowerment, GEWE).

Med tanke p&#xE5; hur j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetssituationen ser ut i Kenya kr&#xE4;vs ett flerdimensionellt f&#xF6;rh&#xE5;llningss&#xE4;tt och flera deltagare. UNW str&#xE4;var d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r efter att ha flera olika partner och arbeta enligt arbetss&#xE4;ttet Delivering as one (DaO). UNW kommer att samarbeta med kvinnoorganisationer, intresseorganisationer, NGO:er, trosbaserade organisationer samt andra civila samh&#xE4;llsorganisationer p&#xE5; nationell och regional niv&#xE5;.
Det f&#xF6;reslagna programmet kommer att fokusera p&#xE5; fem resultatomr&#xE5;den 
1) Kvinnligt ledarskap och kvinnors delaktighet i beslutsfattande
2) Att kvinnor f&#xE5;r ekonomiskt inflytande samt att offentliga upphandlingar och olika verksamheter inom jordbrukets v&#xE4;rdekedja &#xE4;r till gagn f&#xF6;r dem
3) Att kvinnor och flickor fram&#xF6;ver kan leva sina liv utan att uts&#xE4;ttas f&#xF6;r v&#xE5;ld
4) Freds-, s&#xE4;kerhets- och humanit&#xE4;ra insatser utformas under kvinnligt ledarskap och med kvinnligt deltagande
5) I nationell och decentraliserad planering tas genomg&#xE5;ende h&#xE4;nsyn till &#xE5;taganden och prioriteringar som r&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet.

UNW har det prim&#xE4;ra ansvaret f&#xF6;r planering, rapportering och uppf&#xF6;ljning samt granskning av organisationerna.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This appraisal concerns the possibility for a new Swedish support or the UNW strategy for enhancing gender equality and women&apos;s empowerment in Kenya. The strategy takes its departure from the UN Development Assistance Framework(UNDAF) and Kenya&apos;s Vision 2030 as well as the Medium term Plan(MTP II).  

The total cost of the strategy (2014-2018) is  programme is USD 42 Million  approximately SEK 318,8 Million.  The assessment argues for a proposed contribution from Sweden will over a three year period (2015-2017) contribute 45MSEK (25%).  Support will be for core and programmatic support.  

The programme strategies will include grant making, capacity development, policy development and technical assistance.  UNW will also continue to paly the role of coordination and coherence of the UN system faily as egards support to national priorities of gender equality and women&apos;s empowerment (GEWE).

 As the nature of gender inequalities in Kenya, calls for a multi-dimensional and multistakeholder response; UNW will seek various partnerships and work within the Delivering as One (DaO) modality. UNW will cooperate with women&#x2019;s organizations, community based organizations, NGO&#x2019;s, faith-based organizations and other civil society groups at the national and county level.

The proposed programme will focus on five key result areas 
1) Women&apos;s leadership and participation in governance
2) Economically empowered women  benefitting from public procurement and agriculture value chains
3) Women and girls progressively living a life free from violence
4) Peace, security and humanitarian action are shaped by women&#x2019;s leadership and participation
5) National and devolved planning fully reflects accountability for gender equality commitments and priorities.

UNW bears the primary responsibility of planning, reporting and monitoring as well as auditing of the organisations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41146" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNWOMEN/United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2186620.7962215194</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1779507.195140759</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1753053.2343832175</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1579501.5795015793</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2186620.7962215194</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1779507.1951407592</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1753053.2343832175</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1579501.5795015793</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">-2e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">-54721.4028378552</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-01">8527821.105263</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">2186620.7962215194</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">1779507.195140759</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">1753053.2343832175</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">1579501.5795015793</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-28">-54721.3503713463</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Women lead and participate in decision making at all levels- Six legislations were reviewed to for gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment legislation forming a basis for the implementation of women&#x2019;s economic, social, and political rights - The number of women participating in debates in parliament increased from 2 to 12 per cent and to 50 per cent in county assemblies between March and September 2015 due to the development and use of a mentorship curriculum for Kenya Women Parliamentary Association members and members of county assemblies to enable the women leaders to execute their legislative, representative, and oversight roles effectively- Women members of county assemblies formed caucuses in each of the 47 counties, and 90 per cent of the county assemblies registered with the Kenya Women Parliamentary Association- A tool for counties to measure inclusivity and capacity development on gender-responsive budgeting was developed through collaboration with the National Gender Equality Commission- Women&#x2019;s representation in the National Assembly stood at 23.3% a marginal increase from 19.6 per cent in 2013. Ninety-eight women were elected as members of county assemblies in 2017 compared to 82 in 2013, which is an increase of 12.98 per cent. A mentorship programme was provided to women aspirants. Out of the 195 women candidates supported by UN Women, 57 (29 per cent) women secured tickets for various political seats, out of which 26 (46 per cent) got elected for various positions in the 2017 general elections. or the first time in Kenyan history, three women were elected as senators and three women were elected as governors. The northern and north-eastern parts of Kenya &#x2013; which are known to be traditional and hence patriarchal in nature &#x2013; made history by electing two women senators and six members of parliament.23- The Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (IEBC) developed a draft gender and inclusion policy, which is expected to be finalized in 2019. Strategic plans for KEWOPA and ORPP were developed and will be launched by mid-2019. A gender policy for media houses was developed to guide gender mainstreaming in media reporting. The Council of Governors developed the Gender Action Plan 2019&#x2013;2022. Ten counties developed and launched County-specific Gender Data Sheets. All counties have allocated a budget to gender equality and women&#x2019;s empowerment through the responsible county ministries.
2. Women, especially the poorest and most excluded, are economically empowered and benefit from development
- Three pieces of legislation36 related to women&#x2019;s economic empowerment were drafted and UN Women contributed for them to become gender-sensitive.- The State Department of Gender Affairs was supported to raise awareness among women, youth and persons with disabilities on government procurement opportunities -Access to Government Procurement Opportunities (AGPO) with at least ten women-owned businesses obtained their Access to Government Procurement Opportunities (AGPO) certificate- The Association of Women in Energy and Extractives was established, bringing together women gem dealers, artisans and small-scale miners, and women in large-scale mining to ensure that women in the sector leverage government promises related to the extractive industry and registered their businesses with the AGPO programme.- The number of companies that were included as WEPs signatories grew from 15 in 2014/5 to 20 by end of 2018. Although a modest increase in numbers this is good progress noting that Kenya is second after South Africa in terms of number WEP signatories. Ten companies were implementing WEP commitments. Implementation of the WEPs included interalia providing procurement opportunities to women-owned businesses, creating an academy for youth from disadvantaged families to learn from technology and facilitating better working conditions for their employees by organizing child care, and initiating the Professional Applicators Club, which organizes free weekly trainings for members of the public on practical skills such as painting, tiling, and interior decoration. The Association of Women in Manufacturing (WIM) was launched in 2017 by the Kenya Association of Manufacturers (KAM), which is also a signatory to the WEPs. WIM serves as a platform through which women and young women are encouraged to explore career and business opportunities in industry including manufacturing.- Fourteen counties submitted Access to Government Procurement Opportunities procurement plans and quarterly reports to the government authorities using the prescribed formats for the first time.- The State Department of Gender Affairs finalized the first-ever Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment Strategy, to be launched by mid-2019, which was reviewed to incorporate other sectors, including women in agriculture
3. Women and girls live a life free from violence
This result area had three outcomes. 67% (8/12 of the output indicators) targets were reached/exceeded, 16.5% (2/12) were partly reached and 16.5% (2/12) were not reached.- The National Policy for Prevention of and Response to Gender-based Violence was launched; it provides the framework for battling sexual and gender-based violence in the country.- The Protection against Domestic Violence Act was enacted, moving Kenya out of the world&#x2019;s 20 countries that had no specific law for the prevention of domestic violence. UNW supported CSO&apos;s to lobby for the Marriage Act which was enacted. A simplified version of the gender-based violence (GBV) and family laws was finalized and disseminated - In 2015; 5,454 GBV survivors were able to reach out for information and various services through the national GBV helpline, which links survivors to urgent medico-legal and psychosocial support .In 2016; the government took responsibility for running the helpline and 6,111 GBV survivors were reached with information and services. The increased usage of the hotline was a likely consequence of continuous efforts by the Government of Kenya, development agencies, and UN Women and its partners to raise awareness about gender-based violence. Seven GBV Working Groups were established in nine counties to enhance access to justice for GBV survivors and improve access to services. A national Survivors of Sexual Violence Network was established and facilitated to lobby women parliamentarians for better services and budget allocations for S/GBV survivors.- The Joint Programme on the Prevention of and Response to Gender-based Violence was launched by the Government of Kenya and 14 UN agencies.- Approximately 200,000 police and security officers were trained on how to address violence against women in preparation for the general elections in August 2017- 130 male religious leaders and 250 cultural leaders were trained on male engagement in the six counties with a toolkit on parenting skills and gender equality. As a result, these male champions are implementing individual initiatives such as using traditional male spaces to hold conversations on reproductive and maternal and child health and community advocacy to cascade their learning to peers to expand the pool of male champions.- 2,186 children through the 10 Kings and Queens clubs established in schools in two counties to know how to report sexual harassment through the existing channels. As a result, their self-esteem and confidence reportedly improved.- 4,618 community memberswere empowered to challenge one another on commonly held believes regarding gender roles through 60 community dialogues in two counties. As a result, many now embrace family members respecting each other, sharing chores, listening and involving everyone in decision making.- 1,820 men and boys reached through goat eating sessions where sexual harassment (SH) and GBV issues are discussed. As a result, community elders have issued decrees in the community against SH and GBV.
4. Peace and security and humanitarian action are shaped by women&#x2019;s leadership and participationThis result area had six outcomes. 71% (10/14 of the output indicators) targets were reached/exceeded, 7% (1/14) were partly reached and 21% (3/14) were not reached.-A comprehensive audit of the national Early Warning and Early Response Systems (EWER)66 used by County Peace Committees was finalized and gender gaps were identified. The national EWER tools and indicators, which guide the responses were made gender-sensitive.- Gender integrated to peace support operations and development of the International Peace Support Training Centre Gender Policy.-UN Women accepted as a partner to the Eastern Africa Police Chiefs Cooperation Organization and supporting the development and launch of a training manual, used by 13 countries in the organization.-110 staff of Kenya Red Cross trained on gender mainstreaming and the prevention of gender-based violence, sexual abuse and exploitation to relevant programmes.-The Kenya National Action Plan for the implementation of United Nations Security Council Resolution 1325 was launched; a secretariat was established with the responsibility to oversee the implementation of the plan and reporting structures and monitoring tools developed from the county level to the national level. Government commitment to theUNSCR1325 agenda saw a 30%increase in the budget, from KES 62 million for the 2017/2018 financial year to 80.5 million for 2018/2019.- The Uwiano Platform for Peace was supported to integrate gender dimensions into its work on early warning and early response, mediation, electoral gender-based violence security training, and establishing a clear coordination mechanism for election monitoring.-The Kenya Defence Forces developed and finalized their first-ever gender policy in 2017, launched by the President of Kenya. The Ministry of Defence launched its first-ever gender policy.The National Strategy for Countering Violent Extremism by the National Counter Terrorism Centre was launched in 2016, and a gender analysis undertaken in 2017.- Government commitment to the Resolution 1325 agenda was seen in the almost 30 per cent increase in the plan&#x2019;s budget, from KES 62 million for the 2017/2018 financial year to 80.5 million for 2018/2019.- The number of women in in County Peace Committees increased; out of a total of 4,505 committee members, 1,300 (29%) are women and 3,205 (71%) are men, doubling the number of women since 2013.- Over 400 state and non-state actors&#x2019; capacities were strengthened to mainstream gender into disaster risk reduction/management and humanitarian action. As a result, the humanitarian hubs are now part of county disaster platforms, which are expected to provide technical support in mainstreaming gender.- Over 5,000 women and front-line actors capacity was increased to prevent violent extremism in their communities, identify warning signs of radicalization and recruitment, and intervene early.
Partnerships Evaluation- In 2015, UN Women Independent Evaluation Office undertook a corporate evaluation of UN Women&#x2019;s Strategic Partnerships for Gender Equality and Women Empowerment (GEWE). The evaluation found that UNW strategic partnerships have extended the reach, credibility, and influence of UN Women; were aligned to the Convention on the Elimination of all Forms of Discrimination Against Women (CEDAW) and the Beijing Platform for Action principles.
However, the evaluation noted that UN Women&#x2019;s organizational structures, operations systems and approach to risk were not originally designed with the explicit aim of supporting strategic partnerships. thus gave a recommendation to have a comprehensive policy framework towards strategic partnerships and to fully reflect UN Women&#x2019;s feminist values.
The evaluation lead to UNW shift to a programmatic approach with implementation of the Flagship Programme Initiatives (FPIs), which focused on engagement of partners to contribute to results at output level not implementation of stand-alone activities with no clear results identified in the results framework of UN Women SN. The evaluation also lead to a shift in partnerships to work with inter-governmental institutions towards the fulfilment of UNW&apos;s normative and coordination mandate which lead to strengthened partnerships with Government institutions at central and devolved level. 
UNW also engaged various CSO partners for media engagement on women in leadership and sexual and gender based violence (SGBV), engagement with Africa UNiTE, to raise public awareness, stimulate behavior change, coordination for prevention activities and increase political will and resources to respond to national issues related to the prevention of violence against women and girls. UNW also worked with the private sector to support women in agricultural technology, digital literacy, ending GBV in tea plantations and a number Private Sector Companies were also engaged through the Women Empowerment Principles (WEPs), a partnership initiative of UN Women and UN Global Compact Office. Partnerships with other UN agencies including SEPK Elections Programme with UNDP, Joint Programme on SGBV with 13 UN agencies and GOK, the RMNCAH under the leadership of UNFPA, the JP on HIV/AIDS and the Devolution Programme with UNDP and UNICEF. 
Internal capacity to implement RBM at the KCO was limited and remained a challenging throughout the SN period having one dedicated staff also charged with other tasks thus efforts to fully realise a cultural of RBM being very limited.Results Management System and related quality assurance steps were introduced focusing on results and monitoring processes. As observed in the attached results matrix, UNW in the 2014-2018 SN overpromised and under delivered. An Audit was not a requirement in the agreement and the certified financial report is expected in one years time (June 2020) as per hte UNW agreements.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51110073" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
