<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13031A0101-KEN-99810</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to UN Reforms in Kenya</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to UN Reforms in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Detta f&#xF6;rslag har fokus p&#xE5; kritiska funktioner, aktiviteter och kostnader f&#xF6;r FN:s representanter i Kenya (Resident Coordinators) och syftar till att kontorets (Resident Coordinator Office, RCO) ompositioneringsarbete inte tappar fart eller att det uppst&#xE5;r kapacitetsbrist n&#xE4;r nya modeller f&#xF6;r global finansiering av RC/RCO-funktionen med f&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkta befogenheter stegvis inr&#xE4;ttas i fler &#xE4;n 150 l&#xE4;nder runtom i v&#xE4;rlden. F&#xF6;rslaget omfattar b&#xE5;de den RC/RCO-funktion som &#xE4;r utan finansiering fr&#xE5;n januari 2019 och funktioner som kan riskera att f&#xF6;rsvagas under transitionsfasen. F&#xF6;reslaget bidrar till att bibeh&#xE5;lla takten p&#xE5; genomf&#xF6;randet av de investeringar SE gjort i FN de senaste &#xE5;ren.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal targets critical functions, activities and costs of the UN Resident Coordinators, safeguarding that momentum in RCO&#x2019;s repositioning work in Kenya is not lost or severe capacity gaps created, during a period when new modalities for global financing of the empowered RC/RCO function are gradually put in place in more than 150 countries around the world.  The proposal covers both aspects of the RC/RCO function in Kenya that are without funding from January 2019 and functions that could be undermined duringthe trasition phase.  This will help  maintain the momentum of the investments SE has made with the UN in the last few years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal targets critical functions, activities and costs of the UN Resident Coordinators, safeguarding that momentum in RCOs repositioning work in Kenya is not lost or severe capacity gaps created, during a period when new modalities for global financing of the empowered RC/RCO function are gradually put in place</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sectors not specified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unallocated / Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.1 - Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.1 - St&#xE4;rka motst&#xE5;ndskraften mot och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatrelaterade faror och naturkatastrofer i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">1057540.794636</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kenya/13031_Agreement1stamendment13031SupporttoUNReformsinKenya.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement 1st amendment 13031 support to UN Reforms in Kenya</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kenya/13031_Agreement2ndamendment13031SupporttoUNReformsinKenya.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement 2nd amendment 13031 support to UN Reforms in Kenya</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kenya/13031_Agreement13031SupporttoUNReformsinKenya.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement Support to UN Reforms in Kenya</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kenya/13031_Decision13031SupporttoUNReformsinKenya.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision Support to UN Reforms in Kenya</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the first report under this contribution which covers April 2019 - June 2020.  
The support to RCO is on a cost sharing basis and contributes to overall catalytic activities to reinforce RC and RCO leadership and drive innovation, forge and scaling new partnerships. Moreover, this is done by Delivering as One with the backing of UN agencies with comparative advantage.The support to the reforms was through SE, Swiss, the Hilton Foundation, SDGPP MPTF,UN Special Trust Fund (SPTF) and other UN agencies. 
The support was in two main outcome areas: 1. Resident Coordinators office core capacity to drive innovation and advance UN leadership of the SDG Partnership Platform, the Cross-Border Programme, Devolution/FCDC/ASAL and Gender integration - Leaving no one behind strengthened. 2. The funding of senior advisory capacities limited to RC/RCO relevant aspects of advisory capacity, necessary for the empowered RC/RCOs to convene, broker and lead transformative and impartial change enhanced
The following are some of the results achieved:-
Outcome 1: Resident Coordinators Office Core Capacity Strengthened as per the approved Transition Plan in line with UN Reforms 1. The resources from Sweden secured funding for head of RCO for 2019 who played a critical role in institutionalization of UN reforms in Kenya as well as transitioning the Resident Coordinators office. The functions included servicing of the UNCT  to efficiently led/manage the reforms in Kenya; alignment with national, regional and international development processes, mechanisms and goals; monitor progress, challenges and opportunities, and steer overall implementation of the programme. 
2. The UN continued to support the Government and other stakeholders in building national capacity to implement human rights and other universal UN norms and standards, and progress in advocacy of human rights and other UN system values, standards, and principles. 
3. UN agencies produced a documentary, communicating transformative results realized through the UNDAF. The documentary captures human interest stories and voices of beneficiaries on transformative change as a result of programmes implemented by the UN agencies together with the Government of Kenya. 
4. UN agencies produced the 2019 Annual Results Report aggregating UNDAF Results produced through delivering as One. The Documentary and the Annual Results Report have been disseminated widely through the RCO website. Other knowledge products developed and uploaded on its website by RCO in coordination and collation with the UN Agencies include Op-eds widely published by the RC. 
5. In 2019 RC / RCO convened various multi-stakeholder events / missions to catalyze partnerships, financing and innovations for the UN mandate and programming in Kenya. Direct funding from Sweden went to the FCDC mission and to the mission to Silicon Valley and through the catalytic work by the HRCO other additional funding sources were also secured and the RC/RCO championed several other key missions and events 
6.Under the leadership of the Government of Kenya, the UN System in Kenya helped to spearhead the SDG Partnership Platform in collaboration with development partners, the private sector, philanthropy, academia and civil society, including faith-based stakeholders.  The Platform was formally launched by the Government of Kenya at the UN General Assembly in 2017 , received global recognition from UNDCO and the Dag Hammarskjold Foundation as a best practice to accelerate SDG financing, and has become a flagship initiative under Kenyas UN Development Cooperation Framework 2018-2022 (UNDAF) . The Platform Secretariat is housed at the UN Resident Coordinators Office to incubate this transformative initiative while gradually mainstreaming it is approaches UN wide, as well as for coordination and forging of partnership purposes. Primary Healthcare (PHC)  in the SDG 3 cluster  has been the first SDG Partnership Platform window activated, contributing to the attainment of Universal Health Coverage as a key pillar of the Big Four agenda. 
7. SDG Partnership Platform (SDGPP) brokered new partnership and unlocked new resources in support of its overall programming from Switzerland, Rockefeller Foundation and Takeda in 2019. Netherlands, Merck for Mothers, Philips, Hilton C Foundation, and Huawei increased their support to the SDGPP. As a result, the RC/RCO was able to cover in 2019 salaries and benefits for 2 years (2019  2020) for the SDG Partnership Platform Coordinator, as well as for the Lead for the SDGPP Health Window. 
8. GenU is a global multi-sector partnership to meet the urgent need for expanded education, training, and employment opportunities for young people, aged 10 to 24, on an unprecedented scale . The RC has provided strategic support to the Government and UN Country Team for positioning Kenya as a GenU frontrunner. At the Global level, H.E Uhuru Kenyatta is a GenU leader and Hon Mucheru, Cabinet Secretary for ICT, Innovation and Youth, is representing the Country at the Global GenU Board. At the national level, the RC co-chairs the Generation Unlimited National Steering Committee along with the Deputy Chief of Staff in the Executive Office of the President (OP). In 2019 a multi-sectoral Steering Committee was established that includes the Government, multi-laterals, private sector, and others. A Kenya GenU Secretariat has been set up at Kenya Office of the President. From UN side, UNICEF has been designated to lead implementation of GenU activities. Given the alignment between GenU and SDGPP approaches in harnessing private sector drive, financing, and capabilities, the SDGPP will continue to be anchored to this initiative as well in order to create optimum synergies. 
9. RC/RCO Advisory capacity for integrated Cross-Border flagship:- To enhance long lasting conflict prevention and peace building, reinforcing the peace and development nexus, the UN in Kenya has since 2015 through SE support launched two cross border programmes, bringing communities across borders and bordering countries together to resolve conflict, bring peace and development. The programmes include the Ethiopia-Kenya cross border programme, with an office established in Moyale (Ethiopian side) and the recently launched Cross border Kenya-Uganda for Karamoja cluster. In  2019 UNDP HQ contributed with resources and initiated activities on both sides. The Ethiopia Kenya cross border programme has continued to support, coordinate, and convene high level engagements and dialogue on sustainable peace for the cross-border communities. The successful launch of peace dividend to stop conflicts prevalence through alternative livelihood to both youth and women. In 2019, 70 Motorbikes and 500 energy saving stoves were delivered to the communities of Marsabit County through Kenya Ethiopia Cross Border Programme. The UN Secretary General declared and recognized the experiences of Kenya - Ethiopia Cross Border Programme as the most innovative and best practice approach towards sustainable development for borderland communities. The Somalia-Kenya cross border programme was initiated but met with security related challenges at the end of 2019. 
10. RC/RCO Advisory capacity for gender equality integration enhanced:- RCO advisory and capacity for gender integration to ensure that gender is mainstreamed in the UNDAF. RCO led the establishment of structures and advocacy for zero tolerance for sexual exploitation and abuse (SEA) and sexual harassment within the UN in Kenya, and actively supported the visit by the UN office of the Victims&apos; Rights Advocate to map the services available to victims of sexual exploitation and abuse in Kenya.  Through SE funding the Gender advisor strengthened coordination and support of work of the joint UN gender technical working group, to strengthen capacity of UN agencies to jointly monitor, implement and report on gender integration and realization of SDGs goal 5. Through the global UN UNDAF reporting system  UNINFO- the UNDAF strategic results groups are now able to assess adequacy of gender related investments (planned and actual); progress towards gender equality results and determine interventions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13031" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060403" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1750000000" strategy-end-date="2020-12-31" strategy-start-date="2016-01-01">
    <sida:title>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Kenya 2016-2020</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
