<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/APC/INGO/21341</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of holistic child protection in emergency assistance to crisis affected girls and boys in Hirat, Badghis, and Ghor provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK is proposing a holistic emergency child protection response project to address the significant humanitarian child protection needs of drought, conflict, Covid-19, deepening poverty and displacement affected boys, girls, women, and men in three provinces (11 districts) of Afghanistan for a six-month period. This project will be a continuation of a current OCHA-funded Child Protection project activities by reaching more children, increasing the impact of the activities for the targeted children amp communities, and building on the relationships built with the community and key stakeholders and the in-depth local knowledge of the community&#x2019;s needs. It will also include adaptations and innovations using learning from the current project to ensure it is appropriate and relevant to the needs of the affected population. The proposed project will reduce the negative coping strategies and build the residence by enhancing the wellbeing of children and families and by ensuring vulnerable children and families have timely and effective access to individual child protection assistance and improvements in their psychosocial wellbeing to increase their resilience to current and future shocks. Through proposed activities, WCUK will work closely with existing community structures to promote the ownership and sustainability of the intervention. The proposed project will also strengthen Community Based Child protection mechanism through capacity building training, coaching and mentoring, organizing joint awareness-raising campaigns, and strengthening coordination, referral, and linking CBCPCs with multi-sectorial actors such as education, health, food, livelihood, shelter, and water sanitation and this will help create a sustainable approach for longer-term services beyond the project period.
WCUK will ensure the continuation of psycho-social activities through 12 child-friendly spaces across the three targeted provinces. These spaces will ensure children have a safe space to play, learn, and make friends as well as participate in structured and unstructured PSS activities that support their social and emotional learning and promote their resilience and well-being. 
WCUK will continue to manage and capacity build a team of trained caseworkers to provide Case Management to emergency-affected boys and girls including unaccompanied and separated children in the three target provinces to address child protection needs and reduced negative coping mechanisms. Operating help desks in the affected communities in the targeted areas where UASC cases can be identified and reported to the caseworker team for family tracing and reunification will be part of the project intervention. This project will also support the provision of cash assistance/protection assistance for the most at-risk individuals living in vulnerable households to enable them to access services and meet basic essential needs and respond to protection risks and reduce the risks of adopting negative coping mechanisms in the short term. The Cash Assistance is complementary to case management and community-based child protection work through this project to improve the protection of children and families and reduce negative coping mechanism such as child marriage, child labor and unsafe migration. The modality of cash delivery is one time off cash amounting USD 179 per individual as per the March CVA MEB through selected financial service providers (HAWALA). The project will also conduct cash feasibility assessment to determine appropriate and safe delivery of cash.
The project will be implemented in close coordination with community-based child protection committee, child protection in emergency sub-cluster in respective provinces, and other humanitarian actors working in the same locations in order to efficiently fill the gap, link with the other ongoing programs, and strengthen the local capacity to respond to the child protection needs in emergencies in the long term.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abebe Jaleta</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Development Quality Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93(0)728895290</telephone>
   <email>Abebej@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wajid Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93729111504</telephone>
   <email>WajidK@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Eshaq Karimi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93728895252</telephone>
   <email>eshaqk@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hirat</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.34194400 62.20305600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-01">500340.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21341">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-01">500340.34</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
