<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA3/ESNFI/INGO/20121</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NFI and Winterization Packages for Badakhshan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to a 2013 PDMC report, Badakhshan (BDK) remains one of the most hardly hit provinces of Afghanistan in terms of harsh winter conditions due to its geographical topography and the effects of climate change. The Aga Khan Agency for Habitat Afghanistan (AKAH-A) aims to support the most vulnerable communities in Wardoj and Zebak districts of BDK with Non-Food Items (NFIs) and winterization packages. 
To assess the various risks to local communities residing in specific target areas, AKAH-A developed a comprehensive hazard and vulnerability methodology (HVRA), using a set of critical indicators which address proximity and access, exposure to hazards and vulnerability of households. This year AKAH-A developed a specific HVRA report for the target districts (see annexes). To date, more than 776 villages have undergone such assessments. 
Additionally, AKAH-A conducted a market assessment (see annexes) in BDK&#x2019;s border districts in December 2020 with data available on KoBoCollect. All potential suppliers and vendors and the project&#x2019;s available local markets have been identified. 

For this specific project, a general assessment of the market situation was conducted by discussing with district officials and vendors regarding their provision capacity for winterization support as well as voucher distribution capacity for beneficiaries. 655 most vulnerable families (4,585 people) living across 78 villages (24 in Zebak and 54 in Wardoj) have been identified as eligible for this project. The intervention oversees the provision of standard ESNFI winterization items, specifically, 1) cash assistance for fuel, 2) standard emergency winter clothes and blankets, and 3) cash assistance for rent. 

Aid during AKAH-A&#x2019;s 2020 winterization project was fully through paper vouchers printed in Kabul and proved to be very effective and transparent. There will be specific AKAH-A codes or numbers on each voucher which will limit the possibility of fraud or reselling. The design will be given to the printing press along with the number of vouchers required. The heating component will be cash distribution through vouchers. During the very harsh winters and cold weather, locals have been mostly cutting down the forests for firewood as their often-inexistent salaries have rendered them dependent on the forest, which has overtime negatively impacted the environment. Through this heating package, AKAH-A will provide each family with $200 to be used to purchase correctly sourced wood or gas. In the remote areas like Zebak and Wardoj, 90% of the population uses firewood, animal dung and locally available materials instead of gas and fuel. Additionally, rental market assessments will be carried out to link vulnerable families to safer shelters and cash for rental assistance through vouchers will be provided once the rental agreements have been signed. 

The beneficiary selection and distribution will be undertaken in close cooperation with ANDMA, provincial level cluster partners at the regional level and district authorities, including CDCs. The process will be thoroughly monitored and reported to stakeholders. In terms of protection and monitoring, AKAH-A will create a feedback loop for the project through its long-standing partnership with AWAAZ. This will be in addition to AKAH-A&#x2019;s 24/7 call centre used for any communication and coordination between the local stakeholders and the agency. 

Wardoj: 3177 people (1621M/ 1556F) or 454 HH will receive cash assistance for fuel through vouchers, standard emergency winter clothes and blankets. Of these 454 HH, 1057 people (151 HH) will get cash for rent through vouchers.
Zebak: 1408 people (718M/ 690F) or 201 HH will receive cash assistance for fuel through vouchers, standard emergency winter clothes and blankets. Of these 201HH, 469 people (67 HH) will get cash for rent through vouchers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aga Khan Agency for Habitat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aga Khan Agency for Habitat</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planning and Program</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>alinazar.nazari@akdn.org</telephone>
   <email>Ali Nazar Nazari</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resource Mobilization</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior  Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>maia.ramzan@akdn.org</telephone>
   <email>Maia Ramzan</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmad Fahim Shahab</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93795653207</telephone>
   <email>ahmad.fahim@akdn.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badakhshan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.73477250 70.81199530</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-29">123504.29</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-29">195842.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20121">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-29">319346.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aga Khan Agency for Habitat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305265689">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-08">159673.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aga Khan Agency for Habitat</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
