<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/20810</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Live-saving emergency food assistance through cash For IPC 3 or above food insecure vulnerable people in Kunar Province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the last four decades of conflict and large-scale migration have leaded Afghanistan in urgent needs of humanitarian assistances such food, shelter, WASH, education and etc. Nearly half of the country is already in need of humanitarian assistances (UN, 2021). Moreover, the poverty rate could increase by 25 percent as result of the contraction of Afghanistan real GDPs. The prolonged conflict, drought, political upheaval and COVID-19 could cause Afghanistan&#x2019;s poverty rate to soar of 97% by mid-2022 (UNDP, 2021). Approximately 664,200 people have been displaced from January, 2021 to September, 2021 because of the escalated conflict and livelihood factors. Particularly, Kunar Province is facing as well the highest number of IDPs and returnees. Around 166,716 IDPs and 113,790 returnees reported in 2012-2020 (IOM-DTM, 2020). Based on the Integrity Food Security Phase Classification-IPC 3+ (October, 2021), 18.8 million people (47% population) is currently facing high level of acute food insecurity. Thus, it is projected to increase the number to 22.8 (55% population) of affected people in November, 2021 to March, 2022.According to the IPC analysis, Kunar province is facing emergency level of acute food insecurity. The drought conditions driven by La Ni&#xF1;a, the current political crisis and conflict further compound the food security situation of a population which was already on the brink of a hunger crisis. 
To reach to most vulnerable HHs, AABRAR has devised a lifesaving project that will be executed in 2 districts of Kunar Province namely Shigal and Watapur Correspondingly, the targeted districts for food packages is due to the vulnerability of IDPs, returnees, and the most vulnerable host communities. Furthermore, the recent shocks of conflicts, COVID-19, economic crises, recurrent natural disasters and government transition have resulted weakness in the purchase power and economy of the residents of Kunar. The anticipated increase in food insecurity shows that the targeted province will move to (IPC Phase 4) in period of November, 2021 to March, 2022. In this critical situation, AABRAR will save lives of 1,504 HHs (10,528 individuals) thru providing the assistance of cash for food in targeted areas. AABRAR assessment team along with DoRR and ANDMA and other stakeholders will select the HHs in the targeted districts based on the vulnerability through proper selection mechanism of FSAC priorities. In line with FSAC Cluster priorities, cash for food packages to 1,504 HHs (10,528 individuals) in 2 targeted districts of Kunar Province will be provided. To break down it more comprehensively 752 HHs (5,264 individuals) in Shigal, 752 HHs (5,264 individuals) in Watapur, will receive in-cash assistance for foods. In addition, each HHs will receive a standard FSAC Cluster cash for food package of ($ 180 in 2 installments in 2 months ). Likewise, AABRAR team will deliver proper awareness sessions to HHs for using the cash for food assistance by following on PDM. 
The assistance of cash for food will be provided to those HHs who sustain their lives by daily income and are now massively affected by recent conflicts, drought, recurrent natural disasters and COVID-19. Moreover, the target beneficiaries from IDPs, returnees and vulnerable host communities for proposed project will be based on the criteria as: female HHs, PLWs, PwDs, HHs with large family size (having more than 7 persons or large number of female members), elderly aged HHs, and chronically ill HHs. Besides this, the finalized list of beneficiaries will be shared with relevant stakeholders in order to endorse selected HHs and to resolve any dispute. This will help AABRAR to enable support and raise awareness about the selection process and will enlighten members of community that how to complain and report any potential issue. The process of reporting, sharing and monitoring will continue and conclusion of project will come when 1,504 HHs received cash assistance for food.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Abdul Baseer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 (0) 775558885</telephone>
   <email>abdulbaseer@aabrar.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adil Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 (0) 772076141</telephone>
   <email>adilmaftoon@aabrar.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zahid Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 (0) 789327222</telephone>
   <email>zahidsadiq17@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.84658930 71.09731700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">396316.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20810">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">396316.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305471661">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-16">198158.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305675848">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-07-12">198158.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
