<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/21574</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life saving food assistance to acute food insecure and vulnerable families in Panjab District of Bamyan province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The recent political transition, combined with the impact of COVID-19 and the recent droughts, have negatively impacted Afghanistan&#x2019;s socio-economic situation bringing the country to the edge of a humanitarian crisis. In September and October 2021 (the post-harvest season), nearly 19 million people in Afghanistan experienced high levels of acute food insecurity (IPC Phase 3 or above), an almost 30% increase from the same season last year (14.5 million people). Between November 2021 and March 2022 (the winter lean season), a further deterioration in food security is expected, with the number of people in IPC Phase 3 or above increasing to 22.8 million, a nearly 35% increase from the same season last year (16.9m). Out of 22.8 million people, 14 million will likely be in Crisis (IPC Phase 3) and 8.7 million in Emergency (IPC Phase 4). The number of areas in Emergency is expected to significantly increase in the projection analysis period from 21 to 32 analytical domains. It is likely that household food access between the end of winter and the following spring season will further deteriorate due to: the continuing La Ni&#xF1;a climatic episode bringing below-average winter precipitation for the second consecutive year, the impact of high food prices and growing unemployment. In Bamyan, its estimated that around 30% of the province&#x2019;s population will be in emergency (phase 4) and over 35% in crisis situation (phase 3) through the project period of November 2021 &#x2013; March 2022. This makes 65%, or nearly one million people, of the province&#x2019;s population, being in in Crisis and Emergency .JCSSO hire a monitoring officer to monitor the CVA frequently, Daily, weekly and monthly, he/she will provide the report for better implementation .regarding cash feasibility (market assessment &#x2013; safe access availability of goods , beneficiary preference) is considered and detailed at other part of proposal
This project aims to address the immediate food needs and food insecurity challenges among most vulnerable families in the district of Panjab through unconditional cash transfer modality. Informed by best practices and previous experiences of JCSSO in this regard, the proposed unconditional cash transfers will enable households to have improved access to food and improved food consumption this will ensure sustained assistance to food insecure households through provision of predictable and reliable safety nets, lean seasonal support to stabilize vulnerable households. 
JCSSO proposes to reach 1425 household beneficiaries with unconditional and unrestricted cash transfer distributed via hawala-transfer for at least two months, for the period of winter hunger gap, averaging $160 for each household.(80*2=160 as the full cash basket) The payment will reach each household beneficiaries on monthly basis, averaging $80 for each household (based on cluster standard), which will be equivalent to its value in Afghani currency. Targeting and selection of needy beneficiaries to receive assistance through this project will be carried out through community consultations. Beneficiaries will be selected using the FSAC standard vulnerability criteria. Priorities will be given to shock affected vulnerable groups such as women headed households, person with disability, households with poor asset holding and high dependency ratio. The proposed activity will be implemented within a 6 months&#x2019; timeline.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice and Civil Society Support Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice and Civil Society Support Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nasir Mudabir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 765110110</telephone>
   <email>mudabir@jcsso.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="10">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.90732960 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-05">318578.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21574">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-05">318578.76</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice and Civil Society Support Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305568374">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-16">159289.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Justice and Civil Society Support Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
