<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA3/APC/NGO/20240</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing protection violations, strengthening the resilience, and dignity of the vulnerable people in Helmand Province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project responds to the emergency situation created by the prolonged war, drought and COVID-19. In a recent Whole of Afghanistan Survey conducted by HRRAC team in Helmand during the transition period unfolded the miseries, vulnerabilities and humanitarian situation of individuals, host and displaced communities. Active and prolonged conflict forced many households to multiple displacements. Lashkargah, the capital of Helmand, was a refuge to many families that migrated from the districts before the transition but fighting in the city challenged the survival of both the hosts and displaced communities. As per HRRAC findings, about half the population of Lashkargah are in need of emergency support. The situation in districts however, is far worse. The financial capacity to buy groceries for daily use is less than 3 percent in the city of Lashkargah. Majority of the households in Helmand are found to have severe or extreme sectoral needs in one or more sectors. Helmand has the highest number of persons who need individual protection assistance, legal awareness and psychosocial support. Overall, higher proportions of non-displaced conflict affected households desperately need individual assistance, psychological support, legal awareness. As per HRRAC findings of the Whole of Afghanistan survey in Helmand, 97 percent of households reported experiencing at least one type of major shock or event in the year prior to the survey and this has triggered a decline in the wellbeing of these families. However, many of the sufferings and even deaths could have been avoided if they were accessed, identified and their needs addressed. The impact of the conflict has reduced access to essential services and has affected livelihoods and coping mechanisms. Numerous protection issues need to be addressed in order to enhance the urgent needs and well-being of the people, including improved access to life-saving assistance.
By addressing the needs of target individuals including women and children of displaced families will enable them to cope with the existing challenges posed by war, drought and COVID-19. When possible, HRRAC will coordinate with other clusters to maximize the impact of the intervention.  While addressing the urgent needs of individuals through in kind and cash support, psychosocial support, legal awareness. Communities in Helmand resolve their issues in such a way that undermine the fundamentals of human rights and basic principles of protection. Therefore, it is relevant to increase the awareness of communities on legal issues, how can they access legal services and how to resolve disputes peacefully that could protect human rights and dignity of individuals. 
HRRAC understands that the nature and composition of the assistance will change over time given the wide range of shocks and threats to survival that characterize the vulnerability of people living in Helmand. The situation of returning IDPs and affected communities in Helmand is dire and urgently needs humanitarian response and meets the AHF criteria for intervention.
The proposed activities satisfy the specific objectives of HRP third allocation.
Keeping in view the emergency protection needs of communities in Helmand province, HRRAC proposes the following activities: 
(1)	Provide individual protection assistance (IPA) to 800 vulnerable households.
(2)	Provide legal awareness to target communities.
(3)	Provide Psychosocial Support (PSS) to the susceptible individuals, families and communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Research and Advocacy Consortium</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Research and Advocacy Consortium</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Attaullah Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0702917085</telephone>
   <email>director@hrrac.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="32">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hilmand</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.36364740 63.95861110</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-14">249845</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20240">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-14">249845</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Research and Advocacy Consortium</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305454651">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-03">99938</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Rights Research and Advocacy Consortium</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
