<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/WASH/NGO/21049</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of life-saving WASH support to conflict and drought-affected communities in Kapisa and Badakhshan provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Community Coordination and Development (OCCD) registered with the Ministry of Economy is a non-profit, non-governmental, non-political, and independent organization. OCCD is already an active WASH cluster member. 
The proposed action is informed by OCCD&#x2019;s vast experience in humanitarian and development programs in the two-targeted provinces covered by this action. OCCD has been working in Kapisa and Badakhshan in the past decade delivering services to the underserved communities. OCCD has been working in Afghanistan without interruption since its establishment in 2013, focusing primarily on the health promotion domain. Nonetheless, the NGO has been also working in other sectors such as WASH, education, and livelihoods and has a proven record of accomplishment of working with disenfranchised communities such as IDPs and returnees.
Through this project, resilience to disease and illness will be tackled through improvements in WASH infrastructure as well as through improving health and sanitation practices. OCCD aims to improve the health and wellbeing of at least 15,000 conflict and drought-affected people in the provinces of Badakhshan and Kapisa by reducing the prevalence of waterborne and water-related diseases, e.g. Acute Watery Diarrhea (AWD), cholera, etc. This will be achieved by increasing access to sustainable safe water sources and improving sanitation and hygiene practices. The percentage of people with access to safe drinking water will increase from 40 percent to 65 percent, and 50 percent of households will have an improved understanding of good hygiene behaviors as opposed to the current baseline of less than 25 percent. In addition, the project aims to reach the result that up to 70 percent of target communities will eliminate open defecation.
Work associated with this project will include: (1) Providing good quality and increased quantity of water through boreholes, equipped with hand pumps or mechanized systems with taps (2) Rehabilitation and improvement of drinking water systems such as wells, hand pumps (3) Conducting regular shock chlorination campaigns of unprotected wells and networks (4) Providing appropriate sanitation facilities in households, and schools (4) Conducting health/hygiene education and distribution of hygiene kits as a key element to promoting good health and well-being in the targeted communities and (5) Promoting the elimination of open defecation in target communities through CLTS technics. A full CLTS is not feasible due to the nature of the project (emergency) and the timeframe (only 6 months). 
In line with the WASH cluster&#x2019;s &#x201C;kite strategy&#x201D;, to which OCCD is part, the project will continue to adapt the approaches facing the COVID-19 pandemic. This includes addressing the acute vulnerabilities in the context of the COVID-19 crisis, but also taking into account the current humanitarian crisis contributing to mitigating the COVID-19 transmission and stigmatization, and promoting and build-up on handwashing campaigns.
The resilient WASH services will be delivered to women, men, boys, and girls living in hard-to-reach areas of Badakhshan as well as in overcrowded settlements of Kapisa. As stated above, lack of clean drinking water, absence of proper sanitation facilities, and lack of hygiene awareness as major factors contributing to the spread of diseases, which in turn negatively affect household resilience.
The action will be implemented in a timeframe of 6 months. This timeframe includes the time required to: ensure access to safe and protected water sources improved through the construction of  20 water points and rehabilitation of 40 well safe potable water practices are ensured through the distribution of chlorine and Chlorination campaign  and hygiene and sanitation awareness, including on waste management, is delivered to around 15,000 people across the target communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Community Coordination and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Community Coordination and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Noor Mohammad Noori</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy General Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 794 088 633</telephone>
   <email>dm.director@occd.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Najeebullah Wahedi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 777 777 450</telephone>
   <email>gen.director@occd.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badakhshan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.73477250 70.81199530</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="2">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kapisa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.98105720 69.62145620</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-02"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">480254.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21049">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">480254.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Community Coordination and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305536721">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-27">240127.26</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Community Coordination and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
