<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA2/ESNFI/NGO/18741</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life-Saving Shelter  NFI Response to Conflict and Natural Disaster affected IDPs and Non-displaced Population in Daikundi and Bamyan Provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to deliver life-saving shelter and NFI response assistance to vulnerable conflict-induced and natural disaster IDPs and non-displaced population in Center of Bamyan province, and Khedir, Neli, Sang-e-Takht and Eshtarly districts of Daykundi province. As initially planned, 1500 affected households will receive the &#x201C;Standard NFI Package&#x201D; and &#x201C;Standard Shelter Repair Toolkit&#x201D;, 715 affected households will only receive the &#x201C;Standard Shelter Repair Toolkit&#x201D; and 435 affected households will only receive &#x201C;300 USD as Cash for Shelter Repair/Upgrade&#x201D; as per actual needs on the ground, and vulnerability criteria. The total packages breakdown to 1500 NFI Kits, 2215 Shelter Repair Toolkits and 435 units of Cash for Shelter Repair/Upgrade. Considering the needs and defined assumptions, the project will seek to target 65% of natural disaster affected population and 35% conflict affected population which includes displaced and non-displaced. 75% of the assistance will be prepositioned for Daykundi and 25% for Bamyan with no specific targets for the target districts to ensure we can reach the most vulnerable and can cover the major gaps. The project will be implemented through our sub-offices in Center of Bamyan and Center of Daykundi province, and we will also utilized our field offices in Khedir, Sang-e-Takht and Eshtarly districts of Daykundi. Our provincial teams will actively participate in OCTs coordinated by OCHA at provincial level, joint emergency assessments and response meetings to ensure we can timely deliver our assistance to recommended households. We will closely work with OCHA, IOM, WFP, UNHCR, INGOs/NNGOs, ANDMA, DoRRs and other stakeholders to be part of the emergency response coordination team and to play a complementary role in the overall humanitarian response at regional and provincial levels. The cluster recommended tools will be used for data collection, analysis and reporting while we will put additional tools to collect more segregated data as per Age, Gender and Diversity (AGD) approach. Women headed households, child headed households, elderly headed households, survivors of GBVand other protection incidents will be prioritized for the assistance if the needs were higher than the available resources. We will closely work with government line departments, beneficiary representatives and other stakeholders to identify and select our distribution points in both target provinces, which shall be safe and accessible for men, women, children, elderly and persons with disability with enough facilitation in place. The COVID-19 protocols will be strictly applied throughout the implementation process to ensure safety of our staff, beneficiaries and stakeholders. Project visibility, reporting to cluster, AHF and government will be properly managed as per the requirements of each party. We will use the services of AWAAZ Afghanistan and our internal hotline number to register the complaints, and will ensure that the target communities receive our complaint leaflets during the assessments and distribution. With the support of OCT members, we will form a joint distribution committee to ensure the assistance are delivered to the target beneficiaries in a transparent and accountable manner. The cash assistance will be delivered to the beneficiaries by contracted FSP in the presence of joint distribution committee members while the in-kind assistance will be distributed by our field team through selected distribution points. Our MampE and Project Control units will regularly monitor, evaluate and verify the project activities to improve the quality of our work, exercising a comprehensive lessons learned, and to address compliance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Watan`s Social and Technical services Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Watan`s Social and Technical services Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hayatullah Hayati</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0700031071</telephone>
   <email>wsta.finance@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mokhtar Aria</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBPM Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0765637442</telephone>
   <email>wsta.idp@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Ishaq Sherzai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0799449013</telephone>
   <email>wsta_2011@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="10">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.90732960 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daykundi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.66949500 66.04635340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">499999.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-18741">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">499999.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Watan`s Social and Technical services Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
