<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA2/FSAC/NGO/18774</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cash-Based Emergency Food Assistance to shock-affected families in Dolayna District of Ghor Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The latest Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) analysis, published in April 2021, shows that over 14 million people (35 percent of the population) face acute food insecurity (IPC Phase 3 or worse) between March and May 2021, including 4.2 million people facing emergency levels of food insecurity and requiring immediate assistance. Ghor province was classified in emergency levels of food insecurity (IPC Phase 4). Diminished participation during the La Nina period has triggered a water scarcity crisis. For many impacted communities, it has become a challenge to acquire enough water for drinking, hygiene and food production (agriculture and livestock), and low levels of participation and dry spell is anticipated to further affect more population up to November 2021.

The 2021 HRP indicates that food prices are about 10-20% higher compared to the 5-year average, while the purchasing power of casual laborers and pastoralists has deteriorated almost 19% and 20% respectively over the last year. Overall, high levels of poverty and food insecurity are fuelling the adoption of negative coping mechanisms, presenting serious dangers to vulnerable people including elevated risks of GBV, early marriage, child labor, begging and recruitment by armed groups and additional debt accumulation. Without immediate, comprehensive anticipatory action, the already dire food insecurity and protection situation will be exacerbated by the consequences of the La Ni&#xF1;a effect. This also applies in Ghor province.

Through the proposed project, AWRO will provide unconditional cash assistance to 1,319 households (9,235 individuals) in Dolayna district of Ghor province to households in &#x2018;crisis&#x2019; (IPC Phase 3) and &#x2018;emergency&#x2019; (IPC Phase 4) food insecurity and those anticipated to be affected by flood, dry spell and other risks. Based on the cluster standards and the allocation strategy paper, every eligible HH will receive USD 180 (equivalent AFN amount based on the exchange rate of the particular period).

1. Dolayna district
1,319 multiple shock-affected Families (1985 Men, 2494 Women, 2245 Boys and 2511 Girls) 
Will receive US$ 180 for four months food assistance (Half package of FSAC Standard food basket of family 90 US$/month x 2 = US$ 180).

AWRO will use the local Tellers&#x2019; services/Money Service Providers (Hawala/MSP) system based on CVWG response criteria as there are MSPs available in Ghor. The MSPs are the most available and easy to access to beneficiaries. AWRO already has agreement with an MSP to provide service in the target province. The availability of MSPs is ensured and physically checked. The cash will be distributed in AFN currency. 

To ensure transparency, AWRO will establish a committee comprised of four representatives from respective government institutions and village head. The committee will be present at every stage of the project activities related to beneficiary selection and cash distribution, and will monitor and approve related documents accordingly. In addition, a village head will also be present during the stages.

Beneficiaries will be selected as per the criteria set by the FSAC cluster through a house-to-house independent assessment/survey done by AWRO. This assignment will not negatively affect the market, prices, transactions and or any other financial segments. Instead, it would be an added value and multiplier to inject cash into the market. This will make sure that we take account of the &#x201C;Do No Harm&#x201D; policy.

In addition to the cash distribution, AWRO will provide awareness on COVID-19. Protection awareness-raising sessions will take place at the distribution site. Key people of each village will participate in community dialogues in order to discuss protection issues and information will be shared about other services available within the area to enable women to potentially get in touch with support services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmad Fawad Frotan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93780690411</telephone>
   <email>awro.program@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mustafa Ahmadi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93700189189</telephone>
   <email>mustafa.ahmadi@awro.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">279006.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">71908.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-18774">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">350914.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305104166">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-16">175457.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
