<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/21399</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livestock Packages and Vegetable Kits Assistance in Kunar Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the IPC analysis report published in October 2021, 22.8 million people are facing crisis or emergency levels of food insecurity (IPC 3 and 4). More than half of all children under-five face acute malnutrition in 2021. SFSA 2021 data shows that 57 per cent of households have food reserves that would last for only less than 3 months. In urban areas, income loss (driven by economic shocks) has contributed to the rapid deterioration in food insecurity. 10 out of 11 most densely populated urban areas are anticipated to be in IPC 4. Additionally, the higher food prices are negatively impacting the purchasing power of lower-income groups across the country, reducing their access to food.

As per the Afghanistan Humanitarian Needs Overview (HNO) 2022, out of the total 664,000 population of the Kunar province, 237,000 are identified in &#x201C;Severe&#x201D;, and 135,000 in &#x201C;Extreme&#x201D; severity phase with urgent need of humanitarian assistance. Post-August, as direct conflict declined, the main drivers of humanitarian needs affecting physical and mental well-being are the lack of adequate food and livelihoods means, driving millions into crisis. t is likely that household food access between the end of winter and the following spring season will further deteriorate due to the continuing La Ni&#xF1;a climatic episode bringing below-average winter precipitation for the second consecutive year, the impact of high food prices, sanctions on the de facto authorities, growing unemployment and possibly increased displacement. An estimated 8.7 million people in Emergency (IPC Phase 4) and 14 million people in Crisis (IPC Phase 3) require urgent action to save their lives, reduce food gaps and protect their livelihoods. 

Almost all the SFSA 2021 outcome indicators confirmed that the food security situation has severely deteriorated. 92 per cent of farmers reported a lack of seeds for the next planting. As a key food insecurity driver in urban areas, income has reduced for 97 per cent of households in 11 main urban domains. Furthermore, FAO collected additional data during August and September 2021 using a household survey to assess impact of multiple shocks on rural livelihoods. The survey highlights that while conflict has affected 40 per cent of households analyzed, the most-frequently reported shocks by rural households were drought and soaring food prices. As the conflict in the country was unfolding, Afghan farmers and livestock keepers were already suffering from the impacts of a drought and intensified conflict that hit the country during the main 2020-21 agricultural season &#x2013; between June and August, 40 per cent of the farming households in the country faced disaster or crisis affecting their ability to raise income and/or to produce food for their own consumption.

Through the proposed project, AWRO will provide Vegetable Kits and Livestock Packages to 1,600 shock-affected HHs (11,200 individuals &#x2013; based on average family size of 7) in Assad Abad and Sirkani districts of Kunar province . The provision of the mentioned kits will aid in the food security of the target households through increasing livestock products, the families will also have access to fresh vegetables. The training workshops will make sure they are determined to continue growing seasonal crops within their households with proper and effective practices.

Through this project, 6300 individuals (900 multiple shock-affected HHs) in Assad district and 4,900 individuals (700 multiple shock-affected HHs) in Sirkani district of Kunar will receive vegetable kits and livestock packages. FSAC&#x2019;s livestock and vegetable packages will be used for assisting vulnerable households under this project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sayed Farhadullah Ebadi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Managing Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93786126612</telephone>
   <email>director@awro.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mustafa Ahmadi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Focal Point</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93700189189</telephone>
   <email>mustafa.ahmadi@awro.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.84658930 71.09731700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-25">345343.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21399">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-25">345343.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305585114">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-26">172671.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Women Rights Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
