<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA3/H/INGO/20031</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved availability and provision of lifesaving trauma care, essential primary healthcare services for conflict-affected and vulnerable people in hard-to-reach communities of Paktika and Nuristan provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the AHF RA3 2021, IMC proposes provision of lifesaving trauma care and primary health care (PHC) services to hard-to-reach communities in Paktika and Nuristan provinces. This intervention will fulfill critical gaps in the healthcare sector in these provinces, especially trauma care and PHC services which currently forces community members to travel long distances for such services. Services proposed here will also respond to the rising needs exacerbated recently due to fighting which has led to internal displacement/population movement across the country. Also, the third wave of COVID-19 has further revealed the need for health services in Paktika and Nuristan provinces. Considering the BPHS guideline and SPHERE standard for health services, this project will provide safe access to all and especially vulnerable groups, such as women, girls, people with disabilities (PWDs), children and elderly through the following activities:

 Provision of trauma care services through establishment of one new First Aid Trauma Post (FATP) in Kamdish district in Nuristan province.
 Provision of trauma care services through continuation of two FATPs (one standalone and one integrated) in two hard-to-reach districts (Giyan and Dila) of Paktika province 
 Establishment of one new, integrated FATP in Yahyakhil district) in Paktika province.
 Establishment of one new, integrated FATP in Waza-khawa district) in Paktika province.
 Provision of timely/standardized referral system for trauma cases in both provinces -- IMC will provide and functionalize four ambulances (one for each FATP, three in Paktika and one in Nuristan) and equip to provide timely first-aid and basic life support as well as to evacuate patients and ensure access to the next level care.
 Continue support activities of the two existing Health Sub-centers (HSCs) in Gomal district of Paktika to provide emergency primary health care including reproductive, maternal, newborn and child health (RMNCH) services aligned with BPHS guideline. 
The WB has recently suspended financial support to the SEHATMANDI project in Afghanistan. This has affected the service delivery by the BPHS health facilities in Paktika province and resulted in lack of access to health services provided by public health facilities. To ensure the local population has access to emergency primary health services,  as per Health Cluster recommendation , IMC would target 2 existing SHCs which were previously working under BPHs.
-	Proposed New SHC-1: in WazaKhwa (Paktika) will be activated in new location (the fix SHC of Gwashta in same district).
-	Proposed New SHC-2 (initially planned in Waza Khwa) will be shifted to Qarabdin in Yahya Khail district. 

Procuring medicines, medical supplies, medical equipment and non-medical supplies 
IMC will implement the project in close coordination with Health Cluster, PPHDs, MoPH, BPHS/EPHS implementing NGOs along with the support of local/targeted communities.

International Medical Corps (IMC) is a US-registered independent affiliate organization of International Medical Corps UK (IMC UK), with which IMC UK shares the same name and charitable objectives and mission. IMC UK and IMC work together to deliver assistance programs in an accountable and effective manner in pursuit of their commonly-held charitable objectives. IMC UK will engage IMC to implement its programs in the field, with IMC UK oversight, according to the terms and conditions of the agreement that results from this proposal and the terms of the parties&#x2019; administrative service agreement. Together with IMC Croatia, IMC provides administrative and operational support to IMC UK and to the programs on the ground, including but not limited to financial management, banking and cash management, procurement management/international procurements and logistics</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ehsanallah Shafaq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93708269568</telephone>
   <email>eshafaq@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Matthew Stearns</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799737954</telephone>
   <email>mstearns@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Shamail Azimi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country /Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93798809020</telephone>
   <email>sazimi@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="14">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuristan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.32502230 70.90712360</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paktika</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.26453860 68.52471490</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-18">112171.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-16"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-18">432232.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20031">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-18">544404.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305289928">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-24">326642.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
