<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/20817</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Food Response to Shock Affected Communities (IPC Phase 3 and 4) in Narang  Sarkani Districts of Kunar Province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to conflict induced displacement figures from 1 Jan 2021 to 18 Oct 2021, 667,938 individuals fled their homes due to conflict. A total of 34,704 out of 667,938 IDPS recorded in Kunar Province. Constrained humanitarian access hinders assessments, thus preventing verification of the full extent of displacement and undermining the provision of assistance and services. Displacement affects all individuals differently with needs, vulnerabilities and protection risks evolving over time due to exhaustion of coping mechanisms and only basic emergency assistance provided following initial displacement. food insecurity, often result in precarious living conditions that jeopardizes the well-being and dignity of affected families. As per the OCHA report a total of 14,217 people were displaced to Narang, Sarkani, Asadabad, Shegal, Nurgal, and Chawkay districts in Kunar province. 
The A La Ni&#xF1;a drought in 2021 impacted food production and planting seasons in Kunar. Economic decline due to political transition and the consequent freezing in national assets, the economy crashed. The banking system suffered severe disruption, and the national currency lost 12.5% of value, leading to high unemployment and food prices. According to SFSA 2021, 83% of Kunar agricultural HHs reported reduction in this year&#x2019;s harvest. With the recent climate outlook and weak to moderate La Ni&#xF1;a event, it is highly likely that lower than average precipitation and poor soil moisture conditions will result in consecutive drought in 2022. Already 50% of the households already using emergency coping strategies which will further deteriorate during winter lean season.
The latest IPC analysis published in Oct 2021, shows that over 22 million people (55% of the population) will face acute food insecurity (IPC Phase 3 or worse) between Nove 2021 and Mar 2022, including 8.7 million people in emergency and requiring immediate assistance. According to the IPC analysis, Kunar province is facing emergency level of acute food insecurity. The drought conditions driven by La Ni&#xF1;a, the current political crisis and conflict further compound the food security situation of a population which was already on the brink of a hunger crisis.
This project focuses on Theme1: Expanded humanitarian access and response in underserved and hardest-to-reach locations Activity 1: Food assistance for IPC Phase 3 amp 4 people&#x2013;cash or in-kind (Theme1) i.e. OCHR will ensure timely provision of (in-kind) food assistance for 1460 HHs in Narang (730 HHs) and Sarkani (730 HHs)  districts to meet the immediate needs of people in Kunar province. This is considered as a complimentary involvement to OCHR&#x2019;s ongoing interventions providing 1528 HHs with Food, WASH, Livelihood and COVID-19 support to most vulnerable communities in east region (Kunar and Nangarhar) funded by Christian-Aid, UNDP and GNI-A.
OCHR has planned to upgrade its current activities and will select the targeted beneficiaries in a transparent manner as we have already visualized the most at risk/venerable HHs recently. And to ensure that the most affected receive the assistance. The FSAC beneficiary selection and vulnerability criteria will be ensured in the presence of the community elders, local authorities and UNOCHA representatives, while selecting beneficiaries,. The project duration will be 6 months.
Having the experience of implementing various emergency response projects in the region, and knowledge in technical and managerial issues will give an extra advantage to OCHR in implementing this project. OCHR rolled out three similar ongoing project from GNI/UNDP in Kunar province providing Emergency Food, Nutrition and WASH packages to 2100 HHs recently completed. And OCHR is currently implementing two similar ongoing projects in Kunar/Nangarhar funded by UNDP, GNI and Christian Aid providing FSAC,ES/NFI, CDP and WASH emergency responses to 3156 HHs in the targeted areas respectively.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Coordination of Humanitarian Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Coordination of Humanitarian Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghulam Sadiq Safi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director General</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93766661985</telephone>
   <email>director@ochr.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.84658930 71.09731700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-04"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">249850.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20817">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">249850.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Coordination of Humanitarian Relief</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305471663">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-16">149910.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Coordination of Humanitarian Relief</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305632006">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-16">99940.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organization for Coordination of Humanitarian Relief</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
