<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA3/APC/UN/20116</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improvised Explosive Device (IED)-focused Hostile Environment Training for Humanitarian Organizations</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will be managed by the United Nations Mine Action Service (UNMAS)  Afghanistan Programme, in response to the request from a number of humanitarian NGOs to deliver safety and security training with a focus on the risks posed by explosive ordnance, particularly improvised explosive devices (IEDs). UNMAS Afghanistan is a programme implemented by UNMAS via the United Nations Office for Project Services (UNOPS) under the Financial Regulations and Rules of UNOPS. 
Civilian casualties in the first half of the year reached a record high with the deteriorating security situation following the onset of the Taliban&#x2019;s latest offensive, which began in May 2021 - added to the existing explosive hazard contamination across the country, particularly through the use of IEDs by former anti-government elements (AGEs) -  has established an urgent need to prepare humanitarian actors better in the face of explosive threats. It has been already recognized that IEDs are and will ultimately remain one of the main threats to the civilian population, hindering mobility and humanitarian delivery. The aim of the initiative is to prepare humanitarian agencies with the necessary knowledge, skills and capabilities to operate safely in an environment where explosive risks are high, thereby enabling the delivery of humanitarian assistance in the context of the deteriorating security environment within Afghanistan. Under this project, UNMAS will conduct the Training of the Trainer (ToT) safety and security training with regard to managing/mitigating the threats presented by explosive hazards in Afghanistan and to develop Afghanistan-specific training modules to be further used to instruct UN agencies, national and international NGOs, and other relevant stakeholders. Topics will include:  
 Basic recognition of explosive ordnance, including landmines, IEDs and explosive remnants of war  (ERWs), and safe behaviour when encountering one.  
 Minimum safety equipment while on a mission and safe behaviour depending on travel type (by vehicle, foot, and other means) and different environments.  
 Incident management (actions in a dangerous area, how to respond after an explosion or another type of incident, etc.), with basic first aid/triage.  
 Other topics identified at the assessment phase of the project, based on the inputs from relevant stakeholders.  
The project will provide UN agencies, national and international NGOs, and other relevant stakeholders with the knowledge and tools, to reduce the threats posed by explosive ordnance in high-risk areas.  Training material will be gender-sensitive and produced in the relevant language depending on the audience, so will include as a minimum English, Dari, and Pashto. The training will be delivered by the international and national expert(s) and tailored to the Afghan context and needs of the audience. There are two milestones of the project: 1) Develop training materials pertaining to the above-mentioned topics in line with international conventions and standards 2) Provide training to 100 trainers from UN  agencies, national and international NGOs, and other relevant organizations it is then expected that these trainers will replicate the training in their organizations, which UNMAS Afghanistan will monitor and support through technical advice and mentorship as needed. Throughout the project, including the initial courses delivered by the newly trained trainers, UNMAS Afghanistan will provide oversight and qualified mentorship via the hired IED Advisor and Trainer to ensure the targeted personnel are properly equipped and ready to further relay knowledge. This will ultimately enhance the humanitarian community to respond to the threat better.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jilian Piao</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93706952264</telephone>
   <email>JilianP@unops.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief of Mine Action Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>heslop@un.org</telephone>
   <email>Paul Heslop</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Matyas Juhasz</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93705004376</telephone>
   <email>matyasj@unops.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kabul</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.53333300 69.16666700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-31">292582.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-31">7417.59</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20116">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-31">300000.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_AFG_2022_1000099">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-10">300000.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for Project Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
