<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA2/H/INGO/18687</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Primary Health Care  Services, Trauma Care  Psychosocial Support  for conflict and drought affected population of Badghis province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis is one of the hard to reach and remote provinces located in the western region of Afghanistan. The province is included in the list of 25 high risks provinces which will more likely be worst affected by the dry spell as identified in the multi-sectoral need analysis and included in the Humanitarian Response for Spring disaster contingency plan. Being one of the least developed province with poor infrastructures, people have to travel mostly through difficult roads and mine fields. As the conflict continue and fighting between the government forces and AOGs intensifies, collateral damage and injuries of people caught in the crossfire are unavoidable and the demand for trauma care have increased especially in areas where there are constant fighting. More than two third of the province (except central towns in the districts) are under control of Taliban. Assessment data indicates the early effects of dry spell among the local population is already felt with most of them reportedly have taken loans to buy food and other basic needs. As the water crisis unfolds, water availability for livestock and agriculture, as well as for drinking and hygiene will be a challenge for the affected communities. The affected population may need to walk longer distance to reach water sources that are available and may need to expend additional resources to compensate for limited local water availability and/ or poor water quality. Those who cannot afford to purchase water through private water trucks may de-prioritise water for sanitation and hygiene, which in turn will increase risk of infectious and waterborne diseases, including COVID-19 and Acute Watery Diarrhea. At the same time, limited existing or accessible healthcare is a high risk in the affected provinces. Scale-up of mobile health teams and health surveillance to deal with the health implications of the likely drought, disease and malnutrition in these locations will be important and the need will increase in the event of displacement.
The proposed project will cover  catchment population of 52,152 with limited or no access to   primary health and trauma care  in the 5 targeted districts. Difficult terrain, poor infrastructure and the distance people need to walk to reach the health facilities are some of the constraints which makes it very difficult for people to access basic health services. High number of casualties including civilian casualties resulted from frequent security incidences (conflicts, road side bombs and air strikes) has been reported from the targeted locations. Johanniter International Assistance (JUH) amp Medical Management amp Research Courses for Afghanistan (MMRCA) through this project, aims to improve access and utilisation of basic primary health care services, trauma care and psychosocial support by the affected population through the following:1.Establishment, equipping and staffing of 4 FATPs in Bala Murghab, Moqor, Qadis amp Abkamari districts 2.Provision of First Aid Trauma Care to people injured in the conflict 3.Provision of psychological first aid and counselling to patients showing symptoms of psychological trauma and other psychosocial problems 4.Provision of emergency primary health services to the population living in remote amp underserved villages through establishment of two MHTs in Bala Murghab amp Moqor. MHT in Moqor will also extend health services to population living in remote areas of Qadis amp Jawand districts. 5.Integration of COVID 19 response such as screening, contact tracing and referral in the package of services to be provided by the Mobile Health Team 6.Identification, Management and referrals of GBV survivors 7.Community Awareness raising on prevention amp transmission of COVID 19 infections, proper hygiene practices amp prevention of GBV. 8. Nutrition screening, referral of MAM and SAM amp orientation of PLW on breastfeeding amp Infant amp Young Children Feeding.. Project duration is 6 months with 1 month inception period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JOHANNITER</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JOHANNITER</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical Management and Research Courses for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-21" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-20" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Helen Guillermo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+9372 833 0970</telephone>
   <email>helen.guillermo@thejohanniter.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khangelanai Ncube</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93730706750</telephone>
   <email>khangelani.ncube@thejohanniter.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Louis Marijnissen</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93728882615</telephone>
   <email>louis.marijnissen@thejohanniter.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Shah Maqsood Sahebzada</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manager-Program Development and Partnerships</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93728331041</telephone>
   <email>shah.maqsood@thejohanniter.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shukrullah Shinwari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Officer-Partnerships</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93728882615</telephone>
   <email>shukrullah.shinwari@thejohanniter.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-21"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-20"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">300151.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-18687">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">300151.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JOHANNITER</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305104159">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-16">240120.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">JOHANNITER</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
