<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/21229</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livelihood assistance to the vulnerable population in Nangarhar province (Distribution of animal feed, de-wormer, and home gardening)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The prolonged multiple crises unfolding in Afghanistan have had devastating effects on people&#x2019;s ability to meet their daily needs and to cope with sudden shocks. The recently updated Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) analysis shows the food security situation has further deteriorated with worrying implications for the winter lean season ahead. An estimated 22.8 million people, or 55 percent of the population, are expected to be in crisis or emergency levels of food insecurity (IPC 3+) between November 2021 and March 2022 (AHF Allocation Strategy). The targeted province, Nangarhar, is considered to be in the IPC 3 and 4, in an emergency situation (IPC Analysis) and FSAC has categorized the province as at a high priority due to the number of people in need and the multiple needs to be met. Afghanistan is highly prone to natural hazards, such as floods and droughts that have badly impacted farmers&#x2019; production capacity and livelihoods sustainability. 

The estimated population of Nangarhar is 1,896,240. According to IPC acute food insecurity analysis (November 2021-March 2022), 35% of the population is under IPC3 and 25% is under IPC4 situation in Nangarhar Province. Also, the total population under IPC3+ is 1,137,744 (60%). 

The estimated population of Chaparhar district is 68,347. The reports show, that the Chaparhar district faced dry weather, a lack of irrigation water, and has no cultivated wheat on most of the lands as well as facing drought. Furthermore, drought has not only affected wheat crops but most orchards, agricultural crops, and animal husbandry. Also, formers avoided the cultivation of wheat and other crops on rain-fed land due to lack of rainfall. 

The estimated population of Rodat district is 110,000. The reports show, that the Rodat district faced dry weather, a lack of irrigation water, and has no cultivated wheat on most of the lands as well as facing drought. Furthermore, drought has not only affected wheat crops but most orchards, agricultural crops, and animal husbandry. Also, formers avoided the cultivation of wheat and other crops on rain-fed land due to lack of rainfall. The Nangarhar Agriculture Department acknowledged the problems faced by farmers in Chaparhar and Rodat districts of Nangarhar Province due to drought.

To respond to the above situation, RRAA, as part of the proposed project, will provide livelihood support to 7,140 affected people, as follow:
- distribution of livestock packages (Animal Feed, Straw, de-wormer, and transport) to 7,140 beneficiaries in line with FSAC guidelines.
- distribution of vegetable seeds and home-based kitchen gardening kits includes a minimum of 4 different types of vegetable seeds (Cucumber, Okra, Gourd, and Bitter Gourd) and a basic toolkit (spade, rake, hoe). 

The project activities will be implemented in coordination with UNOCHA and FSAC partners present in the field. Also, RRAA will conduct social mobilization in coordination with targeted communities, CDCs and Shura elders, and relevant local sectoral authorities to ensure that the most vulnerable drought-affected population is identified and selected.

RRAA will select a safe distribution point in coordination with the target beneficiaries and will ensure that the day, time, and location for the distribution of food packages are accessible and easy to reach. RRAA will also ensure that measures are in place for the safe and non-discriminatory distribution of the packages. In addition, RRAA&#x2019;s field staff will add to the knowledge, skills, and experience of the beneficiaries through on-the-spot brief hands-on demo training prior to the distribution of packages so that the beneficiaries appropriately utilize the distributed items.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shah Wali Alokozay</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acting Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93700601853</telephone>
   <email>director@rraa.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Menhaj Amir Arifi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93797625128</telephone>
   <email>fin.manager@rraa.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basir Ahmad Monib</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HR/Admin Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93708566388</telephone>
   <email>hradmin.manager@rraa.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Riazullah Wali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93703330314</telephone>
   <email>prog.manager@rraa.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nangarhar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.17183130 70.62167940</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-01">240463.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21229">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-01">240463.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305517067">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-14">144277.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
