<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/WASH/NGO/21156</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH response to the population of the underserved and hardest-to-reach districts in Uruzgan provinces of Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Dec 2021, Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan (RRAA), carried out a needs assessment on the urgent and unmet water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) need of 18 communities in the Dehrawood, Chora, and Trinkot districts of Uruzgan province, with the aim on contributing to reducing the incidence of child mortality and morbidity brought about by the water-borne disease. After assessment and data analysis number of 8 communities in three districts include (a),(Gara Yoghochar Shila, Qalach Blak Awal, and Liblan Usmanzai villages of Dehrawood district, (b) dang kalay, Hajyan kalay, harmistan Markazi kalay villages of Trinkot district and (c), Etefaq Masjed Kalay and Kalach Haji Ali Mohammad villages of Chora district are selected to be covered through this project because selected districts have no access to sufficient quantities of safe water, engage in open defecation (OD) due to the lack of suitable sanitation facilities, have little knowledge on proper hygiene and nutrition practices in emergency situations and to facilitate the provision of WASH services for 25% overcrowded settlements in the targeted villages. The proposed project will reach 20973 population including of men 6502, women 8807, boys 2936 and girls 2728 (2483 families) among which 5342 individuals are overcrowded population ensuring that they have: 1) improved access to a safe water supply 2) improved access to adequate sanitation facilities 3) opportunities to practice safe hygiene and nutrition behaviors. Water sources in the target areas are unsafe, as they can be both unprotected (where they present a hazard to people and animals in the area), contain contaminated water, and be over-stressed. To meet the need for a sufficient and safe water supply, existing broken and open wells will be rehabilitated and protected, solar-powered pipe scheme will be installed. Up to 170 individuals will have access to each water point. Placement of water points within the communities will reduce the burden on women and girls, who currently spend on average more than 30 minutes one-way to reach a water point. The continued functioning of the water points will be managed through local volunteer mechanics, who will be identified and trained in the operation and maintenance of the water systems, and through local caretakers. The implementation of the CLTS approach and installation of lockable latrines, with handwashing facilities, it will mitigate the spread of WASH-related diseases, ensure the privacy and security of women and children, and provide easy access for disabled persons and the elderly. Targeted households with disability and elderly people will receive WASH services accordingly. Awareness sessions will promote hygiene awareness and practices leading to health risk reduction. Hygiene sessions will focus on diarrhea prevention strategies, discouraging open defecation, critical times to wash hands with soap, menstrual hygiene management, safe household water treatment, and, food hygiene. 2000 families will receive hygiene kits. During kit distributions, orientation on the correct utilization of the items in the kits will take place.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hamed Sharifi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Region Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93700257999</telephone>
   <email>cro.manager@rraa.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Riazullah Wali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93703330314</telephone>
   <email>prog.manager@rraa.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="23">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uruzgan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.92712870 66.14152630</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">498296.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21156">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">498296.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural Rehabilitation Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
