<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/WASH/INGO/20922</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency WASH Assistance in Afghanistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the last severe drought that Afghanistan faced in 2018, the population has been affected by the spread of COVID-19, recurrent natural disasters, increasing poverty and economic needs, and an intense conflict between the former government and the IEA. Now, Afghanistan is experiencing the devastating effects of a drought declared in June of 2021 but due to conflict, the change of authorities, financial systems collapse, security/political instability, many rural areas were unable to prepare for the drought as the harsh winter conditions approach. In late 2021, many households are still struggling to ensure consistent safe sources of drinking water while sanitation and hygiene conditions fall below the required levels to protect against COVID-19.
In this context, this 6-month intervention aims to provide WASH services to 90,062 individuals across Balkh, Baghlan and Kunduz. ACTED aims to increase the supply and quality of water accessible to priority districts in these provinces through rehabilitation works to existing water sources and networks to ensure provision of safe water. Furthermore, ACTED will construct a number of new water sources in locations where gaps in water provision exist. All constructed and rehabilitated water sources and networks will be tested to ensure quality of the water.
ACTED will rehabilitate 240 boreholes in Balkh with 80 boreholes per targeted district (Dawlatabad, Char Bolak, Chemtal) rehabilitated to reach 42,000 individuals. In Kunduz, ACTED will rehabilitate 85 wells across 6 districts (Dasht-e-Archi, Chahardara, Khan Abad, Aliabad, Imam Sahib, Qala-e-Zal) providing 14,875 individuals with more consistent provision of safe water. ACTED will also rehabilitate 3 water networks in Kunduz&#x2019;s Khanabad (2 networks) and Aliabad (1 network) districts serving 650 HH. In Baghlan, ACTED will rehabilitate 2 existing water networks in Nahrin and Burka districts providing 1,000 HH with more consistent water supply.
ACTED will construct new water supply infrastructure in Baghlan and Balkh including new wells, solar pumps and solar powered drinking water systems. In Baghlan, ACTED will construct 4 new wells in 4 villages across 2 districts, Dahn-e-Ghori and Baghlan Jadid. In Dahn-e-Ghori, Haji Naim village and Haji Habib, 340 HH will benefit from a newly constructed well connected to a solar pump system. In Baghlan Jadid, 380 HH in Temorian and Lagi ha villages will each receive a new well connected to a water supply system with a solar pump. ACTED will establish 6 solar powered drinking water systems with tap stands connected to a reservoir to service 5 highschools and 1 health centre in Balkh district, Balkh province. This will benefit an estimated 14,500 individuals that use these facilities.
ACTED will install latrines for 300 HH in Kunduz targeting 6 districts (Dasht e Archi, Khanabad, Imam Sahib, Qala e Zal, Chahardara, Aliabad) with 50 latrines per district. In addition to the latrine construction, ACTED will conduct a hygiene promotion training and hygiene kit distribution for all targeted HHs to improve their hygiene situation. This will benefit 2,100 individuals in 6 districts.
All activities will be adapted to the COVID-19 context to ensure the safety of staff and beneficiaries and to disseminate COVID-19 prevention measures. 
Risks related to access and community acceptance are mitigated by ACTED&#x2019;s strong community involvement and acceptance from years of implementing in North and North Eastern Afghanistan. In addition to ACTED&#x2019;s longstanding presence in the region, adherence to the policy of hiring staff from the local area as much as possible to promote acceptance, contextual awareness and support the longevity of the project.
ACTED has coordinated with other WASH NGOs implementing in the targeted districts to ensure there is no duplication of activities. 
ACTED has coordinated, and will continue to coordinate, with other WASH NGOs implementing in the targeted area to avoid duplication</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shah Jahan Rahimi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Project Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 700 157 205</telephone>
   <email>Kabul.reporting@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Francois Hericher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 728 427 169</telephone>
   <email>francois.hericher@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lee Griffin</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 93 (0) 728427177</telephone>
   <email>lee.griffin@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baghlan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.80429470 69.28775350</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balkh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.89091580 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunduz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.85993070 68.71549750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">700000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20922">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-13">700000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305542489">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-29">560000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
