<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/INGO/20886</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life -Saving Food  Assistance for Food Insecure households in Ghor Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan is this year currently experiencing its second severe drought in four years. Food production has been hit hard, livestock are highly stressed and rural livelihoods are facing increased threats. Already, 22.8 million, 55 % of the population- projected between November 2021 and March 2022 to be in IPC Phase 4 (Emergency) and IPC Phase 3 (Crisis) food insecurity phases. Of these, around 4.9 million people (52% % of the analyzed urban population) will face  high levels of acute food insecurity in IPC Phase 3 or above. Sharp drops in income, surging food and other commodity prices, growing unemployment and severed remittances are expected to contribute to the deterioration of food security. No population group had a net positive income in 2021. More than half of all children under-five face acute malnutrition in 2021 Assessments show that more households have higher than average debt this year. This is increasingly concerning as food basket costs are steadily rising, constituting more than 82 per cent of the average household income. 
Ghor province has been classified in IPC 4 is currently experiencing acute food security emanating as a result of multiple key drivers which include the 2020/21 seasonal drought, the recent upheaval that took place in August 2021, COVID-19, loss of employment, reduced income household sources, inflation amongst others. 65% of Ghor&#x2019;s population is classified in IPC3 as per the October 2021 post-harvest analysis. Of these 40% are in IPC Phase 4, which represents a dire food insecurity situation. The majority of its inhabitants are households either facing food consumption gaps that are reflected by high or above-usual acute malnutrition or are marginally able to meet minimum food needs but only by depleting essential livelihood assets or through crisis-coping strategies. According the latest SFSA results, 54.6% of the households in Ghor province have been affected by major shocks/events in the past 6 months and the major ones being Drought / dry spell (18.7%)Loss of employment (9.9%), Reduced income (26.9%), Severe sickness or natural death of breadwinner (non-COVID) (6.4%), Conflict induced displacement (3.2 %), amongst other shocks. The poverty rate currently stands at an estimated 45.6%. 

In line with FSAC priorities detailed in the cluster&#x2019;s specific priorities in the updated HRP 2018-2021 the Allocation&#x2019;s vision (Theme 1: Expanded humanitarian access and response in underserved and hardest-to-reach locations.) as well as OCHA&#x2019;s September 2021 Humanitarian Flash Appeal, WVA proposes to provide emergency food assistance 18,421 vulnerable people (2,632 HH) in underserved districts of (Firoz Khor, Charsada, Pasaband and Saghar in Ghor province. WVA will provide food assistance through unconditional cash (4 months half ration) to acutely food insecure (IPC3) 18,421 individuals from 2,632 Households. As per cluster priorities for this allocation, the intervention will provide in each district with 4 standard half rations for a total of US 180 per household (2021 FSAC&#x2019;s guidelines).

To ensure and cost effective and rapid response, WVA already has a long term agreement (LTA) with a financial service provider who has experience in working in the selected areas. Distribution will be done over 4 rounds of 45 USD per HH per month. Participants with limited mobility will be brought to the distribution point or receive the assistance at home. 

This intervention will provide 18,461 vulnerable men, women, boys and girls with urgent live saving food assistance, to address their immediate food gaps whilst reducing illness and mortality as a result of the current food crisis. The cash will be provided over a period of four months (4 rounds of half ration distributions) through use of a reputable Hawala agent who already has a long term agreement with World Vison Afghanistan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asuntha Charles</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799-209-720</telephone>
   <email>Asuntha_Charles@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Faisal Danesh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance/Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 792 494 002</telephone>
   <email>Faisal_Danesh@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Faraidoon Osmani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GAM Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799861573</telephone>
   <email>Faraidoon_Osmani@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonathan Chifamba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operations Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 7994900407</telephone>
   <email>Jonathan-Chifamba@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biruk Beyene</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 797088426</telephone>
   <email>biruk_beyene@wvi.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghor</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.09957760 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">699963.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20886">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-05">699963.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
