<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/EIE/INGO/21065</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Education in Emergency to crisis-affected girls and boys in Herat and Badghis provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to ensure more children are able to maintain their education to learn and acquire skills that allow them a better chance at future livelihoods to support their communities. The project will increase access to quality education for emergency-affected girls and boys in remote and hard-to-reach areas and ensure inclusive and protective spaces for learning for all children by providing learning opportunities to 7875 children (3, 150 boys amp 4,725 girls) through the establishment and running of 225 temporary learning spaces in 4 high priority districts (2 in Herat and 2 in Badghis). WCUK will recruit and deploy 225 teachers (60 % female) to teach in the 225 temporary learning spaces in line with CBE policy. Teachers will receive training on the standardized TiCC (Teachers in Crisis Contexts) curriculum which includes topics PSS and Social and Emotional Learning. Teachers will also receive structured support from coaches/mentors on safe and supportive behavior management and classroom management, pedagogy, and other core subjects. Moreover, teacher peer-to-peer support will be provided via learning circles or support sessions facilitated by trained supervisors who will oversee the quality of the teacher&#x2019;s performance. 
To reduce risks to female teachers, WCUK will be providing payments to cover transportation to and from the training venue. Temporary Learning Spaces (TLS) will be equipped with PSS kits which include play-oriented/recreational materials suitable for a variety of age categories. The 12 days training that the teachers will receive, will include components on how to safely guide and support children to utilize these PSS materials and unlock their benefits. War Child will conduct minor rehabilitation on identified TLS to ensure that the spaces are safe and suitable to provide quality teaching and learning. The learning spaces will also be equipped with age-appropriate teaching, learning, and hygiene materials. The WASH facilities will also be built or rehabilitated in the TLS to promote hygiene practices. In addition, gender-segregated and accessible latrines for TLS will be constructed or rehabilitated. Feminine hygiene kits (for adolescent girls) will be provided to support the hygiene needs of girls. 
Community members and other education stakeholders will be mobilized to support out-of-school boys and girls in accessing and continuing their education in target locations by conducting community-level back-to-school awareness-raising campaigns with community leaders and parents on the importance of education to children&#x2019;s development and wellbeing, with a focus on girls&#x2019; education. The proposed intervention will strengthen the capacity of communities and educational stakeholders to identify and mitigate risks in the learning environment. Training will be provided to teachers and Community Education Committee/School Management Committees members on child safeguarding and Prevention of Sexual Exploitation and Abuse (PSEA), and how to safely identify and refer children in need of child protection and education support services. WCUK will also conduct six risk mapping workshops with education stakeholders (SMCs, CECs, and EiE WG sub-national focal points), and through this process will identify the age and gender-appropriate community-based solutions to minimize threats to children&#x2019;s access to school, such as girls&#x2019; safe journeys to school. 

In order to transition TLS students to existing CBE classes or hub groups or host community hub schools, War Child will provide support to existing Community-based Education (CBE) classes/learning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abebe Jaleta</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Development Advisor</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+937228895290</telephone>
   <email>Abebej@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Eshaq Karimi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>(+93) 728 895252</telephone>
   <email>Eshaqk@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wajid Khan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93703484038</telephone>
   <email>wajidk@warchild.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hirat</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.34194400 62.20305600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-21">721761.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-21">139619.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21065">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-21">861380.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">War Child UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
