<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/21563</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livelihood Assistance to 12390 Drought-Affected Population in Waras and Yakawlang Districts of Bamyan Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 was a challenging year for the people of Afghanistan as intensified conflicts in many parts of the country during March-August trigger potential number of internal displacement, drought acted as a silent killer and further pushed the population at risks, while unstable political conditions and collapse of republic government in the hands of Taliban led to bigger economic, social and political crisis &#x2013; which have made around 90% of the population eligible for humanitarian assistance. During July-September 2021, due to intensified conflicts and associated risks, thousands of families internally displaced from Bamyan to nearby provinces or within the province to protect themselves from the brutality of Taliban that they had experienced 20 years ago. Waras and Yakawlang districts of Bamyan province, are among those district where the affected population requires immediate food assistance so they can survive the harsh winter conditions and produce food to sustain for longer terms. This can be feasible through provision of animal feed, dewormer and home gardening to ensure they can rely on better source of food to fulfill their basic needs.

The proposed project aims to deliver animal feed, dewormer and home gardening assistance to 12390 affected population in Waras and Yakawlang districts of Bamyan province. 6195  participants in Waras and 6195 in Yakawlang district of Bamyan will be targeted by considering 100% host/local communities as affected population of concern. It will be household level assistance, and WSTA will provide a livestock package to 1835 participant households which will include wheat straw, oil cake, wheat bran, dewormer aiming to support the well-being of the livestock to ensure they can overcome the ongoing drought conditions and be less subjected to diseases. WSTA will also provide a home gardening kit to 12390 participants to support their food and nutritional needs while increasing their resilience to sudden shocks. The kit includes 4 different types of vegetable and fodder seeds, and the participants will have the choice to select the types as per their preference, season, soil and climate adaptation. The kit also includes toolkit (spade, rake, hoe) . As an active member of OCTs and other coordination forums in central highland provinces including Bamyan province, WSTA will closely coordinate the assessment/beneficiary selection, distribution and other activities of the project with new government, UN agencies, INGOs, NNGOs and other stakeholders to avoid duplication in response, and to address transparency and accountability within the overall process. The cluster recommended tools will be used for data collection, analysis and reporting while we will put additional tools to collect more segregated data as per Age, Gender and Diversity (AGD) approach. We will closely work with government line departments, beneficiary representatives and other stakeholders to identify and select our distribution points in target province/districts, which shall be safe and accessible for men, women, children, elderly and persons with disability with enough facilitation in place. The COVID-19 protocols will be strictly applied throughout the implementation process to ensure safety of our staff, beneficiaries and stakeholders. Project visibility, reporting to cluster, AHF and government will be properly managed   as per the requirements of each party. We will use the services of AWAAZ Afghanistan and our internal hotline number to register the complaints, and will ensure that the target communities receive our complaint leaflets during the assessments and distribution. Our MampE and Project Control units will regularly monitor, evaluate and verify the project activities to improve the quality of our work, exercising a comprehensive lessons learned, and to address compliance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Watan`s Social and Technical services Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Watan`s Social and Technical services Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdul Zameer Fatahee</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93766727791</telephone>
   <email>fatahee@wsta.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Ishaq Sherzai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93766725314</telephone>
   <email>sherzai@wsta.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mokhtar Aria</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CBPM Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93766727785</telephone>
   <email>wsta.idp@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="10">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamyan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.90732960 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-03-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-27"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-05">346682.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21563">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-05">346682.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Watan`s Social and Technical services Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305568360">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-05-16">173341.07</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Watan`s Social and Technical services Association</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
