<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/N/NGO/20991</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to integrated Nutrition and Primary health care services to Underserve Population in Zabul Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Proposed project in Zabul is to improve nutritional status of mothers and children integrated with primary health care services including OPD consultation, ANC/PNC and RCCE for health promotion and diseases prevention.
Project will promote IYCF activities including distribution of IEC material both on HFs and community level. Key messages of IYCF will be used for the awareness and improvement.  
Through MIYCN interventions, prevention-oriented services to the PLWs whose children are in borderline in terms of their MUAC on optimal care practices. Provision of supplementary Vitamin-A to Under 5 children is also included in the plan.
Source of Nutrition Supplies: Supplementary feedings (RUSF and Super-Cereal by WFP) will be provided by WFP to U5 MAM children amp PLWs, HADAAF have confirmed with WFP at Kabul and regional level for provision of RUSFs  and  Super cereal to children and women. 
Whole population in Inaccessible areas of Shajoy, Shamalzai, Shinkey, Qalat, Arghandab, Khaki-e-Afghan, Dai-Choopan and Naw-Bahar districts, are targeted through integrated  health and nutrition approach providing  primary health care services and nutrition to PLWs and U5 Children  through establishment of 8 health and nutrition teams. As from the name, Health and Nutrition Team, beneficiaries will also include adults for PHC services whole are more than the children in the population.

To ensure early and timely detection of malnutrition, the Mother MUAC Approach and improving the quality of the screening will be strengthened. Therefore, HADAAF will Involve mothers in nutrition screening, as they are the best placed to detect the earliest signs of malnutrition and reinforces their role in protecting their child&#x2019;s health amp nutrition. HADAAF will provide the orientation sessions to female CHWs on Mother MUAC Approach. Then, they will coach the mothers on using MUAC for early detection of her child nutrition status. Also mothers and caregivers will orient on IYCF key messages and MUAC tape will be given to the mothers. This approach will help in early detection of SAM/MAM and improve the preventive measurement at HHs level. 
Nutrition counsellor will be responsible for the delivery of nutrition services (nutrition counselling, iron-folic acid supplementation, GM, management of uncomplicated SAM/MAM cases, vitamin A supplementation amp deworming. 
CNT will identify SAM/MAM case, it will refer to the nutrition counselor of MHNT. The referred child will screen and counsel the caregivers accordingly. In case of complicated SAM/MAM cases, in consultation with the MHNT doctor, the case will be referred to the nearest IPD-site. 
Eight Community Nutrition Teams, each of them composed of one female nutrition screener, one female nutrition educator and one male community mobilize. CNT will be trained on nutrition counselling package with more focus on IYCF. Each CNT will organize community gathering in the catchment area of MHNT, they will raise awareness at community level and will strengthen link between communities and MHNT. After screening of children under five and PLWs those detected with SAM and MAM will be referred to the MHNT for specialized assistance. CNT will also share key messages on IYCF and nutrition preventive measurement and its consequences with the community. Priority will be given to qualified applicants from the target communities.
Beside nutrition services, primary health care services will also be provided in MHNTs (maternal amp newborn health, child health amp immunization, treatment of communicable amp non-communicable diseases and mental health). Children affected by violence, abuse, neglect amp exploitation will be supported with prevention and response services prevention, mitigation amp response to sexual and gender-based violence will be strengthened.
Community health Shuras will establish in each SDP, made up of six members from local population. MHNTs team will regularly engage with the community health shora</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Assistance  Development Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Assistance  Development Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Shah Mohammad Rahim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director General</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93789206086</telephone>
   <email>hadaaf_af@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr.Labibullah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Technical Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+92 777606915</telephone>
   <email>labibullah@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Noorullah Safai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+92 784999192</telephone>
   <email>noorullahsafai@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zabul</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.19187820 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-25">409973.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20991">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-25">409973.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Assistance  Development Association for Afghanistan</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
