<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/ESNFI/INGO/20646</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency winterization assistance to address the winter needs of those most at risk in PD6, PD8  PD16 of Kabul.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan is entering one of its most uncertain and economically unstable periods of the last 20 years. The combination of structural poverty, rising unemployment, cyclic drought, 40 years of conflict and COVID-19 have constantly stretched the coping capacities of the Afghan population. The events of August 15 have triggered retrenchment of development assistance, an unfolding financial crisis and an unprecedented interruption of economic activities and essential services. The UN predicts that 97% of the population could fall under the poverty line (less than $2 a day) in the upcoming year. The recent Integrated Food Security Phase Classification (IPC) analysis classifies all 34 provinces IPC3+ with 9m people projected to be in IPC 4 the highest number in the world (ICCT). The majority of Afghans have already depleted their food stocks and are pursuing emergency coping mechanisms such as selling of assets, child labour, child marriage and debilitating debt. This is all as Afghanistan moves in to its harshest winter months. As families in Provinces prone to the most extreme cold temperatures, including Kabul, struggle to find where their next meal will come from, their ability to prepare for the winter months and guard themselves and their families from the harshest impacts is depleted. Persons with disability, households with high dependency ratios and pregnant and lactating women (PLW) affected by acute malnutrition are most at risk from the winter elements. Women are also disproportionately impacted by the deteriorating situation. According to surveys conducted by GiHA, 95% of women surveyed report experiencing new public restrictions on their movement, 85% report family imposed restrictions on their freedoms, 95% report knowing of a female friend or relative losing their employment or livelihood, and 79% of surveyed women report knowing a women who has had difficulties accessing health services, especially PLW. These complex, and interrelated social phenomena at a time when job opportunities are rapidly declining, cost of living increasing, and vulnerable women&apos;s ability to access the services and support they need being curtailed by others, vulnerable households and those most at risk from the harsh winter elements do not have the financial means to meet their winterization needs, despite the items required being available in local markets. In response PIN will provide immediate winterization assistance to 1,529 of the most vulnerable households (10,703 individuals) in PD6, PD8 and PD16 of Kabul through unrestricted and unconditional cash assistance for heating/fuel support (AFN equal to 200 USD), winter blankets (AFN equal to 40 USD) and family winter clothing (AFN equal to 65 USD). 1040 of these households, and current beneficiaries of PINs Kabul cash-for-food intervention, will be provided with a full or partial package of winterization assistance informed by actual need. 489 of these households, 32% of the proposed projects total caseload, will have a household member that is a pregnant and/or lactating women affected by acute-malnutrition. These 489 households will be identified by the cooperating nutrition partner whilst PIN provides a full winter assistance package to these women and their households. To meet the immediate need, PIN will provide assistance to the 1040 hh before the end of December to ensure they benefit in the fullest from the assistance. In parallel, PIN will work with the cooperating nutrition partner on the identification of PLW affected by acute malnutrition and work with them to provide the assistance in a way that responds to their specific needs, characteristics and protection requirements by the end of January. PINs choice of cash assistance will support continued market functionality, enable beneficiaries to receive assistance as soon as possible, and increase their agency in how they use it. PDM tailored to beneficiary characteristics will be administered by PINs MEAL Team</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People In Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">People In Need</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-05" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lyndsey Hand</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 729005621</telephone>
   <email>Lyndsey.Hand@peopleinneed.cz</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karolina Halirova</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial Desk Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 729006621</telephone>
   <email>karolina.Halirova@peopleinneed.cz</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="1">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kabul</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.53333300 69.16666700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-06"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-04">492855.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20646">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-04">492855.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People In Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305473294">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-17">394284.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">People In Need</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
