<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA3/APC/INGO/20265</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-based Child Protection for the most vulnerable disaster  conflict affected populations in Laghman and Kunar Provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since 2015, Tdh had been implementing several projects with AHF funding in the Eastern region of Afghanistan (Nangahar, Kunar and Laghman provinces). The needs of the population remain high and since the approaches of former projects proved to be highly effective, Tdh proposes to embark on another project for vulnerable IDPs, returnees, and conflict affected population of the provinces Laghman, and Kunar. The project intends to strengthen the resilience of these groups by reducing vulnerabilities through access to information on CP, by addressing specific needs through community delivered life-saving psycho-social services, the establishment of a case management system (protection) and by strengthening protection mechanisms through Community Based Child Protection Committees (CBCPC, consisting of influential people in the community such as teachers, religious, young age boys and girls who graduated from high school or university) and volunteers. These activities will be delivered to improve the coping mechanism of children and to detect most vulnerable children in need of further assistance. The separated and unaccompanied children will be provided with prevention and response through interim care of DolSA center in Laghman and in Asadabad center of Kunar provinces.  Once the beneficiary is identified through defined selection criteria, the payments of the assistance will reach to the beneficiaries through cash Vander envelope in their districts or a secure accessible location ( Tdh should be having risk assessments to identify the more secure area easily accessible to all beneficiary with no risks , as the project is for protection. the cash will be distributed to the beneficiaries once in the project duration and the amount is mention in the budget part of the proposal.  thus, Tdh promote not to further expose the risks to the ones already having protection concerns, Therefore, Tdh has its Safeguarding amp PSEA policies. Beside of these two policies Tdh will also consider the community based complain mechanism in the intervention area. The activities will be implemented by expert Tdh social worker and social animator in the districts mentioned below. This 12-month will be implemented in the Eastern provinces as follows: 
- In Laghman: Qarghani district (2 villages) Mahterlam district (2 villages including), Alishang district (2 villages), Alingar district (2 villages),- Kunar:  Watapoor district (2 villages)  Shegul district (2 villages), Marwara district (2 villages) and Dangam, district (2 villages)
Total 32 village will be covered during the project implementation period by Tdh expert staff.16 villages will be covered in the first phase of the project implementation and 16 village will be cover in the second phase. In total, Tdh will reach to 32 village in two phases of the project.
The data collected during the planned project activities will be shared with the clusters and OCHA regularly and, when relevant, will be shared with other partners for further support for the intervention area. The sustainability and relevancy of the proposed project will be reinforced by integrating lessons learned and impact analysis based on the assessment report. Tdh will establish child wellbeing center for the children who are at risk of violence in two provinces in the east region of the country focus most on the districts that affected by conflict and IDP present in intervention area. The child wellbeing center will be a safe place for the children to go an engage in wellbeing activities such as games and art and learning about their rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Erhard Bauer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Representative Afghanistan-Pakistan</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 93 707 154 657</telephone>
   <email>erhard.bauer@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Faisal Arozo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 93 (0) 700 29 23 34</telephone>
   <email>faisal.mohammad@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Daud Ibrahim Khail</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Protection Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799337232</telephone>
   <email>mohammed.daud@tdh.ch</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.84658930 71.09731700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="7">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laghman</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.68976870 70.14558050</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-14">429327.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-14">17173.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20265">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-14">446500.15</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305459151">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-08">267900.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Terre des hommes Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
