<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/ESNFI/NGO/20635</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency Winterization Response to conflict affected displaced and vulnerable host communities in Daikundi province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The recent shocks due to disruption of peace and long continuous conflict jolted Afghanistan in each sector, particularly in need for humanitarian assistance. Furthermore, droughts, other natural disasters, unemployment, economic crisis, and COVID-19 compounded problems for resident communities throughout Afghanistan. The large displacement of people is on and people are very uncertain about their future and security of lives. More than 400,000 people were registered as newly displaced since the beginning of May, 2021 that brings the total number of people displaced by conflict in Afghanistan in 2021 to over 550,000. By the start of 2021, the UN estimated 18.4 million people in need of humanitarian assistance in Afghanistan which is almost half of the overall Afghan population. In this critical juncture, AABRAR will save lives of 1,200 households (around 8,400 individuals) in the three targeted districts of Daykundi through cash assistance for heating/fuel and in-kind assistance by providing winterization kits (Standard Emergency Winter Clothing and Blanket Packages) as per the ESNFI Cluster standard. It is worth mentioning that all targeted 1,200 HHs will received both assistances (cash for heating/fuel and winterization kits (blankets and clothing).
The selection of the targeted populations among districts in Daykundi are based on vulnerability of the beneficiaries. Standard winterization kits (in-kind) and cash for fuel/heating will be given to households who sustained their lives through daily income and are immensely affected by COVID-19, drought and conflicts. In order to reduce suffering from winter and health conditions, AABRAR will provide winterization kits in-kind and cash for fuel/heating to the targeted population. Beneficiaries are selected based on criteria such as: female headed HHs, families with pregnant and lactating women, people with disabilities, IDPs and returnees, elderly aged HHs, HHs with large family size (having more than 7 persons or large number of female members) and chronically ill HHs. Moreover, the priorities will be given to HHs having PLWs &#x2013; in this regard based on AABRAR&#x2019;s planning, at least 32% of the targeted beneficiaries will be families with pregnant and lactating women (384 HHs in number). 
The proposed project seeks to address the needs of 1,200 HHs with a period of four months. To target most affected geographic areas suited for project interventions, AABRAR will provide winterization support in three districts (Gizab, Nili and Kiti). 400 HHs shall be targeted in each of the stated district during 4 months project implementation period.
AABRAR will contact ESNFI cluster, community and government departments to develop households&#x2019; inclusion or exclusion criteria to avoid discrepancies between actual and perceived vulnerabilities. AABRAR believes on strong coordination with stakeholders and we will work closely with ESFNI Cluster, DoRR, ANDMA, BSCs and local authorities for avoidance of the duplication in intervention. Moreover, selection of the beneficiaries for type of assistance will be assessed as per their needs through selection criteria. 
Project will continue sharing of the finalized list with communities, to validate selected HHs and to resolve conflict or issue if any. This process will facilitate support, raise awareness about the targeting process and inform community members of how to complain about and report any problems with the targeting and prioritization decisions once implemented. Project will continue developing and executing winterization kits (in-kind) and cash for heating/fuel after households&#x2019; validation by respective communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Abdul Baseer</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 (0) 775558885</telephone>
   <email>abdulbaseer@aabrar.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Najibullah Abdul Khabir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 (0) 704096252</telephone>
   <email>najib@aabrar.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Umar Habib</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093 (0) 767535514</telephone>
   <email>umarhabib@aabrar.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daykundi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.66949500 66.04635340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-14">494090.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20635">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-14">494090.69</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghan Amputee Bicyclists for Rehabilitation And Recreation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
