<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA3/APC/INGO/20083</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated GBV and Health emergency response in Nangahar and Balkh  provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project intends to provide integrated GBV and health emergency response services to women and girls in need of support through deploying 3 Mobile Teams (MTs) in Nangarhar (Dara e Noor and Momand Dara districts) and Balkh (Nahr e Shahi district). Mobile Teams will be composed of two females psychosocial counsellors, a midwife, and male and female community mobilizers. All staff will be trained in PFA and GBV Core Concepts amp Safe Referrals, whereas the psychosocial counsellors will be additionally trained in Survivor Centered GBV Case Management and Caring for Child Survivors of Sexual Assault. Mobile teams will provide services in the field 4 days per week while 1 day per week staff will come to the office for purposes of field debriefing, case supervision and staff care.
Services provided under this project will include group-based health educational sessions , individual consultations to provide basic emotional support, PFA, survivor centered case management services and referrals. Clients who require CMR services will be referred to Family Protection Centers and supported throughout the process to make sure they receive timely care of good quality. Within each session, GBV messaging will be integrated, and IEC materials will be used as per MOPH guidance and global best practices in emergencies. Due to current challenging context, adolescent girls will not be targeted for educational group-based activities. However, case management services will be provided to clients under 18 either as result of self-referral or referral through family members, Community Focal Points or other NGOs. Together with local leaders and women in WGS, IMC will work to make sure that activities are inclusive to people with disabilities, older persons, national/ethnic and religious minorities. Most of the venues where awareness raising, social activities and individual services are provided are on ground floor and easily accessible to people using wheelchair or older persons. Furthermore, these groups of citizens who are at risk of social exclusion will be provided with space and encouraged during activities to voice their concerns, needs but also ideas about social, economic and cultural inclusion. 
Mobile teams will target multiple locations/villages within a given district where spaces/houses for ad hoc community based centers are selected. Locations will be visited once per week on a rotation basis, coordinating a prior appointment through Community Focal Points. 8-week long program of educational sessions around health and dignity kits distribution will be used as entry points to identify survivors or individuals at risk of GBV and provide care and support. After 8 weeks, new locations within selected districts will be identified and the program will be rolled out. A total of 5 rounds of 8-week long project cycles will be organized over the course of 10 months . In each round, 12 community-based spaces will be managed by 3 Mobile Teams and serve as temporary service delivery points. In total 60 spaces will be managed throughout the project lifetime. 
At the community level, IMC&#x2019;s trained Community Focal Points will regularly provide information about the availability of services through this project and at health facilities in the area. Community Focal Points will liaise directly with existing community health workers and health Shuras to further encourage community participation and engagement in project activities. Community Focal Points will also be able to refer GBV cases to IMC&#x2019;s teams for further support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-19" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-18" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ehsanallah Shafaq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93708269568</telephone>
   <email>eshafaq@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Matthew Stearns</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799737954</telephone>
   <email>mstearns@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Shamail Azimi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country /Program Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93798809020</telephone>
   <email>sazimi@InternationalMedicalCorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balkh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.89091580 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="6">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nangarhar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.17183130 70.62167940</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-12-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-12">9195.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-18"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-12">269740.61</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20083">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-01-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-12">278936.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Medical Corps UK</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
