<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/20748</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of food assistance to food insecure and vulnerable households in Charbolak and Chemtal districts of Balkh province.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan is facing severe emergency due to the impacts of the recent political transition, the socio-economic impacts of the Covid-19 and also climate changes. The prices are going up day by day and income for people are decreasing, thus the food security of the households is negatively affected. A total of 22.8 million people in Afghanistan are projected to face high levels of acute food insecurity (IPC phase 3 or above) during November 2021 to March 2022 compared to 18.8 million during the previous period of September-October 2021. 

During the previous season 25 out of the 34 provinces of Afghanistan were affected by severe drought and it is anticipated that precipitation below average over the next winter season could continue to negatively impact food production and food access in the rain-fed agriculture zones in 2022. Increased conflicts during the 3rd quarter of the 2021 has caused displacement and has disrupted the livelihoods system. 

The finding of an assessment conducted in November 2021, shows that the average FCS score in Charbloak district is 21 while it is 22 in Chemtal district both falling in the poor category of FCS. In line with HRP 2021 strategic objective 1 (Save lives in areas of highest needs) and FSAC priorities, through this project, HIHAO will provide unconditional and unrestricted cash assistance to 1,830 households (12,810 individuals) who are in the IPC phase 3 and 4 as per the November 2021 &#x2013; March 2022 IPC acute food insecurity analysis to procure food baskets. The project will be implemented in Charbolak and Chemtal districts of Balkh province over five months. In Charbolak district 6,650 individuals (950 HHs) will receive cash for provision of food and in Chemtal 6,160 individuals (880 HHs) will received support. The total amount of cash to be assisted is US$ 329,400 funded by OCHA/AHF. Each household with an average of seven members will receive an amount of equivalent to US$ 90 per month for two months in Afghan currency. It is based on the cluster standard for food basket which is calculated considering the recent market price data to provide 2,100Kcal per person per day. In order to mobilize and select eligible households, HIHAO will conduct a baseline assessment to determine the Food Consumption Score (FCS) of the households and those with the minimum score will be selected in the project

Cash assistance has been envisaged as unconditional and unrestricted. The decision has been based on findings of a needs assessment conducted during November in both Charbolak and chemtal districts identifying that food is the priority need. Moreover, cash has been identified by 72% of respondents as the preferred assistance modality and markets have been identified as accessible and safe. The findings of the market assessment conducted by HIHAO indicates that market in both Charboak and Chemtal are accessible by both men and women and  food items are available in the district market in sufficient quantities. Considering the current status of financial institutions and the limitations they are facing in terms of cash transfers and withdrawals, cash assistance will be carried out through the Hawala system, identified as the most viable and widely spread solution. HIHAO is also considering the alternative in-kind provision of food baskets in case any challenges arise for transfer of funds to the target participants which will be discusses with AHF and FSAC before any action is taken.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hand in Hand Afghanistan Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hand in Hand Afghanistan Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sama Sahari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief Finance Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799330186</telephone>
   <email>cfo@handinhand.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahmad Kamran Hekmati</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Chief Executive Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 799108196</telephone>
   <email>khekmati@handinhand.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balkh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.89091580 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">445290.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20748">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">445290.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hand in Hand Afghanistan Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305459169">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-08">222645.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hand in Hand Afghanistan Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305632007">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-16">222645.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hand in Hand Afghanistan Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
