<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/NGO/20855</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Food Security Project through Cash for Food Activities in two districts of Wardak Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan has been going through one of the hardest catastrophes in its history. Droughts, collapse of Afghanistan government by Taliban, and freezing Afghanistan&#x2019;s asset by the U.S have hit the Afghan population hard. According to a report of UNDP stating &#x201C;According to the appraisal, this combination of factors could cause the baseline poverty rate, now at 72 percent &#x201C; and as well as  this report expresses that 97 percent of the population is at risk of sinking below the poverty line.  Likewise, The IPC has also highlighted the unprecedented food insecurity crisis in Afghanistan. Recent IPC report has stated, &#x201C;Afghanistan&#x2019;s food crisis reaches unprecedented levels as nearly 19 million people are highly food insecure due to prolonged drought, conflict and economic collapse.&#x201D; This report has further highlighted that 55% of the population has faced acute level of food insecurity. Economic decline, conflict, and drought has been the major drivers of this crisis. These driving factors have affected the population of Wardak province too indicates that the Wardak province is in the IPC-phase4.In reference to the 2021 AHF 1st Standard Allocation and to the HRP 2021 Strategic Objective 1 (SO1): Lives are saved in the areas of highest need, STARS will target two districts- Jaghatoo and Dai Mirdad of Wardak province, which suffered more due to severe drought and disasters, with a particular target group of those families headed by women or disabled citizens.

The proposed project will directly benefit 1,842 households, of which 12894 direct beneficiaries will be reached out. STARS will undertake a rapid household survey on community level to identify the target households. 

STARS will provide food assistance in form of cash to cover food needs of most vulnerable and affected food insecure households in the target area through cash transfer modality. The proposed project will cover 12,894 individuals, 7,926 in Jaghatoo and 4,868 individuals in Day Mirdad districts. The beneficiary&#x2019;s breakdown has been calculated based on the provincial statistics and households&#x2019; data. The assistance will be distributed in two rounds, where each household will receive 90 USD full food package twice. This assistance will help the IPC Phase 4 located households secure their minimum food security packages for at least three months. STARS presence in Wardak Province has been for so long. Based on World Bank report &quot; Prices for basic household goods, including food and fuel, increased substantially&quot;. Our information from the local market indicates that local markets are functional across the provinces, food items are available in local markets and the report of World Bank for prices increase is the ground fact. therefore, the food assistance in form of cash is the most appropriate model in emergency situations. The cash assistance is preferred because it will bring the local markets into motion and will purchase those food items that they really need. Immediate cash transfer is monetary assistance and will be in form of physical cash to targeted households that enables direct access to food from marketplace. Beneficiaries will receive life-saving assistance in form of cash in twice, as there is a risk of purchasing other items if distributed in one distribution. 

STARS will be distributing the cash for food in two rounds. In each round 90USD will be given to every household, STARS will use HAWALA system as Banking system imposed limitations. A spot-check at the end of survey for identification of beneficiaries will be conducted to ensure accountability and transparency. STARS monitoring team will be present in the sites while the cash is distributed. STARS will encourage the target households to purchase their food items in the local markets to ensure the market in local areas is boosted.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Training And Rehabilitation Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Training And Rehabilitation Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdul Wahab Hemat</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Snr. Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093728328328</telephone>
   <email>wahab.hemat@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="4">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wardak</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.35134940 68.23853390</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-08-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">440000.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20855">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">440000.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Training And Rehabilitation Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305540128">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-28">220000.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Training And Rehabilitation Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
