<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/RA2/ESNFI/INGO/18701</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing the urgent humanitarian life-saving ESNFI needs of the shock affected people (conflict and natural disaster) in Faryab in line with the Spring Disaster Contingency Plan.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan still remains one of the world&#x2019;s most complex humanitarian emergencies, driven by escalating conflict and natural disasters. Given the past trends and indications of intensifying conflict, half of this year&#x2019;s projected conflict-related internal displacement (250,000 people) is anticipated to take place between March and June due to escalating conflict. These people will require NFI and shelter support. Over 230,000 undocumented migrants and refugee returnees are expected to cross back into Afghanistan and will require humanitarian assistance. The risk of additional drought-driven displacement remains high, and will depend on the severity of weather-induced conditions. More than 120,000 people are anticipated to be affected by spring storms and flash-floods, resulting in damage to shelters and livelihoods, and posing risk to life.    

The project is designed to support the needs of IDPs and vulnerable host communities affected by conflicts and natural disasters in the target districts (Maimana, Pashtoon Kot and Almar) of Faryab province. According to averaged Household Emergency Assessment Tool (HEAT) assessments in 2020, 64% of immediately shock-affected households reported living in makeshift shelters (including both mud houses and tents). DAARTT need assessment further revealed that 66% of the people were displaced, due to conflicts, 14% due to natural disaster and 20% were returnees from Iran and Pakistan. Moreover, 41% of the houses are partially destroyed, 27% are fully destroyed and 32% are unharmed.

In line with ES/NFI Cluster priorities as detailed in the Allocation Strategy paper, DAARTT under this action will respond to the needs identified under the AHF 2nd 2021 Reserve Allocation strategy with the purpose to provide life-saving assistance to IDPs, returnees and vulnerable host communities in the priority provinces Faryab, identified by the ES/NFI Cluster. Under this action, DAARTT will cover the needs of 3212 families (22484 individuals) in the three districts (Maimana, Pashtoon Kot and Almar) districts of Faryab Province through provision of Complete NFI packages (2800 families) @USD 105 and cash for rent @USD 75 * 3 months (412 families) for displaced and natural disaster affected households. DAARTT through its other emergency/humanitarian funded project supported by Danish People Aid (DPA) will assist a total of 285 families (1995 individuals) through provision of Cash for Rent @USD 225. These 285 families will be supported in Pakhtoon Kot district of Faryab Province

A beneficiary selection and distribution committee will be established which will include representatives from local communities (e.g. CDC heads), Government departments (e.g. ANDMA, ARCS and DoRR) and DAARTT staff. Beneficiaries will be selected according to ESNFI vulnerability criteria to ensure the poorest and most vulnerable are targeted, including displaced people, women-headed households, widows, orphaned families, elderly, people with a disability and families with a large number of dependent children. The cash for rent will enable selected HHs to improve their immediate living conditions either through rental assistance which is also following the CERF allocation providing life-saving shelter assistance to people affected by conflict, drought and COVID-19 in the target areas of Faryab Province. Cash is used as markets (incl. rental market) are functional and materials are locally available. Prioritization is based on vulnerability and need for assistance. As there is a large percentage of HH with vulnerable groups/ PSN, DAARTT will ensure inclusion of these groups in the assistance through an inclusive approach securing their meaningful participation. As per DAARTT standards, gender, protection and COVID-19 are mainstreamed</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Assistance to Afghan Rehabilitation and Technical Training</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Assistance to Afghan Rehabilitation and Technical Training</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mir Aabed Sadat</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chief of Finance and Administration</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93777657708</telephone>
   <email>CFO@daartt.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Salim Kohi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 791 91 0563</telephone>
   <email>Humanitarian.coordinator@daartt.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lars Pedersen (Mr.)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93 (0) 752004414</telephone>
   <email>director@daartt.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="28">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Faryab</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.07956130 64.90595500</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">339206.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">136381.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-18701">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-06">475588.23</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Assistance to Afghan Rehabilitation and Technical Training</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305104161">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-16">237794.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Assistance to Afghan Rehabilitation and Technical Training</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
