<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/ESNFI/UN/21388</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Distribution of cash for construction of transitional shelter and shelter repair to conflict, natural disaster affected/displaced and vulnerable families in Badghis and Kunduz provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To save lives in the areas of highest needs, in line with the Emergency Shelter/Non-Food Item (ES/NFI) Cluster&#x2019;s 2022 strategy and projected need under HRP, IOM proposes the distribution of Cash for transitional shelter and shelter repair to internally displaced persons (IDPs), natural disaster affected/displaced and other vulnerable groups in Badghis and Kunduz provinces. The cash assistance will be distributed in installments of the amount needed by a family of 7 as per ES/NFI Cluster standards and per the customized BoQ to cover shelter construction and shelter repair needs of targeted families. 
IOM will be targeting 2,268 families for construction of transitional shelter and shelter repair. Cash will be provided in 3 installments for transitional shelter and two for shelter repair, following progress of the construction work agreed through MoU with the beneficiary.   

Cash for Transitional Shelter: 350 families will be targeted under this component (326 families = 1,472 USD) that will be disbursed to beneficiaries&apos; conditional completion of a set percentage of construction work agreed with the beneficiary through an MoU and in line with the project set criteria. 
	Badghis: Transitional Shelter Construction support for 326 households affected by Earthquake
	Kunduz: Transitional Shelter Construction support for 24 households affected by natural disasters and conflict or displaced.

Cash for Shelter Repair (Cat B-Major Repairs): 1,314 families will be targeted under this component. 490 USD each will be disbursed to the beneficiaries conditional to completing set percentage of construction work agreed with the beneficiary through an MoU and in line with the project set criteria
	Badghis: Shelter repair/upgrade to 750 households in need of major shelter repairs to households affected by Earthquake
	Kunduz: Shelter repair/upgrade to 564 households in need of major shelter repairs due to natural disaster or conflict

Cash for Shelter Repair (Cat C-Minor Repairs): 480 families will be targeted under this component (480 families = 300 USD each) that will be disbursed to the beneficiary&#x2019;s conditional to completing set percentage of construction work agreed with the beneficiary through an MoU and in line with the project set criteria. 
	Badghis: Shelter repair/upgrade to 300 households in need of minor shelter repairs to households affected by Natural disaster (Earthquake)
	Kunduz: Shelter repair/upgrade to 180 households in need of minor shelter repairs due to natural disaster or conflict
IOM has established long term agreements (LTAs) with financial service providers and has also used the services of banks for disbursement of cash to beneficiaries. All modalities are undertaken in line with IOM Humanitarian Assistance Programme&#x2019;s (HAP) Cash Based Intervention (CBI) SOP and the guidance of the Cash amp Voucher Working Group. 

The proposed intervention will target Badghis province (Qadis, Qala-e-Naw, Muqur) and Kunduz province (Khan Abad). Beneficiaries will be reached through multiple, complementary methodologies including: (i) referrals from IOM HAP teams (ii) upcoming Joint Assessment Team (JAT) assessments led by IOM assisting recent conflict and natural disaster affected populations (iii) complimentary assistance of NFIs, emergency shelter and shelter repair tool kits subject to availability of stocks that are funded by other donors and depending on the needs of the families, backed by HEAT assessment data (iv) IOM field staff conducting house-by-house survey using Kobo tools for data collection (v) referrals from IOM Cross Border Reintegration program (vi) Particular efforts will be made to cover and tailored to the needs of most vulnerable families vii recent assessment conducted through Multi-Sector Rapid Assessment Form (MSRAF) and Shelter technical assessment by joint assessment teams in Badghis. Eligibility criteria will be set as per ES-NFI Cluster strategy and AHF guidelines and requirement</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">David Mavengere</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Resource Management Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251929001380</telephone>
   <email>dmavengere@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Fahim Safie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Program Assistant</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93791730172</telephone>
   <email>fsafie@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Susan Price</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93794795117</telephone>
   <email>sprice@iom.int</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="29">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Badghis</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.16713390 63.76953840</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kunduz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.85993070 68.71549750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-03">1938500.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21388">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-03">1938500.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="FTR_AFG_2022_1000113">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-04-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-04-06">1938500.03</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Organization for Migration</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
