<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/FSAC/INGO/20618</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency agricultural support to vulnerable households in Daykundi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The central highland provinces of Afghanistan, especially, Daykundi continue to face the negative impacts of insecurity, natural disasters, and economic shocks.

According to recent IPC report, the shortfall expected in the winter season will further affect the farmers and inputs&#x2019; prices are expected to increase further. Apart from this, the closure of health facilities will impact the food security situation of the province. As a result, the overall food security will further deteriorate in the province and it&apos;ll remain in phase-4. Hence, Daykundi province require emergency assistance to cope with overlapping challenges including a potential La Ni&#xF1;a-driven drought. Based on a range of weighted indicators, the province has been classified with a high level of risk of drought among the 25 most affected provinces in Afghanistan with 65% of the population projected to be in IPC 3+ during the period November 2021 March 2022.

Thus, provision of certified wheat seeds, fertilizers and vegetable seeds to households in Daykundi, will support the farmers&#x2019; livelihoods and allow them to increase their agricultural yields in the coming cultivation season. Therefore, Afghanaid proposes to support 1000HHs (7,000 individuals) in Shahristan, 1,167HHs (8,169 individuals) in Miramor, 1,000 HHs (7,000 individuals) in Ishtarlay and 1,166 HHs (8,162 individuals) in Khedir with in-kind agriculture assistance for the spring season cultivation accordingly. 

The provision of agricultural inputs to 4,333 vulnerable smallholder farmers in Daykundi will alleviate food insecurity and increase the farmers&#x2019; income from sustainable agricultural production through these inputs for season to improve productivity and households&#x2019; income. The project is aligned with the AHF 3rd reserves allocation strategy, which indicates that the impact of natural disasters has affected an estimated 13 million people in Afghanistan, with Daykundi being in the five most severely affected provinces. It contributes to the Strategic Objectives 1 and 3 and will assist vulnerable households to ensure no regression from IPC 3 to IPC 4.
The proposed project will target 4,333 vulnerable smallholder farmers (30,331 individuals) with including female headed households living in the targeted area. The seed and fertilizers will be procured and provided by FAO and Afghanaid will distribute to the target households. The present response priorities are in line with past experience and capability and represents a scale up of relief and winterization emergency activities in the target area. 
Afghanaid is well placed to implement this project, we have operations in all target districts and excellent access and strong relationships with communities as well as district and provincial authorities. Afghanaid has extensive experience in humanitarian programming, with current and recent humanitarian assistance projects in multiple provinces including Daykundi, funded by AHF and FAO. These projects include emergency livelihoods, winterization, and shelter assistance responses, using both in-kind and cash modalities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Najibullah Namiq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants and Partnership Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+93799733944</telephone>
   <email>najeebullah@afghanaid.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daykundi</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.66949500 66.04635340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-11"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">182014.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-20618">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-17">182014.78</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305471656">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-16">145611.82</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFGHANAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
