<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG-21/3481/SA1/WASH/NGO/21008</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH Assistance for Drought and Conflicted Affected IDPs and Non-displaced Population and Host Communities in Balkh and Baghlan Provinces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of AHF 1st Standard Allocation Strategy, two-thirds of the country are currently in a critical/catastrophic situation for water scarcity with high demand for clean water and hygiene. There is also high risk of deteriorating hygiene and sanitation conditions resulting in sharp increase in malnutrition and diseases such as cholera, particularly in urban areas and informal settlements
The Cluster plans to expand water provision through deepening and rehabilitation of hand-dug wells and boreholes, repair and set-up of hand-pumps, rehabilitation of solar, gravity and mixed water systems. Water trucking will be carried out as a last resort. These activities will be delivered in 14 priority provinces identified with acute WASH needs. The Cluster will further provide hygiene kits, water kits and bath and latrine sets to new IDPs in areas of displacement
Considering the criticality of the WASH situation ADEO recently conducted a rapid assessment and focus group discussion and to observe the living condition of vulnerable Households who are conflict and drought affected communities and IDPs, the assessment conducted in 6 districts of Balkh and Baghlan province, totally 117 HHs assessed as sample and 18 Focus Group Discussions has been conducted
The assessment finding shows, that situation of WASH needs further worsens since beginning 2021, specifically in the remote and hard-to-reach areas of the targeted districts, many communities are in dire needs of WASH services, they do not have enough water for drinking, their existing water supplies either damaged or dried, hygiene is also a challenge, people do no observe hygiene practice due to poor hygiene education
So, to take the priority gaps and needs into account, through this intervention ADEO will construct 30 boreholes fitted with hand pumps and rehabilitate and improve 120 destroyed/damaged hand pumps boreholes/dug wells in (Keshende, Zari and Sholgara) districts of Balkh and (Dahana-e-Ghori, Baghlan-e-Jadid and Burka) districts of Baghlan provinces, for providing safe water for drinking, washing and personal hygiene for totally 3750 HH (26250 Individual, Men 5250, Women 5250, Boy 7875 amp Girl 7875)
Each water point well will cover maximum 25 HH (175 persons) with a flow rate of 7.5 liters per minute. The range of water table is different from one location to another and the estimated average water table is around 40 meters, which the wells in this project area will be deepening average of 60 meters. In Balkh districts (Keshendeh, Zari and Sholgara) the water table is a bit shallow up to 30 meters. In the Baghlan districts (Dahan-e-Ghori, Baghlan-e-Jadid and Burka) the water table is deeper between 32 to 52 meters. From the WASH national guide, the water column should not be less than 10 meters. Due to droughts, the water table is going down and down, thus the project estimated water should be more than 10 meters
Similarly, to response to dire needs of drought affected and potential AWD affected population often have limited or no access to safe sources of water. ADEO as a last resort, where other interventions are not feasible in some communities, will provide safe water through trucking, to ensure lives are saved and dignity of affected populations is restored
Furthermore, ADEO will conduct Hygiene Education Session for 3750 family and will distribute hygiene kits as per the standard of WASH Cluster to 3750 families
During Hygiene Education sessions, ADEO will mainstream COVID-19 risk communication and awareness messaging and materials, including COVID-19 Kits and Hygiene promotion as well as gender-sensitive behavioral change messaging to positively influence expenditure choices and coping strategies. Since the Hygiene Education is conducted in an enclosed space, ADEO will limit the number of participant per session and will provide masks to participants as well as Hygiene promoters and also sanitizers will be procured for use by participants and staff during the session</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Development and Education Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Development and Education Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Noorullhaq</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093799448182</telephone>
   <email>finance.adeo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sayyed Abdul Tawab</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Managing Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093708602222</telephone>
   <email>naqshbandy@adeo.org.af</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammad Nasim</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0093794002515</telephone>
   <email>program.adeo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baghlan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.80429470 69.28775350</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Balkh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.89091580 67.18944880</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-15">494216.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="AFG23-21008">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-15">494216.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Development and Education Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305459148">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-08">247108.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan Development and Education Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Afghanistan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-AFG23-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
