<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>PK-SEC-0080655-dkt-pk-001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="PK-SEC-0080655" secondary-reporter="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DKT Pakistan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delivering Accelerated Family Planning in Pakistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROJECT NAME : Delivering Accelerated Family Planning in Pakistan (DAFPAK). PROJECT LOCATION : Baluchistan, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa &amp; Punjab. ORGANIZATION : DKT International. POINT OF CONTACT : Dawar M. Waraich, Country Director. 3rd Floor, RJ Building, Plot 37-C, 2nd Stadium lane, Stadium Commercial Area, Phase 5, DHA, Karachi. T: +92.21.38651019, E: dawar@dktinternational.org. ACCOUNTABLE GRANT COST : GBP 15,100,000. ACCOUNTABLE GRANT DURATION : December 01, 2017 &#x2013; March 31, 2022. DFID Pakistan has been investing in FP services delivered through the private sector since 2012. DAFPAK is the latest investment of the British people to support Pakistan by delivering accelerated family planning, improving choice, access and cost. With DAFPAK, DFID has become Pakistan&#x2019;s largest donor for family planning. This continuous support from DFID enables the private sector to reach and serve the rural population, leaving no-one behind. DKT with its strong presence in Baluchistan and KPK, is able to effectively balance equity with increased access to family planning products and services through its social marketing and social franchising model, across Pakistan. Key DKT Deliverables under DAFPAK are as follows: DELIVERABLES: &#x25CF; Delivering 2,658,382 CYPs during the project period &#x25CF; To serve 643,894 family planning users &#x25CF; Meet 85% quality standards across 80% of the DHANAK clinics &#x25CF; Increase social marketing outlets from 7,610 to 12,205. FIRST YEAR RESULTS : During the first-year of DAFPAK (Dec 2017 &#x2013; Jun 2018), DKT interventions successfully exceeded its deliverables and offered higher value for money than planned. Key achievements / milestones for the period are as follows: OUTCOMES: &#x25CF; Maternal Deaths Averted 117% for the quarter and 119% for project to date &#x25CF; Unintended Pregnancies averted 116% for the quarter and 109% for project to date &#x25CF; Unsafe Abortions Averted 116% for the quarter and 109% for project to date &#x25CF; DALYs Averted 116% for the quarter and 109% for project to date &#x25CF; CYPs Generated 127% for project to date &#x25CF; Total Family Planning Users 259% for project to date. VALUE FOR MONEY: &#x25CF; Delivered 38% more value for money by achieving a cost per CYP of GBP 5.11 against the target of GBP 8.27 per CYP.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-IATI-SECP-0080655" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DKT International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The DAFPAK project started on Dec 01, 2017</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="US" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DKT International</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="13030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Family planning program across Baluchistan, KPK and Punjab</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
