<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-17/DDA-3558/Aleppo SA 2017/WASH-S/NFI/INGO/4566</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH and Shelter NFI Assistance for Crisis affected Women, Men Boys and Girls in Aleppo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to provide critically needed humanitarian emergency WASH and Shelter assistance in Aleppo City for 3800 women, men,boys and girl. It is focusing especially upon Hanano, Old City, Khaldyah, Sheikh Maqsoud, Ashrafieh, Salah al Dien, Seif al Dwala and Alhamdanya. Oxfam&#x2019;s current response in these districts supports a range of beneficiary groups including IDP&#x2019;s, IDPs who are returning home, and those who remained and have not been displaced. Amongst those populations focus is maintained on women headed households, households with disabled members, and families of those wounded or with detainees. However, Oxfam commits to target locations as per WASH and Shelter Sector guidlines and recommendations given the dynamic changes due to conflict o ground. 
Oxfam will conduct a WASH needs assessment, analysing risk behaviours, hardware needs and community capacity to manage projects in the prioritised locations. Again this will include the identification of vulnerable groups such as women and girls and people with disabilities. Oxfam intends to rehabilitate household shelters moderate and slightly damaged apartments for 1750 beneficiaries housing the most in need providing winterization assistance and shelter rehabilitation (construction, finishing, electrical, water and sanitation, maintenance works, and building shared component), with support to beneficiaries to operate and maintain the provided hardware and reduce their risk of WASH related disease. This also includes emergency rehabilitation to windows and doors to ensure protection against extreme weather conditions and security challenges, minimum lighting to improve safety, and rehabilitation of water and sanitation installations based on need to reach at least national minimum standards, such as family water tanks, latrines, sewage systems and dustbins. Due to the current critical situation in which water supply from the Euphrates River has been cut off to Aleppo, alternative water sources are These pre-selected projects will now be evaluated based on criteria to assess the humanitarian needs, high risk / vulnerable groups, resources and feasibility. The current pre-selected projects are dig, equip and connect to the network, wells in some of essential for ensuring access. Oxfam seeks to rehabilitate 14 wells in Aleppo and Rural Aleppo reaching an expected 32000 women, men, boys and girls, choosing to focus upon contingency wells and will coordinate with WASH actors to avoid the dried-drill well as much as possible. This seems the only alternative plan in case Al.Khafseh station continues to be non-operational as it is now.  The Aleppo Water Establishment had presented a list of prioritized water infrastructure projects that they need funding for, and Oxfam had pre-selected particular well projects from this list. These locations Aleppo Eza&apos;a, Zebdie, Salah Aldin, Sukari. Martini, Merdian, Hariri,Bab Alnerab,West Zahraa or Aasal forest Average Depth of 200 meters.  The scope will include drilling, electrical, mechanical and civil works. Oxfam additionally will work to promote hygiene through the identification of Community Resource Persons (CRPs), responsible for the engagement and awareness raising among their peers, and WASH committees in targeted collective shelters. This will be implemented through capacity building workshops, coaching in the field (where access is permitted) of CRPs, WASH Committees and key community members, providing targeted hygiene promotion awareness activities / campaigns with key beneficiary groups, and provision and distribution of hygiene materials for men, women, boys and girls based on need.
Oxfam in this project will adhere to Sector recommendations and findings in regards to needs assessments and any other coordination event or reporting format. Working with other humanitarian actors is a core principle for all Oxfam programmes, and therefore will pursue collaboration and coordination through out this project life-cy</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hanan Shafai</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00963958001287</telephone>
   <email>hshafai@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moutaz Adham</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00963958001272</telephone>
   <email>madham@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="49" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="51" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-16">414948.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-16">656701.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-16">328350.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-4566">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-16">1400000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302670290">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-22">1120000.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304028454">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-06">280000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
