<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-17/DDA-3558/Aleppo SA 2017/ERL/UN/4648</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restoration of disrupted livelihoods of affected residents and displaced people including returnees in East Aleppo through rehabilitation of basic services and revival of local businesses and affected vocational workshops.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP will use its Area-based Comprehensive Approach to continue addressing the basic needs of affected residents and displaced people including returnees in East Aleppo through targeted interventions. Severity scale and conflict analysis cohesion programming. It is a Context-driven activity process and analysis driven, interactive process to approach will be used to guide the implementation of the project activities building on UNDP experience and ongoing work in Aleppo since 2012. This proposal therefore, aims at enhancing the resilience and restoration of disrupted livelihoods of affected people in Al Kallaseh, Bustan Al Qaser, and Al Sha&#x2019;ar  neighborhoods in East Aleppo through three key interventions will take place: 
-	Supporting the emergency rehabilitation of basic services including provision of solar lighting and solid waste management as well as rubble removal to ensure an enabling environment is created. Emergency jobs will be created through volunteers from the target community to be recruited to implement the project activities. considering that Solid Waste and debris activities have been developed from collection and removal to management (crushing, composting, fuel briquettes, biogas, landfills upgrading), In general, a percentage of 15-20% of the collected Solid waste and debris can be sorted or crushed then recycled. The rest is removed to landfills.
-	Reviving of micro business and provide socio-economic support and rehabilitation of vocational workshops in target areas through provision of vocational training and toolkits and productive assets to target communities to create Jobs for people living in, or returning to, the target areas including IDPs from other neighborhoods in East Aleppo. Through SHF fund, UNDP will support more than 92 workshops which are related to reconstruction (96,8 % of total workshops supported), three other productive workshops were also supported through this project, the first is production of cotton underwear and clothing workshop project, and the second production of jeans clothing workshop project, and the third is production of pastries and food items workshop project. these three projects will be implemented in Al-Kallaseh area which is an trading and residential area that accommodates large number of affected people and returnees, part of them joined existing UNDP supported productive workshops in West Aleppo due to their urgent needs for income generating activities, therefore the area is in huge need for such projects to support livelihood and income generating activities especially for youth and FHH. at the same time the sustainability is a key success factor, therefore, several points considered in order to ensure the sustainability, such as most of the workshops ideas are taken from the owner of the affected workshops whom have the experience to operate such workshops  (please refer to the complementarity paragraph in the background page).
-	Capacity Development of national and local CSOs for community resilience and social cohesion by developing the capacities of NGOs/CBOs to engage in emergency responses with particular focus on livelihoods and early recovery initiatives and promote social cohesion and reconciliation through community based activities. Local NGOs and CBOs members will be equipped with specialized skills, youth and civil society will be engaged to promote for social cohesion and the culture of tolerance and acceptance between host communities, Returnees and IDPs to reduce levels of tensions and local conflict. Given the uncertainty of Syria&apos;s conflict environment, UNDP adopted a flexible and responsive approach to social</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akiko Suzaki</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+963-958880103</telephone>
   <email>Akiko.suzaki@undp.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Recovery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-31">972565.23</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-07-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-31">963433.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-4648">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-31">1935998.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302705818">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-09">1935998.39</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400220538">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-20">2685.16</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
