<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR-17/DDA-3558/Aleppo SA 2017/E-P/INGO/4647</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing  equitable access to education and psycho-social support for conflict-affected Syrian children and adolescents in east Aleppo through school rehabilitation and child protection</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The protracted nature of the Syrian crisis has affected the capacity of the educational structure system to address extremely critical needs of its population. Children and adolescents are in an out of school for more than five years the educational facilities still suffer several damages and being attacked and the MoE has lost an important human labor. 
According with SIF assessment (November - December 2016) conducted in several governorates, Aleppo has developed serious protection concerns among the population living in this governorate. SIF assessment indicates that Aleppo has serious protection concerns for all population groups. Interviewed key informants reported the increased number of unaccompanied children and the lack of protection in their communities. Children under 18 reported to had been forced to leave the schools mainly for three common reasons:  to search for a work or for the unavailability of schools near to their place of accommodation or the inability of families to afford the costs of stationary.
According to focus group discussions (FGDs), many of these children had been out of school since becoming displaced over years ago. These children risk falling significantly behind in their education and struggling to restart their education in the future. For these children, both key informants and households reported that poverty, failure of the educational system and unsafe access to school were the most commonly reported causes. 
The project aims at provide functioning schools and protective learning environment in east Aleppo for returnees. To achieve this goal, SIF is planning to: rehabilitate two public schools in Sayf Ad-Dauleh neighborhood in east Aleppo and, assure child protection and social support system through the establishment of 1 Child Friendly Space in each school. The planned rehabilitation activities will consist of providing the damaged schools with doors, windows, repairing or reconstructing internal and external walls, internal electrical networks, repairing holes in walls and slabs, repairing damages of stairs and courtyards, all needed works for  water supply and sewage networks, sanitation facilities (sink, taps, toilets....etc) in addition to constructing new toilet blocks as needed. All of the mentioned works will be implemented in accordance with the Minim Standards for Child Protection in Humanitarian Action in order to provide safe access to quality education for children.  
At the same time, the intervention has a protection mainstream approach combined with a component of livelihoods since the selection of volunteers for the CFSs will involve the families of the children benefiting from these CFSs. CFS will provide help and support to the children and adolescents who are physically, psychologically, and socially affected by the crisis. 
Children with special needs and disabilities will be assisted through case management and referral to specialized services. Recreational activities will be scheduled by age and gender in order to have harmony within genders especially for girls and women that have suffered from any type of harassment. 
40 recreational activities per month per CFS will be delivered maximum of 30 children in each session will be present and 4 volunteers will be running the session. 
In addition to the planned activities for children, the CFS with host families of those children after school hours at awareness sessions and focus group discussions in order for those families to be as involved as possible in the process of addressing their children&#x2019;s needs. The families can participate in providing topics and ideas that can be incorporated within the design of the activities inside the CFS.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alba Lopez Suarez</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programmes</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0950033305</telephone>
   <email>progco.syria@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="80" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="20" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-28">243877.63</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-28">149924.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6304542017">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-29">17516.86</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SYR62-4647">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-28">393802.41</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302642203-07">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-10">315041.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="KH-3103108458">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-29">78760.48</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Secours Islamique France</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SYR62-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
