<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7429</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Patos Marinza</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Albania-Patos Marinza            Region    Europe        Sector       Project No007429   Projected Board DateMarch 31, 1998   Company NameAnglo Albanian Petroleum Limited    Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The Project will be carried out through an Unincorporated Joint Venture (UJV), among Albpetrol - 42.5%, Premier Consolidated Oilfields Finance B.V. (Premier), a subsidiary of Premier Oil Plc - 25%, Preussag Energie GmbH (Preussag) - 17.5% and IFC - 15% (collectively, the Joint Venture Partners).  Albpetrol is the state oil company of Albania.  Premier Oil Plc, of the United Kingdom, is an independent, publicly traded company involved in the exploration and production of oil and natural gas internationally.  Preussag, of Germany, is involved in the exploration, production and distribution of oil and natural gas internationally.    Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    	The Project will be implemented by Anglo Albanian Petroleum Limited (AAP), a company owned by the Joint Venture Partners, at an estimated cost of US$257 million over six years.  IFC is to provide loans of approximately US$80 million to AAP, of which approximately US$50 million will be for the account of participants, and will invest approximately US$24 million in equity to acquire a 15% participating interest in the Project and to fund its share of Project cost.    Location of Project and Description of Site    	The Patos Marinza oil field is located 10 km east of the city of Fier in South Central Albania.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The Project involves the implementation of an enhanced oil recovery (EOR) scheme for the rehabilitation of part of the Patos Marinza oil field (Patos) including: the rehabilitation/stimulation of existing wells, drilling new wells, and construction of processing facilities and an approximately 22.5 km onshore export pipeline (the Export Pipeline) together with an offshore marine loading facility.  It is expected to result in an incremental peak production of about 19,000 barrels per day and the recovery up to 66 million barrels of crude oil.    	This would represent IFCs first investment in Albanias oil and gas sector.  IFCs participation in the Project would, inter alia, allow it to (i) provide political comfort to Premier and Preussag, (ii) play a catalytic role in mobilizing commercial bank loans for the Project, and (iii) introduce western standards of environmental performance in Albanias oil and gas sector.  It would also signal IFCs support for the development of one of the countrys most important industrial sectors.    	The Project would be the largest foreign investment in Albania to date.  Its successful implementation would (i) increase the country&apos;&apos;s oil production thus helping Albania meet its energy needs; (ii) generate foreign exchange earnings through the renewal of crude oil exports thus helping alleviate the current financial crisis in Albania, and (iii) introduce modern technology suitable for the development/rehabilitation of the country&apos;&apos;s oil fields. The Project will also generate significant environmental benefits for the country, especially the communities surrounding Patos, by eliminating past practices and introducing western standards of environmental performance.     Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category A project according to IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental review procedure.  Environmental issues of potential concern are contamination of soil, surface water and groundwater as a result of prior oil production activities carried out by Albanian government oil agencies and companies, the remediation of existing contamination, the management of produced water and gas, routing of the Export Pipeline, increasing the environmental management capacity of the host country partner, community relations, worker health and safety, and site restoration.  The Project includes a comprehensive environmental baseline study of Patos, an environmental impact assessment (the first in Albania as required by the January 1993 Law on Environmental Protection) of the Export Pipeline to the Adriatic Sea and a comprehensive public consultation program for all components of the Project.  The Project will set the basis for a phased remediation of contaminated soil, surface  water and groundwater conditions in Patos while simultaneously increasing the production of oil in an environmentally appropriate manner.  The Project will significantly strengthen the environmental management capacity of Albpetrol.    The  are  from the Public Information Center.       Host country location of environmental documents       Sektori I Urbanistikes Bashkise, Fier (Town Hall);    Biblioteka e Qytetit, Fier (Library)      Date SPI sent to InfoShop February 25,1998    This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:     Corporate Relations Unit   Telephone: (202) 473-3800    Fax: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglo Albania Petroleum Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7429" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-03-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-08-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Albania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AL-Albania">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.0000000000 20.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Oil and Gas Production (Includes Development)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $58.50 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-03-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1998-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-03-26">28500000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-03-26"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1998-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-03-26">30000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-03-26">30000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglo Albania Petroleum Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-03-26">28500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anglo Albania Petroleum Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7429/patos-marinza">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
