<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="FR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CH-4-2007003700</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CH-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">SDC</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Peace Process Nepal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">The Nepal Peace Trust Fund (NPTF) was created to channel such support to the Government of Nepal (GoN). The Joint Financing Arrangement  for the NPTF was signed between the GoN and a group of donors in February 2007, and implementation of the Fund commenced thereafter. After operating for more than 2 years in a fragile and sensitive political and security environment, the NPTF has successfully implemented 14 projects, while 5 more are ongoing. A further 5 projects are well advanced in the approval pipeline. - Whereas, the government is investing significant finances into NPTF, its capacity is insufficient to finance additional programs out of the regular budget without substantially reducing the resources allocated to basic services or to development activities. The international community is in close consultation with the representative of the UN General Secretary and the UN system, have responded favorably to this initiative. The Donor Advisory Group, which is currently chaired by Switzerland, is formally consulted regarding the choice and design of the individual projects, as well as their monitoring. Switzerland&#x92;s participation in NPTF places it at the core of this essential instrument for the implementation of the CPA and the international community&#x92;s efforts to help prevent the country&#x92;s relapse into conflict. It will also strengthen the existing Swiss engagement in peacebuilding in Nepal, including the work of a PA IV funded senior peace advisor, support and substantive contributions to the constitutional debate, the promotion of human rights, the re-creation of inclusive governance institutions in specific districts and villages as well as the peace sensitive management of the bilateral development program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">12000</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">CH-4</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">CH-4</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="7F-05340.04-12000-660-15230-C01" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="CH-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">SDC</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-28" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation SDC</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+41 31 322 34 75</telephone>
   <email>info@deza.admin.ch</email>
   <website>http://www.deza.admin.ch</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Freiburgstrasse 130,  3003 Berne</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="660" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">N&#xE9;pal</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR"></narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <value currency="CHF" value-date="2013-12-31">9000000</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <value currency="CHF" value-date="2013-12-31">4500000</value>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
