<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="CHF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CH-FDJP-66029860165-Disability Capacity Building Programme Component 2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CH-FDJP-66029860165" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL DISABILITY ALLIANCE</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability Capacity Building Programme (DCBP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Disability Capacity Building Programme (DCBP) will build the capacity and capability of DPOs in developing countries to enable them to advocate for equal rights and participation in society. Through the provision of funding to DPOs to support core functions, advocacy, technical advice and training at national, regional and global levels, the programme will build the organisational capacity, knowledge and skills of DPOs around the world. It will also work with DPOs to build accountability mechanisms to hold decision-makers to account.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development agenda is more inclusive of persons with disabilities thanks to enhanced and meaningful engagement of the diversity of persons with disabilities in shaping and monitoring programmes and policies. 
1. Accountability mechanisms are in place to incentivise genuine and sustained progress, and used by OPDs to monitor commitments made on advancing the rights of persons with disabilities.
2. The disability rights movement and its allies have developed capacities, technical recommendations and standards to influence global efforts and key education initiatives; as well as to provide technical assistance in reforming education systems towards the provision of quality, equitable, inclusive education for all, framed in compliance with the CRPD
3. The capacity of the disability rights movement is strengthened to ensure engagement of the diversity of persons with disabilities in defining, implementing and monitoring strategies for implementing CRPD and achieving sustainable development targets at all levels.
4. Women, children, youths and indigenous persons with disabilities have grown their collective capacity to voice their concerns, and progress is secured to realize their rights in areas of strategic importance to them.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="CH-FDJP-66029860165" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL DISABILITY ALLIANCE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-207544" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sightsavers</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Disability Alliance</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Unit</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Priscille Geiser</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>410227884273</telephone>
   <email>pgeiser@ida-secretariat.org</email>
   <website>https://www.internationaldisabilityalliance.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="11" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">486875</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
