<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-03122495-A0014</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-03122495" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Policy Management Ltd</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic Development &amp; Institutions Research</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our vision for this programme is a rare combination of cutting-edge rigorous research and innovative policy engagement. This proposal sets out a powerful approach to addressing one of the fundamental challenges of economic development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="60000" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aide a la Decision Economique (ADE)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-COH-03122495-A0014" crs-channel-code="60000" ref="GB-COH-03122495" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Policy Management</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-COH-03122495-A0014" ref="GB-COH-03122495" role="2" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Policy Management</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paris School of Economics</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-1-203051" ref="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of California, Berkeley</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Namur</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="0.28">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 organisation (Centre for Economic Research in Pakistan (CERP) ) is conducting RA3 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="2.54">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 organisation (NestBuilders International (SL) Ltd) is conducting RA3 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="1.44">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 organisation (PNDK Solutions Limited) is conducting RA4 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="0.88">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 organisation (TNS RMS Nigeria Limited ) is conducting RA4 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IT" percentage="0.61">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 university (Bocconi University) is conducting RA4 research. Some of this is desk-based research in the country of the research partner focused on low income countries. While some is happening on-the-ground in low income countries.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="1.64">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 university (Instituto Tecnologico Autonomo de Mexico (ITAM) ) is conducting RA3 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="AE" percentage="1.85">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 university (New York University in Abu Dhabi Corporation) is conducting RA4 and RA3 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="0.28">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 university (University of Cape Town) is conducting RA3 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NO" percentage="0.75">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 university (University of Oslo) is conducting RA4 research. Some of this is desk-based research in the country of the research partner focused on low income countries. While some is happening on-the-ground in low income countries.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="US" percentage="51.81">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13 organisations (CEGA, Harvard University, University of Wisconsin System, University of Pennsylvania, Yale University, University of Chicago, Duke University, University of Wisconsin Madison, University of Michigan, Boston University, University of California, Berkeley , Georgetown and Innovations for Poverty Action (IPA)) are working across a range of workstreams (RA3, RA4). Some of this is desk-based research in the country of the research partner focused on low income countries. While some is happening on-the-ground in low income countries.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="DE" percentage="1.6">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2 universities (Goethe-Universit&#xE4;t Frankfurt and Universit&#xE4;t G&#xF6;ttingen) are conducting RA4 research. Some of this is desk-based research in the country of the research partner focused on low income countries. While some is happening on-the-ground in low income countries.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="1.38">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 organisations (Institute for Financial Management and Research, Indian School of Business and J-PAL SA at Institute for Financial Management) are conducting RA3 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="1.31">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 organisations (University of Dodoma, REPOA and Law Associates Advocates) is conducting RA2 and RA3 research. Some of this research is desk-based in the country of the research partner, while some is happening on-the-ground in country.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GB" percentage="4.42">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8 organisations (University of Kent, London School of Economics, University of Oxford, Electric Studio, The University Court of the University of Edinburgh, Elliott Klooss Advisory Ltd, Econ Films and Raw Pictures) are working across a range of workstreams (RA2, RA3, RA4). Some of this is desk-based research in the country of the research partner focused on low income countries. While some is happening on-the-ground in low income countries. Some of these organisations are providing general support across the whole project.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="FR" percentage="11.33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our implementing partner, Paris School of Economics, is implementing RA3 and RA4 research, carrying out RCTs and case studies that analyse interactions between formal and informal institutions in relation to growth and development.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="BE" percentage="11.96">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our implementing partner, University of Namur, is implementing RA4 research, carrying out case studies that analyse interactions between formal and informal institutions in relation to growth and development.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="3.02">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our research partner, South Asian Network on Economics Modelling (SANEM), is implementing RA2 research, exploring the relationship between the characteristics and the functioning of a country&#x2019;s institutions and its economic development performance and constraints.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="DK" percentage="2.9">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our research partner, University of Copenhagen, Department of Economics, is implementing RA2 research, exploring the relationship between the characteristics and the functioning of a country&#x2019;s institutions and its economic development performance and constraints.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-26">13783904.69</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/VND.MS-EXCEL.SHEET.MACROENABLED.12" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/OPM---award-data-Q1-2021-22-(002)-20210708110730.xlsx">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EDI Partner Map</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A03"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-07-08"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
