<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-COH-OC350651-GCBE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-COH-OC350651" secondary-reporter="0" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Montrose International LLP</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research to support government of Ghana implementation of Complementary Basic Education (CBE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DFID Ghana is seeking high-quality research to support the Government of Ghana (GoG) to understand teaching and learning within government-led CBE programmes, the longer-term impacts of CBE on graduate experiences once they are in formal schools, and the systems and relationships required for the government to effectively and efficiently lead implementation of CBE programmes for out-of-school children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-OC350651" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Montrose International LLP</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scope of Work and Requirements The research supplier will be expected to support the following areas of work: 1. Tracker study and action research on cohort of CBE cycle 4 learners. The study would analyse the attendance, dropout and retention rates for learners who completed CBE in 2016/17 and transitioned to formal public primary schools in 2017/18. This study would provide an opportunity to assess the longer-term effectiveness of CBE and the publicschool system in providing formerly out-of-school children with quality education. The tracker study would use an existing database of the 20,000 Cycle 4 learners who were tracked a year into their transition to formal school. The study would assess cycle 4 CBE graduates&#x2019; experiences of education, work and family. The longitudinal study would also track CBE cycle 4 graduates and non-graduates who dropped out before the end of CBE, or during the course of their time in formal school after transferring, to provide information on the barriers to progression they have faced. The action research would asses which aspects of CBE pedagogy, teaching and learning approaches could be transferred to formal government schools 2. Political economy analysis around GoG implementation of CBE. The study would analyse the political economy within and around GoG implementation of CBE and make recommendations on what would be needed to improve efficiency and effectiveness of implementation when DFID funding ends in 2020. The political economy analysis would explore the systems and relationships around transition of CBE to a government-led programme (e.g. GES, MoE, NFED); how CBE implementation by government is working - policy vs. practice; what GoG engagement and relationship with non-state actors/private sector/NGOs around CBE is like; what engagement with different Ministries and bodies (e.g. NSS) is like; and how these might need to be strengthened.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-02-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-29">44055</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-31">42695</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Milestone 2: Tracker Report 1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-31">42695</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Milestone 2 required the submission of the CBE 4 Tracker report number 1, two years after the transition.</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11182" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the research are: (i) to continue tracking CBE graduates from CBE cycle 4 through the formal education system to build on learning around the longer-term impacts and sustainability of CBE pedagogy, with the view to propose improvements to CBE and public basic education pedagogy, and develop a unique evidence base on CBE in Ghana and globally (ii) To analyse the political economy of GoG&#x2019;s systems and relationships for leading and managing CBE programmes, to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of government-led implementation, so GoG can take on funding and management of CBE fully when DFID funding ends in 2020</narrative>
   </sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="Milestone 1: Inception Report">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-29">44055</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Milestone Inception required the submission of the inception report.</narrative>
   </description>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="11182" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the research are: (i) to continue tracking CBE graduates from CBE cycle 4 through the formal education system to build on learning around the longer-term impacts and sustainability of CBE pedagogy, with the view to propose improvements to CBE and public basic education pedagogy, and develop a unique evidence base on CBE in Ghana and globally (ii) To analyse the political economy of GoG&#x2019;s systems and relationships for leading and managing CBE programmes, to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of government-led implementation, so GoG can take on funding and management of CBE fully when DFID funding ends in 2020</narrative>
   </sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
