<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08-GMDC</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GENDER LINKS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and Media Diversity Centre</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Virtual and physical resource centre (VRC)
The VRC is an online resource centre that comprises the research database, clippings database and the media alerts and highlights. 

The Centre uploaded 90 English and 11 French media alerts and highlights on its VRC database. The GMDC strengthened partnerships that exist with training institutions in the region training media students from Malawi Polytechnic (63 students), Malawi Institute of Journalism (25 students) and National University of Lesotho (16 students) on how to write media alerts and highlights. 

Photo library and multimedia database
Currently there 8222 photos have been stored in the database. By December 2012, the GMDC had shortlisted 400 images from the database on all the SADC Gender Protocol themes for the photo e-shop. The images will be sold as part of the GMDC efforts to generate income. 

The GMDC is now storing audio-video footage collected from the field into an audio visual archive called CAT DV. The footage is tagged (country, programme and theme), split and then used to create customised products. This is an an innovative way of collecting evidence of the impact of GL&#x2019;s work in the field.

Seminars
The GMDC continued with the media freedom seminars in 2012. The academics who attended the Advisory Group discussed about gender and media freedom from their different countries. Some of them had the opportunity to go to the University of Pretoria through the GMDC to attend to listen to a public lecture by the Africa Union Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Expression and Access to Information, Advocate Pansy Faith Tlakula. 

Seminar 	Nature	Female	Male	Total
Mainstreaming or male streaming: Gender @ work in organisations	Regional (South Africa)	21	38	59
Half full or half empty? Gender gains and losses in the African Platform on Access to information	Regional (South Africa)	18	14	32
Youth leaders, HIV and AIDS	Regional	28	18	46
Women in Politics roundtable discussions	Regional	7	5	12
Gender and freedom of dressing in Malawi	Malawi	31	31	62
From 30%-50% Women in Local Government 	Swaziland	42	26	68
Sexual harassment in institutions of higher learning	Lesotho	43	9	52
Sexual harassment in institutions of higher learning	Namibia	4	9	13

A total of 247 females and 185 males participated in all the seminars. The seminar on male streaming and mainstreaming targeted participants from local government COEs. Participants discussed gender mainstreaming in the COEs, the challenges as well as sharing best practices on the subject. In February 2012, male street vendors in Malawi stripped women wearing short skirts and trousers. The GMDC took the opportunity to host a seminar at Malawi Polytechnic to discuss freedom of dressing in Malawi. During the Sixteen Days of Activism, the GMDC and nine academic institutions held seminars on sexual harassment. The outcome of these seminars in Lesotho is reported on in the Opinion and Commentary Service report.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="za-cpic-2001/005850/08" role="2" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caroline Takawira</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+27 11 622 2877</telephone>
   <email>finance@genderlinks.org.za</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 Derrick Avenue, Cyrildene, 2198</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="6">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="ZAR" value-date="2013-06-30">1074721</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
