<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08-Justice</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GENDER LINKS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Justice</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The VAW indicators and baseline research provides data on the extent, response, support, prevention, political commitment and individual costs of VAWG using a prevalence/attitude study and various other research tools to come up with figures currently deficient in police and court records. GL initiated the GBV Indicators research in partnership with government, local government and civil society partners in Botswana, Mauritius and South Africa. 

GL completed the research in the South African Provinces of Limpopo, Western Cape and Kwa Zulu Natal (Target for Year 1) and cascaded the research to three additional countries (Target for Year 3), Zimbabwe, Lesotho and Zambia. All the elements of the research are complete in Zimbabwe and in process in Lesotho and Zambia. GL presented the findings of the research to date  at a forum of African Gender Ministers convened by UNECA at the CSW, GL has been asked to join a UNECA reference group designing a study on the costs of GBV, an area that requires further exploration in the research.  

GL envisaged that the research would unfold in a linear way. The plan was to do the research in South Africa, Mauritius and Botswana followed by advocacy and lobbying. The envisaged result was a GBV National Action Plan that incorporated the indicators and baseline data in the three countries. Two factors affected the original plan: the burgeoning interest in conducting the baseline study in several SADC countries and the need to work with governments at their pace in a way that ensures ownership and muscle for the follow-up processes.

In addition to the three countries where GL has moved ahead thanks to PPA flexible funds and accompanying grants from Sida, UNWOMEN and the UNDP, Namibia, Mozambique, Seychelles and Malawi have expressed interest in undertaking the research. With regard to the follow up processes in the countries where the research has been launched, an important first step has been to elevate political buy in and support. This has been most successful in Botswana and Mauritius. 

 &#x201C;In Botswana, the (VAW Baseline Study) findings have sparked an unprecedented engagement&#x2026; The results provided a springboard for a countrywide drive to address GBV. Cabinet sent the Women&apos;s Affairs Department back to the drawing board to come up with baseline data for every district beyond the &quot;narrow statistical sample&quot; to better understand the dynamics in each locality. The President of Botswana (Ian Khama) has tasked everyone in the country to map the response that each current and prospective stakeholder would undertake as part of a multi-sector approach to address GBV as a response to the findings.&#x201D; Valencia Mogegeh, Director, Women&#x2019;s Affairs Division, Botswana.

Four ministers, the head of the Equal Opportunities Commission and an editor in chief of a major newspaper attended the launch of the Mauritian report, that has since been the subject of a cabinet memorandum.  The high profile campaign that ran through the Sixteen Days of Activism from 25 November to 10 December 2012 brought together all GL programmes to &#x201C;get the nation talking.&#x201D; Municipal libraries of the local government COE&#x2019;s hosted daily cyber dialogues in creole on each chapter of the report. MBC radio linked in with a one hour talk show. The report received extensive coverage in the mainstream media. The stage is now set for reviewing the existing National Action Plan on Gender. 

South Africa is more complex. GL had hoped that its membership of the National GBV Council would leverage support for cascading the research to the whole country, but this structure has been slow to get off the ground. GL has followed the parallel strategy of presenting the research to provincial governments (for example to the executive committee of Gauteng province, chaired by the Premier) and canvassing the Commission on Gender Equality (a Constitutional body) to use its muscle to get government support for the roll out. The wheels of bureaucracy move slowly, especially in larger countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="za-cpic-2001/005850/08" role="2" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caroline Takawira</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+27 11 622 2877</telephone>
   <email>finance@genderlinks.org.za</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 Derrick Avenue, Cyrildene, 2198</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern African</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="6">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="ZAR" value-date="2013-06-30">5910369</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
