<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08-Media</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GENDER LINKS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and Media</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proportion of women sources in the news is a key measure of women&#x2019;s voice. GL used the Gender and Media Progress Study (GMPS) average of 19% women sources as a baseline for the COE process. After monitoring an additional 30 media houses not in the GMPS sample but that had signed up as COEs, the average remained at 19%. A further analysis of only the COEs put the proportion of women sources in the 108 media COEs at 21% in 2011/2012.  

In this reporting period, 76 of the 108 media COEs (70%) conducted self-monitoring using a unique on-line tool developed by GL to assess their progress. This the first time ever that such a large number of media houses have monitored the gender-awareness of their own content. GL gathered 25 qualitative case studies of women and men making a difference in the media that forms part of the Changing Lives analysis (Section 9). GL also visited 53 media houses before the SADC Protocol@Work summit to verify the monitoring process and re-administer the GSC to assess progress. The brief highlights of these processes should be read in tandem with GL&#x2019;s summative report: &#x201C;Learning by listening: Findings of the 2013 Gender and Media Verification.&#x201D;   

The 2013 self-monitoring results shows that: 
&#x2022;The overall proportion of women sources in GL COEs is 22%, 3% lower than the target of 25%.
&#x2022;However, five out of the ten COE countries &#x2013;Mauritius, Botswana, Madagascar and Malawi- have achieved or nearly achieved the 25% target.  
&#x2022;All countries except Tanzania (a drop of 20% to 19%) and the DRC (a drop of 19% to 17%) experienced significant increases in the year under review. The fact that two countries registered a decline affirms the high ethical standards of this self-monitoring process: a research concern but a process bonus as self-monitoring is the best proven way to get media houses to improve practise. 

A further analysis of the performance of individual media houses shows that 27 of the 76 media houses (one quarter of the 108 COEs) exceeded the 25% target. The examples in the table include the Mauritius Broadcasting Corporation (MBC)  that registered a phenomenal 39% increase, in a process that GL and the MBC  has documented over time. Capital Radio in Malawi has gone up from 9% to 42% women sources since it joined the COE process, for reasons explained by the station&#x2019;s owner and manager: 

My first encounter with the Gender Links was really embarrassing, since at the time Capital Radio was dominated by men and there were so few women in all departments, they represented only 20%. Gender must be mainstreamed at all levels, we need to move beyond mere representation. Without actually giving women a voice as journalists and sources, the station would not live up to its civic responsibility.&#x201D;- Al Osman, Capital Radio, Malawi.

GL introduced the GSC to measure gender mainstreaming in the media COEs. There are marked improvements in media house performance against key indicators. Overall media houses moved from a baseline score of 57% to 63%. Mauritius made remarkable progress moving from a baseline score of 53% to 80%, a 27-percentage point improvement. The lowest ranking media house in the GSC moved from 39% in 2011/2012 to 47% in 2012/2013. The scores for all media houses are in the Media COE tracking sheet.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="za-cipc-2001/005850/08" role="2" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-30" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caroline Takawira</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+27 11 622 2877</telephone>
   <email>finance@genderlinks.org.za</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 Derrick Avenue, Cyrildene, 2198</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="6">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="ZAR" value-date="2013-06-30">1441630</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
