<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08-Governance</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="ZA-CIPC-2001/005850/08" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GENDER LINKS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and Governance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s political participation is a key MDG and SGP target: women cannot achieve voice and choice if they are excluded from decision-making. The current local government COE&#x2019;s reach approximately 28,887,004 people in the SADC region, 21.3% of the population in these countries.  After narrowing down this measure to the COE&#x2019;s that GL works with to ensure more accurate attribution, a key finding is that women in the COE councils constitute 28%  of the total: six percentage points higher than the regional average of 22%. However, the figure is two percentage points below the 2013 PPA target of 30% for COE&#x2019;s that GL works with. 

The difference is largely due to the Mauritian local government election held in November 2013 in which GL in credited with successfully advocating for the gender neutral quota that led to an increase in women&#x2019;s representation from 6.4% to 26.2%.  All the municipal and district councils in Mauritius are local government COEs. GL Mauritius went beyond advocating for the quota by seeking out women candidates and training them for office. To ensure that this success goes beyond numbers and translates into gender responsive governance, GL is cascading the COE process to 55 villages.  

 &#x201C;Local government ministries and authorities will collaborate and champion gender equality and mainstreaming at national and local level as well as provide human and material support for doing so.&#x201D; - Hon. Herve Aimee, Minister of Local Government and Outer Islands, Mauritius; keynote speaker at the SADC Gender Protocol@Work Summit.   

&quot;Citizens are moving away from such blatant stereotypes towards a more affirming position that women make a difference in politics by voting for them.&quot; Cehl Meeah, Member of Parliament and leader of the Mauritian Solidarity Front (FSM).

The local government Gender Score Card (GSC) measures gender responsiveness in councils. The GSC includes 25 questions that cover five key areas: the gender policy framework, governance, mainstreaming gender into existing programmes, gender specific programmes and employment practices and environment. It is a participatory tool in which beneficiaries assess themselves with independent verification by GL during visits and finally by summit judges.  

Overall, the 124 councils verified in early 2013 scored 63%, eight percentage points higher than their baseline score of 55% in 2012.  South African COEs scored highest (75%) while Lesotho made the most progress (20%). Every country except Swaziland (a traditional monarchy, where the score dropped from 58% to 54%) made progress. The Learning through listening: Findings of the 2013 Gender and Local government COE verification analyses the successes, challenges, strategies and next steps. 

Budget allocation to gender work by COE&#x2019;s compared to donor contributions 

The budget allocations cover a variety of areas including:
&#x2022;Towards the councils participation in the SADC Gender Protocol Summit.
&#x2022;For the implementation of the gender action plan.
&#x2022;Logistical costs for COE workshops.
&#x2022;Specific campaigns such as the 16 Days of No Violence Against Women 

A key VFM finding of the verification analysis (see table above) and indicator of the success of the programme is that Councils now allocate twice what GL has spent on the COE process (6.5 times the PPA spend) for taking forward gender work. Capricorn District Municipality in South Africa (the best performer in the 2012 and 2013 summits) allocated GBP 33 000 towards improving gender mainstreaming in service delivery. Ownership, capacity and performance are also being enhanced through training Drivers of Change: 

&#x201C;I first interacted with Gender Links when they came to train us in Maseru on gender mainstreaming. Now I am one of the trainers for the council. In my work as a councillor, I ensure that there is supply of water for the community and that broken taps are maintained. As a council, we also issue licenses for small dams. We educate people to become aware of climate change. Our programme involves working with social workers in the care of orphans and care workers in the community. We resolve conflicts among people who fight for land or development sites. We ensure accessibility of roads within the village.&#x201D; Cllr Thatho Mokuena, Senekane Community Council, Lesotho</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="za-cipc-2001/005850/08" role="2" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-30" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Links</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caroline Takawira</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+27 11 622 2877</telephone>
   <email>finance@genderlinks.org.za</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 Derrick Avenue, Cyrildene, 2198</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southern Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="6">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="ZAR" value-date="2013-06-30">11290057</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
