<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Nutrire la citt&#xE0;: Agricoltura urbana e promozione del cibo sano e  locale per lo sviluppo di un sistema agroalimentare sostenibile e  inclusivo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">2.1 DESCRIZIONE SINTETICA DELL&#x2019;INIZIATIVA IN ITALIANO 
Nutrire la citt&#xE0;: Agricoltura urbana e promozione del cibo sano e locale per lo sviluppo di un sistema 
agroalimentare sostenibile e inclusivo. L&#x2019;Iniziativa intende rafforzare la sostenibilit&#xE0; e l&#x2019;inclusivit&#xE0; del sistema 
agroalimentare dei distretti 3, 4, 5 e 11 di Ouagadougou, supportando l&#x2019;agricoltura urbana sostenibile e 
promuovendo cibo sano, locale e nutriente (OS). La strategia di progetto intende incidere positivamente e 
virtuosamente sulle barriere di accesso a cibo e contribuire all&#x2019;aumento della sicurezza alimentare nella 
regione del Centro del Burkina Faso (OG), favorendo il nesso tra nutrizione e salute, in linea con l&#x2019;OSS 2 &#x201C;Fame 
Zero&#x201D;. Il concetto di sicurezza alimentare &#xE8; multidimensionale e sottende le dimensioni di produzione, accesso 
e consumo (FAO &#x2013; Food Security1
) cui il progetto si prefigge di concorrere attraverso i tre risultati: 
R1. La produzione agricola urbana nel settore ortofrutticolo e dei PFNL nei distretti 3, 4, 5 e 11 di Ouagadougou 
&#xE8; aumentata quantitativamente e qualitativamente; 
R2. L&#x2019;accesso ad un cibo sano e nutriente in favore della popolazione pi&#xF9; vulnerabile dei distretti 3, 4, 5 e 11 di 
Ouagadougou &#xE8; aumentato; 
R3. La disponibilit&#xE0; e il consumo di cibo sano prodotto localmente &#xE8; aumentato in un mercato sensibilizzato 
sull&#x2019;importanza della sostenibilit&#xE0; ecologica e alimentare nei distretti 3, 4, 5 e 11 di Ouagadougou. 
Il progetto ha una durata di 36 mesi e stima un impatto diretto su 265.984 persone e un impatto indiretto su 
1.045.625 abitanti (50,32% donne) di 4 distretti di Ouagadougou. 
L&#x2019;Iniziativa, rafforzando le capacit&#xE0; e l&#x2019;autonomia della popolazione locale, accoglie i principi di Human rights 
based approach al tema della sicurezza alimentare, favorendo l&#x2019;accesso equo all&#x2019;alimentazione sana e nutriente 
a persone in situazione di forte vulnerabilit&#xE0;. 
Per garantire la riuscita dell&#x2019;Iniziativa &#xE8; stata definita una piena unit&#xE0; d&#x2019;intenti e il coinvolgimento sinergico dei 
partner alla definizione del progetto, valorizzando la complementariet&#xE0; e le specificit&#xE0; tecniche di ognuno. Il 
partenariato &#xE8; composto da organizzazioni italiane (Gnucoop Soc Coop, ITAL Watinoma, Etifor Srl) e locali 
(Comune di Ouagadougou, Association Watinoma e Impresa sociale K&#xE9; de burkinab&#xE9;) e prevede la costituzione 
di un&#x2019;associazione temporanea di scopo tra Fondazione ACRA e Mani Tese Onlus. La strategia di progetto &#xE8; 
stata costruita sull&#x2019;esperienza dei partner, in un&#x2019;ottica di promozione dell&#x2019;ownership dei processi di sviluppo e 
sostenibilit&#xE0;. L&#x2019;Iniziativa intende rafforzare la forte partnership con il comune di Ouagadougou, inserendosi nel 
programma strategico di sviluppo della Cintura Verde allineandosi alle priorit&#xE0; identificate dal comune e agendo 
sulla transizione agroecologica di 15 ha di cintura verde e riabilitazione di 28 ha di aree di verde urbano del 
Parco Bangr-Weogo, un esempio unico di foresta naturale in contesto urbano, svolgendo un ruolo essenziale 
per la conservazione della biodiversit&#xE0;, la mitigazione dell&#x2019;inquinamento, la regolazione del ciclo dell&#x2019;acqua.  
La proposta &#xE8; stata disegnata in correlazione ai principali bisogni identificati in Burkina Faso, uno dei Paesi pi&#xF9; 
poveri al mondo con oltre il 40% della popolazione al di sotto della soglia di povert&#xE0; (World Bank, 20202
). Gli effetti dei cambiamenti climatici stanno impattando significativamente sulla sicurezza e sovranit&#xE0; alimentare 
della popolazione burkinab&#xE9;, dove l&#x2019;80% &#xE8; impegnata nell&#x2019;agricoltura (USAID, 2020)3
. Tra gli ostacoli principali allo sviluppo del settore agricolo nella regione del Centro si &#xE8; identificata l&#x2019;insufficiente preparazione dei 
produttori per una transizione agroecologica delle filiere agroalimentari volte alla sostenibilit&#xE0; del sistema 
alimentare urbano, gestione poco efficiente della risorsa idrica e difficolt&#xE0; di interazione e di scambi commerciali tra citt&#xE0; e aree agricole periurbane.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feeding the city: Urban agriculture and promotion of healthy and local food for the development of a 
sustainable and inclusive agri-food system. The project aims to strengthen the sustainability and inclusiveness 
of the agri-food system of Ouagadougou districts 3, 4, 5 and 11, by supporting sustainable urban agriculture 
and promoting healthy, local and nutritious food (SO). The project strategy intends to positively and virtuously 
affect the barriers to access to food and contribute to increasing food security in the Burkina Faso Central 
region (GO), promoting the link between nutrition and health, in line with SDG 2 &quot;Zero Hunger&quot;. The concept 
of food security is multidimensional and underlies the dimensions of production, access and consumption (FAO 
- Food Security) to which the project aims to contribute through its three results: 
R1. Urban agricultural production in the fruit and vegetable sector and in NFPs in districts 3, 4, 5 and 11 of 
Ouagadougou quantitatively and qualitatively reinforced; 
R2. Improved access to healthy and nutritious food for the most vulnerable population of Ouagadougou 
districts 3, 4, 5 and 11; 
R3. Increased availability and consumption of locally produced healthy food in a market aware of the 
importance of ecological and food sustainability in Ouagadougou districts 3, 4, 5 and 11. 
The project has an expected duration of 36 months and it is estimated to have a direct impact on 265.984 
people and an indirect impact on 1.045.625 (50,32% women) of the 4 target districts of Ouagadougou. 
The Initiative, by strengthening the capacities and autonomy of the local population, welcomes the principles 
of the Human rights based approach to the theme of food security, favouring equal access to healthy and 
nutritious food for those who are in highly vulnerable situations. 
To ensure the success of the Initiative, a full unity of purpose and the synergistic involvement of the partners 
in designing the project were defined, underlining the complementarity and technical specificities of each one. 
The partnership comprises both Italian (Gnucoop Soc Coop, ITAL Watinoma, Etifor Srl) and local organizations 
(the municipality of Ouagadougou, Association Watinoma and the social enterprise K&#xE9; de burkinab&#xE9;) and 
provides for the establishment of a temporary association of purpose between ACRA Foundation and Mani 
Tese Onlus. The project strategy was built on the experience and proven operational capacity of the partners, 
with a view to promoting ownership of development and sustainability processes and sustainability. 
The initiative also intends to strengthen the strong partnership with the Municipality of Ouagadougou,
integrating the strategic programme of the Green Belt and in line with the priorities identified by the 
Municipality. Moreover, the project will also work on the agro-ecological transition of 15 ha of the Green Belt 
and the rehabilitation of 28 ha of green urban zones of Bangr Weogo Park. The park is a unique example of a 
natural forest in a urban context, playing an essential role to the conservation of biodiversity, mitigation of 
pollution, regulation of water cycle. The Initiative was designed in correlation with the main needs identified in Burkina Faso, one of the poorest 
countries in the world with over 40% of the population below the poverty line (World Bank, 2020). 
The effects of climate change are significantly impacting the food security and sovereignty of the Burkinab&#xE9; 
population, 80% of which are engaged in agriculture (USAID, 2020). 
Among the main obstacles to the development of the agricultural sector in the Central region: insufficient 
preparation of people employed in agriculture for an agro-ecological transition of the food processing supply 
chain; partially efficient management of the water resources and difficult interaction and commercial 
exchanges between cities and peri-urban agricultural areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FONDAZIONE ACRA - ASSOCIAZIONE DI COOPERAZIONE RURALE IN AFRICA E AMERICA LATINA ONG</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/01/1" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="49.1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="52010" percentage="29.2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food assistance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43073" percentage="21.7" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food safety and quality</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-14">2918255.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FONDAZIONE ACRA - ASSOCIAZIONE DI COOPERAZIONE RURALE IN AFRICA E AMERICA LATINA ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-30">1750953.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FONDAZIONE ACRA - ASSOCIAZIONE DI COOPERAZIONE RURALE IN AFRICA E AMERICA LATINA ONG</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
