<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">sLuM: fight against malnutrition in informal settlements in peri-urban areas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto &#x201C;sLuM: Lotta alla Malnutrizione negli insediamenti informali delle aree peri-urbane&#x201D;, della durata di 
36 mesi, si pone come obiettivo quello di migliorare le capacit&#xE0; della comunit&#xE0; del quartiere di Zagtouli, nella 
periferia di Ouagadougou, di prevenire e trattare la malnutrizione acuta infantile. Il quartiere, nato come area 
di insediamento informale &#x201C;non lotis&#x201D; e densamente popolato (quasi 60.000 abitanti), &#xE8; caratterizzato da 
povert&#xE0; diffusa e carenza di servizi igienico-sanitari di base. Con il diffondersi della pandemia da Covid-19 che 
ha colpito Ouagadougou e la regione del Centro, con il 66% di tutti i casi identificati nel paese dall&#x2019;inizio della 
pandemia (dati del 26/04/2021, Minist&#xE8;re de la Sant&#xE9;), le gi&#xE0; precarie condizioni igieniche ed abitative dei non 
lotis hanno aumentato la vulnerabilit&#xE0; degli abitanti. Conseguenza della compresenza di povert&#xE0; diffusa, scarso 
accesso ai servizi di base ed elevata insicurezza alimentare &#xE8; l&#x2019;elevata prevalenza della malnutrizione infantile. 
La provincia di Kadiogo di cui Zagtouli fa parte, evidenzia infatti elevati tassi di malnutrizione acuta, causati sia 
dalla scarsit&#xE0; di cibo e da una dieta povera di nutrienti, che da una scarsa conoscenza delle norme igienico-sanitarie di base e dal limitato accesso all&apos;acqua potabile e a strutture igienico-sanitarie, che causano 
parassitosi intestinali e elevata prevalenza di morbilit&#xE0; nei bambini (diarrea, malaria, insufficienza renale 
acuta). Il contrasto alla malnutrizione acuta avverr&#xE0; tramite il raggiungimento di tre risultati attraverso un 
approccio multisettoriale: innanzitutto il rafforzamento dei servizi sanitari locali, per quanto riguarda la
prevenzione, l&apos;identificazione e la gestione dei casi di malnutrizione acuta infantile dei bambini 0-59 mesi. Tali 
servizi saranno potenziati inizialmente tramite l&#x2019;aggiornamento delle competenze degli agenti sanitari, che 
andr&#xE0; a beneficio sia del centro di salute di Zagtouli, sia della comunit&#xE0;. Grazie alle competenze acquisite o 
migliorate, gli agenti sanitari procederanno ad una migliore identificazione della malnutrizione infantile acuta 
(moderata e severa) mediante misurazione dei parametri antropometrici, che avverr&#xE0;: i) ad ogni contatto con 
i pazienti nel centro di salute; ii) mediante campagne di screening organizzate ad hoc, durante le quali gli agenti 
sanitari insegneranno alle famiglie a riconoscere esse stesse i segni della malnutrizione infantile, tramite la 
ricerca degli edemi bilaterali e la misurazione del perimetro brachiale dei propri bambini. Gli agenti e/o le
famiglie riferiranno i casi di malnutrizione identificati al centro di salute, affinch&#xE9; sia garantita la loro presa in 
carico medica. A livello familiare/comunitario, gli agenti sanitari insegneranno alle famiglie la presa in carico 
ed il follow up per assicurare il recupero nutrizionale dei propri bambini malnutriti, attraverso un&#x2019;educazione 
mirata (educazione nutrizionale e dimostrazioni culinarie) e dei cicli di supplementazione in alimenti locali 
altamente energetici da svolgersi direttamente a domicilio. Anche le capacit&#xE0; comunitarie di prevenire la 
malnutrizione acuta saranno potenziate, mediante sessioni di educazione nutrizionale sulle pratiche di corretta 
alimentazione dei bambini 6-23 mesi. Le mamme e le famiglie saranno sensibilizzate sull&#x2019;importanza 
dell&#x2019;allattamento esclusivo al seno, dell&#x2019;introduzione dell&#x2019;alimentazione di complemento, della frequenza e 
della diversificazione dei pasti. Sempre in ottica curativa e preventiva, l&#x2019;iniziativa intende agire sul piano socio-economico delle famiglie, migliorando le loro capacit&#xE0; di accesso ad un cibo vario e di qualit&#xE0;. Si proceder&#xE0; 
quindi allo sviluppo/rafforzamento di attivit&#xE0; generatrici di reddito, che consentir&#xE0; alle famiglie di acquistare il 
cibo, e la promozione di orticoltura urbana mediante tecniche innovative, che permetter&#xE0; l&#x2019;auto-produzione 
di cibo.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 36-month project &quot;sLuM: Fight against malnutrition in informal settlements in peri-urban areas&quot; aims to 
improve the capacity of the community in the Zagtouli neighborhood, on the suburbs of Ouagadougou, to 
prevent and treat acute childhood malnutrition. The neighborhood, born as an informal &quot;non lotis&quot; settlement 
area and densely populated (almost 60,000 inhabitants), is characterized by widespread poverty and a lack of 
basic sanitation. With the spread of the Covid-19 pandemic affecting Ouagadougou and the Central region, 
with 66% of all cases identified in the country since the beginning of the pandemic (data of 26/04/2021, 
Minist&#xE8;re de la Sant&#xE9;), the already precarious hygienic and housing conditions of the non lotis have increased 
the vulnerability of the inhabitants. A consequence of the coexistence of widespread poverty, poor access to 
basic services and high food insecurity is the high prevalence of child malnutrition. The province of Kadiogo, of 
which Zagtouli is part, shows high rates of acute malnutrition, caused both by the scarcity of food and a diet 
poor in nutrients, and by a lack of knowledge of basic sanitary standards and limited access to drinking water 
and sanitation facilities, which cause intestinal parasites and a high prevalence of morbidity in children 
(diarrhea, malaria, acute renal failure). The fight against acute malnutrition will take place through the 
achievement of three results through a multisectoral approach: first of all, the strengthening of local health 
services, as regards the prevention, identification and management of cases of acute infantile malnutrition of 
children 0-59 months. These services will initially be enhanced by updating the skills of health agents, which 
will benefit both the Zagtouli health center and the community. Thanks to the skills acquired or improved, 
health agents will proceed to a better identification of acute (moderate and severe) childhood malnutrition by 
measuring anthropometric parameters, which will occur: i) at each contact with patients in the health center; 
ii) through screening campaigns organized ad hoc, during which health agents will teach families to recognize 
the signs of childhood malnutrition themselves, through the search for bilateral edema and the measurement 
of the brachial perimeter of their children. Agents and/or families will report identified cases of malnutrition 
to the health center, so that their medical care is guaranteed. At the family/community level, health agents 
will teach families how to take charge and follow up to ensure the nutritional recovery of their malnourished 
children, through targeted education (nutritional education and cooking demonstrations) and cycles of 
supplementation in local foods, highly energetic, to be carried out directly at home. Community capacities to 
prevent acute malnutrition will also be enhanced through nutritional education sessions on proper nutrition 
practices for 6-23-month-old babies. Mothers and families will be made aware of the importance of exclusive 
breastfeeding, the introduction of complementary feeding, the frequency and diversification of meals. Still 
from a curative and preventive perspective, the initiative intends to act on the socio-economic level of families, 
improving their ability to access varied and quality food. We will then proceed with the 
development/strengthening of income-generating activities, which will allow families to purchase food, and 
the promotion of urban horticulture through innovative techniques, which will allow the self-production of 
food. Finally, it is planned to strengthen sanitation services at the community level, as another fundamental 
component to prevent malnutrition. For this reason, the initiative proposes the construction/renovation of 
latrines and boreholes in schools, and bornes fontaines in different areas of Zagtouli. The enhanced access to 
hygienic infrastructures, combined with information, education a</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDICUS MUNDI ITALIA ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/02/9" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="14031" percentage="10" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic drinking water supply</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12240" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="10" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12264" percentage="5" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-19 control</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43072" percentage="25" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Household food security programmes</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="6.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end all forms of malnutrition, including achieving, by 2025, the internationally agreed targets on stunting and wasting in children under 5&#xA0;years of age, and address the nutritional needs of adolescent girls, pregnant and lactating women and older persons</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-15">1120388.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDICUS MUNDI ITALIA ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-07-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-07-20">672233.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MEDICUS MUNDI ITALIA ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
