<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="SEK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.wwf.se" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:cso="https://csoadmin.sida.se/iati" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-ON-802005-9823-UG-500409</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading the change - Civil Society, Rights and Environment: International Gorilla Conservation Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;b&gt;Community Based Planning in Conservation&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The proposed programme falls under the IGCP strategic plan (2014-2020) especially in its objective by 2020, mountain gorilla tourism poses minimal risk to the gorillas and provides direct and equitable benefits to communities living around the Protected Areas. The Mission of IGCP is to conserve gorillas through partnering with key stakeholders while significantly contributing to sustainable livelihood development. Since its inception in 1991, the programme has grown in size and workforce and the related operational infrastructure, as well as in portfolio of projects and the range of conservation and development related activities. IGCP has had a long history of working with civil society which cumulated in creation of Sabyinyo Community Livelihoods Association (SACOLA) and Nkuringo Conservation Community Development Fund (NCCDF) that entered into private partnerships for managing the eco-lodges in Kinigi and Nkuringo. SACOLA generates annually around 200,000$ while Nkuringo generates around $75,000. Given the high human population around the protected, communities involvement in NRM is key to achieving the conservation objectives. The voice, interests and aspirations of citizens must always being taking into account for achieving conservation objectives. In this light, IGCP strategy leans towards community involvement in NRM, and this programme will reinforce community participation and the ability to influence key decisions that affect community livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Despite these achievements, there are still several areas outstanding, including enabling local communities to sustainably manage resources and become strong business entities; developing civil society capacity in institutional leadership and long term strategies to drive innovations for change as well as to have the capacity in participating in key decisions making.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Consequently, the proposed programme will implement interventions aimed at improving the capacity of civil society in order to manage natural resources as well as addressing issues within the communities; and promoting the development of partnerships. The programme will support and partners with CSOs/CBOs; support development of partnerships and linkages with private sector and other actors including local and national governments, communities etc.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Collaboration will be developed with GVTC for transboundary activities while country activities will be implemented at specific sites i.e. Virunga National Park, Volcanoes National Park and Bwindi Mgahinga Conservation Area.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The critical role played by civil society is widely acknowledge by WWF in the ARL region as evidenced the country office strategies having civil society strengthening and engagement as  one of the vehicles through which to influence natural resources policies and deliver conservation  outcomes that benefits both people and nature. Central to the CSO strategy will be partnership approach based on equal collaboration and respect, leaving key decisions solely in the&#x201D; hands&#x201D; of CSO partners. This partnership approach is guided by WWF&#x2019;s belief that by playing a catalytic role and promoting a vibrant and democratic civil society that hold governments and private sector accountable for their actions and strengthening the ability of people living in a state of poverty or marginalization, improves the quality of life of the people.  The ARL Hub the will directly work with the country-based landscape CSO platforms in MMS and GVL to establish transboundary CSO networks to act as collective voices for marginalized groups (women, youths and other disadvantages groups in society), and advocate for change in transboundary natural resource policies.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Within the partnership approach, the project will through training, mentoring, networking, information and coalition building strengthen the institutional and technical capacity of civil society to be able to undertake both site specific interventions within the Bwindi Virunga landscape. Within the ARL Hub interventions, the project will directly work with the country-based landscape CSO platforms in MMS and GVL, being institutional and technically strengthened by the country level interventions under this programme, to establish transboundary CSO networks that will  act as collective voices for marginalized groups (women, youths and other disadvantages groups in society), and advocate for change in transboundary natural resource policies and influence key decisions to complement the country based landscape CSO platforms policy dialogue and advocacy processes strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Appropriate capacity assessment tools will be used to identify capacity gaps, especially in areas of multi-stakeholder engagements and transboundary policy advocacy; to guide capacity building initiatives. Strategic partnerships will be formalised through MOUs.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;In the Virunga Bwindi Landscape, IGCP will use the community based planning approach to enable the communities to express their needs. Community Based Planning mobilises and empowers community members in every step of planning and implementation of activities. In order to enable the CBOs and CSOs (representing communities) enable village communities to analyse the situation of their village and identify development changes/ needs for their community, at the same time to facilitate communities to identify strengths, weakness, potentials and opportunities and to prioritise them. The programme will facilitate the integration of the agreed plans, policy and agenda into the local government&apos;s plans. The programme will help to legitimize the community plans where the community members (including women and youths) recognize and own plans as product of their effort. The programme will aid mobilize resources from within and outside the CSOs, and CBOs and put demand on different partners (local government services, NGOs and other active institutions in the area) to deliver quality services in a timely fashion. At the end, the CSOs/CBOs would have developed and agreed on a policy/action plan agenda; CSO/CBOs are engaged in dialogue processes with local government entities and CSO/CBOs and government entities are engaged in joint performance appraisals for agreed actions.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association des Femmes des Gardes de Rumangabo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Buhoma Mukono Community Development Association</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPAVU-MARARO</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gitenderi Environment Project Community Group</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Gorilla Conservation Programme</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jomba Community Group</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nkuringo Artisans Group (wood carvers and Basket weavers)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nkuringo Community Conservation and Development Foundation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sabyinyo Community Livelihoods Association</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union des Apiculteurs de Mikeno et Nyamulagira</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <website>http://www.wwf.se</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">1359863</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">1359863</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">1238898</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">1238898</value>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Association des Femmes des Gardes de Rumangabo</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Buhoma Mukono Community Development Association</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COOPAVU-MARARO</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gitenderi Environment Project Community Group</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Gorilla Conservation Programme</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jomba Community Group</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nkuringo Artisans Group (wood carvers and Basket weavers)</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nkuringo Community Conservation and Development Foundation</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sabyinyo Community Livelihoods Association</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Union des Apiculteurs de Mikeno et Nyamulagira</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-country code="RW"></recipient-country>
   <recipient-region code="998" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator title</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <cso:Strategyid>1</cso:Strategyid>
  <cso:Typeoffundingid>0</cso:Typeoffundingid>
  <cso:contributionstatusid>Active</cso:contributionstatusid>
  <cso:keyWordid>1</cso:keyWordid>
  <cso:sidadepartmentid>1</cso:sidadepartmentid>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
