<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="SEK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.wwf.se" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:cso="https://csoadmin.sida.se/iati" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-ON-802005-9823-MG-500403</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading the Change: Civil Society, Rights and Environment - Northern Mozambique Channel Channel initiative Thematic Hub</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;b&gt;Problem and context description&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The Northern Mozambique Channel (NMC) region is one of the world&#x2019;s most outstanding marine biodiversity areas and serves as a biological reservoir for the entire Western Indian Ocean region, in particular for coral reefs and associated ecosystems. Besides fisheries and tourism, recent natural gas and oil discoveries are adding to the riches of the NMC, likely spearheading the region into an economic and population boom.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;While this growth potential provides immediate welfare opportunities, it may at the same time come at par with livelihoods and biodiversity challenges, as the on-going oil and gas developments in the region are mostly in areas of important biodiversity assets. The threats to the natural diversity are also threats to the human development in the region, particularly for the coastal communities, which are highly dependent on marine ecosystems for their daily survival.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The NMC is under the jurisdiction of Comoros, France, Madagascar, Mozambique, Seychelles and Tanzania. There is a long history of strong inter-governmental cooperation in the region when it comes to the coastal and marine environment, facilitated through a range of regionally mandated institutions. Several countries have already made strong commitments to the application of area-based ocean management, although there are also disputes over certain parts of the oceans space in the channel that may present potential complications when it comes to agreement of a future joint management of the channel.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The coastal communities in the region often possess customary rights over resources, including fish and forest products. However, in reality, the voice of communities in policy debates related to the marine and coastal environment is still very limited. Within the communities, women are often the most vulnerable, as they are very involved in fishery and forestry but lack influence over decisions regarding land and resource allocation. Raising the voice of community, including vulnerable groups, in the policy debates is therefore key to this programme.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Civil society has a crucial role to play. With the active advocacy of CSOs gathered in the Western Indian Ocean Consortium (WIOC), and the support of Sida and WWF, the Northern Mozambique Channel initiative (NMCi) has gained significant momentum over the past years. A key milestone in this regard was the decision by the 8th Conference of Parties to the Nairobi Convention, held in June 2015, which formally recognises the initiative as a model for integrated ocean management that governments should support. However, many of the CSOs in the region, and within this initiative particularly, are still in great need of capacity building to be able to play their parts in relation to duty bearers and the communities.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;b&gt;Programme goal&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The overall goal of the programme is that NMC CSOs will be strengthened and empowered so that they can actively influence marine governance, law and policy making and reform processes across the NMC.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;b&gt;Programme activities&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The planned interventions and activities relate to three programmatic pillars:&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;ul&gt;
	  &lt;li&gt;Capacity building - The first pillar involves technical, organisational and institutional training for CSOs, information workshops for CSOs, establishing platforms for information sharing, supporting CSOs in their advocacy work and organising dialogue meetings with authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;li&gt;Acces to information - The second pillar is targeted towards improving access to relevant information and generating data around the ecosystem-livelihoods-economics nexus. The programme will also contribute to the development and assessment of future scenarios for the NMC, through an innovative multi-stakeholder driven process.&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;li&gt;Law and policy - The final pillar focuses on establishing the necessary platforms that will allow CSOs to participate in the policy and legal processes related to the NMCi. To this extent, forums and committees will be set up, or strengthened, in each country, to facilitate interaction between governments, private sector and civil society.&lt;/li&gt;
	  &lt;/ul&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coalition nationale de plaidoyer environnemental</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum das Organiza&#xE7;&#xF5;es da Sociedade Civil para a &#xC1;rea Marinha e Costeira</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maison des Organisation des Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Civile</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southwest Indian Ocean Tuna Forum</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF Madagascar and West Indian Ocean Programme Office</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wildlife Conservation Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <website>http://www.svenskakyrkan.se</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="31310" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">2970000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">2970000</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">2845113</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">2845113</value>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coalition nationale de plaidoyer environnemental</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum das Organiza&#xE7;&#xF5;es da Sociedade Civil para a &#xC1;rea Marinha e Costeira</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maison des Organisation des Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Civile</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Southwest Indian Ocean Tuna Forum</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF Madagascar and West Indian Ocean Programme Office</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wildlife Conservation Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-country code="MZ"></recipient-country>
   <recipient-region code="998" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator title</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <cso:Strategyid>1</cso:Strategyid>
  <cso:Typeoffundingid>0</cso:Typeoffundingid>
  <cso:contributionstatusid>Active</cso:contributionstatusid>
  <cso:keyWordid>1</cso:keyWordid>
  <cso:sidadepartmentid>1</cso:sidadepartmentid>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
