<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="SEK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.wwf.se" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:cso="https://csoadmin.sida.se/iati" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-ON-802005-9823-KE-500407</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading the Change - Civil Society, Rights and Environment: Africa Energy Thematic Hub</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;b&gt;Problem and context description&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Of all regions, Africa is a continent which is particularly affected by limited access to clean and modern renewable energy services. Sub-Saharan Africa has more people living without access to electricity than any other world region. More than 620 million people lack access to electricity. Rural areas and vulnerable groups are especially affected. A related challenge is the widespread use of traditional use of biomass, such as three-stone fires, for cooking across Africa. This brings with it several negative environmental, health and social outcomes, such as indoor air pollution and the time-consuming and physically demanding task of fuel collection, preparation and cooking, often suffered disproportionately by women and children.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The intensive use of biomass as firewood is the key driver to deforestation in Sub-Saharan Africa which in the end results in loss of biodiversity and land degradation as well as detrimental health impacts due to pollution from solid biomass energy sources (cow dung, crop wastes and firewood) and inefficient cooking technologies. In addition to severe environmental problems these impacts makes the living conditions even tougher in rural areas and for vulnerable groups depending on natural resources for survival. Much of the wood fuel is consumed using traditional technologies, which leads to high-levels of indoor air-pollution. This situation is estimated to cost Africa 600,000 lives of people who die prematurely due to illnesses associated primarily by indoor air pollution (WHO, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Widespread energy poverty combined with the comparative advantages of each country to generate affordable renewable energy services creates an important opportunity for regional cooperation. Already the region is beginning to cooperate in various ways on sustainable energy. However, over the past few years the region has experienced deteriorating governance trends. On-going conflicts and refugee flows are sources of instability and present significant challenges to development. In the foreseeable future, while other energy poor regions of the world are expected to register significant declines in energy poverty, the East and Southern Africa region is going to be the only part of the world where energy poverty is expected to get worse.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Given the centrality of access to clean, renewable, modern and affordable energy services to the attainment of nearly all sustainable development goals (SDGs), Africa is unlikely to achieve its SDG aspirations unless it harnesses the full potential of its sustainable energy resources. Many African governments are undertaking various legislative reforms and projects to increase access to efficient as well as modern fuels and technologies for clean cooking and lighting services including the more efficient use of biomass through clean cook stoves. These measures, however, have been challenged with limited implementation capacity, ineffective integrated energy planning systems, poor energy governance and the fast population growth rates which has outpaced the rate of access to modern energy services. The initiatives do not reach the rural and grass root level. Private sector participation has registered tremendous progress given the increasingly more enabling environment across most African governments. However, even then private sector activities are concentrated in urban centres. Rural remote places where the majority of African, especially the energy poor live, make limited commercial sense.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Civil society is a key pillar in achieving national set targets and also harmonising regional set targets in the energy sector, but very few civil society actors from Africa are effectively operational at regional and international level and present in important forums for decision making. Many of the CSOs who could play crucial roles are disjoint and have limited institutional, technical and programmatic capacity. This also includes a limited understanding of entrepreneurship, knowledge management and private sector engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;Approaches to energy access are often gender blind, and assume that investments in the sector will somehow benefit women, youth, children and men equally. For energy access to become a universal reality and, in such male dominant sector, it is also crucial to address the structural causes of gender inequality, thus advocating for women and youth&#x2019;s involvement in the policy making processes, as agents of change in the supply of rural electricity, as well as in planning processes to ensure the specific benefits of decentralised solutions to women, youth and their respective roles at household and productive use levels are realised.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;b&gt;Programme goals&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The overall desired change of the programme is to contribute towards a future where people and communities in programme areas are effectively exercising their rights, influencing decisions and equitably receiving benefits from energy resources, and contributing to the sustainable energy resources development at national, regional and global levels.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;b&gt;Programme activities&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The overall approach will be based on two work-streams: national level support and regional/international support.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;At the national level, the regional Energy Hub will undertake capacity assessment of national teams to clarify existing gaps and to develop customized country and regional plans to complement on-going national level capacity interventions both at the country level and between countries. Clear and specific strategies specific to each country context will be developed and implemented. Besides, cross-learning between countries will also be facilitated through specific learning events and forums. The Hub will co-ordinate bilateral and cross-cutting partnerships, joint learning and pooling of expertise and competence to support the various countries and the region in strengthening key CSO partners on delivering a human rights based approach to sustainable energy. Trainings and assessments will include a focus on women and youth involvement and engagement. &lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;
	  &lt;br&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;At the regional/international level, the programme will focus on increasing CSO engagement and representation of local communities in key regional and international energy policy and energy agenda setting processes. Regional and international energy forums have been identified as critical for especially representation by African and Africa-based CSOs as well as local communities which have hitherto not been effectively represented at these levels. The hub will do a thorough power mapping of key regional and international actors, programmes and initiatives in order to clearly define its added niche and specific contributions at these regional and international sustainable energy agenda-setting initiatives. An early output at this level will be Knowledge and Information Platform (KIP) focused in particular on the intersection between human rights and sustainable energy issues in the region. The setting up of the KIP is geared at increasing access to information on energy access, efficiency and energy financing for the partner CSOs and other stakeholders as government entities, private companies as well as regional and international agencies. It is anticipated that barriers for off-grid solutions will be of special focus of this work stream, since increased share of off-grid solutions is key if SDG7 shall be reached by 2030 given the focus of regional governments and businesses on scaling up access to off-grid energy solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
	  &lt;/br&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF Southern and Eastern Africa Programme Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <website>http://www.wwf.se</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="014" percentage="100" vocabulary="2"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="23010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">900000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">900000</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">393459</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">393459</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF Southern and Eastern Africa Programme Office</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-country code="TZ"></recipient-country>
   <recipient-region code="014" vocabulary="2"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator title</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <cso:Strategyid>1</cso:Strategyid>
  <cso:Typeoffundingid>0</cso:Typeoffundingid>
  <cso:contributionstatusid>Active</cso:contributionstatusid>
  <cso:keyWordid>1</cso:keyWordid>
  <cso:sidadepartmentid>1</cso:sidadepartmentid>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
