<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="SEK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:linked-data-default="http://www.wwf.se" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:cso="https://csoadmin.sida.se/iati" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-ON-802005-9823-UG-500392</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leading The Change: Civil Society, Rights and Environment: Transboundry Natural Resources Management Thematic hub</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&lt;b&gt;Problem and context description&lt;/b&gt;
	  &lt;p&gt;The Africa Rift Lakes (ARL) region is one of Africa&#x2019;s most densely populated areas with population density exceeding 1000 persons per square kilometre in some areas; and with high annual population growth rates. Poverty is prevalent, and all countries in the region are so-called &#x2018;least developed countries&#x2019; except Kenya. Parts of the region have endured decades of instability with war and armed conflict affecting millions of people in the Great Lakes and Albertine Rift regions, exacerbating poverty and inhibiting normal livelihood activities.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The ARL region is very rich in natural resources and arguably the most biodiverse region on mainland Africa, supporting an extremely unique and diverse array of ecosystems and some of the most spectacular species found in Africa. The region&#x2019;s rich natural resource base is central to national and local economies, and directly supports tens of millions of livelihoods where rural people often have few alternatives for their survival, food security and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/br&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;This wealth is threatened by illegal timber extraction and trade, illegal charcoal production for domestic energy, poaching, illegal wildlife trade, large scale infrastructure investments and extractives particularly in the oil and gas sector.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/br&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The challenges being experienced in the transboundary regions covered by this programme are further exacerbated by shrinking civil society space due to national governments regulations; institutionally and technically weak civil society; fragmented and uncoordinated transboundary civil society networks, limited community-based &#x201C;home-grown&#x201D; methodologies and knowledge for planning and fostering community participation. Besides, men and women are not equally represented in the civil society arena.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/br&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Within the region, there is limited information sharing on conservation and development issues amongst the civil society and other key stakeholders that pose serious limitations to CSOs and their networks in influencing key transboundary NRM decisions and policies. Linked to this is the general lack of information on the social and environmental sensitivities of large scale infrastructure projects associated with resource corridors, and oil and gas sectors, that is both undermining the ability of civil society to engage and hold the private sector investors and governments accountable, including civil society capacity to organise and respond cohesively and proactively to the potential impacts of large scale infrastructure investments, transboundary freshwater governance as well as emerging transboundary NRM issues.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/br&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Programme goals&lt;/b&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The desired long-term change of this programme is that people in the African Rift Lakes Region&#x2019;s selected transboundary landscapes are actively participating, benefitting and effectively contributing to the transboundary management and conservation of important ecosystem services and biodiversity, providing a foundation for sustainable development and secure livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;b&gt;Programme activities&lt;/b&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The programme will be implemented by the Hub coordination unit based at the Uganda Country office and will complement the work of Tanzania, DRC, Kenya and Uganda Programmes as well as of the International Gorilla Conservation Programme (IGCP)  in delivering conservation outcomes directly linked to their conservation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/br&gt;
	&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;The key strategies that will be deployed include capacity development (training, mentorship), coalition building and networking, lobby and advocacy, dialogue and facilitation, technical advice and equal partnerships building. The major transboundary interventions under the ARL Hub will focus on the following:&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Establishing and strengthening transboundary CSO networks/platforms and coalitions.  The capacity strengthening will seek to ensure that civil society networks have strong governance and internal democracy mechanisms; technical expertise in their areas of engagement to be able to effectively perform and command respect in the dialogue and policy influencing processes.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Knowledge management, transboundary learning and sharing of best practices to the civil society arena.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Facilitating permanent equal partnerships between transboundary CSO networks/ platforms and coalitions with key stakeholders (both public and private sector).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Advocating for the creation of effective institutional spaces by duty bearers to improve the enabling conditions for transboundary civil society networks, platforms and coalitions to participate in NRM governance, engage in collective advocacy and influence transboundary environmental policies and legislation.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/br&gt;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GVL Transboundary Platform</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MMS Transboundary Platform</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <website>http://www.wwf.se</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="1"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">450000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-01-01">450000</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">332515</value>
   <provider-org ref="SE-ON-202100-4789" type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="SE-ON-802005-9823" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="SEK" value-date="2018-12-31">332515</value>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF/World Wide Fund for nature</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GVL Transboundary Platform</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MMS Transboundary Platform</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <recipient-country code="CD"></recipient-country>
   <recipient-region code="998" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator title</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <cso:Strategyid>1</cso:Strategyid>
  <cso:Typeoffundingid>0</cso:Typeoffundingid>
  <cso:contributionstatusid>Active</cso:contributionstatusid>
  <cso:keyWordid>1</cso:keyWordid>
  <cso:sidadepartmentid>1</cso:sidadepartmentid>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
