<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8538</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEF Flecol Lda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information     Project Name	Angola-Flecol Lda    Region		Sub-aharan Africa    Sector		Food and Agribusiness    Project No		008538    Projected Board	January 9, 1998   Date    Company Name	Flecol Lda    Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The shareholders are Messrs. Jari Peltokangas (Finnish), Carl Gustav Ruda (Finnish)and Flecol Lda, an Angolan detergent manufacturer. Mr. Peltokangas is an experienced international banker and marketing practitioner who is currently Managing Director of his own investment company.  He has previously held senior positions with Citibank, Karsallis International Bank and Amernet Holdings. Mr. Ruda is the Managing Director of Vaasan Saippua Finland the proposed equipment suppliers and technical partners.    Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    	The project is estimated to cost US$1.9 million and IFC has been requested to provide a loan of US$564,000.    Location of Project and Description of Site    	The project will be located in Viana Industrial Site in Luanda, Angola.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	Flecol Lda (Flecol, the Company) is a small Angola detergent manufacturing company. The company intends to expand into the production of a range of bath and laundry soaps and small quantities of candles.  The company has invited Messrs. Ruda and Peltokangas to take shareholding in the company and invest some money to finance the proposed soap project. The plants products will be sold on the domestic market. The equipment will be purchased from Vaasan Saippua Oy Finland. IFC&apos;&apos;s investment will contribute to the creation of 35 jobs and help bring to Luanda some economic activity at a time when Angola is reconstructing after the protracted civil war. The investment will also help develop the local soap industry which currently has only one manufacturer, and introduce some of the latest soap making technology to Angola.    Environmental Category and Issues    This is a category B project according to AEF&apos;&apos;s environmental review procedure.  Environmental issues associated with this project include site setting and conditions, liquid and solid wastes disposal; handling and storage of chemicals materials and oil; recycling of solvents and oils.  Occupational health and safety issues include employee exposure to dust, heat, noise and hazardous materials, and fire prevention and emergency evacuation.  The sponsor has provided IFC with detailed information regarding its environmental practices.  The facility will be located in an industrial park 14 kms from Luanda.  All production equipment will be imported from Finland.  The production process is a closed system, with the result that waste generation is minimal.  No solvents are used in either production or cleaning of machinery.  Machines are washed down with small quantities of soap.  All flammable materials (perfumes and organic oils) will be stored in a separate locked container located in the facility warehouse.  Damaged product can be reprocessed.  All sewage and waste water from machinery washdown will be disposed in a series of septic tanks and soakaways on the property.  Employees will be provided with appropriate personal protective clothing and trained in the safe operation and maintenance of equipment as well as fire prevention and response methods.  The facility will be equipped with fire extinguishers in accordance with local regulations. IFC will monitor ongoing compliance with World Bank environmental, health and safety policies and guidelines during the lifetime of the project by evaluating reports submitted annually to IFC by the sponsor and by conducting periodic supervision.    The Environmental Review Summary is available from the Public Information Center.    Date SPI sent to PIC	December 8, 1997    This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors.  It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.    For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F&#xE1;brica de Bleach Corasol Limitada</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8538" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-10-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-12-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Angola</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="AO-Angola">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-12.5000000000 18.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GA - Soap and Cleaning Compound  (Soap, Detergent, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.61 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-10-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-10-28">610000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-10-28">610000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F&#xE1;brica de Bleach Corasol Limitada</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8538/aef-flecol-lda">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
