<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/Ed/INGO/12352</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensuring a safe and protective learning environment for crisis affected children and youth in Baidoa IDP camps</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The education system has suffered widespread loss and damage, resulting in limited capacity and resources.
Access to education has reached a historic low, with more than three million children today out of schools in Somalia. The national Gross Enrollment Rate (GER) is 30 per cent for primary education and 26 per cent for secondary level education (HRP 2019 report). 
The project intends to target 16 IDP sites in Baidoa town. The identified camps are among the 391 IDP camps which were in great majority set up during 2017 and which are home to 47,873 HHs (CCCM report, DSA, March 2019). 
This project aims to achieve access to education for IDP children by targeting 2,185 out of school children (1,090 boys and 1,095 girls) living inside IDP settlements in Baidoa to ensure their access to school thus enhancing their safety and protection as well as the enjoyment of their rights. Out of the total 2,185 children, 2,060 are primary school age children while 125 are secondary school age children and/or children above 15 years.
This project will ensure that emergency and crisis affected children/youth have access to safe and protective learning environments in the partner schools. This will be done through a comprehensive action to respond to immediate and longer term needs of the children. The learners will be provided with access to food, water and scholastic material and children with protection concerns will be supported through strengthening/creating referral mechanisms where necessary, to specialized services. Girl  education will be at the center of the project encompassing all activities and it will be promoted with trainings, advocacy campaigns and community mobilization in support of changing negative attitudes and practices. Adolescent school aged girls will also be provided with sanitary pads in support to improving their attendance rates in classrooms and CECs will be sensitized on the importance of girls&#x2019; education during the back to school campaigns. Personal hygiene and sanitation, school personnel and parents&#x2019; commitment to provide leadership in promoting girls&#x2019; education are proven to be two key factors in improving girls&#x2019; attendance rates as recommended by the beneficiaries during FGDs held by INTERSOS staff in the current SHF EiE project implemented din Wajid and Education Cannot Wait project implemented last year in Baidoa. 
The foreseen construction and rehabilitation of temporary learning spaces will ensure access to a safe and enabling learning environment. Additionally, capacity building will be conducted for CECs and teachers on pedagogy, child protection, child wellbeing and psychosocial support. Teachers will also be supported through payment of monthly incentives corresponding to 100 USD for a period of 8 months. 
Among the 16 targeted settlements, the 3 IDP camps located within the Horseed urban village called Shimo Tiyeglow, Kalimey and Bohaladi will be provided with two new learning spaces and segregated gender latrines since no education service is present in this area. 
Child protection is mainstreamed into the project. One of the key focus of the project will be indeed to prevent and respond to children with protection concern considering the school as a safe space and an entry point to enhance children&#x2019;s protective environment. The project will conduct regular analysis of the situation of children regarding causes and patterns of protection concerns and will respond accordingly through prevention and strengthening or creating quick referral pathways, conduct service mapping to facilitate appropriate referrals and strengthen coordination and linkages in service delivery to ensure quality comprehensive services to the children with protection concerns.
 Building communities&#x2019; resilience and promoting the reintegration of children in the formal education system. In 2018 INTERSOS already successfully referred and supported 117 children to the public schools Mustafa Sheik and Sahal Moalim.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Francesco Graziani</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254715054136</telephone>
   <email>mogadishu.somalia@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippe Rougier</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252619304748</telephone>
   <email>somalia@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">348286.83</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">304037.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400310735">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-08">8754.71</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12352">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">652324.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303996792">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-20">391394.46</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304584729">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-05-01">260929.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
