<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/RA2/Shelter/NGO/13285</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of  Emergency Shelter and NFI to displaced persons affected by by drought and conflict  in Merka district, Lower Shabelle region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will involve the distribution of  750 NFI kits to  750 HH  (4500 people) displaced by repeated conflict and drought in  Merka districts in Lower Shabelle region (6 IDP Camps in Merka town namely  Aw yaalle , Nurta Taliyow, Buufow Bacaad, Aw beylow, Tima Cadde and Isman Kunle 
 beneficiaries will be targeted based on vulnerability criteria that will prioritize women headed households, the elderly and children headed households especially girls. The beneficiaries will be distributed equally with each benificiary getting NFI kit comprising 1 Plastic Sheet, 3Blanket, 2 Sleeping mat, , 1Kitchen Set, 1 Mosquito nets, 1 Solar Lumps, 2 Cherrycans
AYUUB will closely coordinate with Other Agencies distributing NFI&apos;s in the areas and start the project implementation with community consultations and coordination with Local Authority to identify vulnerable people displaced by the drought. This will include consultations with local authorities, community elders and host communities to identify and register the most vulnerable people for NFIs support.
The project implementation will involve the following activities:
1. Beneficiaries registration: AYUUB will hold consultations with community members to jointly determine the targeting criteria, identify the most vulnerable and register beneficiaries for the NFIs and Shelter. AYUUB will prioritize the Most vulnerable people in the Targeted area . AYUUB will also target host communities to ensure that other vulnerable people within the target locations are also assisted based on needs and also avoid conflict between the host community and displaced people, the Host Communties are among in the IDP Camps.
We Consider Protection in our Shelter activities, during beneficiary identification we select beneficiaries with Specific needs, Marginalized communities, Female headed house hold and families with orphans, also during our community training we also ensure representation from all the above-mentioned groups.
2. NFIs Throug In Kind distribution: AYUUB will distribute NFIs through in Kind distribution to 750 households (4500 people) who include 1000 women, 800 men, 1400 girls, 1300 boys. The age and gender disaggregation is based on the demographic profile in Somalia and prioritization of women and girls who are the most affected by displacements. The actual gender and age breakdown will be reported once beneficiary registration is completed. 
AYUUB will promote the dignity of the beneficiaries by placing the decision of the content of priority NFIs in their best interests. The approach will empower displaced people in prioritizing needs and give them the power of making decisions for their needs and The proposed content in each set is based on current Shelter Cluster standards for people in humanitarian
emergencies. Since there are no functioning NFI markets in Merka twon,  AYUUB will  procure as in-kind modalityfor provision of NFIs

3. ESK Shelter Kit though in-kind distribution: - AYUUB Will distribute ESK kit through in Kind distribution   to 750 HH (4500 people) 1000 women, 800 men, 1400 girls, 1300 boys in Merka district and will be distributed to the same IDP HH received NFI Kits .
4. Post distribution monitoring: Each distribution will be followed with a post distribution monitoring to get feedback on the distribution process and utilization of the NFIs kits, one month after distribution.
5. AYUUB Will do Community consultations and Meetings for the respective Communities from the 6 IDP Settlements to support community consultations at the initial beneficiary identification and registration, and secure land tenure mainstreaming.
6. AYUUB Will provide cash assistant Support for Construction of Shelter Kits to the targeted Communities themselves and Will be trained 25 Community members&#x2019; on Basic construction of ESK (Emergency Shelter Kit) to construct themselves after the receive of Shelter through in Kind</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Yusuf Mohamed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615815907</telephone>
   <email>ayuubcenter@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Abdikadir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excutive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615808839</telephone>
   <email>ayuubngo@yahoo.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9669">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lower Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.74900000 44.39100000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-16">248409.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-16">50662.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-13285">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-16">299071.85</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304168398">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-26">179443.11</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304347962">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-29">119628.74</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AYUUB NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
