<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/R3/WASH/INGO/14532</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency WASH response to the population of Berdale affected by the floods.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The rains that have inundated parts of Somalia are expected to continue in November with moderate to heavy intensity, according to the FAO Managed Somalia Water and Land Information Management (SWALIM). Heavy rains of more than 100mm are expected in Hiraan, Bay and Bakool regions which are already saturated following weeks of continued heavy rains. In South West State, an estimated 70,000 people have been affected and another 40,000 displaced by flash flooding across the region. Berdale town (60 km west of Baidoa) is worst affected. Three quarters of the town is submerged. Local authorities and humanitarian partners estimate that 30,000 people have been affected. The road to Berdale is impassable. Humanitarian partners are working with authorities to scale up the response in the affected areas INTERSOS is targeting to provide emergency WASH response to the floods affected population in Berdale as in line with the needs assessment report conducted by Inter-Agency to quickly identify the vast damages affected by the floods and the priority needs to immediately intervene the humanitarian situation. The report highlighted that around 360 unprotected shallow wells, which is 85% of the total shallow wells in Berdale, have been submerged by the floodwater. The IDPs and Host communities in the district depends on boreholes and shallow wells as their main source of water which is critical to survive after it has been submerged by the flash floods. The price of one drum of water (200ltr) is 20,000 Somali shilling which is approximately 1 USD therefore, 95% of the Berdale residents have no access to safe water supply due to the pool stagnant water and submerged of all other shallow wells by the floods.

INTERSOS is the focal point for Berdale flood response in collaboration with all partners and cluster leads for distribution of hygiene kits, NFIs and medical supplies mobilized and channeled into INTERSOS. In this regards, INTERSOS will ensure to adhere and coordinate with other partners for identification of vulnerable communities and avoiding overlapping of responses and mitigating to improve the coordination system among partners on ground. 
  

The   objective of the response is to provide lifesaving emergency WASH assistance to 6500 HH from the  most vulnerable population affected by the floods in Berdale district to improve the access of clean and safe water through provision of water tracking, hygiene promotion and shallow wells rehabilitations. The proposed response aims to increase the access of clean safe water to the community and decreases the acute watery diarrhea/cholera outbreaks and waterborne diseases, which is one of the priorities in the HRP strategy of INTERSOS and in line with the SHF reserve allocation of 2019 for the flood response. The project will enable INTERSOS to convert proposed immediate needs outlined by the Inter-agency report into immediate interventions to respond the floods affected communities in Berdale.  

INTERSOS will address the sanitation and hygiene practices among the target beneficiaries through hygiene promotion, distribution of hygiene kits and provision of water purified tablets and water treatment of all water sources through training of water management committees, community volunteers and hygiene promoters with water treatment and chlorination. The project also targets to improve the knowledge, attitude and practices of the community for sanitation and hygiene practices at community and household level to ensure access in water quality and enhancing the level of understanding to the community in public ownership for regular monitoring and supervision. 
Throughout this proposed lifesaving assistance, INTERSOS will provide WASH packages and services to approximately 25,000 beneficiaries (host community and IDPs) of which 8,937 are women and 7,313 men. 4,812 out of the targeted proposed beneficiaries are girls and 3,938 will be boys  . 

30 community volunteers will be trained</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippe Rougier</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252619304748</telephone>
   <email>somalia@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">49342.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">450657.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-14532">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304363939">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-06">200000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
