<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/R3/H-Nut/INGO/14605</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Emergency Lifesaving Health services integrated with Nutrition promotion activities to Floods affected population in Berdale by Establishing 4 Mobile Clinics and one fixed facility supported by a network of Community Volunteers (CVs)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The rains that have inundated parts of Somalia are expected to continue in November with moderate to heavy intensity, according to the FAO Managed Somalia Water and Land Information Management (SWALIM). Heavy rains of more than 100mm are expected in Hiraan, Bay and Bakool regions which are already saturated following weeks of continued heavy rains. In South West State, an estimated 70,000 people have been affected and another 40,000 displaced by flash flooding across the region. Berdale town (60 km west of Baidoa) is worst affected. Three quarters of the town is submerged. Local authorities and humanitarian partners estimate that 30,000 people have been affected. The road to Berdale is impassable. Humanitarian partners are working with authorities to scale up the response in the affected areas INTERSOS is targeting to provide emergency lifesaving integrated health and nutrition services to the floods affected population in Berdale by establishing four mobile clinics and fixed facility supported by a network of community volunteers. 

HEALTH: The proposed project will support 4 Mobile Clinics and one fixed facility in Berdale district with the aim to deliver an integrated package of promotive, preventive and curative services through facility-based and community-based care. Specifically, general consultations, ANC/PNC/Delivery and basic life-saving treatment for those who suffer from common diseases such as AWD/ Cholera, malaria, respiratory tract infections, Routine immunization for children and pregnant mothers. The Mobile Clinics will work with a network of community volunteers in IDPs and host community to improve community sensitization and referral of severe cases and pregnant mothers to the MCH for safe delivery and neonatal care. The CVs/clinical staffs will be provided CP/GBV mainstreaming training to strengthen the referral cases of GBV survivors and clinical management in coordinating with the protection team for Psycho-social Support (PSS) and case management.   

NUTRITION: The proposed  activities will be integrated with the health interventions with an aim to address the underlying causes of high levels malnutrition as well as to enable early identification for screening in targeted IDPs for floods affected population in Berdale district. This program will establish a strong community network through competent CNVs for early detection and referral of children, PLWs with acute malnutrition for active ongoing nutrition services provided by other partners. IYCF counseling will be provided at community in outreach and facility level for effective mobilization on the optimal nutritional feeding to under five children.

INTERSOS is the focal point for Berdale flood response in collaboration with all partners and cluster leads for distribution of hygiene kits, NFIs and medical supplies mobilized and channeled into INTERSOS. In this regards, it will ensure to adhere and coordinate with other partners for identification of vulnerable communities and avoiding overlapping of responses and mitigating to improve the coordination system among partners on ground. 

Through this project, a total of 40,000 (35,000 IDPs and 5,000 Host communities) floods affected individuals in Berdale will have access to a package of Emergency lifesaving integrated health with nutrition services in six months period. The BLS ambulances will provide referral services from IDPs to the fixed facility (MCH) to improve access to the integrated package for the vulnerable community prioritizing to rapidly refer the critical cases (priority will be given to under 5 children and pregnant women). It is estimated to provide BLS services to over 300 critical/emergency medical cases. The project will establish an efficient outreach and referral mechanism from community based to primary healthcare amp for primary to secondary health services through a network of CVs and through the BLS capacity of the Mobile Clinics vehicles for patient transportation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippe Rougier</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252619304748</telephone>
   <email>somalia@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9664">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bay</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.67600000 43.73800000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="70" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="30" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-09">42624.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-09">346675.91</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-14605">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-09">389300</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304368544">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-10">155720</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304716481">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-01">233580</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
