<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/RA2/Prot/INGO/13255</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening integrated protection services for the drought and conflict affected IDPs through prevention and response to gender-based violence (GBV), and mitigation of child protection risks in Wajid and Balad Districts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under this action, INTERSOS proposes to strengthen and improve the protective environment of vulnerable people in areas affected by drought and/or conflict from further risks of exclusion, exploitation and violence in Wajid , xudur nd Balad Districts.This project seeks to sustain, strengthen and scale up lifesaving protection services in Wajid and Xudur IDPs to prevent and respond to protection risks/concerns experienced by women, men, children and persons living with disabilities affected by droughts and conflicts especially among Internally Displaced People and host populations. The project also seeks to conduct protection monitoring in Balad, Xudur and Wajid in order to provide critical protection related data to inform future interventions due to both absence of protection related information and to the increasing influx of newly conflict displaced people into the District witnessed in the last months. 

Jointly with the protection monitoring activities, the key focus of the project will be providing Case management services for UASC through immediate care, referrals and family tracing as well as response to GBV survivors. The project will establish referral system in schools and support community-based Child Protection Mechanisms for quick and efficient referrals of children with protection needs through service mapping within the community and in the schools (community child protection committees and School Management Committees). This project will strengthen service mapping to facilitate appropriate referrals, coordination and linkages in service delivery to ensure quality comprehensive services to unaccompanied and separated children (children at risk of being recruited by armed forces or armed groups and gender based violence (GBV) survivors. The project will further improve prevention and response to separation of children from their families through family tracing and reunification activities and provision of comprehensive case management and psycho-social support including emergency care, referral to INTERSOS medical teams trained in CMR, access tailored material assistance, and follow up on the services for gender based violence survivors. Capacity building of CPWG to strengthen and improve identification of cases and increase their knowledge on child protection minimum standards will also be provided. Moreover, by promoting meaningful access, safety and dignity in our intervention.
INTERSOS will conduct awareness that will focus on rights of children and men and women, roles and responsibilities of children, causes and consequence of separation as well as consequences of the incidences of gender based violence, Mine risk education, identification and reporting unaccompanied and separated children and GBV survivors, services available for Gender Based Violence survivors and unaccompanied and separated children as well as appropriate referrals in place in the target location. 
Moreover, based on the lessons learnt from the previous SHF and UNFPA funded project in the same target location, there is need to scale up protection activities including improving the quality of response services, particularly medical care, psycho social support, case management and emergency safe spaces.

Furthermore, In Balad, Xudur and Wajid, INTERSOS will conduct and strengthen protection monitoring in areas of settlement of returnees and IDPs through community based protection monitors working with CSOs in order to ensure that quality evidence based reports about protection issues and human rights violations and systematic collection of protection related data are produced to inform better response and advocacy. This action aims at responding to the current crisis of newly conflict displaced people that are coming to the District from nearby villages in order to seek refuge.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdirahman Nunow</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252617919555</telephone>
   <email>protection.somalia@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippe Rougher</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254734000710</telephone>
   <email>somalia@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9661">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bakool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.28000000 43.80700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-23">179519.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-23">170543.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1704458207">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-19">14167.63</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-13255">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-23">350063.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304169370">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-26">140025.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304622070">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-02">210038.33</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
