<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/Nut/INGO/12478</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated lifesaving Nutrition Project aimed at reducing morbidity and related mortality, with a strong community component to vulnerable communities in Hobyo district, Mudug Region of Somalia.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Nutrition and health situation remains fragile in Hobyo with children and women being most vulnerable. The key issues for children and women remain access to prevention and treatment interventions in the absence of a fully functional health system. Tied to that is minimal capacity available in the nutrition and health sector and  poor community literacy levels  (UNICEF 2018 WHO 2017). Malnutrition is one of the key issues affecting children 6-59 moths and significantly contributing to mortality, considering relationship between malnutrition and disease (UNICEF,2018, FSNAU,2018).
 Although there has been progress noted in service provision and policy development in Somalia including: roll out of national development plan with inclusion of a section on Nutrition and mainstreaming it to sectors (SNDP,2017), 2017-20 health sector strategic plan (FMoH,2017) and other health related policies, frameworks and guidelines,a lot still needs to be done to actualized these.
Its important to note that disparities in health outcomes among Somali children and women still exist. These are based on: their exposure to violence and insecurity, access, gender and ethnic groupings, and the stability of communities/clan structure. Addressing these inequities, remains a priority (UNICEF,2018). This brings to light the fact that the situation in Hobyo  could be worse than national statistics considering that factors mentioned above fully exist here.
Services in Hobyo barely reach rural areas because of poor infrastructure and harsh climate conditions. Therefore poor performing indicators like: Poor IYCF, low latrine coverage,low immunization coverage, severe food shortages and poor coverage of nutrition service/health facility are reported (WHO,2018SAF UK,2018 SARA ,2016 FSNAU,2019). There are reports of drought and food shortages causing many to leave there homes in search of food and water. The is therefore need for urgent attention if the situation is to be controlled.
Gender issues that lock out significant others increasing negative social pressure on women not to adapt behaviors beneficial to health, should be addressed for positive nutrition outcomes to be realized. Finally capacity of service providers and locals communities to control malnutrition should be improved for quality service, resilient communities and sustainable projects.
The proposed interventions will link with  cluster objective one, two and four, and SHF 2019 1 standard allocation core elements  one,three, four, five and six, which cover provision of immediate life saving and time critical interventions, focus on communities affected by deteriorating nutrition of GAMgt15% , integration of services across sectors, protection mainstreaming and rapid response  enabling the most urgent scaling up of essential humanitarian activities,
Interventions will also seek to provide primary ,secondary and tertiary prevention for acute malnutrition, build resilience to cushion against shocks in future and provide a platform to discuss and initiate durable solutions  in conjunction with other clusters and relevant bodies thus preventing shocks and ensuring protection.
SAF UK has been implementing nutrition (OTP,TSFP,MCHN and BSFP) and health projects in north Hobyo for 2 years, but only covering  Afbarwaqo and surrounding villages, reporting huge impact 
This proposed project seeks to scale up treatment of MAM beyond our current coverage through additional 3 fixed sites in health facilities and 4 mobile sites to access hard to reach areas. Additionally,the current  supplementary feeding project funded by WFP expires on 30th March 2019. We hope to sustain these services (TSFP,MCHN and BSFP) ,avoiding gaps. 
Our proposal is  to provide supplementary feeding interventions (TSFP,MCHN and BSFP)  further integrating with health  project in all proposed sites for cost effective sustainable project</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdiaziz Mohamed Hashi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excecutive director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254725449441</telephone>
   <email>info@safuk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Everlyne Adhiambo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254721498706</telephone>
   <email>programs@safuk.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9672">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mudug</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.49100000 48.01000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-15">236131.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-11-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-15">325560.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12478">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-15">561692.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304003469">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-22">224676.89</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304453160">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-21">168507.67</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills Active Forward Kenya</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
