<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/FSC/INGO/12430</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the immediate access to food, protect and restore livelihood-related food and income sources, and improve the resilience of acutely food insecure people (urban and rural IDPs) against shocks in Galkacyo and Galdogob districts in Mudug region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In alignment with the Somalia Humanitarian Fund&#x2019;s Allocation Strategy and the specific strategy of the Food Security cluster, Mercy Corps proposes to address immediate emergency food security needs, enhance recovery and prevent wide-scale food insecurity for 1 940 vulnerable rural and urban IDP households in Galkayo,Hobyo and Galdogob districts of Mudug region over a period of 6 months,based on a household average household size of 6,this translates to 11 640 individual men,women,boys and girls. Improved access to food by vulnerable households in IPC phase 3 and 4 through an emergency food security response that combine food vouchers, creation of short-term employment for the rehabilitation of prioritized community infrastructures through cash for work and access to livelihoods assets especially donkey carts will reduce hunger, improves dietary diversity and food consumption score at household level. The project will also mainstream stream protection and nutrition through conducting GBV campaigns and nutrition messaging. Mercy Corps will use community based targeting to ensure traditionally marginalized and vulnerable groups such as female headed-households, people with disabilities, elders, pregnant and lactating mothers, children, and minority clans are included. The project seeks to achieve the following outcomes:

Outcome 1: Vulnerable, marginalized and food insecure conflict and drought -affected households, including female-headed households are able to meet their immediate food security and other basic needs through food vouchers and cash for work activities. Accordingly,1220 households will receive a food voucher equivalent to USD $65 per month (70% of the minimum expenditure basket) for 5 months to enable the vulnerable displaced families meet their basic food needs and 700 households will participate in cash for work activities to earn unrestricted wage which improves their access to food and also rehabilitate critical infrastructure required to sustain livelihoods. The selected households, with a specific focus on the inclusion of youth and women who are able and fit to work will participate in the rehabilitation of basic community infrastructures prioritized by the community:6 feeder roads, 6 rain water catchment in IDP camps and 6 solid waste site in IDP camps through Cash-for-Work activities. The participants will include both skilled and unskilled labor to ensure inclusiveness, balance of skill which is required for quality of the rehabilitation. Each pre-registered person will work for 20 days per month and get a wage equivalent to 70% of the cost of the total Minimum Expenditure Basket paid through the mobile money transfer system averaging $65. CFW will take place during low labor demand periods, when target populations are typically not busy with their other economic activities. This outcome directly contributes to cluster objective of improving households&#x2019; immediate access to food through provision of conditional and unconditional assistance depending on the severity of food insecurity phases, vulnerability and seasonality of the livelihoods.

Outcome 2: Improve household and community resilience to shocks through access to productive assets. This will enhance livelihood strategies and strengthen household economy, accordingly 20  women headed households will have access to productive assets(donkey carts) and able to generate adequate income to be economically empowered,access food and to be resilience to the effects of drought ,floods and conflict . This is contributing to the Food Security Cluster objective of supporting household and community resilience to shocks through rehabilitation and/or restoration of productive assets, enhance livelihood strategies and disaster preparedness.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Daud Jiran</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 619933355</telephone>
   <email>djiran@mercycorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">John Mubonderi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Team Leader-Humanitarian Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254791874207</telephone>
   <email>jmubonderi@mercycorps.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9672">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mudug</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.49100000 48.01000000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">599999.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12430">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">599999.3</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304028452">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-06">479999.44</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304574487">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-22">107994.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mercy Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
