<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/FSC/NGO/12491</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Life-saving Emergency response for reducing food consumption gaps and restoring livelihoods most severely affected communities in 13 villages of Lughaya district of Awdal RegionLife-saving Emergency response for reducing food consumption gaps and restoring livelihoods most severely affected communities in 13 villages of Lughaya district of Awdal Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is in compliance with the core elements of the integrated approach and is in line with First Standard Allocation in 2019 and its strategies and cluster objectives by focusing immediate life-saving time-critical interventions of rapid response and enabling the most urgent scaling up of essential humanitarian activities in the target areas. The project activities aligned with the SHF Approach/Objective and HRP January to December 2019 intervention response priorities where 26,000 are in acute food insecurity and in phase 4 of emergency in Lughaya district are facing food-insecure as reported by SHF First Standard Allocation in 2019, Humanitarian Response Plan 2019 and Food Security Outlook Oct 2018 to May 2019. 
The project is in response of acute food insecurity facing pastoral and agro pastoral households who lost their livestock due to floods and wind of the tropical cyclone Sagar. The project is addressing 800  Households in 13 villages in Lughaya district total of 4,800 persons of 18.46% of the 26,000 in Lughaya surrounding and in the Guban Pastoral Livelihood Zone, which is break downed as follows:-
Men 912, Women 1,248, Boys 1,200, Girls 1,440 total of  4,800 persons. The project is in response to integrated SHF First Standard Allocation in 2019, Humanitarian Response Plan 2019 and Food Security Outlook Oct 2018 to May 2019. The project is addressing Food insecurity in Lughaya district of Awdal region, in the Guban Pastoral livelihood zone by undertaking the following activities of the Food Security cluster response priorities: 
i) 500 HHs of 3,000 persons will benefit from the provision of unconditional transfers (food assistance for cash) in seven villages of Osoli 80 HHs, Kalabaydh 80 HHs, Kuure 50 HHs, Idocadeys/Maame 80 HHs, Hulka 60 HHs, Lancawale 60 HHs and Geeriza 100 HHs, the target households are facing acute food insecurity. Food Security Objective 1 (IPC 3-5) relates to SO1 amp SO2.
Provision of unconditional transfers of food assistance for cash value of $71.00 per HHs X 500 HHs X 3 Months, and is focusing lifesaving services of reversing food consumption gaps for the period up to Gu rains of 2019.
ii) 260 HHs of 1,560 persons will benefit from conditional transfers (cash-for-work for small-scale infrastructure repairs) in six villages of which two villages of Xajjinle 50 HHs and Abdi Geedi 50 HHs will work on Cash-for-work by clearing Prosopis that threatens Agricultural areas and four villages of Balliga 40 HHs, Tuurka 40 HHs, Warabedareerey 40 HHs and Hul-xudhunle 40 HHs will benefit from cash-for-work through land preparation. Food Security Objective 1 (IPC 3-5) relates to SO1 amp SO2.
The provision of conditional transfers for cash-for-work will create source of income for most vulnerable with the focus of women headed households whose their source of income has been damaged with no other coping mechanism.
iii) 40 HHs of 240 persons will benefit provision of seasonally appropriate agricultural inputs (seeds, farm tools, training, land preparation and irrigation support) in four villages names Balliga 10 HHs, Tuurka 10 HHs, Warabedareerey 10 HHs and Hul-xudhunle 10 HHs will receive support to restore their livelihoods. Food Security objective 2 and (IPC 2-4) Relates to SO1 amp SO2.
The provision will restore source of income through support inputs of farm tools for 40 farms amongst most severely affected farmer in the targeted areas.
The proposed project is targeting 800 HHs of most vulnerable and severely affected currently facing acute food insecurity in Lughay district. The origin of the 800 HHs are divided 560 HHs of Pastoralist,40 HHs of Agro pastoral and 200 HHs of IDPs, whose facing serious food consumption gaps and belong the most severely affected communities in Lughaya district. Situation of targeted community is reported in Crisis (IPC Phase 3) and likely lead to Emergency (IPC Phase 4) if humanitarian assistance is not continued, as many still face large food consumption gaps,</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamoud Mohamed Duale</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+ 252 634415222</telephone>
   <email>mmducaale@taakulo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Omer Jama Farah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252634403137</telephone>
   <email>omer.farah@taakulo.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9660">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awdal</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.60200000 43.34900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">298979.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12491">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">298979.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303998567">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-20">239183.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304459958">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-24">54069.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400321590">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">1853.24</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taakulo Somaliland Community</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
