<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/FSC/NGO/12477</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food provision and resilience building for drought affected vulnerable rural and IDPs populations in Adaado district in Galgaduud region Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at improving food access for extremely food insecure and vulnerable 804 households (4824 persons - 1158 men, 1446 women, 1254 girls, 966 boys) through unconditional assistance using restricted food vouchers which the beneficiaries will use to redeem food items from food vendor (s), and conditional cash transfer through rehabilitation of five communal assets on a CfW basis.  The targeted people in Adaado district in Galgaduud are those who have been affected by the impacts of below-average Deyr seasonal (Oct to Dec 2018) rainfall and large-scale destitution and displacement due to conflict over resources resulting in food consumption gaps (i.e. poor FCS, high CSI, and severe hunger) increased debt accumulation, and depletion of livelihood assets for e.g. reduction in household herds.  They are the weakest and most vulnerable families that are not able to meet the Minimum Expenditure Basket (MEB) or are not able to meet the minimum living threshold of 2100Kcal per person per day. 
The response will also help stabilize stressed and crisis affected communities and prevent populations from migrating to urban centres in search of food and other services as well as cushion against future shocks.  The intervention will target the following  villages around  Biyogaduud (Bali-cad, TuuloSarman, Hulkujir, Towfiq, Dhuumodle) Habaasley near Gidhays Beendhaarte near Dayaano  and Wadgalinsoor village. The project has 2 components:  
1). Unconditional but restricted food assistance for 600 HHs (approximately 3600 people) &#x2013; The proposed unconditional food vouchers will provide for some basic food needs and render a level of dignity to  women headed households (60%), the elderly and disabled  who are the most affected and whose pre-occupation is meeting their daily food needs due to the precarious nature of pastoralism livelihoods in rural Adaado districts. These households will receive unconditional monthly food vouchers valued at USD 95 per month for 3 months. The value of USD 95 value accounts for 100% of food MEB and was determined by Somalia Cash Working Group (CWG Nov 2017). The voucher value will allow families to receive food items consisting of 90kg of rice, 6kg of pulses, 6 litres of oil, and 3kg of sugar from selected food vendor (s).
2). Conditional cash for  204 HHs ( approximately 1224 people) - These are HHs who are food insecure but have human capital and therefore CfW gives an opportunity for income to purchase essential food items and possibly build up a small asset base that might make them more resilient in the face of another shock. This component of the project, will target the poor but able beneficiaries who can conduct labour work. A total of  204 beneficiaries  will benefit from 30 days&#x2019; job opportunity. Each beneficiary will excavate a soil volume of 1m3 a day at a value of $ 5per day for 30 days for unskilled workers (payment will be made twice for 15 days worked per month for 2 months) and 7 USD for skilled workers. The daily wages are based on agreed work norms in line with food security cluster standards which are based on the prevailing cost of the MEB baskets across the target district. Cash payments will be through EVC money transfer system which is proven to be reliable, safe, and less vulnerable to diversions compared to direct payments.  As well, 2 Water Users&#x2019; Committees (WUC) will be formed for each of the water pans and their capacity in water management and maintenance will be improved.
This project is designed to be implemented in 6 months. Food provision will run for 3 months, while  rehabilitation of community water pans will be rehabilitated during the lean dry Hagaa season after the rain season. The last month of the project is for closure and hand over hence the total project period of 6 months.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Life and Agricultural Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Life and Agricultural Development Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-07" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fredrick Monari</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 722 770539</telephone>
   <email>monarifm@sadosomalia.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9665">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Galgaduud</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.26500000 46.64700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-11-07"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-09">300000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12477">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-09">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Life and Agricultural Development Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303993210">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-17">180000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Life and Agricultural Development Organisation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
