<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/R3/Shelter-CCCM/INGO/14521</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Emergency Response for Flood-Affected People in Beletweyne (Shelter and Non-food Items and Camp Coordination  Camp Management)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased rainfall since the beginning of September in both Ethiopian highlands and within the catchments in Somalia has resulted in a sharp rise in the Shabelle and Juba rivers, leading to severe flooding in southern and central Somalia. According to UNHCR-Protection Return Monitoring Network (PRMN), the recent Shabelle river flooding displaced over 270,000 people, of whom 230,000 are in Beletweyne District. Farmland, infrastructure and roads have been destroyed, and livelihoods disrupted in some of the worst-hit areas. According to the FAO-led Somalia Water and Land Information Management (SWALIM), the rains are projected to continue in the coming weeks and it is expected to end in early December. DRC proposes to undertake a life-saving and sustainable assistance to Flood- Displaced people in Beletweyne through provision of emergency shelter kits (ESK), non-food items (NFIs). DRC will target 2050 households (12,300 people) with ESK and NFIs. The standard emergency NFI package will include plastic sheeting, blankets, sleeping mats, kitchen set, mosquito net, solar lamp and Jerry cans. Where possible, DRC will give the NFIs through cash transfers or vouchers so that beneficiaries can decide based on their needs. DRC will also assist with a standard ESK that contains: Local available stick for vertical post (Philippian Tree) Local available sticks for truss, door and windows (Philippian Tree) or White wood (8cm x 4cm size each) Local available sticks (Philippian Tree) for horizontal frames amp roofing or White wood (5cm x 2.5cm size each) Local available sticks (Philippian Tree) at the base of roof truss or White wood (10cm x 2.5cm size each) Nails No. 5 (5 inch) Nails No. 6 (6 inch) Drum door with frame Hinges for door Local plastic sheet (size: 4m x 7m) and outer wall clothing Buul layer. This provides the most basic shelter which can offer protection from extreme weather. The ESK helps the displaced household to put up by a 4m x 4m shelter structure within the first few days of displacement. DRC is aware that the needs are huge and the available funding cannot cover everyone. DRC is also aware that families of affected persons are normally the first responders and therefore, some families may be better positioned to survive such disaster due to their own social networks. Therefore DRC will develop a selection criteria based on AGD as well as vulnerability to ensure that assistance goes to the ones who deserve it most. Female-headed households, families with many children and the aged (65+ year-olds) will be given priority. DRC will also ensure that, persons living with disabilities (PLDs) or families with such persons are also targeted with assistance.  Families considered extremely vulnerable, will be assisted by DRC to put up their shelter through cash paid after erection. DRC determines that this cash shall be 60 USD and targets 540 hhs out of 2050 hhs. DRC will undertake a post-distribution monitoring (PDM) study four (4) weeks after distribution to measure the effectiveness of distribution and also the satisfaction of the beneficiaries on the items distributed. This will help inform future programming in shelter, NFIs and CCCM programming. Specific to CCCM, DRC shall engage in installation of solar lights and in settlement maintenance including clearance of any solid waste and access roads. DRC will also, jointly with the camp/settlement committees undertake mapping of available services and establish a referral system. Through that, DRC will establish information boards at strategic points like social centers like water points and markets for people to have easy access to information. DRC will support community governance structures through trainings to ensure that camp/settlement committees can manage their daily issues in a structured manner. At sub-national level, DRC will ensure coordination of CCCM meetings happen and deliberations are reported.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lugard Kaunda Ogaro</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH  Infrastructure Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254712655045</telephone>
   <email>lugard.ogaro@drc.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Muse Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy Head of Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252907788434</telephone>
   <email>mohamed.muse@drc.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">William Babumba</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252 612500752</telephone>
   <email>william.babumba@drc.ngo</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9667">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hiraan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>4.22300000 45.37600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="15" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="4" percentage="85" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">116970.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">830487.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-14521">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">947457.68</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304363938">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-06">568474.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304940784">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-15">366227.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Danish Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
