<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/WASH/NGO/12405</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of sustained access to safe water and adequate sanitation to crisis-affected population in Jowhar district, Middle Shabelle region.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims at providing reliable and sustained access to safe water and adequate sanitation facilities to target population residing in nine riverine villages in Jowhar district that are facing water shortages and have limited access to sanitation facilities. The target population was heavily affected by floods that occurred in 2018 where water supply infrastructures and sanitation facilities were severely damaged and are yet to be repaired. Poor rainfall received during the 2018 Deyr season and the ongoing dry conditions has resulted in critical water shortages and a rapid decline in the remaining water reservoirs in Jowhar district. The river Shabelle that is the main source of water and a vital source of livelihood for communities residing along the river has dried up once again in now four consecutive years.

In this context, WOCCA will implement a WASH cluster-specific intervention aimed at providing sustained access to safe water through the rehabilitation of 22 strategic wells and fitted with hand pumps. To reduce pressure on the few functioning wells 2 shallow wells will be constructed in Bardheere and Nuukay village. A water distribution system that will include pipeline extension, overhead tank and water kiosk with 8taps and a solar pumping system will be installed in Nuukay village so that more people including neighboring pastoral communities can benefit from the water since the well has a good yield. In Gashaanle village rehabilitation of a shallow well, water tank, kiosk, and installation of a solar pumping system will be done. Identification of these targeted locations for construction and rehabilitation was done in consultation with the community elders and the local authority. The water sources will be located 30m away from latrines to avoid contamination. Dewatering of the rehabilitated/constructed shallow wells and application of shock chlorination will be done to ensure that the water is safe for consumption. 

To strengthen community ownership and ensure sustainability of WASH assets 130 Water management committee members (at least 40% of women) will be trained on operation, maintenance and safe water storage. The project staff and WMC members will be trained on DRR and protection mainstreaming. 310 gender-sensitive latrines with hand-washing facilities, raised to avoid flooding and fitted with locks from the inside to curb GBV will be constructed in the targeted villages. Women, girls and vulnerable groups will be consulted in siting and design of the WASH infrastructures to maximize safety, privacy and dignity. To ensure the WASH infrastructures endure future floods, WOCCA will incorporate DRR aspects in the design of the WASH infrastructures. Sensitization meetings will be held at the inception of the project with all project stakeholders including groups at risk of exclusion to inform them about the project objectives, scope, beneficiary selection criteria, and beneficiary entitlement and roles. Accountability to the affected population will be enhanced through the provision of a feedback hotline to beneficiaries where they can provide feedback and complaints. To ensure quality in the project outputs the project staff will continuously monitor and report on project indicators. WOCCA will also share GPS coordinates of all WASH structures and monthly project reports with the WASH cluster and donor. Signing off and handing over of WASH structures to beneficiaries upon completion will be done through community elders, government officials and religious leaders. WOCCA will also adhere to the principles of &quot;Do no harm&quot; through not creating any partial, nepotism, conflict-oriented and sensitive issues within the project beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-04" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sarah Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254714796100</telephone>
   <email>nairobi@woccaorg.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Robbert van der Steeg</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254 734 775 122</telephone>
   <email>robbert.vandersteeg@woccaorg.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">263013.83</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">136986.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12405">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-13">400000.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304003077">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-21">160000.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304368543">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-10">120000.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304712851">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-28">117745.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women and Child Care Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
