<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/R3/Prot/NGO/14535</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of integrated protection services for the flood affected IDPs through prevention and response to gender-based violence (GBV), and mitigation of child protection risks in Jowhar and Balcad Districts of Middle Shabelle including Buurfule .</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is aimed to deliver lifesaving emergency protection services to vulnerable flood affected population in Jowhar and Balcad districts of Middle Shabelle region. The project will benefit and support to 4215 which include (men 15, women 2000, boys 1120, and 1080 girls) of flood affected IDPs and vulnerable host communities. 

The proposed project is designed to strengthen and improve protective environment of vulnerable IDPs displaced as a result of the severe flooding situation in Jowhar and Balcad districts of Middle Shabelle region. This project will sustain, scale up lifesaving gender-based violence (GBV) and child protection services including case referral and case management particularly for GBV survivors and family separation. The intervention will respond to protection risks/concerns experienced by women, men, girls and boys affected by the floods especially those among the internally displaced persons and host communities in the key displacement/evacuation areas. 

The key focus of this project will be providing Case management services for unaccompanied or separated children (UASC) through immediate response for child and family separation as well as provide equitable, timely and accessible GBV services for women, men, boys and girls through provision of live-saving medical services, and Identification and PSS Counselor training will be conducted to provide counseling training to traumatized women and girls affected by the flood in the targeted project areas, Psychosocial support will be provided to children and caregivers to protect and promote children&#x2019;s wellbeing and full participation. Psychosocial support will focus on engagement of children, caregivers and families through restoring, strengthening and mobilising family and community systems by:  reducing and preventing harm strengthening resilience to recover from the impact of the drought and improving the care conditions that enable children and families to survive and thrive. . The project will also strengthen confidential reporting and referral mechanisms which are accessible to women and children, linked to comprehensive response mechanisms for GBV. The community-based child protection committees will be established in the community to facilitate identification and efficient referral of children with protection concerns or needs as well as provide timely response and appropriate care to survivors of GBV.New Ways will establish two outreach mobile teams who will have the capacity to deliver clinics and comprehensive GBV services in flood affected remote villages of Jowhar and Balcad districts. Each GBV mobile team will consisting of 4 female and 1 male (1 community mobilizer, 1 caseworker, 1 PSS, 1 nurse and 1 adolescent girls assistant) to provide comprehensive response mechanisms for GBV and strengthen confidential reporting and referral mechanisms 

The project will further improve prevention and response to separation of children from their families through identification, family tracing and reunification activities and provision of comprehensive case management and psycho-social support including emergency care, and referral to foster families in Jowhar and Balcad district. New Ways will establish temporary Child Friendly Spaces (CFS) in targeted flood affected areas to support children wellbeing, emotional needs through provision of psychosocial support and recreational activities. 

New Ways will enhance monitoring of GBV and child protection concerns in the displacement/evacuation areas through community based child protection focal points and local community structures. The local coordination mechanisms will be utilized with aim of improving standard/quality of services and ensuring systematic collection of GBV and Child Protection related data to inform better response and advocacy</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Ways Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Ways Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Abdirahman Mohamed Haider</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+252615508193</telephone>
   <email>info@new-ways.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdulahi Ali</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254725058419</telephone>
   <email>new.ways.org@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9671">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Shabelle</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.82500000 45.93700000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">62201.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">188679.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-14535">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-05">250881.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Ways Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304363942">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-06">200704.86</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Ways Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304641118">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-16">43253</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Ways Organization</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
