<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/H/INGO/12472</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of essential health services to drought affected communities in Sanag and Sool region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will be an a rapid response integrated health, wash and nutrition project which will target the  16 villages under Badhan, Bocame and lascanood  districts identified by the MOH as experiencing huge health and nutrition service gaps. Care will  focus on health system strengthening activities which will include the provision of equitable access to basic and emergency health services  in 16 villages through static and mobile health teams with focus on children under 5 and PLWs. 

CARE will support the provision of care for communicable diseases at all sites. The focus of this intervention will be to treat and prevent common causes of morbidity and mortality. This intervention will seek to prioritize the provision of care and immunization for children lt5 years of age, pregnant and lactating women.  Diagnosis and treatment of common causes of morbidity, including diarrhea, ARI, malaria, and other targeted illnesses will take place according to IMCI guidelines. Monthly data to the respective District Health Management Information System (DHMIS) will be submitted as well as weekly surveillance data to WHO with MOH officials in copy to support the established CSR/Early Warning and Response Network (EWARNS) mechanism in Somalia. CARE will also train and support staff in completion of DHMIS reports during the MCH training and in subsequent monitoring to ensure accurate data collection. Outbreak investigation, rumor verification, timely response and control of communicable disease in conjunction with other stakeholders and clusters will be done.


Care will support community health activities including the provision of individual and group counselling on positive heath practices supporting the provision of community links to basic health, nutrition, IYCF and WASH care and sensitization. To extend case management of childhood illness beyond health facilities, Community Health Workers (CHWs) will be trained on prevalent conditions such as management of fever, diarrhea and respiratory illnesses, and malaria. They will also refer all pregnant women to health facilities for care and encourage safe deliveries at facilities. The focus will be on early case identification and treatment, referral and compliance to treatment using the community&#x2019;s own mechanisms. CHWs will be trained on referral systems, and equipped with referral slips and a register to refer cases to the static MCHs. CHWs will be tasked with dissemination of pertinent health information, including preventive reproductive health and immunization activities, and in disease surveillance.

Reproductive health services will be provided and include the provision of equitable access to prenatal and postnatal health services provision of access to facility-based safe deliveries at static sites training of health staff on early detection, treatment and referral of pregnancy-related complications. CARE will establish referral pathways for CEMOC and complicated IMCI cases to three district hospitals currently supported by CARE (Lascanood, Erigavo and Badhan).  CARE will therefore support training for service providers focused on Clinical Management of Rape (CMR), psycho social support in coordination with GBV working groups in target areas.CARE will conduct training  for midwives and nurses in collaboration with CARE protection team, MOH and UNFPA on CMR. Targeted health workers will be sensitized about the health consequences of GBV and trained to identify and refer GBV survivors, while ensuring confidentiality and respect, response to survivors in a non-stigmatized way and provision of clinical care.  The health workers will also refer identified cases of rape to other services for survivors of sexual violence including safety planning, psychosocial support and other social and legal services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdinur Elmi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Humanitarian Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+254715816381</telephone>
   <email>Elmi.nur@Care.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9674">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanaag</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.25900000 47.48300000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="9675">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sool</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.72400000 47.52900000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">225715.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">161073.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12472">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-28">386788.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304028444">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-06">232073.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304792801">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-18">154618.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE Somalia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
