<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM-19/3485/SA1/WASH/INGO/12410</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide life-saving and sustainable WASH services for the vulnerable drought and conflict displaced populations in Bari</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to Humanitarian Dashboard (issued on 22 February 2019) by the Somalia WASH Cluster, several regions of Somaliland and Puntland are experiencing severe shortage of water, due to the over-exploitation of already-limited resources and the breakdown of equipment &#x2013; the construction and restoration of water points are subsequently needed. The 2018 Deyr rainy season (October-December) was poor, with parts of Puntland receiving only 25-50% of average rainfall. Some regions have experienced drought for several seasons. Bari is among the regions worst affected by poor rains, with large moisture deficits and drought conditions.

The recurrent drought together with nutrition crises and other natural emergencies combined with poor WASH coverage and influx of internally displaced people (IDP) in target regions of Bari including Ishkushuban, Bosasso (IDPs), Qardho (IDPs) highlight the need for Save the Children to continue providing emergency services to vulnerable communities. 

Therefore, Save the Children is proposing a 12 months WASH project targeting drought and conflict affected communities in Bari regions targeting Ishkushuban, Bosasso (IDPs), Qardho (IDPs) to provide immediate life-saving WASH services to the most vulnerable members of the community, reaching a total of 48,889 individuals (men: 14,373, women: 14,960, boys: 9,778 and girls: 9,778).

The proposed project aims to provide lifesaving emergency and sustainable WASH service through drilling of two new strategic boreholes and rehabilitation of three strategic boreholes complete with hybrid power system (solar and diesel power), distribution systems, storage tanks and new water kiosks, and rehabilitation of rain water harvesting berkeds in rural target communities. The project will also improve overall hygiene and sanitation of the target communities through the construction of 150 shared household latrines  affected by the drought.

In terms of centrality and mainstreaming of protection, the project targets to reduce the risk of violence against women, children and vulnerable groups while accessing water and sanitation facilities by providing gender segregated facilities and establishing the facilities within 500 meters&#x2019; distance of the settlements. The project will also address gender issues by collecting gender and age disaggregated data. Save the Children will analyze this data to identify gaps, provide gender sensitive interventions and ensure participation and empowerment of women. Save the Children will ensure protection during access and utilization of services, to reduce the risk further. 

The project beneficiaries will be selected through a community consultative process with the community leaders and local authorities in order to ensure that only those who meet the specified vulnerability criteria including women and girls, people living with disability, people from minority clans, female headed households,  child-headed households,  survivors of sexual and gender base violence,  and households with a high number of dependents (children, elderly, people with disabilities, pregnant and lactating mothers will be given high priority. Save the Children will maintain and expand synergies across all the programs by ensuring that this project is implemented alongside the other emergency response programs, such as nutrition and health programs, to ensure that benefits arising out of multiple actions to the same target groups are exponentially increased.

The project is designed in such a way that while providing emergency lifesaving interventions it will also provide longer term sustainable solutions for affected population. To ensure the emergency interventions are linked to durable solutions, the project included construction, rehabilitation and upgrading of water supply systems and promotion</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-04" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-04" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition and WASH</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Health</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Binyam.Gebru@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Dr. Binyam Gebru</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Program Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Stephen.Mwangangi@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Stephen Mwangangi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="9663">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bari</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.64800000 50.23200000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-05-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-15">723289.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-15">376713.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400346639">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-26">192.6</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SOM21-12410">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-15">1100003.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304003465">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-22">880002.58</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304744950">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-28">190213.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somalia BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SOM21-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
