<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-16/DDA-3379/CP/NUTRITION/INGO/2324</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Emergency Nutrition and WASH Interventions in Sodo Woreda, Guraghe Zone, SNNPR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this project is to provide lifesaving emergency nutrition and WASH services, thereby contributing to reduction of morbidity and mortality associated with malnutrition amongst under-five children and pregnant and lactating women (PLW) in drought affected district, Sodo Woreda, Guraghe Zone, SNNPR. 
The project will mainly  focus on providing tailored and effective technical and logistics support to the WrHO to effectively treat and manage severe and moderate acute malnutrition (SAM and MAM) in children under five years and PLW. The project also work to minimize suffering associated with malnutrition in what is predicted to be a lengthy and worrying hunger season. WVE will support the WrHO to deliver high quality full CMAM services including treating severely malnourished children with medical complication in SC, treating and feeding malnourished children without complication at OTP, rehabilitating at risk and moderately malnourished children to prevent deterioration in to SAM through Targeted Supplementary Feeding Program (TSFP), and community mobilization in hot spot Priority 2 (P2) Woreda, Sodo Woreda in Guraghe Zone. 

The project will be implemented as the under-nutrition alongside the hunger season is expected to extend until the 2016 belg harvests. In order to attain the project objective, it employs core strategies including capacity building, community mobilization and participation strengthening the existing health programs and integration of CMAM in to various Areas Programs (APs) currently run by WVE. The project will directly benefit 2,699 children with SAM amp MAM and 1,525 malnourished PLW in the Woreda. This project prioritizes the most vulnerable groups of people &#x2013; children with high degree of vulnerability like children with disability as primary beneficiaries, particularly malnourished under-five children and pregnant and lactating women in all steps of the project implementation. In addition, the project is designed to integrate gender throughout the interventions. The project aims at achieving outputs including strengthened CMAM program, increased knowledge and skills on SAM and TSFP management, early detection and management of SAM children at SC/OTP and rehabilitated at risk and moderately malnourished children to prevent deterioration, and improve access to safe water supply. 
On&#x2013;the-job mentoring through supportive supervision by the Woredas Health offices focal persons, CMAM supervisors, and HEWs&#x2019; supervisor is an effective way of strengthening performance and one of the main ways WVE will apply to improve service quality in the intervention Woreda. HEWs will conduct community mobilization and train Health Development Armies (HDAs) who are assigned to households in the ratio of 1:5, in order to galvanize the efforts at household level and promote behavior change for appropriate health practices. This project will provide technical and logistical support to Woreda Health Office to support CMAM in 54 Health posts and 9 Health centers. 

Admission at OTP will be based on the national SAM management guidelines . All children with MUAC lt110 mm and/or bilateral pitting oedema and not suffering from medical complications will be treated as an outpatient at the nearest OTP sites. Therapeutic Feeding Unit referrals will also be rehabilitated in OTP once their condition has been stabilized and they can be managed using the OTP protocol. Admitted children will receive routine drugs (antibiotic, vitamin A, de-worming, anti-malarial, if required) and a weekly ration of RUTF i.e. 12.5kg/child/cure according to their body weight, and will be seen on a weekly basis until they meet their discharge criteria. Children will be discharged from OTP to TSFP when medically well and attain target weight (if admission is by MUAC) in two consecutive visits or once the child has reached 85% WFH without oedema in two subsequent follow ups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alex Whitney</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251-11-6293034</telephone>
   <email>alex.whitney@worldvision.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SNNPR</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.46580872 36.80646946</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-31">272074.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-2324">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-03-31">272074.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3301708607">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-13">272074.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2016" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6304706390">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-18">23830.95</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision Ethiopia</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2016</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2016" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
