<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-27973</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veolia Voda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The challenges in the water sector in this region, where access is almost universal, include inadequate and deteriorating infrastructure, high levels of leakage and poor water quality. Insufficient funding for maintenance is a pervasive weakness contributing to most of these issues.   Capital is needed to rehabilitate aged infrastructure, increase the efficiency of utilities and improve water quality and sanitation services.  Safe drinking water and better waste treatment impact health and productivity directly.  Veolia Voda has demonstrated its ability to enter the water sectors of post-Communist markets in central Europe, achieve significant improvements in operations and generate returns for the long term upgrading of the networks. Through its entry into Russia and Ukraine, the Company will be able to bring more reliable service, address issues of declining water quality and pollution due to poor treatment of waste and through better management, to mitigate the long run costs of maintaining their water and wastewater networks.    Veolia Voda is active on a regional scale in Eastern Europe and has a strong and stable base from which to enter higher growth markets.  In addition to providing investment, the Companys engagement in these regions is likely to facilitate improved technical, operational, managerial, environmental, and corporate governance standards in municipalities in less developed regions.  The target cities in Russia and the Ukraine lie outside the St. Petersburg- Moscow- Kiev axis and have had limited opportunities to benefit from direct foreign investment;  The close partnerships required with the municipalities will promote the development of public-private partnerships (PPPs) and contracting-out of services in other sectors.  This transaction therefore supports an important element of the World Bank Groups strategy for both Russia and Ukraine - investment through development of the PPP model.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veolia Voda (the Company) operates water and sanitation infrastructure (water treatment plants, water distribution systems, wastewater treatment plants, sewerage collection systems) owned by municipalities or associations of municipalities in the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary and Poland.  Apart from a few exceptions (concessions or operating models with limited contractual investments), the Company does not own these assets.  The vast majority of its contracts involve only the operation and maintenance of the systems.  Over the next 12 months, the Company plans to enter the Russian and Ukrainian water and sanitation sectors, as well as explore other opportunities in Central and Eastern Europe. To support the Companys expansion into these new markets, IFC is considering an equity investment in Veolia Voda for up to 50 million.  Veolia Voda is 90 percent owned by V&#xE9;olia Eau-Compagnie G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale des Eaux (CGE), the worlds largest water services company.  Since 2007, EBRD has owned the remaining 10 percent stake in the Company.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">VEOLIA CESKA REPUBLIKA, a.s.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-27973" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-05-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-06-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Etienne Petit Deputy CEO Veolia Water Europe Veolia Eau 36-38, avenue Kleber,  75 799 Paris Cedex 16 France Tel. +420 606 608 609 www.veoliaeau.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Europe Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Eastern Europe Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Company currently provides drinking water and/or waste water treatment through twenty water distribution companies: thirteen in the Czech Republic, two in Slovakia, four in Hungary and one in Poland.  Several other subsidiaries provide common services to the water distribution companies. The Company is looking to expand east to Ukraine and Russia.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>42.0000000000 43.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BA - Water and Wastewater Utilities</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $70.51 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-05-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-05-31">70510000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-05-31">70510000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">VEOLIA CESKA REPUBLIKA, a.s.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/27973/veolia-voda">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
