<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Detroit Investments</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Private sector development:    DI plans to expand in the juice sector via the privatization of underperforming assets in a frontier country. To date, there has been negligible progress on the privatization front and little Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) in Belarus. DIs Investment Program is likely to be a catalyst for further FDI. DI will rehabilitate and transform idle assets into a juice plant that will be comparable to international production standards. This will result in the production of safe and affordable juice products that will be available to a wider segment of consumers and serve as a vital source of vitamins during the colder season. The successful privatization of a high-visibility company will have tremendous demonstration effects beyond the immediate sector.   - Employment and living standards:    The juice plant will be significant employer in their respective local municipalities. These operations will create new and direct employment and provide indirect job opportunities along its supply chain. Additional jobs will also be created indirectly as the company develops its transport and distribution networks.   In the IT sector, BAC has more than 500 employees and is expected to employ more than 1,000 people in the next 2-3 years. BAC has in-house training programs on leading software applications that provide specialized knowledge and capacity building for its employees.  - Backward and forward linkages:   The establishment of the beverage operations will help create a class of micro-entrepreneurs who run small retail outlets, kiosks, restaurants and transport companies. This investment will also facilitate the transfer of modern distribution, warehousing and retail techniques and enhance supply chain efficiency in Belarus.   - Offering consumers a more affordable and reliable IT services   The development of local IT service companies will provide end-users will more affordable, reliable and efficient IT services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Detroit Investments Ltd. (DI or the company), a Cyprus-based entity, is the main investment vehicle of the Detroit Group which is involved in the production and distribution of beverages (beer, mineral water, fruit juices) in Belarus and Russia. DI is also the sponsor of two IFC projects: DBBC and PIP-Vladpivo.   Detroit Investments requested for further IFC support as the company expands into the juice sector in Belarus and the IT services sector in Russia.  IFCs investment and participation in this transaction will facilitate the  establishment of the first commercial juice company in Belarus via the privatization of underperforming assets and support DI, an existing client, as it diversifies into a regional player and enters the IT services sector. DI will be acquiring a minority stake in BAC, a Russian IT services provider, that provides systems integration and business application services to the agribusiness, finance, telecommunications and transport sectors.   Note: This SPI was updated to incorporate information about DIs investments in the IT sector in Russia in lieu of its original plans to invest in the retail sector in Belarus.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Detroit Investments</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25113" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-11-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2007-03-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Nicholas Henderson-Stewart Detroit Investments Ltd. 3/1 Barykovsky Alleyway Moscow, 119043 Russia</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Eastern Europe Region</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="XX-Eastern Europe Region">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The juice plant will be established by the company on the site of a state-owned vegetable canning plant in Bobruisk. The company will purchase the plant in a privatization transaction with the administration of the Mogilev region. The old vegetable canning plant was built in the early 1990s and had never started functioning to its full capacity due to the economic decline associated with the transition in the 1990s. In January 2006 the plant effectively stopped its operations. The brownfield site (5.4 Ha) currently contains several production facilities with infrastructure, few unfinished constructions and dilapidated equipment in the production areas.    DIs IT project is headquartered in Moscow with key branch offices in Kazan Perm, Omsk and Saransk.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>42.0000000000 43.5000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BA - Soft Drink</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $40.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2006-11-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-11-08">35500000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2006-11-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2007-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-11-08">4500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2006-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-11-08">35500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Detroit Investments</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2006-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2006-11-08">4500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Detroit Investments</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25113/detroit-investments">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
