<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-3.2.2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" secondary-reporter="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan(INBAR)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo Brought Under Sustainable Management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo forests and farms in Ethiopia, Kenya and Uganda are not sustainably management owing to the lack of technical skills. The project aimed to bring 1500 hectares under sustainable management. During Year 2 of the project, a total of 735 hectares of bamboo are brought under sustainable harvesting and management regime. During Year 3, a total of 467.65 hectares of bamboo forests and farms brought under sustainable management regime benefiting 1,289 smallholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2.2" crs-channel-code="62000" role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Adal Bamboo</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2.2" crs-channel-code="62000" role="4" type="72">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Pot Enterprises</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2.2" crs-channel-code="10000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, Ethiopia.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2.2" crs-channel-code="10000" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Forest Authority, Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable management of bamboo forests and farms are planned during the year 2 of the project. The project collaborated with private sector players in Ethiopia to identify the locations from where the bamboo are sourced and the smallholder farms are brought under sustainable management. In Kenya, the project collaborated with Green Pot Enterprises to undertake sustainable management in small holder farms. In Uganda, the project collaborated with National Forestry Authority to sustainably managed a 300 hectare of degraded bamboo forest in Echuya Central Forestry Reserve.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities are accomplished and closed by the end of Dec 2019</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="34">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable bamboo management in Echuya Central Forestry Reserves and in other plantation areas.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable bamboo management in smallholder bamboo plantations along with Green Pot Enterprises</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable bamboo management mainly in smallholder farms</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15" percentage="100" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable management of bamboo forests and farms enhancing climate change benefits, provision of sustainable raw materials for enterprises and industries; and enhanced ecosystem services.</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
