<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-Activity3.2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development for local communities on bamboo resource management, on-farm planting and restoration.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INBAR and Chinese Experts will provide technical assistance to INBAR national focal points and other designated national partners to conduct trainings. By the end of the project, 60 training courses and one MOFCOM Training course will be held in East Africa, with at least 5,000 community members and agriculture/forestry technical extension service members trained in Ethiopia (3,000), (Kenya 1,000) and Uganda (1000). A total of 50 training programmes were conducted in Ethiopia, Kenya and Uganda on bamboo resource management, planting and restoration. During Year 1, 36 training programs were conducted in Ethiopia, 8 trainings were conducted in Kenya and 7 in Uganda for a total of 1763 participants (1257 M/ 506F). During year 2, 42 capacity building training program on bamboo resource development and 2 MoFCOM ToT training program was organised for 1629 (1116 M/513 F). During Year 3, a total of 49 capacity building training program (88 PD) for 1649 (1177M/472F) beneficiaries organised to capacitate the smallholder farmers, entrepreneurs, line department extension staff on bamboo nursery, plantation and sustainable management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Forest Research Institute, Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Forest Authority, Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme completed by end of Dec 2019.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-03" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This activity aims to develop the capacities of local communities and line departments on bamboo planting material production, nursery management, bamboo plantation establishment, maintenance and sustainable harvesting and management.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of local communities will be built on bamboo cultivation and management.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="35">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of local communities will be built on bamboo cultivation and management.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="35">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity of local communities will be built on bamboo cultivation and management.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15" percentage="100" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It activity comes under sector forestry education and training</narrative>
  </sector>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
