<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5117010801-TZA-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Childrens Dignity Forum Strategic Plan 2016 - 2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Childrens Dignity Forum Strategic Plan 2016-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDFs function is to strengthen and facilitate human rights advocacy   for children at risk and or affected by child marriage, FGM, GBV and  other gender inequalities. CDF also intends to facilitate             establishing a supportive environemnt for enhancement of meaningful   child protection and sustainable participation of children in         development initiatives and promote men and boys engagement for GE.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Childrens Dignity Forum&#x2019;s (CDF) roll &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka och underl&#xE4;tta opinionsbildning kring m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r barn som utsatts f&#xF6;r, eller riskerar att uts&#xE4;ttas f&#xF6;r, barn&#xE4;ktenskap, kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning, k&#xF6;nsbaserat v&#xE5;ld och andra k&#xF6;nsbaserade or&#xE4;ttvisor. CDF kommer &#xE4;ven att arbeta f&#xF6;r en mer st&#xF6;djande social milj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r skydd av barn, f&#xF6;r involverande av barn p&#xE5; ett meningsfullt s&#xE4;tt i den lokala utvecklingen och f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja m&#xE4;ns och pojkars engagemang f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet. Insatsen kommer ocks&#xE5; att bidra till att st&#xE4;rka CDFs kapacitet som organisation i syfte att CDF p&#xE5; ett effektivt s&#xE4;tt skall kunna genomf&#xF6;ra sin strategiska plan.
CDF arbetar holistiskt med alla barn, samh&#xE4;llsmedlemmar, ledare och andra intressenter i syfte att g&#xF6;ra det m&#xF6;jligt f&#xF6;r lokalsamh&#xE4;llen att utforma sin egen verksamhet baserat p&#xE5; egna id&#xE9;er. Metoden syftar bl.a. till att fr&#xE4;mja att barn bidrar och v&#xE5;gar uttrycka sina &#xE5;sikter med tillf&#xF6;rsikt inf&#xF6;r andra. 

ENGLISH
CDFs function is to strengthen and facilitate human rights advocacy for children at risk and or affected by child marriage, FGM, GBV and  other gender inequalities. CDF also intends to facilitate establishing a supportive environemnt for enhancement of meaningful child protection and sustainable participation of children in development initiatives and promote men and boys engagement for GE.. It also focuses on strengthening the organisations capacity in order to effectively and efficiently implement its strategic plan.

Childrens Dignity Forum promotes a wholistic approach that focuses on the inclusion of all children, community members, leaders and other stakeholders.. These approaches aim at enabling the communities to design their own activities, generate own ideas and develop information. These approaches also aim to promote children to contribute freely and express their views accordingly, and with confidence in front of other community members. The specific approaches used include: Advocacy, building partnerships, participation, networking and capacity building.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development intervention&apos;s vision is promotion of children&apos;s rights for most vulnerable children, through creation of working forums that empowers children, families and communities. The overall goals is socially and economically independent children capable of contributing towards the development of Tanzania by 2018 - 2019. The thematic goals of the development intervention are:

1) Girls Empowerment: Effective realisation of social, economic and political rights of girls in the Childrens Dignity Forum programme areas.
2) Child Protection and Participation: Effective protection and participation of children in decision making at all levels in the CDF programme areas.
3) Boys and Men engagement: Boys and men effectively promoting the rights of women and girls in the CDF programme areas.
4) Organisational Development, sustainability and growth: A financially sustainable and progressively growing CDF organisation.

The development intervention will aim to target and benefit beneficiaries who are predominantly in school and out of school boys and girls below the age of 18 years living within selected programme districts in Mara, Mwanza, Dar es Salaam, Coast, Mbeya, Dodoma, Njombe and Iringa regions. It will also target beneficiaries in Singida, Lindi, Shinyanga, Manyara, Arusha and Mtwara regions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDF/Children&apos;s Dignity Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CDF/Children&apos;s Dignity Forum</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.1 - By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla flickor och pojkar fullbordar avgiftsfri och likv&#xE4;rdig grundskole- och gymnasieutbildning av god kvalitet som leder till relevanta och &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenliga kunskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.3 - Avskaffa alla skadliga sedv&#xE4;njor, s&#xE5;som barn&#xE4;ktenskap, tidiga &#xE4;ktenskap och tv&#xE5;ngs&#xE4;ktenskap samt kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.3 - Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">309706.0714077018</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">742950.7429507428</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">690417.0118751726</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">634524.4767816919</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">309706.0714077018</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">742950.7429507428</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">690417.0118751726</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">634524.4767816919</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-01">2454274.528136</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-09-28">151931.2803132122</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">157774.7910944896</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-28">157950.1579501579</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">585000.585000585</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">345208.5059375863</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">345208.5059375863</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-28">317262.2383908459</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">317262.2383908459</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/contract-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement on Core Support</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/contract-3.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment no 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Examples of Programme Results for the period 2019 from the External Evaluation Report and CDf Annual Report 2019.
Examples of results from the External Evaluation Report
1) CDF&#x2019;s Strategic Plan is fully aligned with the Government&#x2019;s National Plan of Action to End Violence against Women and Children in Tanzania 2017/18 - 2020/21 and with Sida&#x2019;s policies and Results Strategy for Tanzania. CDF&#x2019;s Strategic Plan is challenging some of Tanzania&#x2019;s existing laws (the Law of Marriage Act) and working in line with others.&#xA0;The girls interviewed in the respective programme areas were empowered by CDF in terms of knowing and acting upon their rights.
2)CDF&#x2019;s Strategic Plan is found to be based on a solid evidence-based analysis of the specific challenges in the areas in which CDF works. The process of developing the Strategic Plan included consultation with the target groups.
3)The Evaluation Team found evidence that CDF invests carefully and on an on-going basis in identifying beneficiary needs and adjusting interventions to meet those needs. In this manner CDF continues to remain relevant to the needs of the rights holders.CDF is found to be &#x201C;doing the right things&#x201D; as it has a multi-pronged approach to addressing the many drivers of FGM, child marriage and teenage pregnancy.
4)CDF has contributed to the existence of formal and informal structures for protecting women and children at ward, district and regional level and that these structures have become more effective. There is evidence of boys and men actively changing their behaviour toward their wives, children, friends and siblings and engaging with their communities to stop children being abused or neglected.
5. The core funding provided by Sida has primarily allowed CDF to grow as an organization, but also offered CDF flexibility in addressing the needs of the target groups, and incrementally building its model. The Strategic Plan has contributed to the development of CDF to become the pre-eminent national CSO dealing with challenges of FGM, child marriage and teenage pregnancy in Tanzania.
Examples of results from the CDF Annual Report 2019
1. CDF as a convener of two national networks: MenEngage Tanzania ( MET) and Tanzania Ending Child Marriage Network ( TECMN) coordinated member organisations to mobilise joint efforts in advocating for women and childrens rights and welfare.Through advocacy campaigns on ending child marriage, TECMN members conducted multisectoral campaigns with relevant stakeholders i.e. policy makers, traditional and religious leaders who were able to push for the amendment of Law of Marriage Act of 1971 and a notable result was the decision made by the High Court of Tanzania declaring Section 13 and 17&#xA0; of the LMA of 1971 unconstitutional and were against the best interest of the girl child.
2. CDF supported 50 girls and young women to advocate for their rights in different media sessions. THe aim was to ensure that their voices are amplified and heard for social change. CDF Club members participated in the production of a documentary on Adolescence Sexual Reproductive Health Rights which was aired on Azam TV. Furthermore, three special newspaper articles focusing on: 1) Available supportive child protection systems and structures in Tanzania 2) Engagement of men in ending VAWC and 3) CDF&apos;s young women leadership programmes. The articles were published by CDF in partnership with Mwananchi newspaper. A total of 56,000 newspaper articles were published and distributed all over Tanzania.
3. On raising Voices of children, 45 inschool clubs have provided a platform for over 1350 club members to speak out on childrens rights violations to their peers and community members. The clubs provided students with an opportunity to show their skills in advocating for their rights and to provide peer support and education reaching a total of 12, 372 ( 4,128 boys and 8,244 girls) in schools and within their communities.&#xA0;
4. In June 2019, in-school club members participated in a Model Parliament that was organized by the Legal and Human Rights Center (LHRC) in collaboration with CDF, as one of the ways to commemorate the Day of the African Child. During the model parliament, a secondary school student, who represented the Child Marriage Constituency, was honored as the best presenter and became the overall 4th winner of the National Essay Writing Competition that was prepared by LHRC. This highlights how club members have an in-depth understanding of children&#x2019;s rights, as well as the ability of displaying their level of confidence and resilience in advocating for their rights and the rights of their peers.
5. Through community outreaches, a total of 285 young women from 19 CDF&#x2019;s out-of- school clubs (15 members per club) in Ilala, Tarime and Mpwapwa Districts reached a total of 2,335 (916 male, 1,419 female) community members with advocacy messages on ending VAWC, particularly ending teenage pregnancy, child marriage and FGM as well as promoting Sexual Reproductive Health Rights (SRHR). Empowering young people with the right information on their SRH allows them to make informed decisions on their bodies, as well the ability to demand and access their rights.
6. CDF through its interventions continued to foster a platform and engaged with 949 (492 female, 457 male) duty bearers tasked with the protection of women and children from violence. These said interventions focused on strengthening the capacities of Gender and Children&#x2019;s Desks, improved coordination among teachers and school management, police protection committee&#x2019;s and other stakeholders to respond and support survivors of VAWC. This also involved facilitating skills strengthening to 30 (18 male, 12 female) police personnel in Mpwapwa District who work directly with the survivors to ensure that they understand how to handle and manage Gender-Based Violence (GBV) and children related cases, including child abuse and children in conflict with the law
Despite the significant achievements that CDF has made in 2019, there were some challenges encountered throughout the year in implementation of its work. These include:?
1. Absence of youth-friendly centres for provision of ASRH services to youth in both infrastructure and trained personnel has been a challenge. Therefore, due to the increase in demand, CDF convened different meetings with District Medical Officers (DMOs), Sexual Reproductive Health coordinators and other health care providers on provision of youth friendly services in order to build the capacity of health care staff in provision of SRH services and establish youth friendly service centres.&#xA0;
2. Unresponsiveness of the justice institutions continue to deter women and children from seeking justice despite the support from the Police on reporting and taking to court some of the perpetrators. In many cases, conventional justice reforms have effectively side-lined the justice needs of women hence making victims of VAWC to lose faith in the justice system and opt for out of court settlement which largely limit access to women and children rights as they are more patriarchal in nature. CDF continues to use advocacy avenues to adress these constraints at community and district levels.
3. Poor enforcement and reluctance of the government in amending the conflicting policies and laws that are not in favour of the welfare of children and women rights, for instance the Law of Marriage Act 1971 remain daily reality for large number of women and children to face violence. CDF in partnership with other like-minded organizations have been doing advocacy work to change the policies and laws with the key decision makers as well raising awareness to the community on the effects of the conflicting laws in order to ensure rule of law and access to justice to facilitate gender equality.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51170108" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
