<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12447A0103-TZA-15160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOUNDATION FOR CIVIL SOCIETY 2018-2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FOUNDATION FOR CIVIL SOCIETY 2018-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FSC is an independent Tanzanian non-profit organisation that provides grants and capacity building services to Tanzanian based civil society organisations. FCS was registered as a legal entity under the National NGO Act No 1666 in September 2002 and started its operation in January 2003.  Since its inception, FCS has contributed immensely to the capacity strengthening of teh civil society sector in Tanzania. thereby ( in) directly enabling CSOs and citizens become key driving forces for positively influencing democratic governance in Tanzania and better quality of life for all. This is realised through provision of grants, facilitation of linkages, as well as enabling a culture of on-going learning within the civil society and Tanzania as a whole. 

FCS aspires to maintain its position as a leading financing mechanism for CSOs in Tanzania; and to effectively complement government and development partners efforts towards poverty reduction as set out in Tanzania&apos;s main development frameworks: Vision 2025 and the five year development plan 2016 - 2021.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Foundation for Civil Society (FCS) &#xE4;r en oberoende, icke vinstdrivande civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisation i Tanzania som utdelar bidrag och ger kapacitetsst&#xF6;d till civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer i Tanzania. FCS som formell organisation registrerades inom Tanzanias regelverk som styr civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer (National NGO Act No 1666) den 22 september 2002. Verksamheten p&#xE5;b&#xF6;rjades i januari 2003. Sedan tillkomsten har FCS bidragit avsev&#xE4;rt till st&#xE4;rkandet av det civila samh&#xE4;llet i Tanzania och d&#xE4;rmed m&#xF6;jliggjort f&#xF6;r medborgare och civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer att p&#xE5; ett positivt s&#xE4;tt bidra till st&#xE4;rkandet av ett demokratiskt styrelseskick och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrade levnadsvillkor i Tanzania. St&#xF6;det har utgjorts av utdelade bidrag och st&#xE4;rkande av n&#xE4;tverk. FCS har &#xE4;ven bidragit till utvecklande av l&#xE4;rande inom civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationerna.

FCS str&#xE4;var efter att vara den ledande finansieringsmekanismen f&#xF6;r civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer i Tanzania. De str&#xE4;var &#xE4;ven efter att komplementera bist&#xE5;ndsgivares och statens insatser f&#xF6;r fattigdomsminskning, s&#xE5;som uttryckt i landets huvudsakliga strategier och planer f&#xF6;r utveckling och fattigdomsminskning (t.ex. Vision 2025 samt den fem&#xE5;riga utvecklingsplanen f&#xF6;r 2016-2021).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Foundation for Civil Society ( FCS) Key Result Areas
1. GovernanceThe focus is on supporting social accountability, monitoring women&apos;s land rights, harmful traditional practices and conflict resolution. It is acknowledged that governance in the context of sustainable livelihoods means working across sectors and levels. This involved changing power relations, developing people capacioties ( resilience, assets base) as well as positively changing attitudes ( sense of vulnerability and powerlessness) There is also recognition between micro actions and macro conditions and their effects on people&apos;s livelihoods. In order to realise these results, FCS works with CSos at both local and national levels abd uses them as a vehicle to empower communities to address governance issues. The desired outcomes in this area are that: a) By 2020, Local government authorities ( LGAs) in areas that FCS works are delivering improved quality services. b) By 2020, decision making and democratic processes are better reflecting citizens rights especially those of marginalised groups, PWDs, minority and women. c) By 2020, communities have strong capacities and institutions for dialogue and conflict management.
2.Livelihoods and MarketFCS recognises that there is a strong linkage between governance and livelihoods. FCS approach to livelihoods&#xA0;is based on adressing systems, policies and structures that constrain the target groups from realising their potentials. the livelihood programme is modelled on three pathways: a) First targetting youth and women economic empowerment b) Targetting smallholder farmers access to extension services and productive assets and 3) tragetting communities resilience to climate change and management of natural resourxes. FCS has also pointed out that more and more citizens are organising through economic self-help groups including Village Community banks ( VICOBAa), saving and Credit societies as opposed to traditional NGOs. FCS intends to tap into these already organised spaces while also linking economic empowerment to social empowerment&#xA0; while promoting the participation of the marginalised groups in decision making. The livelihood desired outcomes are: a) Ensuring tha youth and women entrepreneurs have secured greater access to market and livelihood assets and resources b) Enabling smallhoder farmers to access adequate extension services and improved security of tenure and; c) Ensuring that communities have increased capacity for climate resilience and are more accountable on natural resource management.
3. Capacity DevelopmentFCS collaboates with smaller and grassroots based CSOs who work directly with communities to identify innovative solutions to address poverty. The goal of this component is to contribute to the enhancement of civil society and other development actors to effectively and sustainably attain their mandates. The intention is that by 2020, FCS envisions that the CSOs they work with are strong, coordinated and able to serve their constituents effectively and efficiently. THese smaller CSOs lack proper systems especially those for financial managment, human resources management, monitioring and evaluation as well as suitable checks and balances, capacity to document and disseminate results and also low innovation in adressing societal challenges in a rapidly changing environment.
FCS has modelled its programme to ensure that the supported organisations are constantly capacitated to deliver efficiently and document results in such a way that the evidence of the successes is acheived and shared widely. FCS recognises that the capacity of Civil society is central to giving voice to citizens and putting them at the center of good governance, livelihood and economic development processes that form part of their day to day living. FCS supports performance improvement, institutional growth and organisation as well as capacity to relate and link with others.FCS regards Capacity development as a means towards strengthening and enabling key actors - civil society, policy makers and private sector- to actively engage in dialogue about developing appropriate policy responses. It also focuses on identifying key knowledge gaps, equipping decsiion makers with the necessary tools, frameworks ands skill sets to effectively tacle development challenges at individual, institutional and societal levels.
4) Institutional DevelopmentThe overall objective of this area of work is to enable FCS to become a dynamic, efficient and sustainable entity that is effectively relaising its mandate. FCS intends to focus on improving its monitoring, evaluation and learning approach with a focus on constant reflection in order to maintain relevance and competitiveness. It also works on improving internal policies, systems and structures to safeguard its integrity and capacity to safeguard resources entrusted to it. This includes recruitment and retention of high quality staff as well as enhancing and diversifying the resource base so as to improve the sustainability of operations.
The key objectives to ensure this are: a) FCS is delivering high quality services efficiently and effectively b) FCS has a diverse and stable portfolio of financing sources c) The internal policy environment (systems, structures, procedures) are upto date, comprehensive, relevant and fully operationalised. FCS is also complying with statutory and donor requirements.In summary, FCS main role is facilitation rather than direct implementation. Facilitation in this regard includes, but is not limited to funding/grant-making, coordination, mobilisation/leveraging resources, enabling of learning and reflections, linking and brokering partnerships and knowledge management. FCS ultimate target group is Tanzanian citizens with particular attention given to the poor, women, people with disabilities, youth.
SWEDEN&apos;S PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE WITH THE FOUNDATION FOR CIVIL SOCIETY
Sweden has previously supported the Foundation for Civil society in 2011. Sweden performed an Efficiency Audit and gave recommendations to the Institution and contributed MSEK 30 to the FCS Strategy 2009 - 2013. In this assessment, it has been noted that the recommendations of the Efficiency audit conducted 7 years ago have been taken onboard and the organisation has grown. It has been documented in the Report of Review of the FCS Strategy 2009 - 2013 that during this period FCS has grown and developed to become a respected institution by Stae and Non Stae Actors alike. Furthermore it has been noted that the work of FCS, its products and services are regarged as very relevant to stakeholders. FCS has also exhibited significant levels of adaptability and tenacity, and has significantly grown in terms of programmes, number of supported partners and financial resource base.&#xA0;
In 2018, Sweden has decided to assess possible support of MSEK 55 to the Foundation for Civil society due to a number of reasons. The FCS contribution will contribute towards the Embassy Open Space Project whose main focus is addressing the issue of shrinking democratic space, since this organisation has the capacity to make linkages with organisation working on matters of&#xA0; civic space. Another reason is that Sweden&#x2019;s direct support via contributions to civil society has been solid and persistent over a long period of time. Sweden has a well balanced portfolio in this regard and should remain with the support also under present circumstances. However,new approaches and innovative actions are necessary and this may include providing additional funds to ongoing contributions to address issues that are of critical importance in the civil societies. This proposed support to the Foundation for Civil Society will contribute towards this goal. This support will also enable Sweden to have local outreach as this is the only organisation that can reach community based organisations as well as vulnerable groups that Sweden does not have the capacity to reach within its current contributions. There is no other organisation with the capacity to forward funds to community based organisations in the country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BDO Llp</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation for Civil Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">29083.0020170458</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">29083.0020170458</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-01">28703.166712</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-28">29262.3208851683</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-28">-179.3561776399</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCS Annual Reports 2019
i. The Accountability Report highlights progress against the approved workplan for the year, which includes key activities implemented and expenditures at FCS.ii. The Annual Outcomes report provides evidence of changes and learnings obtained in the year. It is supported by case studies from the field.
Results - Accountability Report 2019i. The Accountability report reports that during a call for proposals in 2019, a total of 1,004 applications were received and processed and out of these 154 managed to reach the approval stage and underwent Manage Your Grants ( MYG) training. FCS contracted 151 grantees under the basket fund and dropped 3 CSOs following various malpractices. Grantees were evaluated in terms of risk level where due diligence for new grantees, audit reports, internal performance reviews by FCS for ongoing grantees served as baseline risk levels. Grantees identified to have low capacity were subjected to necessary capacity building. Out of 151 grantees, 123 grantees were rated as low risk and 28 grantees rated medium risk.
ii. A Risk management Policy and Risk management Framework were developed. Risk owners and champions were identified. FCS publicly shared whistle blowing policy procedures and matters on fraud allegations which included how to treat official communication and contact persons. FCS took measures against corruption in order to enhance internal accountability, transparency and reduce risk of funding fraudulent organisations or individuals.
ii. FCS registered a commercial arm (FCS Trust Limited) whose mandate is to ensure FCS is financially stable. FCS will continue to be an NGO and not for profit entity, the Trust is the Income generating arm of FCS and will be exclusively owned by FCS.
iv. FCS Grantees were facilitated in order to ensure that they complied with the Written Law ( Miscellaneous Amendments) Act of 2019. vii. FCS sought clearance with Registrar of NGOs before issuing new grant contacts with the grantees. The names of approved grantees were submitted to the Registrar of NGOs to check their compliance status hence FCS confirmed that they work with Grantees who are compliant with the legal framework.
v. In terms of challenges, FCS received USD 6,353,851 from DPs against a target of USD 8,283,400. This was approximately 77% of the target. It is stated that delays in receiving funds from DPs has greatly affected the grant cycle and disrupted the implementation cycle of grantees projects. There is also a financial gap of GBP 625,000 due to non-disbursement of funds by DFID/Act II. FCS failed to make disbursements to a total of 47 grantees due to financial gap. This had an impact on results as well as trust with other stakeholders including the Government.
Results- Outcome Report 2019
i. FCS issued grants to 151 projects. The grants enabled FCS grantees to implement projects in 185 districts in the country, reaching a total 411,823 people, 210,605 (51%) of them being men and 201,218 (49%) being women.
ii. In Social Accountability, FCS grantees have conducted scrutiny on public funds. In 2019, they monitored 291 different public projects in health, water, education and agriculture with the total value of about 132.4 Billion ( appox USD 57.5million). The monitoring efforts have resulted in: a) About TZS 136.47 million shillings which was said to have been stolen or misused, have been recovered as a result of grantee efforts b) TZS 1.12 Billion shillings which had not been released for a long period which then got released after citizens efforts and c) TZS 296.92 million was contributed by citizens to support various public projects.
iii. FCS grantees are contributing towards increasing the number of LGAs publishing up to date income and expenditure information. Between January &#x2013; June 2019, about 77% of villages that grantees were implementing SAM/PETS were publishing up to date income and expenditure reports. The rates varied per sector, whereby in the Agriculture projects, only 38% of the villages are publishing upto date income and expenditure reports, compared to 67% in water and health, and 81% in education.
iv. FCS grantees have observed an increased responsiveness of LGAs towards ensuring protection of women and children&#x2019;s rights. This is a result of FCS grantees contribution towards implementation of the National Plan of Action to End Violence against women and children. Grantees reported that 3,933 cases of GBV were identified. 74% of GBV cases identified were reported at some level, with the majority being reported to LGA (29%), NPA- VAC Committees (26%), school committees (15%), GBV clubs (9%) and other places (26%). Furthermore, 52% of the cases reported were resolved. This represents a slight improvement in the identification, reporting and solving of GBV cases, yet its still reveals a huge gap in addressing GBV.
v. FCS grantees have contributed towards efforts to ensure PWDs and youths are accessing the 2% and 4% of district budgets as loans. The grantees have helped PWDs and youths to form groups and strengthen groups so that they can apply for district loans. In 2019, 173 youth groups and 3PWD groups were formed. A total of TZS 1.54 million was available for PWD loans in 17 councils, of which 10 councils issued a total of TZS 151 million. The loans benefitted over 261 PWDs who were in groups formed by FCS grantees. A total of TZS 2.96 billion was available for youth loans in 21 councils, of which 11 councils issues a total of TZS 683 million.
vi. Grantees efforts in various project areas have led to the formation of women&#x2019;s land rights platforms which are joint avenues for mobilizing women to seek ownership of land. In 2019, grantees 84 land rights platforms and 24 women economic empowerment platforms. In women land rights, FCS grantees have invested in reactivating land tribunals to process land rights cases more efficiently. It is reported that the number of active tribunals in FCS Grantees areas increased from 61% - 88%. Efforts to reactivate the tribunals and raise awareness on women&#x2019;s land rights resulted into 1,474 women submitting formal applications for land ownership, 207 women successfully obtained Certificate of Customary Right of Occupancy (CCRO) giving them ownership to over a total of 118 acres of land with a total estimated worth of TZS 3.94billion.
vii. In capacity development, FCS contributed to strengthening the capacity of CSO networks, umbrella organisations in advocacy, collaborative policy engagement, learning and reflection through a number of activities e.g. CSO Week 2019, Regional Directors Forum, National Directors forum, Disabilities People Organisations ( DPOs) forum, annual stakeholders meetings in Zanzibar, strengthening the capacity of network organisations, supporting the participation of CSOs in forums, learning and experience sharing forums as well as supporting movement and coalition building. FCS efforts to enhance the institutional and performance of supported CSOs in technical skills on policy analysis and evidence-based advocacy, financial management, fundraising and others has been quite intensive. The increasingly changing context enhances the importance of regular contact between FCS and relevant officials in the Government through events such as the CSO week and Directors Forum as important avenues to build joint understanding.
Regional Directors Forums created space for 400 upcountry CSOs to discuss and generate evidences to use to advocate for improved relationships between CSOs and the Government as well as to establish linkages between grassroot situations, national and global initiatives for wider CSos and government engagements.&#xA0;
Examples of High level Advocacy
1. The presence of high profile leaders at regional and district levels of governance had several meaning and advantages including 1) good indication of presence or a possibility of good working relationship between CSOs and the Government at these levels and ii) effective and handy mechanisms of absorbing issues pertaining partnership.&#xA0;
2. Involvement of government leaders in the CSO forums either as chief guests or presenters is the best way of lobbying them to engage directly in the CSO forums. In his opening remarks the Regional Commissioner of Mtwara commented that he would like to hear the challenges that CSOs are facing that could be attributed to the way the Government is conducting their work so that they will know the shortfalls.
Testimonial: Woman with Albinism wins councillorship and inspires others
Sarah Abdallah is a Councillor of Mzinga Ward in Ilala Municipal and also a member of Women with Disability Network. Sarah lives with Albinism, she contested for the position of Councillor in 2015 but she encountered many challenges and obstacles because of her disability so during this time she couldn&#x2019;t win the election. It was hard for the community to believe that a person living with disability has the ability to lead. But I did not give up, I kept upgrading myself through participating in various forums which empower women but also educating the community about the effect of stigma. Unfortunately, in 2018 the ward Councillor died. this was an opportunity for Sarah to contest for the position, and fortunately this time she won the election. To date Sara is doing well in her leadership. Sara inspired her fellow disabled women to contest for different positions in the upcoming local government election.
Case: Enhancing Peaceful relationship between local communities and investors in Mkuranga district
Six staff (1F/ 5M) of Amani Foundation benefited from the local fundraising/ resource mobilization mentoring and coaching. Staffs used the skills and knowledge acquired to fundraise TZS 10,532,000 and currently AMANI is implementing a project on Enhancing Peaceful relationship between local communities and Investors in Mkuranga District.. We are using the resources to conduct District security committee meetings which were successful and deliberated on the formation of the District Dispute Management and Reconciliation Committee charged with the duty of early detection and quick response to disputes or signs of their occurrence.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12447" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2020-01-01">
    <sida:title>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
