<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11664A0104-TZA-11110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TEN/MET 2018-2022 Education for All Strategy</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">TEN/MET 2018-2022 Utbildning f&#xF6;r alla strategi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education sector is wide and challenges are so many. TEN/MET is aware of the challenges including the poor learning outcomes as reflected by poor pass rates in the national examinations at basic education level (primary and lower secondary education), poor literacy and numeracy skills of children, poor livelihood and poor implementation of education policies at all levels. TEN/MET as a coordination agency for CSOs education sector in Tanzania is only going to focus on few key activities that would impact in improving quality and equality of education sector in Tanzania. 

1. Coordinating education sector by assessing and ultimately bring togather all actors in education to share challenges and success to better inform policy initiatives at higher level. Embassy of Sweden is aware on presence of many actors in education and recognizes their contributions in the sector. 

2. To build a strong national and international network for CSOs to engage. TEN/MET as a secretariat has been able to recruit 200 member organizations and at the same time within the five year strategic timeframe TEN/MET will continuously assess legibility and activeness of such organizations to ensure that it works with right partners, focus, documentation and aspirations. Different from last strategic plan 2015 - 2017, the new TENMET strategy 2018 - 2022 breaks members in to zones and thematic area to allow for prioritization and capacity development initiatives. 

3. To adress areas of education financing gap, inclusive education through evidence based research. As a secretatiat, TEN/MET for next five years has positioned itself to utilize research and experiences from other member organizations to appeal to the government on behalf of education sector to expand incluciveness and education budget in the sector. TEN/MET is aware of the recent inclusive strategy developed by the government with exclusion of clear articulations on how specific affected groups are going to be reached. For next five years, TENMET has indicated to capitalize on documenting gaps and sharing best practices that will promote quality and equality education in Tanzania.

4. The fourth area is enhancing effective dialogue and participation of CSOs in education partners development group and ESDC meetings. TEN/MET for next five years has innovatively designed a specific budget line to allow member organizations to meet, review, analyze and comment on proposals or government documents that are submitted to donor group for review. 

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 11.3 billion TZSH for five years, out of which the Embassy of Sweden contribution is expected to be around 5 billion and the rest 6.3b will be fundraised by TENMET from other donors. Already there are donors that have committed fund to TEN/MET but not as in longer term as Embassy of Sweden has done. CSEF- Civil Society Education Fund has confirmed support of 260,040,000 TZSH for each year of the new strategy. Porticus who has been funding TENMET last year has also committed 186,480,000 for 2018. Another committed fund for 2018 is the LANES support from government Worth of 761,113,255 and also from another donor called APHRC with 30,000,000 support. TENMET is positive that all the donors who are currently funding them will continue to do so and their expectation is high for other potential donors like NORAD, DFID, GIZ and Equality Now.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Tanzanias utbildningssektor &#xE4;r bred och utmaningarna &#xE4;r m&#xE5;nga. TEN/MET &#xE4;r medvetna om de utmaningar som finns i sektorn; F&#xE5; klarar de nationella proven som ges i grundskolan, f&#xE5; elever har en god l&#xE4;sf&#xF6;rst&#xE5;else och &#xE4;nnu f&#xE4;rre klarar av simpla matematiska uppgifter. &#xC4;ven p&#xE5; policyniv&#xE5; har Tanzania problem med b&#xE5;de formulering och implementering. TEN/MET koordinerar de civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer som &#xE4;r aktiva inom utbildningssektorn i Tanzania. Genom att fokusera p&#xE5; fyra omr&#xE5;den ska TEN/MET bidra till en &#xF6;kad kvalitet och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet inom utbildningssektorn. 

1. Genom att koordinera de civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer som finns inom utbildningssektorn kan organisationerna dela med sig av sina utmaningar och framg&#xE5;ngar f&#xF6;r att effektivt p&#xE5;verka policy p&#xE5; h&#xF6;g niv&#xE5;. Ambassaden har kontakt med flertalet av civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationerna inom TEN/MET och deras bidrag till utbildningssektorn &#xE4;r stor. 

2. Att bygga ett starkt nationellt och internationellt n&#xE4;tverks d&#xE4;r civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer kan samlas. &#xD6;ver 200 civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer &#xE4;r medlemmar i TEN/METs och den nya strategin syftar delvis till att analysera medlemmarnas aktivitets, f&#xF6;r att se till s&#xE5; att TEN/MET samarbetar med r&#xE4;tt organisationer, har r&#xE4;tt focus, dokumentation och vision. Till skillnad fr&#xE5;n f&#xF6;reg&#xE5;ende den strategiska planen f&#xF6;r 2015-2017, s&#xE5; kommer den nya strategin f&#xF6;r 2018 &#x2013; 2022 att dela upp medlemmarna i zoner f&#xF6;r att kunna priorietara och koordinera kapacitetsbyggnad. 

3. Att p&#xE5;verka de finanseringsgap som finns inom utbildningssektorn genom evidensbaserad forskning. TEN/MET har de senaste &#xE5;ren positionerat sig f&#xF6;r att anv&#xE4;nda forskning och erfarenheter fr&#xE5;n dess medlemmar f&#xF6;r att p&#xE5;verka regeringen att utveckla en inkluderande utbildning samt att &#xF6;ka regeringens budget f&#xF6;r utbildningssektorn. TEN/MET &#xE4;r medvetna om att regeringens nya strategi f&#xF6;r en inkluderande utbildning exkluderar specifika grupper, s&#xE5; som unga m&#xF6;drar. F&#xF6;r de kommande fem &#xE5;ren str&#xE4;var TEN/MET efter att brygga dokumentationsgap f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja en kvalitativ och j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lld utbildning i Tanzania. 

4. Att skapa en effektiv dialog och &#xF6;kat deltagande av civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer i givargruppen f&#xF6;r utbildningsfr&#xE5;gor samt ESDC m&#xF6;ten. TEN/MET har skapat en specifik budgetlinje f&#xF6;r att till&#xE5;ta att medlemmasorganisationerna kommer att m&#xF6;tas f&#xF6;r att analysera och kommentara regeringens f&#xF6;rslag och strategier f&#xF6;r de kommande fem &#xE5;ren. 

Budgeten f&#xF6;r de kommande fem &#xE5;ren uppg&#xE5;r till 11.3 miljarder TZS. Ambassaden kommer att bidra med ca 5 miljarder TSH. De resterande 6.3 miljarderna kommer TEN/MET att s&#xF6;ka fr&#xE5;n andra givare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The long term goal of TEN/MET is to see a national education system that embraces quality education for all. TENMET is an umbrella organization with almost 200 member CSOs working in education sector in Tanzania. Since it is a member based organization, its intended outcomes are divided into two connected categories.  

Secretariat. 
The outcome number 1 focusses on building institutional capacity of the organization and the board to be able to play effective oversight role. The new strategy 2018 - 2022 aims at recruiting new board members with education and thematic background. To blend the strategy with right skills, TENMET is also going to recruit new people over time to competitively navigate safely in a politically changing environment. TEN/MET believes that the long term goal of ensuring national education system is embracing quality education for all will not be sustainable if as an institution does not equip itself better to confornt realities on the ground.  

As a Network 
There are four intended outcome to be achieved; To develop CSOs capacity, to strengthen the network, conduct evidence based research and lastly join hands with other CSOs to do advocacy. TEN/MET will have CSOs equipped with relevant skills, CSOs as network will get connected to regional and international affiliations and jointly with members TENMET will generate knowledge to inform policy change in education sector in Tanzania.  During the time of TENMET appraisal, Tanzania&apos; largest share of the national budget went to infrastructure and education sector is the second. According to Ministry of Finance Sector Analysis (2017/2018), The Ministry of works, communication and infrastructure has 5,541,3 billion TZSH while ministry of education has 4,706,4. Again; Interestingly, despite the increase in enrollment since 2016, education sector budget is decreasing from 16% in 2016/17 to 15% in 2017/18. One of the TEN/MET&apos;s advocacy strategy is to challenge the government to consider education as high in the agenda and increase national annual budget allocation for education sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TENMET-Sida/Tanzania Education Network Mtandao Wa Elimu Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TENMET-Sida/Tanzania Education Network Mtandao Wa Elimu Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="111" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education, Level Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">19820.6811318775</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-06-07">24998.11586937</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/11664_TENMET2018-2021agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contract 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnership with TENMET is now halfway of strategy implementation with mixed realities. First year 2018/2019 implementation didn&apos;t respond very well to strategy results due to challenges noticed in TENMET leadership capacity and internal control reporting challenges. The 2019/20 financial year seems to be different as TENMET shows significant improvement in reporting and compilation of their annual and financial report. It seems TENMET is complying and aligning to its internal reporting requirements however accuracy of data reported in 2019/2020 TENMET financial statement is still a challenge. 
&#xA0;
TENMET has also positively responded to 2018/2019 challenges and action plan. There were a number of issues identified for improvements and it is assessed that progress on implementation of such challenges is generally good. There are still some few challenges in achieving the strategy results as anticipated by their 2017-2022 strategy vision, for example failure to forward fund as required by the agreement. It is reported that as soon as TENMET finalizes the development of grant management procedure, fund forwarding will be executed.

TENMET as a network of organizations striving to improve equitable access to quality education in Tanzania, will be assessed based on objectives that are designed around five areas of focus. These are, building strong members capacity, advocacy and campaign, conducting research, strengthening the network and improve the secretariat or governance capacity of the secretariat.&#xA0;

The 2019/2020 report shows that board members were trained on their roles and responsibilities through the Board Charter and were oriented and updated on the 2018-2022 Strategic Plan. It is also reporting that various staff in the Secretariat were trained on financial management and compliance and IPSAS, 6 staff were trained on crisis management, performance management and change management and 16 staff were equipped with interpersonal/communications skills, presentation skills and on how to organize and participate online meeting. It seems that there is a good investment made to the team.

According to the narrative report, there are new staff recruited to fill the positions of Resource Mobilization, Human Resource, Monitoring, Evaluation and Learning, Advocacy and ICT and Knowledge Management. Embassy of Sweden is also notified that in November 2019, the Tally system was replaced with Odoo, a comprehensive open-source Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) software thereby improving TEN/METs internal controls and operational efficiency. The annual report goes on stating that three proposals for funding were developed in response to COVID-19 for Eastern, Northern, and Lake Zones program area.&#xA0;

Networking and coordination of members
&#xA0;According to TENMET 2019/2020 annual report, TENMET seems to have actively engaged with members and CSOs to the extent of growing membership base from 181 to 210 with 26 organizations joining the network in the year 2019/20. The new members were duly approved by the General Assembly. It is assessed that growing membership is probably either a good sign that CSOs are willing to work together or could also mean that new members have trust on the secretariat.

TENMET annual report also shows that, 43 members shared their interventions to address COVID-19 after being facilitated by the networks secretariat.&#xA0;Embassy&apos;s assessment is that TENMET was able to monitor and follow up on partners doing work to address COVID 19. Also, a total of six (6) meetings were organized for COVID 19 feedback and experience sharing. Members were equipped with information regarding COVID 19 government intervention strategies and plans.

It is also noted that TENMET as secretariat did not adjust their own activities to address COVID 19 and as a result there was more than 349m TZSH activities that had to be postponed to 2020/2021. The inability to adjust activities to COVID 19 is assessed as not a problem as members were already doing interventions on the same. For knowledge sharing, Embassy of Sweden will follow up with TENMET to share lessons and results or noted contributions that partners made when implementing COVID 19 interventions.

TENMET report shows there has been collaboration with the local and central government to improve the network and coordination. An example is shared in 2019/2020 reporting that a good collaboration with the government resulted in FYMC member organization getting free office space from the Local Government and the member is also invited in participating in district planning committee meetings. 

TEN/MET annual report also indicates that, they provided inputs in different guidelines, strategies, and themes to the Ministry of education. The network was engaged by the government to develop the Action Plan for the Inclusive Education Strategy for 2018/21. There were Sixteen (16) Member organizations engaged by the government in that process.

Robust research on education
TENMET is reporting that, members and partners were provided with an avenue to present and disseminate their research findings in Dodoma in December 2019, where one of the nine papers from a member organization and another from a partner, and the rest from research institutions were presented.&#xA0;
The annual report continues to show that, the last quarter of the year, the network established a research partnership with the Dar es Salaam University College of Education (DUCE) following the signing of the Memorandum of Understanding. The College has been commissioned to undertake a study on alternative pathways for teen mothers and out-of-school girls due to early pregnancies. Another study on alternative financing for training, recruitment and deployment of teachers was also being finalized by a consultant. All these studies are assessed as important not only to our bilateral education support but also to inform the government.

Advocacy and campaign
Annual report 2019/2020 shows that TEN/MET participated in four radio and TV talk shows, appeared in more than seven newspapers, six TV stations, and in different social media including Twitter, Facebook and Instagram. The discussions in all the media focused on the provision of basic education and learning outcomes. For example, In January 2020, TEN/MET participated in the TV talk show organized by StarTV, that assessed delivery of fee-free education in Tanzania

It is also reported that, TEN/MET staff, TEN/MET members, and African Population Health Research Center representatives met with 23 Dar-es-Salaam Parliamentarians (12 males and 11 females) at one of the parliamentary reserved rooms for Parliamentary Committees. The meeting aimed at broadening Members of the parliaments understanding of the urban poor who cannot access education despite fee-free policy. Using a video documentary on Dar es Salaam, the MPs had an increased understanding of the plight of children living in poor urban settlements. The Chairperson of Dar MPs, the minister for Social Welfare, promised that the Dar es Salaam MPs would sensitize, advocate and ensure the implementation of this agenda of poor urban education in their respective constituents and provide TEN/MET with whatever support they would need on this agenda so long as the statistics/data is available.

TENMET also conducted quality education conference one of the flagship event that brings on board national level speakers and those beyond Tanzania.
The conference was organized in December 2019 with the theme Quality Education, my right, the theme was expected to contribute to the achievement of sustainable development goals 4 &amp; 5. Nine papers were presented thereby provoking discussion on five TEN/MET thematic areas namely: (i) Early Childhood Education and Development (ii) Child Protection, (iii) Girls Education, (iv) Inclusive Education, (v) Teaching and Learning Environment (Quality education).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11664" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2020-01-01">
    <sida:title>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
