<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-3200007401-TZA-23110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WB TF 071411 ElectrAccess</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">WB TF 071411 Eltillg&#xE5;ng</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">F&#xF6;rberedelse av ett uppskalningsbart program till Rural Energy Agency f&#xF6;r eltillg&#xE5;ng till landsbygden och genom f&#xF6;rnyelsebara k&#xE4;llor. St&#xF6;d  till elreglersystem till reglermyndigheten f&#xF6;r el- och vattenbolag i  Tanzania. Finansieras genom en bilateral st&#xF6;dfond hanterad av         V&#xE4;rldsbanken.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preparation of a rural/renewable access-scale up programme to the     Rural Energy Agency. Support to the electricity regulatory system at  the Electricity and Water Utitility Regulatory Authority in Tanzania. Financed by a single-donor trust fund (TF) managed by the World Bank.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over several years, Sweden has financed the World Bank Trust Fund entitled &#x201C;Tanzania: Swedish Support to Electricity Access and Regulation in Tanzania&#x201D; (TF071411) with a total amount of SEK 55 million to support renewable energy scale-up; energy access acceleration; and improvements in the electricity regulatory system. The Administrative Agreement was signed in December 2009 and has been amended several times. The most recent amendment to the Trust Fund (TF) occurred during November 2019, and this amendment extended the Parent Trust Fund&#x2019;s closing date to December 31, 2020.
Over its lifetime, the TF has provided vital strategic support to supplement technical assistance resources to REA and EWURA in order to strengthen the ability of both to carry out their tasks in support to rural electrification through both on-grid and off-grid means.&#xA0;
The new Tanzania Rural Electrification Expansion Program TREEP&#x2014;whose preparation was supported by this TF&#x2014;is an innovative Program for Results (PforR) operation which was approved by the World Bank&#x2019;s Board in June 2016. The Project Agreement was signed in 15th August 2016, and the project became effective on March 17, 2017. TREEP&#x2019;s Project Development Objectives are: &#x201C;a) to increase access to electricity in rural areas; and (b) to scale-up the supply of renewable energy in rural areas while strengthening sector institutional capacity. Sida TF resources have been used to support the preparation and early-stage and supervision of the implementation of the TREEP.
The Sida TF has two Project Development Objectives: PDO I &#x2013; Rural Energy Agency (REA) and other sector stakeholders to gain capacity to develop, finance and implement a scaled-up rural electrification program, supporting renewable energy development and both on- and off-grid components. The approach to scaling-up access would be consolidated to include both grid extension and off-grid electrification.
PDO II &#x2013; Energy and Water Regulatory Authority (EWURA) to gain capacity to develop regulatory system to promote the performance of TANESCO and other organizations across the energy sector: A regulatory system for reviewing the power purchase costs from large IPPs, promoting efficient and financially sustainable Small Power Producers (SPP) and the development and implementation of credible systems to monitor the commercial, financial and operational performance of TANESCO and others.
This Conclusion on Performance provides an overview of the major achievements and activities supported under the Sida TF during the period from January 2019 to December 2019. It also provides the annal work plan and budget for coming year Jan to Dec 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBRD/International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="231" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy Policy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="23110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="7.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">7.1 - By 2030, ensure universal access to affordable, reliable and modern energy services.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">7.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomliga, tillf&#xF6;rlitliga och moderna energitj&#xE4;nster.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2009-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-01-01">655119.1006524987</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">1575907.361639499</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">947728.5335634593</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1108008.6867881045</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1995946.6928698642</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">392133.9961223925</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1055128.8778422168</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2009-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-01-01">655119.1006524987</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">1575907.361639499</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">947728.5335634593</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1108008.6867881045</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1995946.6928698642</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">392133.9961223925</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1055128.8778422165</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-12-01">7187900.212258</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-12-28">655119.1006524987</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-11-28">1575907.361639499</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-08-28">947728.5335634593</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-08-28">1108008.6867881045</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-28">1995946.6928698642</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-06-28">392133.9961223925</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">1071297.0634263095</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">-16168.1855840928</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/thailand/32000074-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The following summary provides an overview of the major achievements and activities supported under the Sida TF during the period from January- December 2019. This include all the activities and priorities for CY19, it should be noted that WB submits its Annual Progress Report in 30th April of each year.&#xA0;
A. Support the operationalization of the SPP-CL and REC-CLThe World Bank continued to support the operationalization of the Small Power Producer (SPP) and the renewable companies (REC) Credit Line (CL) but at the end of CY19 there had been only limited progress and no disbursement under the CL. This is because the Small Power Producer (SPP) market has stalled since 2017 due to a lengthy stakeholder consultation process on the revision of the SPP projects framework and new Standard Power Purchase Agreements (SPPAs). The new SPPA Rules were formally adopted by EWURA and published on June 20, 2019. However, TANESCO has been reluctant to sign long-term PPAs at fixed published tariffs due to concerns that costs of power and TANESCO&#x2019;s tariffs may fall in the future, when major new power supply projects come online. TANESCO has therefore opted to negotiate both the terms and tariffs with individual SPP developers. The continued uncertainty around the SPPA Rules has negatively affected the SPP sub-sector and the mini-grid supported by Sida and TREEP SPP CL program supported by the WB.
However, WB in colaboration with TIB and REA are making efforts to consult various stakeholders including commercial banks on how the credit lines might be enhanced to make them more attractive. Furthermore it was noted that&#xA0;lack of collateral remains a barrier to borrowing. WB, REA and TIB during the comming reporting period (2020) looking forward to&#xA0; &#xA0;one-on-one matchmaking between each PFI and REC, in order to help facilitate potential lending transactions.&#xA0;
B. Independent Verification Agent (IVA) report
The Bank hired PricewaterhouseCoopers (PWC) to serve as the Independent Verification Agent (IVA) for the TREEP project on October 1, 2018. The role of the IVA is to review and ensure accuracy of REA&#x2019;s annual progress reports that are submitted to enable disbursement against the pre-determined Disbursement Linked Indicators (DLIs) under the TREEP project . During the reporting period three reports were submitted to the Bank by REA and its Trust Agent, which showed&#xA0; the reporting Period, number of connections reported, number verified eligible connections, and percentage eligible connections over reported connections. The report and database submitted by REA had considerably less errors allowing a faster verification process, representing significant improvement in the effort of REA and its Trust Agent in collecting and compiling the data.&#xA0;
C. Community-Based Energy Education Program (C-BEEP) progress
The consultants for the C-BEEP (Energy for Impact &#x2013; E4I) made good progress on training program to support REA&#x2019;s outreach program for beneficiary communities under the grid extension program. During the reporting period a training of trainers (ToTs) was conducted in Ruangwa District during June 12-27, 2019. The Bank team accompanied REA, TANESCO and E4I for a field visit to observe the implementation of the training. The fieldtrip noted the positive response of the communities towards the program, which was found to be useful and informative.
The trainings increased interest in connections following the program and hoped for its extension to other areas that are yet to be electrified. In addition, because of the program, there was a clearer understanding of the processes of obtaining a connection and the potential hazards of electricity, and increased interest in using alternative wiring technologies such as Ready Boards in place on conventional house wiring. During the outreach, some important information and feedback was collected about concerns pertaining to the (i) transparency in the scope of eligible connection beneficiaries, (ii) demand for connections beyond REA&#x2019;s current project/program scope (iii) lack of alignment in messaging on future project scope, timelines and comparison between solar and grid electricity, (v) long lead times between applications/payments of connection fees and actual connections by TANESCO.&#xA0;In response to these concerns, the Bank agreed on some actions and new communicating strategies to be adopted by REA.&#xA0;
D. Strengthening of Environmental and Socials Safeguards Supervision
Safeguards system strengthening, monitoring and reporting remains a high priority for the TF support and is critical to deliver sustainable and equitable infrastructure services. A series of three World Bank Safeguards Implementation Support Missions conducted during the reporting period, which had observed shortfalls in safeguards implementation in the field. Inadequacies were seen particularly on labour management, occupational health and safety management and reporting, and land access procedures.
At the end of the August 2019 mission, REA and the task team agreed on a set of corrective actions for safeguards performance including: written instructions from REA to all current grid-extension contractors to abate health and safety problems identified during the field missions; finalization and distribution of the Procedural Manual that was by then available in draft, and incorporation of relevant provisions from it in bid documents and contracts for the next group of grid extension projects; completion of the guidance on voluntary land access agreements; roll-out of the Stakeholder Engagement Plan (SEP) that was included in the draft Manual; and set-up and operationalization of the Grievance Redress Mechanism (GRM) also included in the Manual. Since it had been confirmed by this time that TANESCO would not be able to place environmental staff in zonal offices, a requirement for the Program Management Consultant to be engaged to provide health, safety, environmental and social experts to allow periodic field supervision was added to the corrective actions. A follow-up WB safeguard mission is scheduled in 2020 to monitor those corrective actions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="32000074" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
