<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12105A0103-TZA-11230</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KTO Skills development for Young women through FDCs 2019-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">KTO Skills development for Young women through FDCs 2019-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KTO&apos;s overall objective is: &quot;To contribute to the socio-economic advancement of the Tanzanian society through Folk Development Colleges (FDCs) as a way to ensure progressive communities, democratic practices, citizen engagement, gender equality and sustainable development&quot;.&#xA0;KTO&apos;s&#xA0;Theory of Change rest on Folk and Adult Education philosophy, which focus on making knowledge accessible to people at the grassroots level and a strong belief in the idea that education should be organised and defined by the needs and interest of the people and that this should all rest on the firm foundation of democratic ideas.
KTO aims to develop FDCs as training and learning institutions, institutions promoting gender equality through lifelong learning and inclusive education and as platforms for meaningful citizen engagement. KTO focuses on the 55 FDCs located all over the country and these are the only institutions providing vocational training, adult education and supporting community development where young adults regardless of their educational background are accommodated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen syftar till att genom projektst&#xF6;d st&#xF6;dja Karibu Tanzania Organization, KTO, arbete med programutveckling och implementering av utbildningsprogrammet &quot;Skills development for Young women through FDCs &quot; vid 10 folkh&#xF6;gskolor samt utveckling av KTOs organisatoriska kapacitet f&#xF6;r att bidra till organisationens framtida f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;ga att driva och p&#xE5;verka utvecklingen av folk- och vuxenutbildning nationellt, regionalt och internationellt. KTO bed&#xF6;ms i detta sammanhang kunna bli en stark plattform och akt&#xF6;r som h&#xE5;ller samman ett strategiskt t&#xE4;nk och verkar i ett nationellt och internationellt sammanhang f&#xF6;r folk- och vuxenutbildning. Detta &#xE4;r relevant ur framf&#xF6;r allt ett &#xE4;garskaps- och h&#xE5;llbarhetsperspektiv.  

KTO &#xE4;r en medlemsorganisation best&#xE5;ende av mer &#xE4;n 5000 medlemmar (rektorer, l&#xE4;rare och studenter) vid Tanzanias 55 folkh&#xF6;gskolor. Medlemsorganisationens &#xF6;verordnade m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att bidra till Tanzanias socio-ekonomiska utveckling genom att p&#xE5; olika s&#xE4;tt st&#xE4;rka folk- och vuxenutbildning i Tanzania. F&#xF6;r att kunna bidra till progressiv och demokratisk samh&#xE4;llsutveckling, st&#xE4;rka medborgarnas samh&#xE4;llsengagemang, j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet mellan k&#xF6;nen och h&#xE5;llbar utveckling, arbetar KTO med och f&#xF6;r folkh&#xF6;gskolorna. KTO har utvecklat aktiviteter inom tre strategiska omr&#xE5;den: omprofilering av folkh&#xF6;gskolorna, st&#xE4;rka folkh&#xF6;gskolorna roll i arbetet med j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet genom livsl&#xE5;ngt l&#xE4;rande och inkluderande utbildning, samt utveckla KTOs roll i partnerskap och dialog med nyckelakt&#xF6;rer som verkar nationellt, regionalt och internationellt, i syfte att st&#xE4;rka folk- och vuxenutbildning. 

KTOs &#xF6;verodnade m&#xE5;l vittnar om att KTO har som ambition att vara en plattform f&#xF6;r strategisk utveckling av folk- och vuxenutbildning och bidra till ett inkluderande utbildningssytem. I KTOs arbete ing&#xE5;r utveckling och implementering av specifika utbildningsprogram av h&#xF6;g kvalitet vid folkh&#xF6;gskolorna d&#xE4;r s&#xE4;rskilt fokus &#xE4;r att inkludera unga m&#xF6;drar.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to support Karibu Tanzania Organization, KTO, with program development and implementation of the education &quot;Skills Development for Young Women Through FDCs&quot; at 10 Folk High Schools, as well as the development of KTO&apos;s organizational capacity to contribute to the organization&apos;s future ability to drive and influence development of FDCs  nationally, regionally and internationally. KTO is expected to become a strong platform and actor that holds together a strategic think and act in a national and international context for adults and adult education. This is relevant, above all, from an ownership and sustainability perspective.

KTO is a membership organization consisting of more than 5000 members (principals, teachers and students) from Tanzania&apos;s 55 Folk Development Colleges. KTO&apos;s overarching objective is &quot;to contribute to the socio-economic advancement of the Tanzanian society through FDCs as a way to ensure progressive communities, democratic practices, citizen engagement, gender equality and sustainable development&quot;. To reach this objective, KTO has operationalised the objective into three interlinked strategic areas: Rebranding the FDCs; Develop KTO&apos;s role in partnering and lobbying for Folk and Adult Education nationally, regionally and internationally; and Strengthening FDCs as a platform working for gender equality through lifelong learning and inclusive education. 

KTO&apos;s overall objective witnesses about KTO&apos;s ambition to become a platform for  strategic development of Folk and Adult Education in Tanzania and contribute to inclusive education for all. Development and implementation of high quality learning programs at the FDCs, specifically focusing at young mothers, is part of KTO&apos;s work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KTO/Karibu Tanzania Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KTO/Karibu Tanzania Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="112" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Basic life skills for youth and adults</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.1 - By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.1 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla flickor och pojkar fullbordar avgiftsfri och likv&#xE4;rdig grundskole- och gymnasieutbildning av god kvalitet som leder till relevanta och &#xE4;ndam&#xE5;lsenliga kunskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.3 - By 2030, ensure equal access for all women and men to affordable and quality technical, vocational and tertiary education, including university.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.3 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla alla kvinnor och m&#xE4;n lika tillg&#xE5;ng till yrkesutbildning och eftergymnasial utbildning, inklusive h&#xF6;gskoleutbildning, av god kvalitet till en &#xF6;verkomlig kostnad.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.1 - Avskaffa alla former av diskriminering av alla kvinnor och flickor &#xF6;verallt</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.1 - End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">349776.7258566615</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">349776.7258566615</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-18">634524.476781</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-28">325743.509560572</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">0.032574351</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">349776.7258566615</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/agreement-kto-2019-2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contract 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/12105_KTOSecondamendmentagreement2021-07-07.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Karibu Tanzania Organization (KTO)-Institutional Capacity Development and Program Implementation 2019-2022</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/decision-kto.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contract A</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key achievements 

- Folk Development Colleges as institutions have been secured in the Education sector, they are becoming popular and the government is planning to increase the number of FDCs.

- Among the major achievements during the year, where KTO was very active in advocacy together with other stakeholders, were the re-entry of girls who dropped out from education into the formal system and the Ministry&apos;s decision to adopt the program Elimu Haina Mwisho (EHM), for young women, as an alternative education pathway in all FDCs. Scale of the EHM program by the government to include all 54 FDCs. 

Sweden supports three programs: 

- The Elimu Haina Mwisho; for girls who dropped out of school due to various reasons including early pregnancies, These girls are now getting a second chance to continue their formal education in a very supporting environment at the same time learning a profession and improve their life skills. Engagement with MoEST, resulted to a directive by the Permanent Secretary to all FDCs to reserve at least 50 spaces in boarding for young mothers in 2022. This is expected to be an amicable solution to the challenge of accommodation to EHM participants and therefore boost recruitment from 2022. Strengthened delivery of training through improvement of the EHM curriculum.  FDCs collaboration with neighboring secondary education to enhance delivery of science subjects for EHM participants. 

- Training of Early Child Hood teachers and we know see the number of Early Childhood Daycare centers with trained caretakers developing to support the young mothers and the community, having a great impact on early learning and on gender empowerment. 33 Daycare centers are operating in FDCs and have been upgraded. Increased number of childcare workers in the sector through ECD training in 10 FDCs.

Mpira Fursa: a program where the FDCs also contribute to challenging gender norms and bring self esteem and learning for girls through the football programs, also involving the community and surrounding schools. Mpira Fursa program scaled to all 54 FDCs, collaborating with 2 primary schools each.

- Capacity building to tutors  to build a more cost efficient way of training and also introducing more local collaboration between FDCs who swill support each other, making it more sustainable. 

- Increased number of participants in the FDCs, both young men and women, as a result of our programs being implemented in FDCs.

- Zanzibar showing interest in the Elimu Haina Mwisho program and the FDC concept. Some participants from Zanzibar have joined the program

- Increased collaboration with Folk High Schools in Sweden and exchange programs has started.

- Anti-sextortion campaign has started in FDCs. 

- Improved institutional capacity: With support from PWC, KTO has continued to strengthen its capacities and systems with the aim to be effective in its functions with for example a revised constitution, new policys and strategies developed.  

- Election of the new KTO board: Combined they have extensive experience and expertise covering international development, education and education management, human resources, project management, public administration, governance, and law.

- The continuation of COVID-19 pandemic during the year has affected KTO with staff and their families being sick. Despite these challenges KTO managed to implement all activities on time.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12105" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2020-01-01">
    <sida:title>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
