<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5117002101-TZA-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UTPC Strategic Plan 2011-2015</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UTPC Strategic Plan 2011-2015</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UTPC&#x2019;s intervention aims at promoting democracy and development by enhancing the capacity of journalists in the regions, building institutional capacity of 27 press clubs and improving UTPC&#x2019;s secretariat to serve its stakeholders. UTPC has applied to Sida for an extension of the specific agreement with sum of SEK 11 386,860 to implement its work plan during July 2014-December 2015. 

This request comes up because the three year funding from Sida to support UTPC&#x2019;s strategic plan ended in on 30 June 2014. The requested fund will bridge the gap between the current strategic plan and next strategic plan 2015-2019 at the same time enables UTPC consolidate the gains achieved under the current strategic plan. In addition, the extension will allow some space for UTPC to complete development of the next strategic plan and time for mobilizing founding sources, beyond Swedish funding. 

UTPC&apos;s total cost during 2011-2013 has been SEK 34,303,656 out of which SEK 33,583,656 (98%) is the Swedish conTribution on components 01 and 02 and SEK 720,000. i.e 4%  is from UTPC. With the additional sum of SEK 11,134,516 the Swedish total contribution during 2011-2015 will amount to SEK 45,352,445 ( as seen on decision on page one ) and UTPC&apos;s share of SEK 422,000 will add up to SEK 1,142,000.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Union of Tanzania Press Clubs (UTPC) has applied to Sida for an extension of the specific agreement with sum of SEK 11,386,860 to implement its eighteen month work plan during July 2014-December 2015. This request comes up because the three year funding from Sida to support UTPC&#x2019;s strategic plan ended in 30 June 2014. The requested fund will bridge the gap between the current strategic plan and next strategic plan 2016-2019 at the same time enables UTPC consolidate the gains achieved under the current strategic plan. In addition, the extension will allow for space for UTPC to complete development of the next strategic plan and time for mobilizing funding sources, beyond Swedish funding. 

UTPC&#x2019;s total budget during July 2014-December 2015 is Tshs 2,798,699,820 MSEK 11,808,860; out of which Tshs 2,698,,686,326 (MSEK 11,386,860, i.e. 96%) is the expected Swedish contribution and the remaining Tsh 100,000,000 (SEK 422,000, i.e. 4%) is from UTPC. As SEK 381,929 remains to be disbursed from Sida to UTPC, an additional Swedish contribution of SEK 11,134,516 is required to fill the gap.

With the earlier decided costs of Tshs 900,000 for procurement audits, and with a total contribution corresponding to SEK 1,142,000 from UTPC (additional SEK 422,000, and earlier SEK 720,000) the total contribution for the intervention will increase from SEK 35,456,000 to SEK 45,352,445 ( as seen on the decision page one) with the Swedish share constituting 98% and the UTPC share 2%.

The said Swedish contribution SEK 11,386,860 shall be made available in two disbursements. The first disbursement shall be SEK 7,386,860 and shall be made upon signature of the amended agreement by both parties and request for payment by UTPC. The second disbursement shall be SEK 4,000,000 and shall be made after approval by Sida of results and  audit reports for 2014.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UTPC/Union of Tanzania Press Club</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UTPC/Union of Tanzania Press Club</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1710883.1597115207</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1618550.724637681</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1749677.577841921</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1350764.5949248455</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1710883.1597115207</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">1618550.724637681</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1749677.577841921</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1350764.5949248453</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-06-01">6909953.615237</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-06-28">760818.8343709548</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-11-28">950064.3068483017</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-28">1618550.7660033386</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-28">1749677.577841921</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-28">876229.3428873097</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">474535.2520375358</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General question: Results related to the intended outcome 2015Question: Summarise results related to the intended outcome (this information will be sent to Open Aid)Answer: Improvement of Journalist capacity.
Evidence from the 2015 annual report indicates some improvement in Journalist&apos;s capacity in exercising their roles. Investment in training for 900 Journalists in areas of business reporting, investigative journalism, Feature Writing, Human Rights governance and democracy, policy analysis budget tracking and Court reporting has contributed in enhancing efficiencies and effectiveness in their work. For example for a print media, a total of 920 stories, 420 features and 300 Photos were published as a result. For electronic media, UTPC monitored 1300 stories which is an increase of 71% compared to the year 2014. The coverage from the print and Electronic media is an evidence of improved reporting capacity and stimulation for regional development in respective regions.  

According to the 2015 annual report, 5 members of press clubs won Journalist Awards for different categories. It is also evident that some stories by different Journalist have influenced decisions of the duty bearers for the benefit of the right holders. For example, there were actions taken by different authorities in response to media intervention: Dispensaries were built, theatre rooms constructed, pediatric ward, and medical equipment bought to improve poor people conditions in accessing health services. This link between media and improvement of service delivery opens up for dialogue and contribute to an expanded role the media in promoting right to Health care. 

Press Club institutional capacity.
Press Clubs have had better prerequisites during the period since the offices have been equipped with technical tools, ICT facilities and furniture to enable them to perform their duties more effectively. At Tanga Press Club for example, journalists use office computers five times a week as opposed to two times last year.  

Exchange visits amongst press clubs have shaped thinking and management of individual Press Clubs. Simiyu a newly established Press Club visited a well-functioning Press Club in Kigoma to understand and learn office practices and management proceedings. Similarly a new Njome Press Club visited Tanga Press Club which has built a unique linkage with other stakeholders like Tanga Sewage and Water Authority, Blood Bank unit at regional hospital and Police Force. Through a media Campaign pioneered by UTPC, this linkage was able to mobilize more than 500 people to donate blood voluntarily and at the moment there are reported cases of more regular donors visiting the hospital for voluntary blood donation. The Campaign compliments Ministry of Health initiative in Tanzania promoting departure from blood replacement to regular donation.                                                                                                                                

Another achievement in ensuring press contribute to sustainable development by the year 2015 is the support UTPC has provided in reviewing press club&#x2019;s constitutions in light of improving governance and democracy. The 2015 report also highlights very good achievements from individual press clubs in the regions. For example Iringa PC has started its SACCOS, Arusha PC has established a media firm and Kigoma and Tanga PC bought a plot of land for purpose of building their own office in future.

UTPC (Union of Tanzania Press Clubs) capacity to serve its stakeholders
UTPS trained individual press clubs on diverse management and organizational concepts envisioned to enable them to develop relationship with other stakeholders outside media and explore fundraising opportunities. As a result, UTPC was able to partner with a program called Evidence For Action (E4A) to Campaign for better conditions for maternal and newborn in Tanzania. UNESCO developed a partnership with UTPC to monitor Radio and TV coverage during election last year for the purpose of promoting Peace and security. For promotion of democracy and good governance in Tanzania, UTPC interviewed and featured stories of 78 aspirants for councilor position during October 2015 election and fortunately 58 of them won the election. This Project was funded by Mariestops in Tanzania to promote Citizen Participation in political processes. 

Press clubs and its members still face challenges, especially notable are limitations in the mandate to push for better working conditions and better payment for journalists. The solutions to advocate and negotiate are beyond UTPCs&#xB4; control and scope.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51170021" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
