<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5117001401-TZA-33120</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Mark East Africa - Tanzania window</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Trade Mark East Africa - Tanzania window</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased Trade Competitiveness among EAC partner states (and South Sudan) through1. Increased physical access to markets2. Enhanced trade environment3. Improved business competitiveness</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Detta beslut avser ett till&#xE4;gg till tidigare fattat beslut om insats (2010/211) och avtalsf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndring (2012/204). Till f&#xF6;ljd av f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringens storlek ska enligt insatsregeln ett kompletterande Beslut om insats fattas.

Ambassaden i Dar es Salaam beslutade i december 2010 om st&#xF6;d till det regionala programmet TradeMark East Africa som DFID utvecklat tillsammans med partners. Syftet med programmet &#xE4;r fortsatt att st&#xF6;dja &#xF6;kad regional integration och konkurrenskraftig handel inom &#xF6;stafrikanska gemenskapen (EAC) och med samma &#xF6;vergripande resultatramverk. TMEA Tanzania var ursprungligen ett 5 &#xE5;rsprogram 2010-2015 och omfattar nu perioden fram till december 2016. En ny TMEA strategi f&#xF6;r fas 2 av programmet, regionalt och bilateralt, &#xE4;r under utformning och avser perioden 2017 - 2021. Det st&#xF6;d som ambassaden beviljade 2010 avs&#xE5;g perioden 2010-2013, d v s inte hela 5 &#xE5;rsprogrammet, och f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;ngdes sedan till december 2014. I beredningspromemorian fr&#xE5;n december 2010, stycke 3.2, st&#xE5;r att ett eventuellt fortsatt st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r den resterande delen av programperioden ska bed&#xF6;mas utifr&#xE5;n programmets utveckling och finansieringsbehov samt insatsen relevans i f t den nya resultatstrategin f&#xF6;r utvecklingssamarbetet mellan Sverige och Tanzania.

De insatser som d&#xE5; kan genomf&#xF6;ras/ut&#xF6;kas &#xE4;r:

1. St&#xF6;d till kvinnor som sysslar med handel &#xF6;ver landsgr&#xE4;nserna och utveckla en strategi f&#xF6;r gr&#xE4;nshandel.

2. Inf&#xF6;rande av WTO avtal om underl&#xE4;ttande av handel (TFA) och handelsportaler
3. F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttrad marknadstillg&#xE5;ng och konkurrenskraft p&#xE5; exportmarknaden f&#xF6;r jordbruksprodukter

Genom att tillf&#xF6;ra ytterligare medel om 25 MSEK m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;rs genomf&#xF6;rande av ovan n&#xE4;mnda projekt som genom sitt fokus p&#xE5; kvinnors m&#xF6;jligheter till f&#xF6;retagande och &#xF6;kade inkomster; nyttjande av informationsteknologi f&#xF6;r effektivisering; samt utveckling av exportmarknader f&#xF6;r jordbruksprodukter bed&#xF6;ms vara angel&#xE4;gna bidrag till genomf&#xF6;randet av resultatstrategin f&#xF6;r utvecklingssamarbetet med Tanzania. Utbetalningarna f&#xF6;rdelas &#xF6;ver tv&#xE5; &#xE5;r med 10 MSEK 2015 respektive 15 MSEK 2016. &#xD6;verv&#xE4;gande har gjorts om utbetalningen 2016 b&#xF6;r delas upp i tv&#xE5; tillf&#xE4;llen men med tanke p&#xE5; att Sveriges bidrag fr&#xE4;mst avser budget&#xE5;ret juli 2015 - juni 2016 och &#xE4;r relativt begr&#xE4;nsad i den totala budgeten har endast en utbetalning f&#xF6;r 2016 f&#xF6;reslagits f&#xF6;r att inte i on&#xF6;dan &#xF6;ka transaktionskostnaderna f&#xF6;r organisationen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This decision concerns an amendment to an earlier decision on contribution (2010/211) and amendment of agreement (2012/204). Due to the size of the change the Contribution Management Rule states that there should be a complementary Decisions on contribution.

The Embassy in Dar es Salaam decided in December 2010 on support for the regional program Trademark East Africa which DFID has developed together with partners. The program is continuing to support increased regional integration and competitive trade within the East African Community (EAC) and with the same overall results framework. TMEA Tanzania was originally a five year program from 2010 to 2015 and now covers the period up to December 2016. A new TMEA strategy for Phase 2 of the program, regionally and bilaterally, is under design and covers the period 2017 - 2021. The support which the Embassy decided on 2010 referred to the period 2010-2013, i e not the full 5 year program, and was later extended to December 2014. In preparing the memorandum of December 2010, paragraph 3.2, states that a possible further support for the remainder of the program period will be appraised in relation to the program&apos;s development and financing needs, as well as its relevance in relation to the new Results strategy for the development cooperation between Sweden and Tanzania.

By providing additional funding of SEK 25 million the implementation of the above projects is made possible. The projects with their focus on women&apos;s opportunities for employment and increased incomes; use of information technology for efficiency; and the development of export markets for agricultural products are important contributions to the implementation of the results strategy for development cooperation with Tanzania. The payments are distributed over two years, with 10 MSEK in 2015 and 15 million in 2016. Consideration was made if the payment in 2016 should be divided into two occasions but considering that Sweden&apos;s contribution mainly concerns the financial year July 2015 - June 2016, and is relatively limited compared to the total budget, only one payment for 2016 is proposed in order not to unduly increase transaction costs for the organization.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trademark East Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trademark East Africa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="331" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Policies &amp; Regulations</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="33120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade facilitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B04" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">1388464.635805726</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1541022.0057942427</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">1388464.635805726</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">1541022.0057942427</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2012-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-12-01">5553858.543222</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-12-28">1388464.635805726</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-12-28">1541022.0057942427</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-28">1535343.6098998955</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The TMEA- Tanzania programmes showed mixed results during the programme period of 2010-2017. Many activities were severely delayed and implementation was to some extent at a stand still during long periods. As a result, some results are exceeding targets and some are&#xA0;below expectations.
Furthermore, as&#xA0;the result framework and the indicators to measure success&#xA0;are on such aggregated level, is it rather difficult to clearly assess attribution and the role of TMEA. Also, most of the reporting of TMEA is focused on output level rather than results&#xA0;and outcomes. Therefore the summary of results focus on those activities that there has been a clear and direct involvement of TMEA.
Examples of results during the programme period are:
1. TMEA contributed to reduction&#xA0;of cross-border time&#xA0;with a measured overall reduction of 49,6% compared to the targeted 30% average through the construction of One-Stop Border Posts (OSBPs). &#xA0;For example the construction of the Uganda-Tanzania OSBP at the Mutukula border crossing contributed to a 67 % reduction, Holili to Kenya&#xA0;24 % and Kabanga to Burundi 58%. The planned OSBP at Tunduma crossing to Zambia, expected to be completed in 2015, was&#xA0;not completed during the programme period. The idea behind the OSBP is to reduce clearance time by avoiding duplication of clearing processes, which would also contribute to increases in trade volumes at the OSBP in particular. The OSBPs include merging of services by the police, customs and immigration, including inspection sheds and warehouses.&#xA0;After&#xA0;construction,&#xA0;the OSBPs have been&#xA0;handed over to the Tanzania Revenue Authority.
TMEA has also supported the creation of institutional and legal frameworks for border management through an integrated border management (IBM) system that includes OSBP procedures, training of border officials and installation of ICT networks and equipment.
2. TMEA supported the Tanzania Private Sector Foundation (TPSF) to develop a web portal with information on regional integration, which has had 12 000 visitors per quarter. The TPSF also developed and started the implementation of a 5 year strategy to increase the interest, awareness and participation of the Tanzanian private sector in the EAC integration. As part of its development, a number of workshops and a value chain study for rice were conducted as well as a policy scoping study on improving rice exports as well as a high-level policy dialogue for Tanzanian rice value chain stakeholders.
Furthermore, the support from TMEA to TPSF and Civil Society foundation contributed to the submission of 42 recommendations for adoption by parliament committees and relevant ministries,&#xA0;out of which&#xA0;21 recommendations were adopted.
3. According to the former PS at Ministry of East Africa Cooperation (MEAC) Ms Joyce Mapunjo, TMEA has supported the Ministry in providing needed leadership and coordination of EAC integration at the national level. The support from TMEA has been in the form of developing an electronic monitoring system for EAC integration, drafting a common market implementation strategy and a national integration strategy, and conducting training needs assessments and training programs for ministry staff. As part of public information campaigns the MEAC also developed billboards at border crossings to provide information on EAC integration and aired 13 television and radio programmes on EAC integration in local TV and radio.
4. Women cross border traders face specific and different challenges than men. They are more often informal, undeclared, unaware of rules and procedures and more often exposed to harassment. TMEA has therefore sought to support women cross border traders through training and the establishment of information desks. As part of this, a baseline survey on constraints faced by women&#xA0;was conducted and about 2000 women have been trained on EAC trading rules, regulations and standards.
5. Non-tariff barriers (NTBs)&#xA0;are one of the greatest challenges to trade in East Africa as they inflict high costs&#xA0;of trade to businesses. NTBs include border procedures, police roadblocks, and bureaucratic procedures. TMEA has therefore collaborated with Tanzania Chamber of Commerce (TCCIA) to introduce a NTB SMS reporting system. In one month after its introduction, TCCIA received 87 NTB related cases and 54 % were resolved. In 2016/17 the target of 45 NTBs reported and resolved&#xA0;was reached and exceeded and actual was 53. The elimination of NTBs has led to lowering the time it takes to transport cargo through the central corridor from 14 days in 2014 to average 3.5 days in 2017.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51170014" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
