<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-11146A0102-TZA-23210</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultancy support for procurement in the REF-support</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Konsultst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r upphandlingar inom REF-st&#xF6;det</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consultancy support to validate procurments undertaken within the support to Rural Energy Agency</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Konsultst&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r att validera upphandlingar inom st&#xF6;det till Rural Energy Agency</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Rural Energy Agency (REA) is responding to the Tanzanian Governments aim to reach the UN initiative for Sustainable Energy for All (SE4ALL) Agenda of achieving universal access by 2030 by opening a window for co-financing private sector renewable energy investments. Cooperation between the Government and the private sector through different types of public private partnerships is considered key elements in the effort to rapidly expand sustainable energy access. The Government of Sweden and United Kingdom through Swedish International Development Agency (Sida) and Department for 
International Development (DFID) respectively have contributed for supporting investments in Green Mini and Micro Grids.

The private sector financing window used strategically to incentivize small scale oriented investors to enter the rural electrification area and/or to expand ongoing electrification activities into less-served, more remote off-grid areas  within Mainland Tanzania for socio-economic development. A Results Based Financing (RBF) approach used where capital grant incentives be offered to Green Mini and Micro Grids (GMGs) project developers with realistic business plans, based on the verified number of electricity connections resulting from the financing support.

The Government of the United Republic of Tanzania, through the Rural Energy Agency (REA), is implementing a rural electrification programme financially supported by Sweden. Part of this programme is supporting the development of minigrid projects, i.e. small and isolated electricity generation and distribution facilities. Projects eligible for financial support are selected through a Call for Proposals process. REA is incharge of this process and has stipulated criteria that projects must meet in order to be eligible for financial support. The financial support given to eligible projects are the same to all as do
not vary according to their level of service, i.e. the amount and quality of the power provided to the customers connected facility.

The objective of the consultancy service (KPMG) was to support the Rural Energy Agency (REA) analyse and comment on the evaluation process; of its fairness and transparency. The objective was also to provide advise and backstopping to the embassy during the procurement and evaluation processes, as it was likely that questions of how to evaluate raised during the process. Additional objective was to provide advise and backstopping on the financial robustness of some proposals (i.e. those that to Sweden may appear unusual in their financial model). Lastly, an objective was also to assist Sweden in assessing how the proposals intend to finance the part of the projects that is required to be covered by the project proponent themselves.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KPMG Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KPMG Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="23210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy generation, renewable sources - multiple technologies</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="232" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy generation, renewable sources</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="7.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">7.2 - By 2030, increase substantially the share of renewable energy in the global energy mix.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">7.2 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligen &#xF6;ka andelen f&#xF6;rnybar energi i den globala energimixen.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">88854.0148538516</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">88854.0148538516</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-20">89164.853164</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-28">55147.2210239131</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-28">33706.7705114902</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first round of RBF grant call for proposal was launched in September 2016 whereby mini and micro grid project developers in Tanzania were invited to submit applications for result based grants geared to supporting accelerated access to sustainable energy services in un-served rural areas of Mainland Tanzania. During the first call for proposed 13 companies were awareded RBF grant total of USD 10,805,200, for 113 villages with total connection 20,020. The implementation of the grants awarded under RBF Round 1 completed and it was therefore decided to launch the second round of the RBF program
towards the end of 2019.

The RBF Second Call invitation noted Tanzania&apos;s islands specifically to Lake Victoria, Lake Tanganyika and along the Indian Ocean coast as high priority areas and prospective applicants were given access to the list of priority islands to assist in crafting their applications. The second round of RBF grant call for proposal was launched in November 2019 whereby mini and micro grid project developers in Tanzania were invited to submit applications/Concept Notes for result based grants geared at supporting accelerated access to sustainable energy services in un-served rural areas of Mainland Tanzania. The application closing date was 7th February 2020 and a total of 27 Applications/Concept Notes were received and the evaluation team recommended to the Rural Energy Agency, a total of 12 proposals with a combined grant amount of USD 15,945,000 and connection of 24,005 within a total of 122 villages (i.e. 64 are new villages and 73 villages for densification) as stipulated in the REA RBF Off-Grid Operating Guideline. The financial support given to projects vary according to the level of service, i.e. the amount and quality of the power, provided to customers connected to the facility implemented by the project. The Consultancy service (KPMG) played  a role during the call for proposals and evaluation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="11146" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061203" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3000000000" strategy-end-date="2024-12-31" strategy-start-date="2020-01-01">
    <sida:title>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Tanzania 2020-2024</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
