<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5117008506-TZA-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TGNP MTANDAO CORE SUPPORT 2016-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">TGNP MTANDAO CORE SUPPORT 2016-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the signing of the core support in 2016, the TGNP Mtandao has drafted a new strategic plan for 2021-2025. Although the outcomes have to some extent been altered the overarching mission of TGNP remains the same:
&#x201C; To build a vibrant transformative feminist movement that contributes to the struggles against patriarchy and neo liberalism for social and gender equality and women empowerment in Tanzania and beyond.&#x201D;
The current strategic plan for 2021-2025 focuses on the following four core outcomes:
Outcome areas 1: Increased generation and use of reliable transformative feminism knowledge among civil society actors and particularly women rights organizations for evidence-based advocacy, collective organizing for enhanced movement building and public policy influencing.
Outcome areas 2: Strengthened transformative feminism and gender analytical capacity, ideological clarity of women movement constituencies that effectively demand inclusiveness, agency in participation, voice, ownership, and promotion of accountability at the local and national levels.
Outcome areas 3: Expanded and strengthened spaces and platforms for advancing transformative feminism, gender equality and women&#x2019;s rights and empowerment.
Outcome areas 4: Enhanced institutional and organizational capacity for further promotion of growth, sustainability and health organization for increased efficiency.
These outcomes are expected to contribute to the overall goal which is &#x201C;to contribute towards deepening and enhancing ideological clarity on Transformative Feminist agenda for advancing social, gender equality, women empowerment, and movement building.&#x201D;
The organisations main strategies include analysis and research; especially participatory action research; Communication and information; capacity building; engagement with policy and budget formulation, building and strengthening networks and coalitions with likeminded organisations for collective voices on women rights and social justice, implementation and monitoring process (with a focus on key sectoral policies as they link with macroeconomic policy frameworks).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TGNP Mtandao formerly the Tanzania Gender Networking Programme was formed in 1993. TGNP Mtandao has been identified as a partner who will contribute significantly to the achievement of results in gender equality in the Results strategy for Sweden&#x2019;s international development cooperation in Tanzania 2013&#x2013;2019.Since its inception, the organisation has strived to become a major voice for womens rights, gender equality/equity  and social justice in Tanzania and beyond. The focus of the intervention during 2016 - 2019 will be on improving citizens participation  especially women in decision making systems at both local and national levels. This will be achieved through:
1) Pursuing strategic interventions aimed at strengthening citizens voice in demanding for accountability from the government in provision of social services.
2) Building skills and capacities of grassroots animators to sustain their livelihoods while undertaking advocacy campaigns on issues affecting women and marginalised people in their communities. 
3) Capacity strengthening programme for women elected in various leadership positions
4) Mainstreaming women issues into National Policies and Budgets

TGNP seeks to build a vibrant transformative feminist movement that would contribute towards social and gender equality and women empowerment in Tanzania. The organisation has strong focus both at grassroots, national level and beyond; at grassroots TGNP facilitates strengthening of the transformative feminist movement through collective organising and actions in demanding for government accountability in improving the provision of social services and livelihoods; while at national level and beyond TGNP works with likeminded coalitions, networks and organisations in policy engagement to influence for gender responsive policies, budgets and programmes. 

In 2015, a midterm review of current TGNP Strategic Plan highlighted the need to extend the Strategic Plan for an additional two years (2018- 2019) in order to build on the realities of the developments in the Global arena, with the advent of the Sustainable Development Goals which demand that development actors shape their priorities in line with the SDPs goals. The relevance of TGNP is particularly linked to goal 5 which focuses on achieving gender equality and empowement of women and Girls and goals 2, 3, 4 and 6 which prioritise agriculture, health, education, and water. These goals provide an opportunity for the development actors such as TGNP to be innovative and maximise delivery of results and impact.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">TGNP Mtandao, tidigare k&#xE4;nd som the Tanzania Gender Networking Programme, grundandes 1993. TGNP Mtandao har identifierats som en partner med potential att aktivt bidra till att resultat som r&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mlikhet i resultatstrategin f&#xF6;r svenskt utvecklingssamarbete i Tanzania 2013-2019. Organisationen har sedan grundandet str&#xE4;vat efter att bli en framtr&#xE4;dande r&#xF6;st f&#xF6;r kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter, j&#xE4;mlikhet och social r&#xE4;ttvisa i Tanzania. Insatsens fokus under 2016-2019 kommer vara att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra medborgerligt delatagandet, s&#xE4;rskilt f&#xF6;r kvinnor, inom beslutsfattande processer p&#xE5; b&#xE5;de nationell och lokal niv&#xE5;. Detta kommer att uppn&#xE5;s genom:
1)	Strategiska insatser i syfte att st&#xE4;rka folkets r&#xF6;st s&#xE5; att ansvar kan utkr&#xE4;vas av regeringen f&#xF6;r hur sociala tj&#xE4;nster tillhandah&#xE5;lls.
2)	Kapacitetst&#xE4;rkande program f&#xF6;r ledare i byadministrationer med syfte att de ska kunna ha en inkomst samtidigt som de arbetar i sina byar f&#xF6;r kvinnors och utsatta gruppers r&#xE4;ttigheter.
3)	Kapacitetsst&#xE4;rkande program f&#xF6;r kvinnor i ledarroller runt om i landet.
4)	P&#xE5;verkansarbete f&#xF6;r att kvinnors perspektiv ska influera nationella policys och budgetar.
TGNP vill bygga en tranformativ feministisk r&#xF6;relse som bidrar till j&#xE4;mlikhet, social r&#xE4;ttvisa och kvinnligt sj&#xE4;lvf&#xF6;rverkligande i Tanzania. Organisationen arbetar p&#xE5; lokal s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l som p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5;. P&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5; st&#xE4;rker TGNP den feministiska r&#xF6;relsen genom att organisera och koordinera ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande av regeringen n&#xE4;r det handlar om sociala tj&#xE4;nster, och p&#xE5; nationell niv&#xE5; samarbetar TGNP med liknande r&#xF6;relser, n&#xE4;tverk och organisationer f&#xF6;r att p&#xE5;verka politiskt i linje med sina m&#xE5;l.
I 2015 &#xE5;rs halvtidsutv&#xE4;rdering av TGNP:s strategiska plan belystes vikten av att f&#xF6;rl&#xE4;nga planen i tv&#xE5; &#xE5;r f&#xF6;r att kunna bygga p&#xE5; utvecklingen efter lanseringen av FNs h&#xE5;llbara utvecklingsm&#xE5;l som kr&#xE4;ver att utvecklingsakt&#xF6;rers m&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttningar &#xE4;r i linje med utvecklingsm&#xE5;len. S&#xE4;rskilt relevant f&#xF6;r TGNP &#xE4;r utvecklingsm&#xE5;l 5 som fokuserar p&#xE5; j&#xE4;mlikhet och kvinnligt sj&#xE4;lvf&#xF6;rverkligande. &#xC4;ven m&#xE5;l 2, 3, 4 och 6 ber&#xF6;r TGNP d&#xE5; de fokuserar p&#xE5; jordbruk, h&#xE4;lsa, utbildning och sanitetsfr&#xE5;gor. Utvecklingsm&#xE5;len inneb&#xE4;r tillf&#xE4;lle f&#xF6;r utvecklingsakt&#xF6;rer, s&#xE5;som TGNP, att maximera resultat och p&#xE5;verkan genom innovativa l&#xF6;sningar.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TGNP/Tanzania Gender Networking Programme Mtandao</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TGNP/Tanzania Gender Networking Programme Mtandao</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/contract-1-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement on Core support to TGNP Mtandao</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/contract-a-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on core support</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Examples of TGNP programme results 2019
In 2019, TGNP engaged directly with a total of 10,179 people ( 6555F:3624M) through various interventions.This is an increase of 30% from the previous year 2018.
A. Mapping of Potential Women Leaders and stakeholders in 9 regions and 24 districts
The mapping of potential women leaders aimed at identifying potential women to contest for various positions in the local government elections.
1) The maping identified 686 women aspirants, out of these 415 were trained. Of the 415 aspirants, 291 ( 70%) were sufficiently knowledgeable of their political rights, 73% (303) have 10 to 25 years experience as party members, 320 ( 77%) stood as candidates in previous elections, and 286 (69%) played leadership roles. Also, a total of 80 mentors were identified to mentor 400 women aspirants.
2) Mapping of stakeholders focused on identifying influential people with constituencies behind who could raise awareness on the importance of participation in leadership through local government elections.
3) A total of 718&#xA0; ( 429F: 289M) stakeholders were identified, including 72 NGOs, 72 Faith based organisations, 125 Community Networks, 96 Traditional leaders, 125 Religious leaders, 50 community media. 150 Community based organisations and groups and 48 women LGA leaders at village and ward levels. 411 stakeholders were trained on the importance of supporting women&apos;s participation in political leadership. As a result, the stakeholders utilised their constituencies and platforms for sensitisation. A total number of 6,699 people ( 3817F:2,882M) were reached directly.&#xA0;
4) 320 stakeholders ( 187F:133M) were trained on how to influence and support women&apos;s participation in leadership for local and national elections. &#xA0;

B. Mapping of Womens rights organisations in 9 regions and 19 districts
The Mapping of Womens Rights Organisations (WRO) aimed at identifying WROs from various sectors and geographical locations to assist TGNP in coordinating and strengthening the transformative feminist movement building through capacity buidling of WROs, movements and networks, forums, platforms and coalitions in selected regions and districts who can be engaged as partners in the Womens Voice and Leadership Project implementation
1) A total of 509 organisations and groups were mapped of whom 80% did not have any knowledge about feminism, 45% were womens rights organisations, 35% were women organisations, 20% feminist organisations at a varying conceptual understanding of feminism.&#xA0;
2) As a result of the mapping, 120 organisations were selected to be part of the TGNP Womens Voice and Leadership Tanzania project.
3) The mapping will also facilitate the management and sharing of information from movement building interventions executed by the stakeholders.

C. Support to elected and appointed women leaders to participate and influence gender responsive decisions&#xA0;
1) In order to strengthen the capacity of women leaders, TGNP conducted capacity building interventions to 2000 selected women leaders including parliamentarians, councillors, local government aspirants, candidates and women leaders at LGA level.The capacity strengthening interventions included training and advocacy sessions, mentorship and coaching, one on one dialogues and intergenerational discussions. Major topics covered were gender responsive budgeting, financing of national plan of action against VAC, menstrual hygiene management, availability of water in rural areas, women control and ownership of land and women participation in leadership.
2) As part of tracking utilisation of knowlegde, skills and evidence provided to influence the inclusion of gender issues, TGNP monitors parliamentary proceedings,to assess gender/feminist issues raised and who raised the issues. During the 11th Parliamentary session , a total of 23 women and 49 male Parliamentarians raised important gender issues.
3). TGNP engaged with oversight and decision making structures through evidence based advocacy using information, data and realities generated through knowledge and analyses. Information generated from analyses and research findings was used as evidence to inform Gender Champion Members of Parliament ( MPs) so that they can substantiate their arguments/views during National Assembly discussions.TGNP strengthened the capacities of elected, appointed and other women so that they could participate in and influence gender responsive decisions at various levels. This enabled women MPs to raise various issues including the impact of unsafe Menstrual Hygiene Management on the education of girl students, slow pace in financing implementation of the National Plan of Action to end VAWC, and removal/review of interest rates on women empowerment related interventions.
4) Training was conducted to the Local Government Women Leaders Association whose members are all women councillors in Tanzania. The Association is led by women chairpersons from 5 councils in Tanzania. 68 women councillors participated in the training. The training focused on gender responsive budgeting and leadership, coaching and mentorship. Mentorship and coaching were identified as key means of supporting women to graduate from special seats to electoral constituencies. One important result of this initiative is that women leaders at village and hamlet level in 5 councils increased by 75% from 565 to 989 during local government authority ( LGA) elections in 2019. The mentorship program has 198 mentors and 1,040 mentees at the national and local levels.

Some of the Key challenges noted during the implementation period include:
1. Persistence of negative beliefs, norms and traditions that are major stumbling blocks to women&apos;s political participation and leadership. The patriarchy system views women as weak creatures so many women are neither allowed to participate in meetings nor allowed to speak in front of men or become leaders.
2. Shrinking Civic Space: the recent Written Law Miscellaneous Amendment No 3 Act 2019 is another stumbling block that continues to constrain CSOs from providing an alternative voice in the country.
3. The Local Government Elections were an opportunity to increase the number of women in leadership positions. However, the LGA elections did not adequately provide for that opportunity,due to the fact that political parties, which are a gateway for political leadership positions some did not fully participate in the elections, hence denying women their rights of contesting for leadership positions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51170085" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
