<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5117008701-TZA-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media Council of Tanzania, MCT</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Media Council of Tanzania, MCT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall Outcome for MCT Strategic Plan The environment for media/press freedom and freedom of expression is enhanced and defended and the media are accountable while exercising their rights enabling them to provide the public with diverse information and views in a professional manner. 

 Outcomes for the areas for Swedish support
 - Outcome 1 Advocacy for repeal and review of anti-media laws - Concerted efforts by media and political stakeholders to make current media and other laws and regulations more media-friendly and accountable to press freedom 
 - Outcome 3 Arbitration MCT Arbitration of complaints is improved and widely accepted by public and the media</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sverige har varit med att fr&#xE5;n b&#xF6;rjan bygga upp Tanzanias medier&#xE5;d vilken fyller en viktig demokratisk funktion i landet. R&#xE5;det &#xE4;gs av medierna sj&#xE4;lva och &#xE4;r en frivillig instans dit allm&#xE4;nheten kan v&#xE4;nda sig med klagom&#xE5;l. MCT medlar, arbetar med medieetik och p&#xE5;verkansarbete. Denna insats st&#xF6;der ett projekt som framf&#xF6;rallt &#xE4;mnar att st&#xE4;rka pressfrihet, yttrandefrihet och medieetik. En del av projektet &#xE4;r inriktat p&#xE5; p&#xE5;verkansarbete f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra den nuvarande och kommande medialagstiftningen p&#xE5; fastlandet och p&#xE5; Zanzibar. Detta arbete g&#xF6;rs i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med en rad nationella, regionala och internationella partnerorganisationer och n&#xE4;tverk, samt i dialog med regeringen p&#xE5; fastlandet och Zanzibar. Den andra delen av projektet fokuserar p&#xE5; &#xF6;kad mediaprofessionalism och ansvarstagande av medier och journalister. MCT vill uppn&#xE5; detta genom forts&#xE4;tta och &#xF6;kat fr&#xE4;mjande av sj&#xE4;lvregulation av medier och organisationens medlingsarbete som ska g&#xF6;ras mer k&#xE4;nt f&#xF6;r allm&#xE4;nheten i hela Tanzania.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden has been part of building up the Media Council of Tanzania from the outset, which fills an important democratic function in the country. The council is owned by the media itself and is a voluntary body the public can turn to in order to file complaints against media. MCT mediates, works with media ethics and advocacy work. This initiative supports a project aimed primarily at strengthening freedom of the press, freedom of expression and media ethics. Part of the project focuses on efforts to improve current and future media legislation in the mainland and Zanzibar. This work is being done in close cooperation with a number of national, regional and international partner organizations and networks, as well as in dialogue with the government on the mainland and Zanzibar. The second part of the project focuses on increased media professionalism and ethics of media and journalists. MCT wants to achieve this by continuing and increasing the promotion of self-regulation of media and the organization&apos;s mediation work, which will be made more widely known to the public throughout Tanzania.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media Council of Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media Council of Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-26" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania, United Republic of</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.b - Promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.b - Verka f&#xF6;r och genomdriva icke-diskriminerande lagstiftning och politik f&#xF6;r en h&#xE5;llbar utveckling.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">230139.0039583908</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">148055.7112490614</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">86864.9358828192</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">230139.0039583907</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">148055.7112490615</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">86864.9358828192</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-26">483291.908312</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-28">115069.5019791954</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">115069.5019791954</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">74027.8556245307</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">74027.8556245307</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-28">86864.9358828192</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/tanzania/51170087_GrantAgreement2018-2020.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contract 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Quality of Journalism and Compliance with Media Code of Ethics: This is attributed to quality media monitoring and training programmes through regional press clubs whose journalists have benefited from. According to MCT 2020 annual report, It is worth noting that about 70% of reportage of local content in the mainstream media comes from upcountry journalists, and MCT involvement together with partners like UTPC has been instrumental.

In 2020, There was Dar es Salaam Declaration on Editorial Freedom, Independence and Responsibility (DEFIR): DEFIR emphasizes on the duties and obligation of media practitioners and other stakeholders, NOT their rights. This was a major output by the MCT Think Tank on Freedom of Expression and Media Issues led by distinguished Professor Emeritus Issa Shivji. The Swedish Embassy is lso a signatory of this Declaration.

MCT has managed to bring together and lead a coalition of 12 CSOs to fight for the right to information legislation and a progressive media regulatory legal framework. In 2006, CORI work halted plans to legislate the controversial 2006 bill. In 2015 it stopped another attempt to pass such a law in Parliament by a Certificate of Urgency. When another bad law was passed a year later, MCT led its partners in court to contest the law and the Government was directed to amend or do away with 16 clauses in the law. An appeal by Government has just been thrown out. This in itself is a major achievement, and once again confirms the fact that MCT, with crucial Sida and other partners support, is accepted as a doer and a leader in its own right.

Support and Nurture Other Organizations: MCTin its 2020 report claims to have successfully nurtured the Union of Tanzania Press Clubs (UTPC) to a point where it had a fully fledged secretariat, a functioning Board, and operational financial, administrative and human resource systems. The UTPC is now a major player in the Tanzania media sector in its own right. MCT also supported the establishing of Tanzania Editors Forum (TEF) and nurtured it for two years.

Standardized journalism training curricula in place: Following demand from editors and schools of journalism, the Council embarked on bench-marking and standardizing journalism training in the country up to Ordinary Diploma level. According to the 2020 report, The MCTs efforts were rewarded when the National Council for Technical Education (NACTE)&#xA0; validated the curricula for NTA levels 4, 5 and 6 and adopted the same as national curricula. Up to now, 23 journalism colleges have been granted permission to use the curricula after meeting MCT and NACTE requirements.

MCT has also had a landmark court decision at the East African Court of Justice (EACJ) where together with its partners, they successfully challenged sections of the Media Services Act. An intended appeal by Government has not been successful and MCT is now undertaking a massive effort to train editors, journalists and media trainers on what the court decision means. This includes other successful court battles like the ones challenging the ban of a number of newspapers.

According to the MCT report in 2020, with Sida support, MCT has taken media self regulation to the newsrooms by giving expert support to media houses to draft in-house self regulatory and peer oversight mechanisms such as style books, internal codes of conduct, and editorial policies. MCT has also been able to engage and bring together editors and journalism trainers to agree on effective preparation of trainee reporters, and incorporating values of self regulation and practical monitoring of ethical reportage in journalism foundational training. Thematic guidelines and training manuals have also been published and made available.

During the ongoing COVID 19 crisis and issued guidelines on how to report the pandemic safely, ethically and effectively. This has had a tremendous impact in the way our media outlets are now approaching the issue, including avoiding sensationalism, correct sourcing, and moving from treating COVID 19 as a purely health issue, to presenting it as also an economic and social issue.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51170087" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
