<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>CH-FDJP-107.856.445-FSI_AnnualReport_2019</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="CH-FDJP-107.856.445" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Economic Forum</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food System Initiative &#x2013; Shaping the Future of Food</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This document serves as the First Annual Report as requested in the Grant Agreement between the Government of Netherlands and the World Economic Forum to support the activities of the Food System Initiative &#x2013; Shaping the Future of Food, made possible by the generous support of the Government of the Netherlands under the grant entitled, &#x201C;World Economic Forum &#x2013; Food System Initiative - Shaping the Future of Food- &#x201D; (Ref: XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002396) for the grant period, from 1 April 2019 &#x2013; 31 December 2022. In 2019 the World Economic Forum launched a new institutional strategy, positioning the Food System Initiative as a pillar of the Impact Cluster. The new Forum strategy is anchored in increasing and accelerating impact of the initiatives supported by the forum; serving as a platform to not only develop for the Forum&#x2019;s own projects, but also to support and accelerate partner-driven initiatives; and exploring the implications and potential of cross cutting problematics. Going forward, the Food System Initiative team will be able to work even more closely and build stronger ties with other teams&#x2019; part of the Impact cluster. Such interlinkages with Forum&#x2019;s team working on climate change, land-use or water, but also country financing and technology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FSI has embarked on an ambitious agenda to identify and develop transformational pathways for more inclusive, efficient, sustainable, nutritious and healthy food systems for the future. The following annual one-year report, spanning April -1 st 2019 to December 31st 2019, outlines the key activities of the System initiative on Shaping the Future of Food including: Building on its established mission (see box), the FSI identified what it sees as the next transformative opportunities through which to strengthen the quality of public-private collaboration in relation to food (see box below). Key objectives were identified for 2019-2022: 1. Workstream 1: Supporting Country and Regional Platforms: Strengthen global and regional action platforms that enable country-led multisectoral initiatives to transform valuechains and wider integrated food systems agenda. 2. Workstream 2: Addressing Systemic Issue Areas (expanded scope from initial focus on Innovation with a Purpose only- explanation provided in section below): Generate insights and catalyse collaboration and action to unlock systemic bottlenecks in specific enabling areas such as Innovation, Incentives, Resilience, Protein, Food and Health and others. 3. Workstream 3: Strengthening Global Food Systems: Facilitate systems thinking and leadership alignment for an inclusive transformation agenda.</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Economic Forum</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food System Teams - Shaping the Future of Food</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sean de Cleene</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Future of Food</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+41228691274</telephone>
   <email>sean.deceleene@weforum.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Route de la Capite 93, 1223 Cologny</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">563333</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">422543</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The three years grant provided by the Government of the Netherlands totals USD 2,600,000. The table below summarises the expenditure for Year 1 of the grant; from April 1 st 2019 to December 31st 2019.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement between the Government of Netherlands and the World Economic Forum to support the activities of the Food System Initiative &#x2013; Shaping the Future of Food, made possible by the generous support of the Government of the Netherlands under the grant entitled, &#x201C;World Economic Forum &#x2013; Food System Initiative - Shaping the Future of Food- &#x201D; (Ref: XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002396) for the grant period, from 1 April 2019 &#x2013; 31 December 2022.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="CH-FDJP-107.856.445" type="21"></receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="3"></disbursement-channel>
   <recipient-region code="998"></recipient-region>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://aidstream.org/files/documents/NL-Food-System-Initiative_First-Year-Report_Final-14042020-20200421090444.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NL Food System Initiative_First Year Report_Final 14042020</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">First Annual Report &#x2013; April 1 st 2019 &#x2013; December 31st 2019 Ref: XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000002396; MINBUZA-2019.176431 Date Submitted April 14th, 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <category code="B01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
