<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-40409352-PRJ13-123-0002</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-40409352" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chronic Crisis - Food insecurity in Haiti</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the inception phase a preliminary assessment will be conducted in the target municipalities together with local governmental and technical authorities, local civil society organizations (including women&apos;s association and other CSOs working with marginalized groups), community leaders, to  identify and select the villages which will be targeted by the operation based on selected criteria (e.g. food security, level and diversity of livelihood sources, access to drinking water, etc.).

Gender and social inclusion focus group discussions will be conducted to identify the most vulnerable and at risk groups as well as to address their pressing needs, also in terms of protection and avoid to leave behind some of the most neglected.

At community level,  the project will apply the standard participative approach of Red Cross by using the community vulnerability and capacity assessment including specific technical assessment on food security, livelihood and water access and focus group discussions with women and vulnerable groups The assessment will allow to develop a community development and resilience plan which will be under the lead of community development committee.

The project will apply a Climate-Smart Agriculture (CSA) approach which is an integrated approach to managing landscapes and ecosystems - cropland, livestock, forests and water sources - that address the interlinked challenges of food security and accelerating household vulnerability to climate change.

The project will operate on two main areas of focus: 1. Livelihoods and basic needs and 2. Water, sanitation and hygiene. It will also include targeted activities that enhance a better integration of protection, gender and  inclusion in the programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haiti Red Cross</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The food insecurity situation has been worsening over the last months in Haiti. The latest harvest has provided poor yields because of an extended drought in the South and South-East Department of the country. The rainy season saw little rainfall, stressing out livelihoods for most of the farmers. Food insecurity is such an important issue because affected communities are dependent on harvest as their main income-generating activity but also and foremost because agricultural yields are the primary source of food for families. The already severe food insecurity situation in the South-East and South department has been further impacted by Tropical Storm Laura who damaged several water distribution points and key irrigation systems used by local communities for agriculture and human consumption. Households used coping mechanisms such as fetching water directly from small rivers and going to other households&apos; water source. This situation put further pressure on households and especially women and children who are responsible to fetch water resulting in more time spent and increase of waterborne diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the operation is to tackle food insecurity chronically affecting vulnerable families exposed to disaster risks that are driven by climate change in the South district (Les Anglais, Chardonnieres and Tiburon municipalities) and South East district (Cayes Jacmel, Marigot municipality). The operation will apply a Climate Smart Agriculture and Water Management approach to enhance resilience of 160,000 people in the target area.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">the South district (Les Anglais, Chardonnieres and Tiburon municipalities) and South East district (Cayes Jacmel, Marigot municipality).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haiti Red Cross Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-40409352" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-40409352" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PPU (Programmatic Partnership Unit)</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>070 - 44 55 678</telephone>
   <email>projects@redcross.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.rodekruis.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Postbus 28120, 2502 KC Den Haag, Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-31">600000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-03-09">135000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-40409352-PRJ13-123-0002" ref="NL-KVK-40409352" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haiti Red Cross Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-40409352-PRJ13-123" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other - People reached</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
