<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-40409352-PRJ13-132-0008</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-40409352" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovating Climate services through Integrating Scientific and local Knowledge</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European and international collaborative research efforts have established a solid scientific foundation for an effective CS value chain. This includes advanced scientific knowledge, monitoring and modelling of climate change and the impacts of climate extremes; and services for the provision of new and relevant climate data through open access data platforms such as Copernicus and GEOSS, citizen science, through open data exchange standards and interoperability (e.g. INSPIRE, OGC). There are, however, several barriers that impede the current generation of CS achieving the full opportunity of their value-proposition. These challenges include the failure to incorporate the social and behavioural factors and the local knowledge and customs of their users. Additional challenges are in; (i) the understanding of the multi-temporal and multi-scalar dimension of climate-related impacts and actions; (ii) the translation of CS-provided data into actionable information; (iii) the consideration of reinforcing or balancing feedback loops associated to users&#x2019; decisions based on CS; and (iv) the lack of trans-disciplinary 
approaches across the full CS value chain. There are also challenges in delivering tailor-made and robust services at the scale relevant to users; and an as yet maturing European climate services sector7. The I-CISK project aims to seize these untaken opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In seven geographically and sectorally diverse living labs (LL), I-CISK showcases its human-centred co-design, co-creation, co-implementation, and co-evaluation approach across key sectors vulnerable to climate change in Europe and beyond. This I-CISK co-production framework builds on the wealth of existing and expanding data and services from Copernicus and GEOSS to provide locally relevant CS. The framework will innovate existing CS frameworks by integrating the local data and knowledge, perceptions and preferences of users with research 
based scientific knowledge. I-CISK will seamlessly link climate and impact and adaptation information at different temporal scales from sub-seasonal to seasonal forecasts to decadal predictions and climate scale projections by including in the decision-making process the effects of adaptation options in a multi-timescale, multi-sector, multi-hazard setting. This human-centred approach realises the full potential of the CS value proposition through bridging the current gap at the downstream end of the CS value chain.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The NLRC/510 is part of a consortium that implements the overall project. The main objective of the I-CISK project is to develop next-generation CS that follow a social and behaviourally informed approach for co-producing CS that meet the climate information needs of citizens, decision makers and stakeholders at the spatial and temporal scale relevant to them.

NLRC/510 is responsible for the following tasks in this programme:
WP1: Lead the Living Lab in Namibia, supported by the Namibia Red Cross Society. 
WP2: Lead task 2.2 on identifying local knowledge and contribute to the other tasks. 
WP3: contribute to tasks 3.2 up to and including 3.5. 
WP5: contribute to task 5.5 business development bringing in also the perspective of public services versus private sector services. 
WP6: contribute to several dissemination and capacity building activities. 
WP7: Contribute to the evaluation of the impact of the Living Labs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Users of Climate Services</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-40409352" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-40409352" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-40409352" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-10-30" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned End</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PDM (Programme Development &amp; Management Unit)</narrative>
   </department>
   <telephone>070 - 44 55 678</telephone>
   <email>projects@redcross.nl</email>
   <website>https://www.rodekruis.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Postbus 28120, 2502 KC Den Haag, Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2025-10-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-10-31">310893</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-13">127</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-40409352-PRJ13-132-0008" ref="NL-KVK-40409352" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Netherlands Red Cross</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-40409352-PRJ13-132" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other - People reached</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
