<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-1409-1862</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-1409" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Integrated Framework</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DTIS Update, VANUATU TRADE POLICY FRAMEWORK (TPF)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Vanuatu&#x2019;s Diagnostic Trade Integration Study (DTIS ) was finalised in 2008, but unfortunately didn&#x2019;t receive the expected domestic and international support. Since 2012 the Vanuatu&#x2019;s Trade Policy Framework 2012 (TPF 2012) is the main national document on trade matters, effectively taking over the role that the DTIS was expected to play. The TPF 2012 is complemented by a comprehensive Implementation Matrix (TPFIM), a tool which allows the government to pursue a sector-wide approach to trade. The TFPIM plays an equivalent role to the DTIS Action Matrix and to the Medium-Term Program for Trade Development sponsored by the Enhanced Integrated Framework (EIF). Following approval of the TPF 2012 and the TPFIM, the Vanuatu trade mainstreaming program has received significant support within the government and from donor partners. The EIF has provided a decisive contribution towards the program through resources allocated under its two Tiers. Importantly, the EU has recently selected the TPF as its Sectoral Policy for the purpose of budget support to be provided to Vanuatu under the 11th European Development Fund, National Indicative Program (EDF 11 NIP). The EIF Tier 1 project for Vanuatu includes an allocation for the DTIS update. Upon consideration of the Vanuatu&#x2019;s policy landscape, the government and the EIF have concurred that the most promising results in terms of trade mainstreaming will be achieved by using EIF Tier 1 resources to update the TPF 2012 and the TPFIM. The TPF Update 2017 (TPFU 2017) will be carried out by adopting DTIS guidelines, as adapted to best fit the national conditions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development Division (TDD) of the MTTCNVB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VU" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction ref="620180429">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-26">100000</value>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS helps the UN and its partners run peacebuilding, humanitarian and development operations for people in need.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
