<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-1409-809</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-1409" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Integrated Framework</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nepal: Pashmina Enhancement &amp; Trade Support (PETS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will build sustainable capacities within the National Implementation Unit and other relevant entities through their active involvement in each step of the project cycle. The aim is to support Nepal&#x2019;s efforts in advancing its trade-related development agenda. At the sector level this initiative will play a key role in allowing CP exporters to brand, position and promote their newly designed products, while also creating new market links with overseas buyers. The newly created CP trademark will be promoted in priority markets and domestic industry surveillance established. The project will also contribute to find pilot solutions for adding increased value in the local wool industry by building the necessary capacities at the Nepal Pashmina Industry Association to analyse backward linkages, i.e. the fibre supply situation and to develop business plans and project proposals that address value addition at farm level and linking farmers to processors. It is expected that these will be taken on by other potential donors such as e.g. the ADB-financed HIMALI project. Thus, NPIA will be strengthened to support the sector&#x2019;s export development in a sustainable manner. The project office will therefore be located in NPIA. The implementing team will work closely with the NIU, the EIF Focal Point, other Governmental entities and support institutions (at national and sector level) to bring about the project&#x2019;s objectives. In order to assure country ownership and an effective day-to-day support for project related tasks inside of Nepal, a National Project Coordinator will be hired and located within the NPIA. The approach rests in &#x201C;learning by doing&#x201D;, with local TSIs and firms taking an active role in delivering project activities. Synergies and complementarities between the current project and other similar initiatives developed by international bilateral and multilateral development agencies will be promoted. As an EIF project, existing local institutions will be given preference as implementing partners, if and where deemed sufficiently effective.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Trade Centre (ITC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-06-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-17" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32163" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction ref="862824">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-07-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-07-18">749248</value>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS helps the UN and its partners run peacebuilding, humanitarian and development operations for people in need.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="1268257">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-11">657331</value>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS helps the UN and its partners run peacebuilding, humanitarian and development operations for people in need.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="620116491 &amp; 620129863">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-02-20">455024</value>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS helps the UN and its partners run peacebuilding, humanitarian and development operations for people in need.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
