<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-1409-1779</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-1409" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Integrated Framework</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability proposal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The NIU is seeking to extend the type of support it has enjoyed from EIF and provided to stakeholders during the EIF Tier 1 implementation in order to ensure that the sustainability and exit strategies designed in 2014 could be fully implemented within the next two years. To achieve this, MoC has developed a robust ?Sustainability Support Phase? proposal, to seek funding from the EIF partnership for a maximum period of two years. The proposal proposed outcomes and outputs directly contribute to the EIF Phase 2 result framework. The technical details ?work plan, budget plan, logical framework- have been prepared with Value for Money in mind and are fully aligned with EIF Phase 2 project templates.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Training and Research Institute, Private Sector Department, Trade Policy Department, Ministry of Planning, Silk Development Committee, Cambodia Rice Federation, District Cassava Associations, District Marine Fisheries Associations, EIF Core team members (25 officials representing 8 line ministries), Main implementing entity: Department of International Cooperation (DICO), Ministry of Commerce</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-22" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="33110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction ref="620129396">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-04-02">60000</value>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS helps the UN and its partners run peacebuilding, humanitarian and development operations for people in need.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="620225180">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-02-19">60000</value>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS helps the UN and its partners run peacebuilding, humanitarian and development operations for people in need.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
