<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-1409-1299</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-1409" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Integrated Framework</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Bee Disease and Pest Management for food security in Yemen.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen has relied during the past three decades on oil exports for its main source of hard currency. During the last few years, oil production has declined due to dwindling oil reserves and exports. To counter balance this situation, the government sought to diversify its economy with a view to rely on its non-oil sectors. Five economic sectors were identified as promising. The agricultural sector is one of such sectors, within in which apiculture has emerged as an important subsector having relative advantages and enjoying world renowned reputation for the quality of its honey. This outlook has been reflected by a steady increase of projects in Yemen that target honey production. However, honey production is under threat due to several pests and diseases that may destroy thousands of beehives, and consequently drastically reducing the honey production in Yemen. Beekeepers in Yemen have experienced major diseases and pests in recent years. It is estimated that up to 40% of hives may be contaminated by diseases, pests and predators reducing the yield, quality of honey and even reducing drastically the number of colonies. Colony poisoning through application of agro-chemicals also needs to be investigated, poisoned honeybees will have compromised immunity and hence will be more susceptible to diseases and pest attack. There is inadequate understanding of the problems but the main diseases and pests are cited as a deadly mite Varroa jacosoni/ destructor and foul brood. Beekeepers have neither access to reliable veterinary advice nor any control measures and are trying various traditional treatments on their own initiative including burning of hives, most of which have proven unsuccessful and resulted in economic losses to the beekeepers. It has been observed that some of indigenous Yemeni bees (Apis mellifera yeminitica), recover after the first attack of Varroa and co-exist with the diseases i.e. they acquire resistance to the disease. This adds weight to the need to improve the breeding and management of indigenous species of bees and also to control the diseases and pests in the imported races to Yemen. Enhanced Integrated Framework (EIF) Yemen, in collaboration with icipe Kenya have proposed a strategy to save the bees through non chemical pesticides control measures and build the capacity of the institute and beekeepers associations in Yemen. This project will test the herbal pesticides derived from plant material against the bee pests and diseases, and validate them in the apiary as well as develop products for the beekeepers. This requires establishment of a Center with satellite stations for honey bee surveillance and risk assessment. This innovation center for research, development, advocacy, capacity building and strategic networking for honeybee diseases and pests in Yemen will coordinate action along the bee health service chain. The purpose of this project is to establish a Center for Bee Diseases and Pests (CBDP Yemen) in Hadhramout , with four satellite stations to cover the main honey producing regions in the country (Shabwah, Taizz, Al Dhala and Hodeida). This would improve colony health, increase honey productivity, support pollination services for food security and generate new knowledge regarding bee diseases and pests and their control measures for the beekeepers associations. Thus, the Center will contribute to agricultural and rural growth and poverty reduction through research, capacity building and policy dialogue. EIF/icipe believe that only if research in the field of honeybee pathology and pollination services is conducted at the cutting edge of science will we be able to address the pressing questions on sustaining honeybee health, preventing colony losses due to diseases and pests, by 15-20% and improve crop yield by 20-25% through pollination services. Documentation and development of promotional materials in this regard will provide a strong basis for awareness raising and capacity building, advocacy and promoting uptake and upscale. The project will facilitate more efficient knowledge management systems, provide skills and resources necessary to raise awareness and profiles of the stakeholders, provide policy makers and regulators with advice (with the aim of harmonising procedures and legislation relating to bee health issues), and develop framework on bee health in Yemen. These activities, which focus on identifying and piloting policies and best practice options, will have far-reaching effects on achieving the envisaged goal of the project. The project will attract women, youth, local entrepreneurs and scientists and will facilitate inter-professional clusters based on innovation systems and effective public and private partnerships.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Center of Insect Physiology and Ecology (icipe)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-16" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="32161" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction ref="1101858">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-18">1027200</value>
   <provider-org ref="41AAA" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOPS helps the UN and its partners run peacebuilding, humanitarian and development operations for people in need.</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
