<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-UGA100314</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development SmartUp Factory Community Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creating an innovation centre for impoverished youth in Kampala</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nearly two thirds of youth in Uganda are unemployed, and youth in Kampala&#x2019;s poorest district, Kawempe, face additional problems of high crime, drug use, and prostitution. This pilot project seeks to establish an innovation centre in Kampala&#x2019;s poorest district that will provide a safe space for mentoring, training, and empowering young men and women to become problem solvers in their communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Smart up Factory project emerged from the idea that poor and marginalized youth are in a crucial position to identify problems in their communities and in society, and should be empowered to produce solutions to these problems. To tap into this unrealised potential, the Smart up Factory project will create a space in Kampala&#x2019;s Kawempe division where marginalized young men and women will be enabled to develop innovations with the ultimate goal of positively transforming society. Currently, the ideas of their better-educated and -resourced peers are the ones most often heard, meaning the voices of those who live in the target areas are mostly left unheard, and their potential remains untapped.  This project aims to change that.
This is a pilot initiative, initially working with 20 selected youth (10 men and 10 women) who will be trained and mentored and grow to become champions of the project, recruiting more youth as the project Factory will be developed with input from the youth, and the project team will work out a convenient schedule for programmes that will ensure access and convenience for participants.  
The Smart up Factory project will seek to work with local youth and a number of partners, including the government (Kampala City Council and the Divisional offices), RLabs (from South Africa), the Hub (in Kampala), Projectics, to ensure that the space and associated programmes are youth friendly and will nurture social expands. Youth coming to the centres and obtaining various skills will be encouraged to set up youth centres in their own communities. 
The project will also seek to establish value adding relationships with other relevant organizations through coordination and consultations; this will mainly involve working with Ministry of Gender, National Youth Council, Uganda Communications Commission (UCC), Breakdance Uganda, Babaluka Foundation, Scouting clubs, Slum Kids Festival, Straight Talk, and others. The common goals of these relationships are to explore how young males and females&#x2019; capacities can be built to enhance their social entrepreneurship and active citizenship. The project will also seek to build relationships with UNICEF to provide digital learning content and Design with Borders/ Bank of Uganda to provide content for financial literacy games that enhance learning.  
Since the vast majority of marginalized youth don&#x2019;t have access to this type of training and mentoring, and since most development projects address only one aspect of their lives (e.g. employment, health, security, entrepreneurship or life skills), this is a ground breaking project that aims to provide youth with multiple routes to achieving success in society, in their communities, and in their personal lives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be implemented in collaboration with the government, namely the Kampala City Council and the department of Community Service and Education. From a sustainability perspective, this will ensure that district officials continue interacting with the young women and men even after the project has ended.  The mentioned departments will also be involved in mentoring and conducting some components of life skills training on gender, Child protection and environmental protection.
Financial sustainability will be achieved by encouraging CSOs, Government Entities and private sector companies to support young people&#x2019;s skill development in areas like website design, printing, and graphics design.  Young people will also be supported in networking with groups and individuals in order to attract credit from independent financial institutions and other local sources of finance which will enable their businesses to grow and expand. 
The project&#x2019;s finances are budgeted for three years and will shrink in subsequent years, where the slack will be picked up by local resources. The procured assets and equipment will be considered donations and will continue to provide sustainable income and improve the livelihoods of those benefiting from the project. As necessary, the youth-run projects will engage in crowd funding (like Kiva and Kick starter) to solicit more financial resources. 
The team will also be supported in resource mobilization efforts by providing training in proposal writing, participatory governance approaches (peer mediation, community score cards, voice and participation), participatory M&amp;E, documenting case stories, and use of ICT4D in the programs.   
The project contributes towards the &#x201C;Skilling Uganda&#x201D; government initiative, which seeks to improve the quality and inclusion aspects of education and training systems and to make them responsive to the labour market. This synergy will allow for project activities to more easily be taken up by the government. As part of Plan&#x2019;s wider programme in Uganda, learning from the project will be shared among the government networks and Plan will lobby for the scale up of successful initiatives. The project also seeks to connect young women and men with the Youth Livelihood Programme (YLP), and Community Driven Development (CDD) Fund, which will help finance their business initiatives. The project will also enable young women and men to influence the planning and services provided by local governments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will seek to achieve the following objectives:
1.	To create a safe, inspiring and enabling space for young males and females. 
2.	To provide training and mentoring to the young men and women to gain skills and the confidence to pursue and implement their ideas e.g. through social entrepreneurship, community leadership, employment and volunteering.
3.	To empower youth to customize and take ownership of the running of the Smartup Factory as well as scale it up to reach as many youth as possible with extensive partner support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unemployment is a significant problem in Uganda, especially among young people. 61.6% of youth in Uganda are unemployed, the majority of whom live in urban areas. The failure of the Ugandan economy to generate sufficient jobs for its growing workforce is a rising concern, with the current surge in youth population (currently making up over 70% of the population) resulting in an ever-increasing demand for jobs.

In the Kawempe division of Kampala, Uganda&#x2019;s capital city, the majority of the population lives in slums. The Kawempe Division has the lowest income per capita of the city&apos;s five divisions and the largest population (over 265,000). The Kawempe Division has a high mortality rate compared to the city&#x2019;s other divisions, and most youth are reported to be involved in crime, with high rates of prostitution and an estimated 70% of youth in the division abusing drugs and alcohol.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young men and women aged 17-26 living in the Kawempe slum in Kampala.  During the first year of the project, 20 youth champions will be mentored. As the youth champions evolve, more youths will be registered and will have opportunity to create, innovate and develop sustainable ideas for continuing the smart up factory.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projectic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reconstructed Living Labs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3338" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.354435 32.569962</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-05-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">210901</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3338/Project_3338_current_image_2015-11-30_09.21.50.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smartup youth training session in Kampala, credit: Clinton Liedermann / Rlabs</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
