<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-ETH102113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating harmful practices in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing the detrimental effects of gender inequality on women&#x2019;s health</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Ethiopia, 26,000 women die annually due to pregnancy-related complications, with the majority of deaths occurring at home. These deaths are due to unwanted pregnancies, unsafe abortions and harmful practices such as child marriage and female genital mutilation. Although the Ethiopian Criminal Code of 2005 addressed a number of issues negatively affecting the reproductive lives of women, many girls in Ethiopia are still at risk: 23% of Ethiopian girls aged 0-14 have been subjected to female genital mutilation, and 41% of women aged 20-24 were married before the age of 18, with 16% before the age of 15. In addition, more than 34% of women age (20-49) gave birth by the age of 18 and more than half (54%) by the age of 20.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific Objective 1: To create dialogue and action at the community level related to gender discriminatory practices and violence in order to reduce the barriers that women face for optimal health.

Specific Objective 2: To raise awareness at the community level about the health services available and to change the health-seeking behavior of women, specifically those related to reproductive health and sexual &amp; gender-based violence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 12 month project will reach approximately 700 women&#x2019;s groups, 100 community leaders, 120 health extension workers, 72 health workers, 206 government officials, and 40 gender-based violence survivors. 

At the community level, the project will reach approximately 526,813 community members (direct and indirect beneficiaries) of which 60 % will be women</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to address harmful practices against women and girls, including sexual and gender based violence, that negatively affect women&#x2019;s reproductive health. The project will work in two regions of Ethiopia: Oromia (Tiro Afeta and Kersa districts) and SNNPR (Bolososore and Darra districts), aiming to change community and women&#x2019;s attitudes about harmful practices and their negative health impacts while also creating awareness about the relevant health services available and the importance of utilizing those services, specifically those related to reproductive health and sexual and gender-based violence. The project will apply a comprehensive community-based approach, including awareness creation through mass community mobilization, improved service delivery, and the documentation and dissemination of best practices.  The project recognizes the importance of engaging men and boys in such initiatives and Plan will make a special effort to encourage their participation and contributions.

The project will work closely with women&#x2019;s groups, community leaders, health workers, health extension workers, regional and district offices of Women, Children and Youth Affairs, as well as Health offices in order to increase their understanding of&#x2014;and ability to address&#x2014;issues of gender inequality, sexual violence, reproductive health, women-friendly and respectful service delivery; male engagement; gender-based violence mitigation; and response to&#x2014;and referral of&#x2014;survivors of gender-based violence. 

The expected project outcomes are: 
1.1	Health extension workers, community facilitators, women&#x2019;s groups and community leaders are better informed to change attitude and practices related to harmful practices and gender-based violence
1.2 Increased awareness among community members about the negative consequence of harmful practices and gender-based violence on reproductive health
2.1	Increase in number of women seeking reproductive health services and in men who support this behavior
2.2	Increased quality of care and support for sexual &amp; gender-based violence and fistula survivors</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to improve service delivery by the government and increase understanding among individuals and the wider community on the negative impact of harmful practices on women&#x2019;s health. All activities will be implemented in partnership with the government, helping to ensure improved services in the long term. In addition, the project&#x2019;s activities will bring about long-term changes in behavior, knowledge and attitude change, ensuring the sustainability of the intervention beyond its implementation timeline. 
The following activities, in particular, will contribute to the project&#x2019;s sustainability:
&#x2022;	The project will strengthen the health extension package by improving health workers&#x2019; understanding and skills on crucial issues, such as women-friendly and respectful service delivery, family planning, management of sexually transmitted infections, prevention of mother to child transmission of HIV, post abortion care, gender equality, HPs and community mobilization, increasing the quality services to survivors of harmful practices and fistula. These health workers will be able to apply acquired knowledge and skills beyond the project implementation.
&#x2022;	This project will organize mass awareness activities at the community level on the health services available to survivors of violence and fistula, and organize life-skills training to help fistula and sexual- and gender-based violence survivors reintegrate into their communities. The improvement in knowledge resulting service-seeking behavior will not only increase service use in the short term, but service users will be more likely to return to these services in the future and encourage others to do the same, thus resulting in a long-term impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women in Ethiopia face numerous health risks stemming from harmful practices related to pregnancy and sexual- and gender-based violence. This project is implemented in two regions in Ethiopia and aims to increase awareness of adverse health effects of these harmful practices and the importance of utilizing currently available health services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3908" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>5.262522 37.416081</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.083333 37.666667</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.75 37.083333</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.916667 37.333333</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-06-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-07-01">193457.66</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3908/Project_3908_current_image_2015-11-27_09.31.08.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
