<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-DOM136</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preventing violence against children</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to data from the ENHOGAR 2006 survey, 86 % of children and young people between the ages of 6 and 13 in the Dominican Republic are disciplined using physical and psychological punishment methods within their families.  
Though legislation exists to protect children from violence, a culture of tolerance for violence still exists in the Dominican Republic, much of which is gender-related. The main problem in this area is not an absence of laws, but the weak application of existing legislation. Legislation is dispersed, resources for its enforcement are limited, and the public and implementing authorities are largely ignorant of current laws and relevant policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child abuse and gender-related violence is a pressing issue in the Dominican Republic. This continuing project aims to minimize the amount of violence against women, girls, and boys by raising awareness, by providing advocacy and capacity-building support for community-based organizations, and by working with authorities at various levels to strengthen the National Protection System.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children aged 8-12, adolescents ages 13-18, young men aged 18-24, families, schools, community and religious leaders, civil society networks, community based organisations, congress, political candidates</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protecting girls and boys through social accountability and advocacy</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The long-term societal impact of this project has four aspects: First, communities will be aware of the gender dimensions of violence against children. Second, civil society will be more organised and empowered in rights enforceability, leading to a more participative democratic process. Third, this project will promote the application of legislation that protects, assists and prevents violence against women and children, reducing the number of cases of violence and cultivating a more gender-equal society. Finally, we will be promoting a more active and responsible citizenry.
Building the capacity of civil society organisations and community based organizations should impact the country&#x2019;s democratic reforms. The training aspects of the project will focus on contents and processes that strengthen the capacity for continued advocacy for children&#x2019;s rights with other national and local governmental entities. The project also proposes coordination mechanisms between civil society and the state at national, provincial and municipal levels, which are expected to be adopted by authorities at all these levels and will continue to function after project completion.
Finally, a strategy will be developed to ensure the sustainability of community protection networks in the medium and long term, not just in terms of financial resources but also for staff turnover. Plan will coordinate with community organisations, particularly with management committees, as well as with other tiers of the protection system at municipal level (e.g. Local Protection and Rights Restitution Boards) and provincial level (e.g. Provincial Protection Networks) to ensure that the community protection network continues to function effectively after project completion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the project is to promote children&#x2019;s rights to protection against all forms of violence by strengthening the role of community and civil society involvement in rights promotion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to contribute to fulfilling children&#x2019;s and adolescents&#x2019; rights in the Dominican Republic, especially the right to protection from all types of violence. This project focuses on child protection, with an emphasis on strengthening the democratic governance processes at local and national levels. The project has been constructed based on the conviction that all of the strategies for preventing and providing a response to violence against children should take the gender dimension into account, by challenging gender stereotypes that directly or indirectly promote violence against children (which by definition includes tackling violence against women). Therefore, the intervention seeks to tackle the problem of gender-based violence against children in the Dominican Republic.
Through this project we seek to raise awareness in Dominican society about the gender dimensions of violence against children and to increase the negotiation and advocacy abilities of community-based organisations and civil society networks to influence decision makers at a local and national level, in order to ensure that sustainable links between civil society and the government are developed. The project also seeks to impact candidates in presidential, congressional and municipal elections that will be held in 2016, in order to ensure that they prioritise the protection of children from violence in their political programmes. At the same time, the adoption of an active and responsible citizenry will be promoted among the population. This is an important step towards democratic governance as it opens the channels for civil society as well as interest groups to demand greater responsibility by both parties, by generating and sustaining a citizenry-government dynamic that significantly supports the reforms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coalition for Children NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Council for Childhood and Adolescence</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Dominican Republic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="2937" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="DOM136" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="5"></activity-scope>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.035607 -71.747594</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.2165 -71.12799</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.448431 -70.742896</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.474976 -69.949312</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.813828 -71.229607</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.879766 -71.701694</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 1" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">206114</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 2" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">186650</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 3" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">192784</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/2937/Project_2937_current_image_2015-04-14_10.46.29.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Teaching about child protection in Barahona, credit: Plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
