<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-UGA0288</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Combating silent violence against children</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">45,000 children aged 0-8 in 5 districts of Northern Uganda</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing neglect and maltreatment in post-conflict northern Uganda</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northern Uganda is recovering from a long insurgency. Dysfunctional social support structures and family-related stressors (including extreme poverty, high disease burden and trauma) lead to children experiencing high levels of domestic violence.  The issue of &#x201C;silent violence&#x201D;, or violence occurring within families due to neglect or maltreatment, has not yet been tackled in Uganda. Social service interventions are difficult due to an attitude of acceptance of corporal punishment as a form of discipline. In addition, gender inequality remains high in Uganda, especially in rural areas, where women are expected to be submissive to men.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this project is to contribute to the reduction of all forms of violence against children 0-8 years old in post-conflict northern Uganda within homes and communities using early childhood care and development as a key strategy. Specifically, this project hopes to improve relationships between children, parents and caregivers for approx. 22,500 families, strengthen community-based and sub-national child protection systems, and enable local and national governments to develop and implement comprehensive policies that address violence prevention and response.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to make a positive impact on the development and protection of approximately 45,000 children aged 0-8 in 5 districts of Northern Uganda where Early Childhood Care and Development (ECCD) and child protection services are not currently available. Through parenting education, children in targeted communities will benefit from improved care practices and long-term protection due to increased awareness and respect for young children&#x2019;s rights. The project will contribute to enhancing gender equitable attitudes and relations in families. The involvement of parents&#x2014;especially males&#x2014;through parenting groups and fathers&#x2019; meetings will enhance their commitment and support to children&#x2019;s survival and protection. Finally, the impact at the community level will be stimulated through community participation&#x2014;especially for women&#x2014;in  policy dialogues and community development planning processes. The project is expected to positively change attitudes and practices of both community members and local authorities in terms of addressing younger children&#x2019;s rights to protection.
A strong emphasis on capacity development of parents and caregivers will result in increased and improved support to children. By involving local authorities in all stages and activities of the project, local ownership will be enhanced, resulting in increased commitment and acknowledgement of responsibilities for delivering high quality child protection services.
Finally, the innovative practices of ECCD and child protection in a post-conflict context used in this project will be used as evidence to influence child protection laws at the national level. Good practices will be promoted for inclusion in revised or updated national legislation and child protection issues will become apparent in the local government&#x2019;s development plans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project brings together two areas of child-centered development work: Early Childhood Care and Development (ECCD) and community-based protection mechanisms. These two areas are linked by mobilising parents as a positive force for children&#x2019;s wellbeing, connecting them with the local child protection authorities and public service providers as well as with political decision-makers and the broader public. This holistic, multi-level approach seeks to create a setting where the key duty-bearers (parents, public service actors, communities etc.) are each mobilized to act against violence against children. Approaching the problem of violence from the point of view of both protection and early childhood care and development in a single intervention is particularly well justified in a difficult post-conflict environment such as Northern Uganda. 

This project uses a multi-faceted response that includes the family, community and national policy framework to reduce violence against children in the 5 targeted districts of Northern Uganda. Project actions include:

&#x2022;	Supporting the establishment and development 50 ECCD centres to prepare children for early learning and to help parents and caregivers to form parenting groups to support one another on issues of child care. Parents and caregivers will be taught basic skills in savings, credit management and financial literacy.

&#x2022;	Supporting the establishment and development of 50 Child Protection Committees, whose task is to regularly and proactively prevent and respond to child protection issues at the community level and be enabled to link up with other structures to support child protection at other levels. In addition, key stakeholders, including Local Councils, Women&#x2019;s Groups, and teachers, will be equipped with the knowledge and skills to prevent abuse and protect children.

&#x2022;	Enabling local and national governments to develop and implement comprehensive policies that address prevention and response to violence against children at family, community, sub-national and national levels. The understanding and application of existing laws protecting children and families will be promoted among government officials and law enforcement, which should contribute to a reduction in cases of violence against children and an increase in response rate for reported cases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project tackles the issue of &#x2018;silent violence&#x2019; that occurs within families in post-conflict nothern Uganda. By implementing early childhood care and development strategies and strengthening community-based protection mechanisms, this project will address violence related to neglect and maltreatment toward children 0-8 years of age.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="EU" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitation for Peace and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lango Samaritan Initiative Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Women&apos;s Parliamentary Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3883" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.635 32.825</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>1.983333 32.533333</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.247222 32.9</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.25 33.315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.428611 32.801111</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-10-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2013-11-01">1792033</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3883/Project_3883_current_image_2015-11-13_08.19.21.JPG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child guest of honor speaking at celebration event, credit: Plan Uganda</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
