<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-VNM0342</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Gender Responsive School Pilot Model</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">15,000 girls aged 11 to 18 in 20 lower and upper secondary schools in Hanoi; teachers; parents; media; society; local governments</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creating &amp; Implementing a gender responsive school model in Vietnam</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender-based violence in schools is prevalent in Vietnam and is a barrier to girls&#x2019; empowerment and gender equality. This project pilots a gender responsive model in 20 schools in Hanoi. After ensuring its effectiveness, the model will be expanded by the Hanoi Department of Education to 766 schools. The project will also work with mass and social media to engage adolescents, teachers and parents.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Once its effectiveness has been proven, the model is expected to be used by the Hanoi Department of Education and Training and expanded to 758 schools. The implementation of the program itself in schools will not add a significant financial burden, since the model mainly involves modifying current practices, attitudes and behaviour and does not require investment in infrastructure or equipment (with the exception of school counselling). 

In order to ensure public funds will be released for the scaling up of the model, relevant departments will be lobbied (including Hanoi city administration, the Department of Education and Training (DoET) and the Department of Planning and Investment).

The project will draw on meaningful partnerships with the Hanoi DoET; the Centre for Study and Applied Science on Children, Women and Adolescents; and International Centre for Research on Women. These partnerships, along with the active involvement of the DoET, will greatly contribute to reducing gender-based violence in schools, successfully demonstrate the model in the Vietnam context, and ensure sustainability by providing a strong platform for future expansion throughout the city&#x2019;s schools.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall goal: that adolescent girls attending schools in Hanoi are safe from gender-based violence and free from discrimination.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The prevalence of gender-based violence is high in Vietnam. The 2010 National Study on Domestic Violence against Women found that 25 percent of women were experiencing mental/psychological violence at the time of the survey. The prevalence of violence against children by fathers is as high as 25 percent, and children of mothers who were victims of violence were twice as likely to be victims themselves. In high schools, 1 in 10 respondents reported being sexually harassed in the past year, and 81 percent of these respondents were girls. These numbers are likely underestimated due to the social stigma associated with sexual harassment.

The Vietnamese government passed several laws related to gender-based violence; namely, the Gender Equality Law in 2006 and the Law on the Prevention of Domestic Violence in 2007. However, major challenges to policy implementation exist, primarily regarding funding, coordination and monitoring and evaluation of efforts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project pilots a research-based model of gender responsive schools in 20 schools in Hanoi. The model takes a holistic approach that has been effectively demonstrated in other contexts, that seeks to (1) engage adolescents, teachers, school management, parents, media, and the community to promote non-discriminatory practices at school, (2) bring about positive change in attitudes and behaviours at the individual level, and (3) develop an enabling environment within schools and society to sustain individual change, ultimately leading to a change in societal norms.

The proposed project will use the following four strategies to test the gender responsive school model in context and promote its scale-up and institutionalization:
(1)	Change the attitudes and behaviours of adolescent girls, boys, and teachers towards school-related Gender Based Violence using Plan&#x2019;s gender transformative approach
(2)	Create an enabling environment to help sustain individual change by engaging teaching and non-teaching staff and parents;
(3)	Strengthen institutional response mechanisms by altering school processes and practices, establishing a school-based counselling system and setting up a reporting, response, and referral system
(4)	Employ evidence-based advocacy for scaling the gender responsive school model and institutionalization through coalition, media sensitization, evidence building, and knowledge management.

This project is planned to benefit approximately 15,000 girls aged 11 to 18 in 20 lower and upper secondary schools, with the goal that they will become better aware of gender discrimination and school-related gender-based violence and have the skills and institutional mechanisms available to prevent and respond to incidents. In addition, the project will build the awareness and capacity of teachers, actively engage parents, and sensitize and facilitate the media&#x2019;s promotion of gender equality.

The gender responsive school project will also contribute to more effective implementation of existing laws by integrating gender issues into the education system to transform adolescents&apos; understanding of gender equality, violence and to make school safer, in turn raising awareness of gender equality and violence in schools. The project will also provide the Government with a successful model that can be expanded city-wide and into other provinces and will offer evidence that can be used for future policy making.

This comprehensive approach will systematically address the root causes of gender inequality and violence to ensure schools are gender-responsive, and are a place where girls and boys feel safe and are free from discrimination.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Studies and Applied Sciences in Gender&#x2013;Family-Women and Adolesce</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hanoi Department of Education and Training</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Center for Research on Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International France</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Vietnam</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Vietnam</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Entity for Gender Equality and the Empowerment of Women</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3882" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.012578 105.84222</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="90" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-11-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 1" currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">450323</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-11-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 2" currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">398921</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-11-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 3" currency="USD" value-date="2013-12-01">499456</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3882/Project_3882_current_image_2015-11-12_15.12.23.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A girl voicing her opinion in a school event, credit: Plan Vietnam</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
