<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-PAK100273</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Childhood Education and Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expanding and improving care and education of children aged 0-6 in Pakistan</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Girls and boys age 0-6; youth; parents, caregivers, and family members; and the general public in Muzaffargarh, Sujawal and Thatta provinces</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Pakistan, 25 million boys and girls between the ages of 5 and 16 are not in schools. The proportion of out of school children increases as the level of education rises; almost 85% of higher secondary school age children are not in school, and as many as 70% of children who are out of school have never seen the inside of a classroom.  Girls make up 55% of all out of school children (13.7 million in total). 
Contributing to low school enrolment is the lack of attention given to early childhood care and development programmes. Completion of quality pre-primary education significantly increases a child&#x2019;s likelihood of completing primary education. In addition, 400,000 Pakistani children die in their first year and the under-five mortality rate is very high, at 70 per 1000 live births, due in large part to malnutrition. In Pakistan, 31% children are underweight (40% of children in Sindh province) and 44% of children under age 5 are stunted, with numbers skewed higher in rural areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Pakistan, 25 million boys and girls between the ages of 5 and 16 are not in schools. The proportion of out of school children increases as the level of education rises; almost 85% of higher secondary school age children are not in school, and as many as 70% of children who are out of school have never seen the inside of a classroom.  Girls make up 55% of all out of school children (13.7 million in total). 
Contributing to low school enrolment is the lack of attention given to early childhood care and development programmes. Completion of quality pre-primary education significantly increases a child&#x2019;s likelihood of completing primary education. In addition, 400,000 Pakistani children die in their first year and the under-five mortality rate is very high, at 70 per 1000 live births, due in large part to malnutrition. In Pakistan, 31% children are underweight (40% of children in Sindh province) and 44% of children under age 5 are stunted, with numbers skewed higher in rural areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Pakistan, early childhood care, development, and education services are inadequate, especially in rural areas. This project seeks to improve services in three districts in Pakistan, with a focus on including marginalised girls and boys. The project will also strengthen communities&#x2019; ability to advocate for the provision of early childhood care and education services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The adoption of Plan&#x2019;s low cost model in public schools by the district government has been key in ensuring programme sustainability. Plan has established strong linkages with the district and provincial government both in Sindh and Punjab provinces, where district governments agreed to establish early childhood education centres in public schools to use as a low cost model for the government to adopt and upscale. 

Strong local mobilization, awareness raising, and engaging the community in the local management and implementation of the projects have helped to improve community ownership of the programme. The project has also seen sustained enrolment and retention of the children in early childhood programmes and increased parental commitment to enroll their children in schools. In addition, the improved knowledge of caregivers and teachers on ECCD/ ECE and child protection have improved parenting practices and contributed towards developing skilled human resources in the community.

At the provincial level in Punjab, the Directorate of Staff Development has revised and adapted Plan&#x2019;s syllabus and it is being used in 1,000 newly initiated early childhood education centres throughout the province. Moreover, the process of adopting and continuing Plan-supported school-based early childhood education has begun and public-private partnerships are expected to materialize by the end of this project for adoption of these centres by government. 

Due to Plan&#x2019;s recent intervention in Thatta district, there has been significant progress in seeking the government&#x2019;s commitment to initiate early childhood education programmes in the province and adopt Plan&#x2019;s model for replication. Early childhood education has been set as priority intervention in the Education Sector and targets have been set.  
 
The technical capacity building of civil society organisations, community-based organisation, and implementing partners has developed knowledge and skills at the local level and the model has been replicated by one civil society organisation at the local level. However, the goal of bringing lasting attitudinal change in respecting the rights of every child will require work with policymakers to develop policies and laws that are in line with the Children&#x2019;s Rights Council and ensure its implementation at all levels.

This second phase of the project will be implemented with close coordination and support of government education departments.  In this phase, a dialogue with the government will be continued and linkages further strengthened to demonstrate and provide technical support for an efficient, cost-effective model that will function within the public sector.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this project is to enhance participation of children in early childhood care, development, and education by creating safe and healthy environments where girls and boys are respected, protected, empowered and active in their own protection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Pakistan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3768" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>24.601723 68.082426</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>24.74741 67.929408</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.073491 71.191449</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11240" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">737414</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3768/Project_3768_current_image_2015-10-05_08.01.12.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children preparing for a role playing game, credit: Plan Pakistan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
