<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-KEN100277</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Securing a Strong Foundation for Children</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Girls and boys age 0-8
- Parents/caregivers
- ECCD teachers and primary school teachers
- Government officials
- Communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Childhood Care and Development programs address the different needs and rights of a child during their early years by integrating aspects of health, nutrition, protection, intellectual stimulation, exploration and active learning as well as social and emotional care and nurturing. This project uses the Plan-developed Community Led Action for Children model to improve early childhood care and development in project areas. This model includes a parenting education program that improves knowledge and practical skills to benefit child health, learning and protection in the home and wider community; establishing and maintaining low &#x2013;cost, high- quality early childhood centers that serve every child in the year or two before primary school; focusing on the transition to primary school with school- and community-based activities that enable disadvantaged children to enter school on time, stay in primary school, and learn effectively; and integrating public/private partnerships to ensure that health, education, and human services reach the most vulnerable children.

The project will work with 80 centres, by rehabilitating or constructing some centres, improving water and sanitation facilities, providing teaching and learning materials, and providing training for teachers. In addition, 96 parenting groups will be formed which aim to improve parents&#x2019; knowledge and practical skills. There is also a focus on easing girls&#x2019; and boys&#x2019; transition to primary school. In addition, the project aims to increase collaboration with county governments and other like-minded partners to encourage increased resource allocations for government child care and development services and programs and to ensure that county strategic plans for education are well implemented. 

The direct target group includes 8000 girls and 8000 boys 0-8 years old as well as 6000 primary caregivers (3000 women and 3000 men). These actions will take place in four project areas (Homa Bay, Bondo, Kisumu, and Kwale). 

This particular project is a continuing phase of a long-term programme started in 2012.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Sub-Saharan Africa, 71 million children under age 5 lack the nurture, care, and stimulation they will need to benefit from primary education. In Kenya, where Plan has worked since 1982, 40% of children aged 3 to 6 years are not participating in early childhood care and development programmes. Poverty is widespread, with over 58% of the population living below the poverty line, which affects the ability of the poor to meet educational costs for their children. Additionally, the status of maternal and child health is poor, the commitment to early childhood care is weak, there are increasing cases of child abuse, and the number of orphans and other vulnerable children is on the rise.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Only 60% of children in Kenya aged 3 to 6 years participate in early childhood care and development programmes. This project aims to increase involvement and improve the services of 80 ECCD centres, which includes constructing centres, providing teaching &amp; learning materials, training teachers, creating parenting groups, and collaborating with governments and others for increased resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Early Childhood Care and Development program in Kenya</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this project is that girls and boys aged 0-8 in the project areas enjoy their right to grow up in a nurturing, stimulating, safe and clean environment protected from violence by improving the quality and accessibility of early childhood care and development programs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project provides opportunities for communities to acquire skills in the following areas: parenting, child rights, health, nutrition, and income generation.  This should allow community members to carry on programme initiatives after the programme ends. In addition, relationships between communities and key government ministries and departments (including the District Centre for Early Childhood Care and Development, which provides technical support) will be strengthened through this programme, easing future early childhood care and development implementation. 

Over 50 Community-based organizations will be involved in the implementation of these childhood care programmes. The project will utilize community strengths and resources, including use of locally available materials. The caregivers at the community-based centres are volunteers who will continue to devote their time and services after the project phase ends. Plan will provide necessary training on child care and development and on income-generation activities to ensure volunteers&#x2019; participation in programme implementation is worthwhile.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-DOS-C1669530" role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conrad N. Hilton Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="2952" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="5"></activity-scope>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.098662 34.760213</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.10261 34.274211</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.535833 34.455893</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.175417 39.452548</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11240" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="24040" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">1196157</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/2952/Project_2952_current_image_2015-04-20_14.45.06.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children playing outside an ECCD center in Kisumu</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
