<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-MOZ100046</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Childhood Care and Development (Moz)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expanding programming for young children in Mozambique</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Mozambique, opportunities for early childhood care and development (ECCD) for children aged 0-6 are very limited, especially in rural areas. This is due to poverty, lack of awareness among communities and parents, lack of supporting policy and commitment of governments, and neglect on the part of donors to this crucial sector. The vast majority of programs are concentrated in urban areas via private ventures, meaning access to pre-school education is generally limited to children from wealthier families.
Though a national strategy on ECCD was approved in 2012, the government still lacks an approved implementation policy and ECCD is not a priority in terms of budget allocation. In addition, responsibility for ECCD is shared by three departments: the Department of Health (for children 0-3 years), Department of Social Welfare (for children 4-5 years) and Department of Education (for children 6-8 years) resulting in coordination issues between departments and with civil society.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Mozambique, programmes for young children are limited and inadequate, especially for families living in rural areas. This project seeks to expand the availability and quality of programming in the Inhambane and Nampula Provinces of Mozambique by expanding the number of centres, strengthening gender components, and continuing to work with civil society to advocate the government.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives:
&#x2022;	Improved access to quality pre-school education for children aged 4-5
&#x2022;	Strengthened knowledge of parents on early childhood issues, focusing on parents and caretakers of children aged 0-3, including pregnant mothers
&#x2022;	Following up on children&#x2019;s transition process from ECCD centres to primary schools
&#x2022;	Generate, document and disseminate knowledge and practices that can assist in the integration and standardisation of national ECCD policies, strategies and structures
&#x2022;	Strengthened ECCD outcomes through linkages to disaster management committees and children&#x2019;s clubs</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan will incorporate a savings and lending model into the parenting component of the project to enable parents to save and increase income in order to afford ECCD services for their children.  

Plan Mozambique will continue to actively participate in advocacy at both national and provincial levels to pressure the Government in instituting new ECCD policies, increasing budgets for ECCD, and integrating appropriate accountabilities and mandates into the system. Community capacities and networks will be enhanced so that they are able to demand and advance the rights of their children. Provincial ECCD networks will be promoted, which will advocate for change together with the national ECCD focus group/network.

In addition, Plan Mozambique will make sure that external technical information is available on a continuous basis either for training, assessments, documentation, and evaluation. Plan will also build relationships and partnerships with civil society organizations involved in ECCD such as Save the Children, Aga Khan Foundation, etc. This will ensure that Plan&#x2019;s strategies, approaches and methods are on track and consistent with the result areas to be achieved. Government officials in this sector will be invited to visit the project on an on-going basis to assess and monitor project performance on the basis of government guidelines.

Technical knowledge and information will be transferred to the teachers and key members of the ECCD committees to boost the capacity of the community and to improve the chances of continuity. In addition to the volunteer teachers, community ECCD facilitators will be trained to lead and champion the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target group is children 0-6 year old, their families and their communities in Plan operational area.  The project will give particular attention to vulnerable and marginalized children to ensure their participation and inclusion in the ECCD project. Other categories of vulnerable children that will be monitored for their inclusion include very poor children, neglected children, children in households headed by women, and children with disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the second phase of a project that started in 2012. In the first phase, which took place in 2012-2014, Plan facilitated the establishment of a total of 40 centres for early childhood care and development (ECCD) in 20 communities in Jangamo and Homoine districts of Inhambane province. Vital experiences and lessons were learned in community and parental mobilization, setting up the community ECCD committees, selecting teacher volunteers, and mobilising communities to establish safe ECCD centres where children can play, learn, and share socio-cultural experiences. 

The overall objective of this project is to build opportunities for 0-6 year old girls and boys in project areas to grow in a healthy and stimulating environment through inclusive and integrated community-based early childhood care and development programmes. In this new phase of the project, Plan Mozambique seeks to scale up implementation into additional areas (Mogovolas- Nampula Province), building 25 new community ECCD centres in two districts. New project interventions also include establishing more parenting groups, increasing focus on gender issues, and introducing elements of ICT4D&#x2014;for example, using arts and media to increase youth engagement and producing a participatory video for learning and advocacy purposes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3896" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-23.880997 35.149232</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-24.109462 35.305972</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11240" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 1" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-10-15">466767</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 2" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-10-15">401767</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 3" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-10-15">401767</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3896/Project_3896_current_image_2015-11-19_11.04.09.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A parenting session in Mozambique, credit: Plan International Mozambique</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
