<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-TMP0086</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Childhood Care and Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Better early childhood development for a better future</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child mortality rates in Timor Leste are high, around half of children under age 5 have stunted growth, and estimated pre-school enrolment was only 14% in 2013. This project seeks to enhance health and education for boys and girls age 0-5 by introducing or improving Early Childhood Care and Development programs in 29 communities and advocating for improved policies at national and district levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Targeted direct beneficiaries:
- Children aged 0-8 years 
- Parents
- Civil Society Organisations

Indirect beneficiaries: 
- Suco (village) facilitators 
- Community and local leaders
- Government</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main method of ensuring project sustainability is by advocating the National Government to increase its budget for Early Childhood Care and Development programs and by encouraging the Ministry of Education and district education health authorities to make early childhood care a greater priority. In addition, several village authorities have promised to use some of their government-provided funds to support Community Pre-Schools. Our hope is that as parents&#x2019; understanding of the importance of ECCD increases, they are more willing to contribute, also financially, to the running of the preschool centres and start demanding greater support from the government for early childhood programmes.

All communities are planning on continuing programme implementation for play groups and community pre-school activities even after support from Plan ends. An example of this is the successful phase out from 9 communities in Lautem district in the end of 2014. One of the ECCD centres was handed over to the Ministry of Education and 8 were handed over to the communities which will be supported by a Mother-Tongue project of UNESCO&#x2019;s National Commission (EMBLI).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of the project is that all children up to the age of eight in Plan Timor-Leste target areas, especially excluded children, have access to quality and sustainable Early Childhood Care and Development, including smooth transition to primary school. Additionally, this plan seeks to support gender mainstreaming for girls, boys, mothers and fathers in all program communities by the end of 2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The previous project phase (2012-2014) established and supported community pre-schools and playgroups in two districts:  20 communities in Aileu District and 9 communities in Lautem District. The work in Lautem communities ended in 2014 and was handed over to the communities, Ministry of Education and EMBLI (the Mother-Tongue project of UNESCO&#x2019;s National Commission). The Ministry of Education will also take up funding for 5 of the preschools in Aileu in 2015. During the current phase, the project activities will be scaled up to 5 new communities in Aileu and 9 new communities in Ainaro district, making a total of 29 ECCD centres covered by the project by 2017.

This project utilises a holistic approach to child development. In addition to work on preschool education, the project includes health education (especially for issues related to stunting and identifiable disabilities), child protection issues such as Universal Birth Registration and child protection referral system at the district level, supporting mothers and fathers to increase capacity to support their children aged 0-8 years old, and a component on Disaster Risk Reduction. The approach will promote inclusiveness and gender equality among girls, boys, mothers and fathers in the 29 programme communities in Aileu and Ainaro. The project also intends to establish an ECCD coordinating body at District level and to improve policies and practices related to ECCD at national and district levels.

Project activities for this phase of the project include:
&#x2022;	An increased focus on strengthening the quality of school readiness for girls and boys aged 5 years, in gender equal and inclusive settings so they can more effectively transition into primary school
&#x2022;	Increase the capacity of mothers and fathers to practice child development with their children.
&#x2022;	Regular home visits to increase the involvement of fathers.
&#x2022;	Increasing the capacity of facilitators/community volunteers in order to better support girls and boys in regards to the child development milestones (cognitive, social-emotional, language and motoric abilities). 
&#x2022;	Increasing the capacity of facilitators to identify children with disabilities (mapping) in their own communities and enrolling girls and boys with disabilities in community pre-schools.
&#x2022;	Advocacy to promote holistic approach to ECCD in cooperation with other civil society actors.
&#x2022;	Strengthened cooperation with the health sector and more attention to challenges related to malnutrition</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Timor-Leste is among the world&apos;s poorest nations, ranking 128 out of 187 countries in the 2014 UNDP Human Development Index. Much of Timor-Leste continues to experience deep-seated poverty, particularly in isolated rural areas with minimal employment opportunities. In 2011, 52% of the population lived below the poverty line. Due to food shortages and poor nutrition, 52% of children under 5 years old are stunted (up from 40% in 2002). In addition, child mortality rates are high (64/1,000 live births), and estimated enrolment in pre-school education was only 14% in 2013.

Access to basic education has improved during the recent years, with primary (grade 1-6) net enrolment of 94%. However, only 32 % of students were at the official school age when entering the first grade, dropout rates in grades 1 and 2 are high and over 70% of students leave school by Grade 9. Further, the 2010 Census indicates that only 59 per cent of children aged 6-14 with disabilities were attending school.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Timor-Leste</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sentro Treinamento Vocasional Maseu</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ylen Hyv&#xE4;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3086" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="5"></activity-scope>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-8.716667 125.566667</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-8.838056 125.597222</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-9.083333 125.483333</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11240" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 1" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">383977</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 2" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">334190</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 3" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">334190</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3086/Project_3086_current_image_2015-05-19_10.36.13.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children outside an ECCD Center in Timor Leste, credit: Plan International Timor Leste</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
