<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-ETH102106</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building Strong Foundation for Boys &amp; Girls</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to care and development services for young children in Ethiopia is very limited. This project seeks to improve the wellbeing of the most disadvantaged children in two districts in Ethiopia by increasing access and quality of early learning programs. This includes establishing new learning centres, improving parental and facilitator training, and increasing community involvement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing early childhood care &amp; development services in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia is the second most populous country in Sub-Saharan Africa with a population of over 90 million. Approximately 84% of the population lives in rural areas. Despite significant economic growth over the last decade, Ethiopia remains one of the poorest countries in the world. 

Early childhood programmes have received limited attention in the country, in spite of the fact that 19% of the Ethiopian population are children under the age of six. As of 2010/2011 only about 5% out of the estimated 7.31 million children of the appropriate age group (ages 4-6) had access to formal pre-primary education. In 2010 the government introduced a new policy: the Early Childhood Care and Education Policy Framework. However, comprehensive resources have not yet been released for its implementation, meaning that access to care and development services for young children is still limited.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Girls and boys under age 8, parents and caregivers, ECCD center facilitators, early grade school teachers and principals, community volunteers, local governments</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main Goal: That all targeted girls and boys (0-8 years) grow to their full potential in a nurturing, stimulating, safe and clean environment protected from violence. This will be accomplished by increasing parental and guardian knowledge and skills, supporting the equal participation of boys and girls in quality early learning programs, enhancing school and community support for transitions to primary school, and supporting government and non-government to work in partnership to ensure the development and protection of children at community, district, regional and national levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Ethiopia is committed to overall sustainability of both program interventions and the results achieved through the program. Developments in knowledge, skills and support systems, as well as linkages with the government health extension program, will help make the parenting education program highly sustainable. On the other hand, the pre-school program presents a bigger challenge, due to the recurrent costs&#x2014;namely, incentives for facilitators&#x2014;that must continue to be met. Ideally, local governments will provide support for running costs; for this reason, Plan has set out to establish a long-term partnership with government entities from the programme&#x2019;s inception. 

Plan will enhance the requisite capacities of District Education and Training Boards, PTAs, and implementing partners, both organizationally and technically, to have the tools and skills necessary to continue to provide quality services. The goal of capacity development is to ultimately allow organizations to provide effective coordination, training, quality service delivery and other forms of support to marginalized children and their families. 

Access to Village Savings and Loan Associations, Savings and Credit Organisations, and viable income-generating programs will be provided to the parenting groups as early as possible to help parents share the costs of education. Cost-recovery mechanisms such as user fees or in&#x2013;kind contributions (e.g. volunteer work, cereals, grains, construction material) will also be encouraged. 

Moreover, Plan will work in partnership with indigenous partners who have years of experience implementing development projects with excellent recognition across communities and in regional states. These partners have deep roots in the communities they serve and a strong desire to ensure the wellbeing of children in their communities beyond the end of the program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is a continuation of a programme that began in 2012. In this phase, the project is expanded into 12 new rural communities in the Toke Kutaye and Bolososore districts in the Oromiya and the Southern Nations, Nationalities, and Peoples&apos; regions of Ethiopia. This project takes a holistic approach to early childhood care and development in order to address all spheres of development, including health, nutrition and protection. Particular attention will be given to children from disadvantaged communities, ethnic minorities, children with special needs and children living in remote geographical areas. Steps are also taken to systematically strengthen the resilience of children and their communities to respond to natural disasters. 

Taking into account recent research and survey findings, the following gender-related issues are addressed: gender-related division of duties in the home, low involvement of fathers in child care and development, and discrimination toward female teachers. In addition, the following issues will be tackled: inadequate teachers&#x2019; and caregivers&#x2019; pedagogical expertise, lack of local materials, lack of awareness of the importance of educating children with disabilities, and the absence of early childhood programs that benefit disadvantaged children. This project will also encourage parenting group involvement by integrating nutrition interventions, Village Savings and Loan Associations, Savings and Credit Organizations and Cooperative Learning education into the programme. 

Finally, the project also seeks to assist governing bodies at the national, regional, zonal, district and community levels to manage early childhood care and development interventions. Networking, advocacy, and communication components will raise awareness of the national policy framework and increase community and government support to increase investment in early childhood care and development programs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finland Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Ethiopia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ratson Women, Youth and Children Development Program</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wolaitta Development Association</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="2938" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.05 37.4</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.971302 37.760807</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="5" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="5" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15110" percentage="45" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="16010" percentage="15" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="24040" percentage="5" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">830000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/2938/Project_2938_current_image_2015-04-14_10.47.04.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A parent group learning about early childhood care, credit: Plan Ethiopia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
