<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-LAO0047</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bokeo Basic Education Program</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access and quality of education for marginalised children in Laos</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary-school-age children in rural areas of the ethnically diverse Bokeo province of northern Laos face culture- and language-related learning issues that lead to poor school performance. This project seeks to improve educational performance in 42 primary schools in the poorest areas by expanding access, improving learning outcomes, strengthening school governance and ensuring child safety.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Primary-school-age children, teachers, teacher trainers, head teachers, village education development committees, District Education and Sports Bureaus and the Provincial Education and Sports Bureau</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The mountainous Bokeo Province in northern Laos is home to an 80% non-Lao population from over 40 different ethnic minorities. These ethnic groups are disproportionately poor, tend to be geographically and socially isolated, and lag behind the rest of the country in key development indicators including literacy, education, nutritional status and access to essential services. Although Laos has seen improvements in school performance nationally due to a recent focus on education, improvements in the ethnically diverse, rural provinces lag behind. Children in these areas also face issues of gender inequality, with many girls marrying under the age of 18 and women having little &#x2018;voice&#x2019; at community levels or in interactions with social services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the project is to help schools in the Bokeo province achieve the national primary education targets and goals with a focus on gender dimensions and educational quality,  including:
&#x2022;	Ensuring that all children, particularly girls, children in difficult circumstances and those belonging to ethnic minorities, have access to and complete free and compulsory primary education
&#x2022;	Achieving gender equality in education with a focus on ensuring girls&#x2019; full and equal access to and achievement in high quality basic education</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the third phase of a project started in 2009, which is implemented in 135  of the poorest schools in three districts in the Bokeo province of Laos. Implementation in 110 schools is provided by Plan Finland through the Finland Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Ylen Hyv&#xE4; funding, and implementation in 25 schools is provided by Plan Switzerland. This phase of the project will address key challenges associated with a) access to education, b) quality of learning outcomes, c) school governance, management and administration and d) school safety and a healthy environment. 
In terms of sustained access, Plan will provide educational materials to participating schools and families, which have been widely reported by parents as being a major factor contributing to their decision to send their children, both boys and girls, to school. In addition, the project will assist children from the poorest families by providing small scale, conditional subsidies to parents to support their children&#x2019;s enrolment and continued participation at school in order to remove economic barriers to education.
To improve learning outcomes, the project will establish three demonstration schools (one in each district) with the goal of developing more effective teaching and learning models and pilot an expanded summer pre-school course in five schools with the assistance of external consultants and the Luang Namtha Teacher Training Centre, that will ultimately better prepare children for entry into primary school.
The project will strengthen village education development committees and support the establishment of Parent Teacher Associations in 44 target schools, which will increase parental involvement and help improve school accountability. Additionally, child safety will be enhanced through disaster resilience training and promotion of positive discipline, which seeks to eliminate physical and emotional abuse in schools. Children&#x2019;s clubs will provide an addition platform for safety trainings and provide additional opportunities for learning outside of school. 
Finally, the project will draw on previous experience in contributing to national level policy debate and development, which is particularly important with respect to quality of learning outcomes. Since girls are more marginalized throughout, this project will specifically focus on improving their situation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is carefully designed to fit within existing structures/policies as well as pilot new innovations that have the potential to make substantive long term impacts on learning outcomes (and thus influence policy development). That being said, the extent to which individual project activities will be sustained post project will vary by activity; these areas are listed below.

Community engagement in school management through Parent Teacher Associations and other groups: It is anticipated that the higher levels of community engagement in school management and monitoring will be made sustainable by developing strong links between groups and the management of school block grants that are provided by the government. 

Demonstration schools: it is expected that teachers in demonstration schools will continue to utilise the developed teaching methods as a results of improved learning outcomes and increased pupil engagement. The extent to which teachers from other schools adopt and sustain such approaches will be a key subject for evaluation at the conclusion of the project.
Multi-grade teaching: the expansion of multi-grade teaching will continue after project end. Investments in strengthening teacher skills in areas such as making efficient use of student classroom time are expected to be sustained post-project and it is hoped that the linkages with teacher training colleges will result in a wider and sustained application of the developed teaching methods.

Finally, the most important long-term sustainable results will be the improvements in learning outcomes and awareness of gender roles resulting from the project, which will have a long-term positive impact on the lives of boys and girls involved in the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Laos</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ylen Hyv&#xE4;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3335" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="5"></activity-scope>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>20.102476 100.592376</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>20.216626 100.550523</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>20.741887 100.470614</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="75" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">844700</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3335/Project_3335_current_image_2015-07-16_11.13.45.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Students in Pha Oudom, credit: Plan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
