<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-UGA100309</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Scaling up Community-Led Action for Children</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children (aged 0-8), especially those with special needs and disabilities; Parents and caregivers; the government, Civil Society Organisations</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing Early Childhood Care and Development in Uganda</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main objective:  that all children (birth to 8 years) in the target communities will develop and learn to full potential through the support of effective &amp; holistic early childhood care and development programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over 20% of Uganda&#x2019;s 36 million people are under age 5. Half of these children live in poverty and 33% of them have stunted growth. Early childhood stimulation and development is not well understood nor widely practiced in the rural areas of Uganda, and a majority of children under five are not achieving their developmental potential due to factors related to poverty, poor health, poor nutrition, and lack of stimulation and learning opportunities. An integrated early childhood development policy has been drafted and is awaiting approval, but awareness of the importance of early childhood care and development is still very low among key decision makers in government.

In addition, gender relations have a negative impact on child development, with domestic violence and limited parenting support from fathers significantly impacting the social and emotional development of children in Uganda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research shows that children taking part in quality Early Childhood Care and Development programmes have better social and emotional development and improved language and cognitive skills, which result in better health, school performance, and increased completion rates. This project seeks to increase the accessibility and quality of early childhood care and development programs in Uganda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to increase parental and community involvement, knowledge, and capacity for Early Childhood Care and Development (ECCD) in four areas in Uganda. 
In 2009, Plan Uganda developed a holistic, high-impact community-managed Early Childhood Care and Development model titled Community-Led Action for Children.  The learnings from the model development phase (2009 &#x2013; 2011) were applied in the second phase of the project (2012-2014), which included implementing the model in 40 community-managed centres in Uganda. 
The current phase of this project (2015-2017) will expand the Early Childhood Care and Development services to 24 new communities in the Tororo, Kamuli, Kampala and Lira areas of Uganda. Specifically, this stage of the project seeks to strengthen facilitators&#x2019; capacity to incorporate aspects of gender, child protection and disability inclusion into the curriculum. In addition, initiatives to promote male involvement in child care and development will be undertaken.
Specifically, this phase of the project seeks to interweave four key project components: strengthening parenting skills and knowledge to support child development; increasing access to quality early learning services for vulnerable children; facilitating effective transitions to primary school; and advocating at the community, district and national levels to meet the developmental needs of children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will provide comprehensive technical assistance for the first two years (2015-2016) and limited support in the third year in order to transition the programme into community management.
Parenting groups involved in this project will be trained on participatory advocacy and social activism with the ultimate goal of using their collective force to influence government policies, legislation, services and investments in areas that support early childhood care and development for all children. Over the three year project period, it is anticipated that parenting groups will have gained appropriate capacity to hold these duty-bearers accountable in fulfilling their children&#x2019;s rights. 
The program has been built with an emphasis on strong community involvement and most components are designed at no- or low-cost. As the demand for high-quality early childhood services grows, the minimal maintenance costs of the centres can be covered by parental contributions, which are subsidized by stipends offered to parenting groups and facilitators in compensation for time and commitment to the project. Training and support for financial information systems will be prioritized for school and centre management committees in order to maximize self-sustainability.
In addition, as part of phase-out, parenting groups will be supported to form Community-Based Organisations and trained to work with School Management Committees to identify alternative sources of support. The groups will be facilitated to agree on a contribution towards centre management and to adopt the concept of Savings Groups to use the savings and have a proportion of the returns on interest apportioned for the school. The groups will also be officially linked to other potential partners for funding of identified activities and with other partners interested in working with groups/volunteers. 
Finally, a cost and financing study has been carried out as part of the project in partnership with UNICEF. This is currently being analysed by the government, with a plan to allocate a certain amount of money per child to ECCD programmes. It should be mentioned that this program is in line with Uganda&#x2019;s National Early Childhood Development guidelines and the national policy framework, which place an emphasis on community ownership and management of early childhood programs, low external input/investment, and a sector-wide implementation approach.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mbarara University of Science and Technology, Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">McGill University, Montreal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3757" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan.fi</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="5"></activity-scope>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.308871 32.577992</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.691178 34.181428</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>0.94506 33.123436</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.246375 32.898838</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11240" percentage="70" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="12261" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 1" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">316116</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 2" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">330311</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 3" currency="EUR" value-date="2015-01-01">331253</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3757/Project_3757_current_image_2015-09-28_14.22.39.JPG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children participating in the CLAC project, credit: Plan Ethiopia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
