<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-KEN100268</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth Action for Governance &amp; Accountability</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">At government level: 48 County Budget and Economic Forum members from Tharaka Nithi and Kwale counties; 35 County Assembly members (20 members from Kwale and 15 members from Tharaka). 

At CSO level: 3,858 youth members from  both Tharaka Nithi Youth Governance Network composed of 24 affiliate youth groups and Kwale Youth governance council composed of 40 youth groups. 

Media: 15 journalists from 4 local FM stations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial sustainability: 
This project has been designed with sustainability in mind. No new institutions or bodies will be created, and the project does not contain any direct service delivery elements. The bulk of the budget is going to intensive training and capacity building, as well as activities that will serve to increase programme momentum and public outreach. Through the training, a significant number of youth and county and ward governments will gain necessary skills that will place them in a position to continue to carry out activities in the spirit of transparency, mutual cooperation, and understanding.
Youth groups and especially those who have received support through small grants will have the capacity and skills to function independently and fundraise for their needs. Through various trainings, youth will have enhanced opportunities to receive resources from funding partners. In addition, youth groups will collect membership fees to maintain their operations.

There are several factors that will contribute to the financial sustainability of the online portal. The platform will be created based on existing websites that are currently administrated by county governments, and the project will be linked to existing portals that are supported by the Ford Foundation, the United Nations Development Program and the Institute for Security Studies. Finally, the online platform will not increase the workload of the county governments, but will be a tool for simplifying the routine work of the governments. Counties are working with different international donors and if need arises they can apply for funding from institutions that support governance projects in Kenya. 
Institutional sustainability: 
The project is designed and will be implemented together with county governments, which are formal project partners, so the project will be largely anchored to existing county authority structures, departments and offices. To formalize the approach as an element of exit strategy, an agreement will be signed between Plan and county governments (and possibly with the national government) ensuring provision of institutional support after the project ends. 
Youth groups will be stimulated to undergo formal registration in order to be able to maintain their organization capacities and raise the necessary funds. The groups will continue to operate and will be equipped with skills and knowledge (for example in social accountability, project management and proposal writing) while receiving support from network/umbrella organizations.  

Policy level sustainability: 
The Current County Integrated Development Plans (2013-2017) (CCIDP) already include positive plans regarding the role of youth in governance processes and mention gender as an important development issue. However, the CCIDP of Tharaka Nithi County does not emphasize growth of information communications technology (ICT) and its benefits for the public. It will therefore be ensured that the upcoming CCDIP (2018-2022) of both counties include issues that were identified by the project and take into consideration the growing needs and opportunities of citizens to provide meaningful feedback. The lessons drawn from the project will be used in shaping the next policy documents on the county level. At the same time, this project will work with both governments to issue a bylaw that enforces the usage of the platform as main information exchange resource. Additionally, the project will seek to enforce the implementation of existing legal and policy documents at the county level that would require the use of ICT in the county by law. 

Finally, the Jubilee manifesto (launched in 2013) and Vision 2030  both recognise the important role information communications technology can play in the country&#x2019;s economy. This action will build on the opportunity provided by both policy documents emphasising the use of technology to add value to various sectors of the economy, including education, health, agriculture, business and finance, governance and leadership. It gives the project broader acceptance by the national policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing youth participation and government accountability in Kenya</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya is frequently perceived to be one of the most corrupt countries in the world, recently being rated 145th out of 174 countries in the 2014 Corruption Perception Index. Inadequate transparency and accountability exists in the management of public resources, which, coupled with limited public information on actual government revenue and expenditure, has directly contributed to corruption, ineptitude and inadequate public service delivery for citizens.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya ranks very high globally in terms of perceived corruption (145th out of 174 countries). This project seeks to battle corruption and ineptitude in public service delivery in Tharaka-Nithi and Kwale counties by building the capacity of youth and community groups and by creating technology solutions&#x2014;such as an online transparency portal&#x2014;to increase government accountability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective: To contribute to an accountable and responsive governance system at the county level that fully recognises active citizen participation as a core principle of good governance. 

Specific Objective: Enhance participation and engagement of youth in county decision making and accountability process for improved allocation of county resources to the needs of vulnerable youth and children and improved service delivery by County governments in Kwale and Tharaka-Nithi counties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project works to strengthen the participation of youth (male and female) and vulnerable communities in county decision making to improve service delivery of County governments in Tharaka-Nithi and Kwale, Kenya. This project will advocate for county authorities (executive committee members, members of the county assembly, chief officers and county ward administrators) to effectively allocate county resources according to the needs and priorities of youth, children, and vulnerable communities including people living with disabilities and HIV/AIDS. 
The action will use an Information Communications Technology platform to promote transparency and accountability in government budgeting processes and to improve service delivery through an online transparency portal. The action supports the use of social accountability processes (social audit, participatory budgeting, public expenditure tracking and community score cards), as a mechanism to monitor performance of projects and programmes supported by county governments. One of the main outcomes of the project will be an online portal that will facilitate the communication between communities and the government. 
The action further supports gender-responsive budgeting by the two county governments to promote participation and equitable resource allocation according to the needs and priorities of women, men, girls and boys. The action will cooperate with local media and government agencies such as the Transition Authority, the Commission for Revenue Allocation and the Office of the Controller of Budgets to increase the participation and impact of local communities in community development and to bring county government spending more in line with local development needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Institute for Health and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">County Government of Kwale, Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">County Government of Tharaka Nithi, Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="EU" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3894" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-0.3 38.0</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.166667 39.45</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2014-11-01">671757</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3894/Project_3894_current_image_2015-11-18_14.50.58.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A woman follows the Kwale County budget process, credit: Plan International Kenya</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
