<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.01">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.01" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-PRO-1498487-2-IND0206</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Women&#x2019;s Economic Empowerment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By population, Indonesia is the fourth largest country in the world, with approximately 228 million people, of which 38.4 million are young people aged 15&#x2013;24. It is a stable democracy with a strong economy and a growth rate of over 6% in 2010-2012. From the perspective of investors it has a vast pool of educated labour, an economy nearly half industrial, and the lowest unit labour costs in the Asia-Pacific region. Impressive as it is, the country&#x2019;s high growth rate is still too low to absorb the annual increase in the labour force of 2&#x2013;2.5 million, adding 300,000&#x2013;500,000 more unemployed to the total unemployed each year. Gender disparities are also seen, with unemployment among young women being significantly higher than among men of the same age (23% for men vs. 28% for women in 2010).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Female youth (15-29 years), community members, gender working groups, employers</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective: 
To enhance young women&apos;s economic empowerment and fulfilment of their rights in Indonesia.

Specific objectives:
1)	Strengthen the policy and economic environment in Indonesia in favour of young women&#x2019;s economic empowerment and gender equality.
2)	Develop and pilot an integrated approach to training, financing and other related services which support gender equality and youth access to decent employment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="7" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project brings together key drivers of change &#x2013; private sector, central government, local authorities, microfinance institutions and the youth themselves &#x2013; to develop and pilot a holistic model of youth economic empowerment (YEE) with a particular focus on young women. It combines training and access to credit and employment with  an innovative, market-led approach, while also targeting the relevant government policies, strategies and legislation to make them more gender responsive. 

The target group is 3,000 young women aged 15-29. Through this program, young women are expected to become more economically independent and improve their living standards. In addition, the economic empowerment of young women will also indirectly impact up to 52,000 other young women and men in their respective communities.
 
The project is based on field experience and analytical work done by Plan in partnership with the World Bank. The actual implementation is designed in the way that puts the public, private and people&#x2019;s partnership at the centre, thereby seeking to maximise sustainability and potential expansion of the model within Indonesia and beyond. The project plan includes:
&#x2022;	Improved implementation of gender-sensitive laws, policies and strategies in public and private sectors at national, provincial and district levels in favour of young women&#x2019;s employment.  This will be accomplished by making ministries, provincial governments and employers aware of the practical implications and benefits to be gained from the economic empowerment of women in general, and young women in particular. 
&#x2022;	Offering young women better access to training, including non-traditional vocations through government-funded vocational and technical training providers.  
&#x2022;	Providing knowledge and skills training through the microfinance institution KOMIDA in North Central Timor District and South Central Timor District, which will benefit 3,000 women in the areas of individual career counselling, provision of job placement and business development support and mentoring.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="10" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project is designed to secure sustainability after completion of the action as follows: 
Financial sustainability 
&#x2022;	Beneficiary businesses will fund the technical and vocational training of youth, which will greatly reduce costs. This has already begun in the YEE Programme at the Grobogan pilot site.  
&#x2022;	Transaction costs per trainee will be reduced through upscaling. With economies of scale, we estimate that the cost per trainee will be $100-$150 after three years of operation. In order to cover this amount, trainees may have the opportunity to pay for training by accessing educational loans and/ or covering training costs through their own savings and contributions. 
&#x2022;	In-kind contributions from local and national government in areas will be utilized, such as cost-free use of vocational training venues and use of public land.
&#x2022;	The microfinance component of the project will use its established methodologies to expand its business and is expected to become operationally and financially sustainable within three years.
&#x2022;	The donor community present in Indonesia will be kept informed about the Project operations and results, resulting in a possible expansion of project activities in collaboration with Bappenas/IYEN resources. 

Institutional sustainability 
&#x2022;	This project involves developing and testing a low-cost model for the state to adopt, since the responsibility to meet international commitments on decent work and youth employment rests with the state and its institutions. 
&#x2022;	The integrated approach and careful choice of local partners with strong ownership over the proposed activities will ensure that activities will continue beyond the timeframe of the project. At the central level, the Ministries and partner APINDO will adopt the improved policy and program. At local level, the local government, APINDO member companies and training providers will adopt the new training program for young women. 
&#x2022;	The project seeks to enhance existing working procedures which will in turn enhance institutional sustainability.  The design of activities involving key Ministries and government agencies at the national level and duty bearers at the local level as partners and stakeholders will further promote the adoption of gender-sensitive training and empowerment of youth. 
&#x2022;	One of the project&#x2019;s main approaches is increase the community&#x2019;s role in managing the local education establishments (e.g. village schools). This promotes ownership and increases the potential for replication.     

Policy sustainability 
&#x2022;	This project will strengthen enforcement and implementation of existing laws and policies by providing the responsible ministries with adequate monitoring tools that will help monitor the impact of actions, which will ultimately contribute to better decision making. 
&#x2022;	Private sector codes of conduct will be reviewed and enhanced to reflect gender equality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unemployment rates in Indonesia are higher for young women compared with similarly-aged men. This project aims to enhance young women&apos;s economic empowerment and rights fulfilment by (1) using an innovative, market-led approach to improve work training and access to credit and employment opportunities and (2) targeting relevant government policies and strategies to make them more gender responsive.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training and policy strengthening for young women in Indonesia</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employers&apos; Association of Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="EU" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia Business Links</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Koperasi Mitra Dhuafa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Women&apos;s Empowerment and Child Protection Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-PRO-1498487-2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="3886" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International Finland</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mika V&#xE4;litalo</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>mika.valitalo@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-10.183333 123.583333</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-6.2 106.816667</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-9.446667 124.478056</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-9.471667 124.804722</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 1" currency="EUR" value-date="2013-02-01">465000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 2" currency="EUR" value-date="2013-02-01">675000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Year 3" currency="EUR" value-date="2013-02-01">735000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/media/db/project/3886/Project_3886_current_image_2015-11-17_09.24.46.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A young woman learning how to plow a field, credit: Plan International Indonesia</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
