<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5402008501-LKA-14020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sri Lanka, Waste water treatment- GPOBA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Sri lanka, Vattenrening -GPOBA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Resultatbaserad bidrag f&#xF6;r anslutning av fattigare hush&#xE5;ll f&#xF6;r        avloppsrening n&#xE4;r Colombo.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resultbased grant for connection of poorer households to system f&#xF6;r   wastewater treatment close to Colombo.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Sri Lanka Output-Based Aid (OBA) in the &#x2018;Increasing Household Access to Domestic Sanitation in Greater Colombo&#x2019; was designed to address the degraded sanitary and environmental conditions of densely populated low-income settlements in the outskirts of Greater Colombo. At the time of project preparation, the geographical coverage of the sewer network in Greater Colombo was less than 50 percent of the total area, most of which were concentrated in the central area, while surrounding small towns had lower coverage ranging from 15 percent to 40 percent.
The existing wastewater treatment plants (WWTP) were not adequate, and sewage flows were only screened before discharge to water bodies. There were around 100 water customers for every one sewer connection in the project area. The majority of households that were not connected to the sewerage network, both poor and non-poor, had some form of on-site sanitation (either septic tanks or pits). According to NWSDB estimate, there were about 80,000 such tanks and pits throughout the Greater Colombo area. Many of such on-site sanitation facilities were in poor condition and discharge into the environment &#x2013; either directly into rivers and canals or into storm drains.
The very low rate of connection to sewers coupled with unregulated management of on-site sanitation resulted in high levels of contamination of the environment and cross contamination into the water supply system. Illegal unregulated dumping of fecal sludge into the sewer network also caused blockages and contributed to poor performance of the whole network. Australia and Sweden provided funding as donors of the Global Partnership for Results-Based Approaches (GPRBA, formerly Global Partnership on Output-Based Aid [GPOBA]). Australia, a traditional donor of island nations in Oceania, hoped to see the testing of innovative approaches to sanitation for an island nation with a promising tourism sector. For Sweden, this project was meant to enhance the development impact of the Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency (Sida) as it was completing its support to Sri Lanka, a post-conflict nation on a path to becoming an upper-middle-income country (this status was achieved in 2019).
Sida provided a US$91 million concessional loan to the National Water Supply and Drainage Board (NWSDB) to build two state-of-the-art WWTP&#x2014;in Ratmalana/Moratuwa to the south of Colombo and in Ja-Ela/Ekala to the north of Colombo. Sida invited GPRBA for parallel assistance in 2006 and GPRBA provided technical assistance to design a results-based financing (RBF) project. In 2010, a grant of US$ 5.08 million for connecting 13,107 households and providing on-site sanitation to 2,300 households was committed by GPRBA.
Project Development Objectives (PDOs) was to improve sanitation services to low-income households in Greater Colombo by increasing the number of sewerage house connections to existing and new sewerage networks and improving on-site sanitation services at household level. The PDO was not changed over the project period.
Key Expected Outcomes and Outcome Indicators was designed to increase the house sewer connections and improving sanitation services in place. The three Key Outcome Indicators were: (a) number of new sewer household connections constructed under the project; (b) number of eligible low-income households provided with improved on-site systems; (c) new PPP framework for delivery of improved sanitation services in place; and (d) number of direct beneficiaries and its ratio of female.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sri Lanka</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water supply and sanitation - large systems</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">2157430.8081119396</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2010-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2010-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2011-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-01-01">2157430.8081119396</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <capital-spend percentage="100"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-12-01">1943850.490128</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2011-02-28">2157430.8081119396</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project&#x2019;s cost discovery helped the government to better budget for sanitation in poor neighborhoods, and to target truly low-income families as well as to find suitable and inclusive solutions that were categorized and ready to go to scale. Directed by the sociologists on staff of the national utility, the project sought women&#x2019;s voices, and ensured that eligible beneficiaries from among minorities have not been left out (see poster that illustrates community sensitization campaign in Tamil). Almost 50 thousand beneficiaries obtained access to safely-managed sanitation with support of the almost $5 million GPRBA grant disbursed against verified results.[1] A small percentage of the grant has not been disbursed because of two reasons: the conventional sewer connections, the only option near heavy-traffic roads, did not find enough potential low-income customers, and secondly, the PPP was delayed because its stakeholders could not move fast enough initially. The project created important environmental, health and social benefits. Lower water-pollution rates were recorded, and there was less sludge and wastewater in public spaces. This decreased the number of disease-carrying mosquitoes and rats, and made the public spaces more inviting to the general public. In coastline settlements where public health and environmental points of view differ, the project demonstrated cost efficiency of the environmental viewpoint. Particularly, the disposal of minimally-treated gray and black wastewater into Indian ocean is not harmful to humans if the ocean outflow pipe is about 100 meters long but it is cheaper to have a DeWaTS that treats wastewater well and can have the outflow pipe of less than 10 meters long. At the conclusion of the project, it was determined that its outcomes were operationally and financially sustainable, and that the project has great potential to scale, in other parts of Sri Lanka, as well as in other island nations. One of the PPP partners with experience in manufacturing concrete poles invested close to $1 million into the new only island&#x2019;s only production facility of concrete septic tanks with environmental safety suitable for high-water-table, flood-prone and low-lying areas. Building on this pilot, the Sri Lankan government has requested the World Bank to support a new wastewater-management project scheduled to start in 2021 or 2022.[2] &#xA0; [1] See ICR report for project P111161. Accessed on 11/20/2019: http://documents.WorldBank.org/curated/en/109961569513666711/Implementation-Completion-and-Results-Report-ICR-Document-LK-GPOBA-Access-to-Sanitation-Project-P111161. [2] The World Bank is preparing the first IBRD loan for sanitation in Sri Lanka. Also, AFD is preparing the next phase of Sida&#x2019;s support to wastewater treatment plants (see reference above Nilsson et al. 2018).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="3" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="54020085" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
