<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-18/3559/RANOV18/WASH/NGO/11302</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH intervention to reduce the water-borne diseases among the host community and IDPs by providing emergency water services in north Aleppo, Idlib governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to reduce the incidents of hepatitis, which has spread in the area of Afrin. The project will provide clean drinking water temporarily as an emergency response to calls of infection of Waterborne diseases in north-west Syria through special mobile treatment plants in areas where water-related diseases are widespread.
After several reports from the WASH cluster regarding the spread of hepatitis A and B, the main cause of the spread of which is water contamination
The Technical Team of Hand in Hand for Aid and Development (HIHFAD) visited these areas to conduct a technical assessment. The tasks of the project were determined as follows:
- The project will do water analysis in the water sources in the northwestern region of Syria, especially in the Afrin region.
- In the first stages of the project, water will be fully treated and supplied to the public buildings temporarily as an emergency response, especially to schools and hospitals. The project is an emergency response to the most affected population in the target area until sustainable solutions provided, such as including the operation of the local treatment plant in Midanki. 
- In the later stages, water will be treated in public gathering places such as mosques, gardens and other assembly areas where the water sources are available. The mobile treatment plant will be connected to the existing water sources in the public areas, treat the water and supply it to the storage facility. The treated water will also be supplied to the existing local water network wherever available in remote areas Which is a shared reservoir between a number of houses and are connected to a local network.
- In addition, the pumping station in AlMahmoodiah neighbourhood in Afrin will be operated to provide clean drinking water till the main water network is maintained and operated.
-In the communities where storage systems are neither available or damaged, the proposed project will repair or install new ones. Also, the existing water storages will be assessed again at the beginning of the project, and they will be cleaned and treated before the treated water is supplied there. 
-Water will also be treated in nearby sources of the residential areas of the most vulnerable and needy beneficiaries and in remote settlements where treatment stations are not available, and people use untreated water. The mobile unit will travel to those settlements as far as minimum road structure and security situation allow. This is important not just for the travel of the mobile plant, but also for the safety of staff and beneficiaries.
- Water suppliers and beneficiaries receive appropriate quantity of chlorine for the treatment of water &#x2013; HIHFAD will establish a team of 6 people to visit the water sources and make sure the water is chlorinated with the chlorine they will be supplied with.
In general, the mobile water treatment plant is capable of providing potable water in a fast, reliable and cost-effective manner. This makes them an ideal choice in critical situations like the one in Afrin. Mobile water treatment systems are ideal as emergency water purification systems as they are also portable / transportable if required. In this project, the mobile plant will be used to treat borehole, surface and spring water and will provide drinking water to 70.000 people in Afrin subdistrict.  In addition, these mobile water plants will be transported  to outreach any other locations in NW Syria during the lifespan of the units wherever needed in northwest Syria and in coordination with WASH Cluster. HIHFAD will try its best to secure the operational costs of the treatment units, beyond the project duration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-21" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-21"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-21">650004.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400306113/565">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-13">41310.54</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-11302">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-21">650004.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303797211">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-25">520003.99</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
