<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-18/3559/RANOV18/NFI/NGO/11253</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Winterization Shelter response to most vulnerable women, men, boys and girls in Badama, Jisr-al-Shugur and Khan al-Asal.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The prolonged conflict in Syria led to great destruction in buildings and properties. Moreover, the forced mass displacement taking place to northwest Syria during the recent influxes led to the arrival of thousands of IDPs in the north of Syria. Badama, Jisr-al-Shugur and Khan al-Asal are among the areas with highest levels of destructions and have received great numbers of displaced men, women, girls and boys who live in bad humanitarian conditions or living environment in houses or shelters that are unprotective and unsuitable for living, in certain cases with structural damage, which threatens the lives and jeopardizes the protection of people, especially girls, women, elderly and people with special needs especially under the extremely cold winter weather in project areas.

This proposed intervention will be implemented in coordination (Shelter/NFI) cluster targeting the most conflict-affected men, women, boys and girls in northwest Syria, Idleb governorate (Badama, Jisr-Ash-Shugur, and Khan Al Asal) in order to provide life-saving and life-sustaining shelter assistance, which will promote protection and meet immediate and urgent needs of IDPs and hosting communities through hosting them in sustainably rehabilitated housing units for at least one year. 
This project aims at rehabilitation of 650 partially damaged houses at an average cost of $865 per house and hosting 650 households (195 HHs of hosting communities and 455 of IDPs), at a total count of 3900 individuals, roughly divided as 730 men, 820 women, 1175 boys and 1175 girls where female beneficiaries are no less than 51%.
The project will select beneficiaries based on clear criteria prioritizing women/child/elderly and disabled-headed households in addition to HHs with members of special needs, chronic disease, small children or elderly members. 
Mapping and needs assessment were conducted to help select implementation locations depending on preset criteria prioritizing areas with the greatest number of partially damaged houses and IDPs and in accordance with allocation strategy. 
Housing, Land and Property (HLP) rights of both shelter beneficiaries and house owners will be considered before final selection of houses and throughout all stages of the project. 
In Jisr-Ash-Shugur area, in particular, there will be continuous cooperation between Qatar Red Crescent (QRC) and SDI to ensure geographical separation and avoid overlapping/duplication regarding beneficiaries.
Through this intervention, we will contribute into enhancing the prevention and mitigation of protection risks, and respond to protection needs through supporting the protective environment in Syria, by promoting international law, (International Humanitarian Law) IHL, (human rights law) HRL and through quality principled assistance.
The project will allow direct beneficiaries&#x2019; access to dignified and durable shelters which will contribute in saving and sustaining lives providing better living conditions and a healthier living environment, especially during winter. Moreover, it will support the targeted communities and contribute to the resilience and cohesion and protection of targeted communities and IDPs, including the creation of job opportunities for both IDPs and local communities. 

The main project output will be:

Providing 650 HHs of most vulnerable conflict-affected IDPs and host communities, selected based on validated needs while prioritizing women headed HHs and those with special needs, chronic diseases, elderly, people and small children, with decent shelter and better living conditions through the rehabilitation of 650 partially-damaged houses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-09"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-09">792099.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-11253">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-09">792099.6</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303781825">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-16">316839.84</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304491036">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-12">329004.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
