<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-18/3559/SA1/P-NFI/UN/9505</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Continuation of Integrated Protection and Provision of Legal Services to IDPs and Host Community members in Darkoush sub-district, Idleb, and enhanced shelter solutions for IDPs and Host Community in Rural Aleppo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project has two main components:

IOM, in partnership with Hope Revival Organization (HRO), aims to continue providing protection services in the community center established in Idleb Governorate, Jiser Al Shughour District, Darkoush Sub-District to ensure that a greater number of Syrians have access to information and protection services in their community. 

With the continued provision of already existing protection services and the initiation of new protection services in Darkoush community center, currently run by HRO, the overall aim of this component is to reduce protection risks and vulnerability for persons living in Darkoush in Idleb Governorate through the provision of integrated protection and legal services following a protection-centered and community-based approach. The community center aims to provide a space where men, women, boys and girls can socialize and strengthen previously fractured social networks, and gain access to specialized protection services, including GBV and CP case management, obtain specialized information/legal support on Civil Status Documentation (CSD)/Housing Land and Property (HLP), and receive information on services available in the wider area. IOM will implement this program through HRO, a humanitarian organization with a strong track record in protection programming, including specialized GBV case management and MHPSS activities. This component of the project will assist 4,656 beneficiaries IDPs: 823 men, 1,386 women, 385 boys, 665 girls Host Community: 339 men, 610 women, 210 boys, 238 girls).

Second, IOM seeks to mitigate the health, protection, and security risks for displaced populations being hosted in transit reception centres, and those living in makeshift camps, by providing alternative shelter solutions.

Aiming to provide new shelters to 1,800 IDPs (300 men, 300 women, 600 boys, 600 girls). Specific focus will be on displaced women-headed households (at least 20% of the caseload), who are continuously increasing in number and most at risk of protection concerns such as GBV and unequal access to HLP.

In the shelter rehabilitation component, IOM will provide shelter solutions to newly displaced populations, through rehabilitation of privately owned unfinished buildings (HLP verified). These sites will provide 1,800 IDPs with shelter for one year rent-free. The selection of IDPs residing in ad hoc makeshift camps referred by local communities for the shelter assistance will be based on predetermined vulnerability criteria. In coordination with the newly established Technical Working Group (TWG) of the CCCM cluster, the selection of the newly displaced population or currently residing in transit and reception centres will be based on strategic planning with shelter actors. Emphasis will be placed on the provision of adequate shelter for women-headed households.

For the shelter rehabilitation and components, the catchment population is vulnerable IDP families living in inadequate and damaged shelter in Rural Aleppo, Jebel Samaan district, Anadan, Haritan and Kafar Hamra sub-districts</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-19" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-08-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-04">261900.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-08-19"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-04">454879.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-9505">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-04">716779.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303537716">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-10">716779.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Agency</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
