<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-18/3559/RANOV18/FS/NGO/11288</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food baskets distribution for most vulnerable people in Idlib City, Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This initiative will contribute to meeting the basic needs of the most vulnerable households from host communities and displaced people out of camps in underserved areas by improving food consumption, dietary diversity and positive coping strategies by of the targeted households in Idlib City. 
Violet is proposing a five and a half months intervention to cover the basic food needs of 1,818 food insecure households (9,090 individuals) in Idleb city with standard WFP food kits (1,515 kcal) for 4 distribution rounds. Through this project, Violet aims to contribute in covering the food basic needs of the most vulnerable households who were supported by Violet by distributing FFP baskets in order to alleviate the impact of the FFP project end, knowing that the last Food baskets distribution round under FFP project will be in Feb 2019.

Throughout the project, the beneficiaries will be receiving the GFA rations distributed. Nonetheless, the beneficiaries will not solely act as recipients of commodities, but also play an active role in the project design and implementation. By actively engaging the different groups of the communities in community representative boards, the beneficiaries are asked for their feedback, opinions on the implementation strategy as well as to act as a connecting point for feedback.

The designed Family Food ration (FFR) aims to provide a 1,515 kcal per person per day is also calculated on a base to reach 70% of the minimum kcal needs. The calculation is made on a reference family size of 5 for a period of 30 days.

The proposed percentage breakdown of the ration is 55-65% of energy to be contributed by Carbohydrates, 10-15% from Protein and 17 to 20% from fat, and It is assumed from the Food Security Assessment at household level that in general food insecure households will be able to meet the rest of the kcal/person/day from their own sources. kindly find attached BOQ (Annex 1) and Annex 2 nutritional values of the kit. 

In order to ensure the transparency and competitive of the procurement, Violet will ensure the food baskets procurement is announced properly to enable the interested suppliers to apply. The best offer will be selected by a committee based on specific selection criteria including - but not limited to - the price and quality of the items.
The procurement modality for the proposed FBs will be via a clear tender process, where the purchase request will be deeply specified and detailed with the all technical specifications. Violet will ensure the wide announcement of the tender through advertising it on the well-known procurement websites to ensure the transparency and competivity. the winner supplier will be selected based on specific criteria including the quality of the provided samples, price, and validity duration of the items. the FBs will be purchased from Turkish national suppliers of food items. A lab test results for the sample of each batch will be provided by the supplier from a third-party laboratory (agreed by Violet and winner supplier) for both chemical and physical food safety and in accordance to WFP technical specifications (annexes 1,11), quality and compliance checks. Prior to dispatch, a sample will be checked by VIOLET&#x2019;s technical project team at the vendors&#x2019; warehouse to ensure compliance. Customs clearance and handling will be provided by the supplier, as will export and import taxes, handling fees, documentation costs, and other legal and official fees. The goods will be transported from the Syrian gate of the border crossing to VIOLET&#x2019;s Idlib warehouse. The goods will be verified in terms of quantity and quality before receipt documents are issued and signed. The supplier will also provide extra empty packaging in case of re-packaging requirements for potentially broken boxes and bags. The supplier will also provide additional dry food rations to cover any potential loss incurred in transit as VIOLET will only pay for undamaged kits received to VIOLET WH</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-23" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY07">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Idleb</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.92900800 36.63527600</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-02-08"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-23"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-08">493100.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400271240">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-13">4828.85</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-11288">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-08">493100.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303839236">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-15">246550.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303998725">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-21">246550.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
