<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR-18/3559/SA2/FS/NGO/10200</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support the livelihood situation and improve the resilience of the most vulnerable populations in Afrin, Aleppo.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MWL proposed project aim to select 500 local farmer whom their lands are near their homes (for host community, for IDPs whose can rent or plant a land in a participatory way with a neighbor of the host community) with no affordability to agricultural supplies, financial resources or guidance in cultivating their lands. The selection of these crops comes from need assessment as it shows the local farmers have long experience in dealing with these crops and eligible class of soil, as well as the availability of natural water sources close to their lands.

Regarding agriculture inputs (Kit) distribution, the methodology will be based on the cultivation of three types of mentioned crops (Peas-Beans-Spinach) on the same area unit which will depend on poly-culture. 
This intervention as mixed-farming will reduce the probability of losing a crop in case of several high effects of climate change via diseases and insect invasions.
The land (half dunum) will be divided into parallel lines and the distribution will be as follows: (100 sq meters Spinach, 200 sq meters Bean, 200 sq meters Peas)

The share of both Peas and Beans was increased due to higher productivity compared with spinach. Also, project locations have access to nearby natural water sources such as (tributaries, local wells).  So, the availability of irrigation for these crops will be easy in case of drought during the crop life cycle. Otherwise, the three types of winter crops require a similar dealing in terms of service and skills which already available with local farmers.
These 3 crops will provide a good source for beneficial family members by minerals, vegetable protein, carbohydrates plus vitamins. The needs of each crop (fertilizer, seed) will be distributed according to the size of the cultivated unit and based on the recommendations of the response package SO 2, SO3.

In addition,MWL will support 500 families to provide them by 10 Eggs Laying-Hens as one-time with fodder batches for 6 months with needed veterinary services. Regarding the number of poultry flock (10 hen,1 rooster), its meet the recommendations of kit composition/response package for SO2 and SO3. At the same time,those family who supported by poultry kit will give another 500 families under (specific criteria) 10 eggs weekly/as free for 6 months in order to enhance social cohesion and nutrition status.

In part of distributing eggs, MampE team will be responsible to following-up the distribution process off eggs according to the signed agreement that will include a condition to ensuring the commitment for reguler distribution, in case of one of poultry beneficiaries refrain from distributing the eggs S/He will not benefit from fodder distribution.

The project locations contain a number of IDPs and host community. According to information received by the field team, social fabric status still fragile because of different cultures between the two parties.
When a beneficiary family giving 10 eggs per weekly as free to another family in need, its consider a matter of rapprochement and friendship, promotes ties of intimacy and increases cohesion among them in the society over time.
In addition, a written agreement will be signed between the parties clarifying the responsibilities and rights of each party in order to take all require actions relating to any violation of the provisions of that agreement, which will be explained in advance and signed.Otherwise, the real-time monitoring role in all its means and mechanisms will be present and apply to ensure the effective implementation of that mechanism, Complaint procedures applying by beneficiaries will be clear, useful and it will be circulated to everyone.

Beneficiaries details
Total Beneficiaries (1500 HHs / 7500 Person) including: (M 1374, W 1688, B 2014, G 2424)
Total IDPs 2475 Person including (M 453, W 557, B 665, G 800),
Total host community 5025 Person including (M 921, W 1131, B 1349, G 1624).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">xxxx (Secured)</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>xxxx (Secured)</telephone>
   <email>xxxx (Secured)</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SY02">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aleppo</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.20601300 37.15242000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-10-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-05">69947.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-05">195117.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="TUR70-10200">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-05">265065.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303661423">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-15">106026.09</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304078266">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-03">79519.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304497131">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-18">79224.25</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National NGO</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Cross border BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-TUR70-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
