<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/CCM/INGO/14591</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving quality of life for populations living within collective sites in Qa&apos;atabah, Al Dhale&#x2019;e</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to UNHCR, there are almost 2.4 million IDPs currently in Yemen, with 80% displaced for over a year. 1 in 4 of these HHs are residing in public areas such as schools, unoccupied buildings, and sporadic sites. They are often the most vulnerable as there is a limited access to services, protection issues and threats of eviction. Relations between IDPs and HCs can be strained by the presence of IDPs and tensions increase when additional pressure is put on the insufficient resources, putting IDPs at further risk. Al Dhale&#x2019;e is no exception to this and face strong challenges in dealing with the influx of IDPs and other site populations. This has overwhelmed available services and resulted in an intensification of gaps and needs, and tensions in these governorates. While some HHs are supported, this assistance is sporadic and often doesn&#x2019;t cover the full needs of those in sites. ACTED&#x2019;s recent initial site assessments identified 4 sites in close proximity to each other with 1,992 individuals in Sahada, Qa&#x2019;atabah and no actor to coordinate service provision, raise needs for potential service delivery and refer cases. With no endpoint to the conflict in sight and ongoing movements of site populations, SMC is vital to ensure that services are delivered to respond to diverse needs. To address these issues, ACTED proposes a comprehensive static area-based intervention to improve the living conditions for vulnerable site residents in the 4 sites in the Sahada area of Al Dhale&#x2019;e. ACTED will conduct stakeholder inclusive-SMC activities, information management and sharing, strengthening coordination, community engagement and participation structures through tailored capacity building and engaging in area care and maintenance support. Protection and dignity-led programming will be utilized to achieve site ownership and increased independence of aid as well as measures to enhance social cohesion between site and HCs. ACTED has also incorporated measures to mitigate potential risks. Notably, 2 of the biggest challenges, acceptance of the activities by stakeholders and approval from authorities will be addressed by inclusive programming and capacity building of actors throughout the project. ACTED will work to build strong relationships with all actors and maintain engagement with them throughout the project, thus reducing these risks. The main beneficiaries will be individuals living in targeted sites IDPs and muhamasheen. ACTED will strive for inclusion, taking cultural sensitivities and the needs of marginalized groups into account. Given the inherently inclusive approach of SMC, there will be opportunities for all, including women and vulnerable groups to raise concerns and needs and further tailor project design. ACTED can then respond either through direct support or its referral process to identify partners that can provide assistance. This intervention will build on ACTED&#x2019;s current work funded by ECHO, in partnership with DRC and NRC. Under this, ACTED is addressing the aforementioned issues in a harmonized manner by assisting site residents in a multi-sectoral manner. This is being done through on-site SMC activities and integrated WASH and Shelter service provision through a mobile and light response approach, and SMC trainings to local committees and site focal points. This proposal would enable ACTED&#x2019;s to strengthen this work, allowing ACTED to strive towards a more coordinated and holistic response for IDPs, strongly benefiting from its ongoing ECHO grant experience. In addition, ACTED is the CCCM and WASH Cluster focal point for area coordination in Al Dhale&#x2019;e and the lead of the Global CCCM Capacity Building Technical Working Group (TWiG). This means ACTED is well-placed to deliver CCCM programming reflective of the Cluster&#x2019;s strategy, can integrate much needed WASH support and TWiG knowledge to ensure coordination between actors delivering assistance to site residents in sites and provide support for the CCCM cluster.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Niamh Foley</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Project Development Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967716603481</telephone>
   <email>niamh.foley@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oliver Stoffa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Finance Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967716603440</telephone>
   <email>oliver.stoffa@acted.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Dhale&apos;e</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.85996808 44.67423913</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Camp Coordination / Management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-24">393676.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-24">100942.65</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14591">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-24">494618.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304468788">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-29">395695.18</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
