<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/Health/INGO/14772</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Health Response in Dar-Sad, Tuban, Al Maqatirah districts in Aden and Lahj Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children (SC) plans to deliver health interventions that focus on providing access to quality, high impact health services to internally displaced people (IDPs), host communities and highly vulnerable populations in conflict affected areas in 1 district in Aden and 2 districts in Lahj Governorates. These interventions consist of life-saving health services, linked with community-based interventions through the mobile health team and community volunteers. The project targets reaching 155,939 direct beneficiaries.

Through this Action, IDPs living in the collective sites and the host communities will have improved access to quality primary healthcare based on the Yemen Minimum Services Package (MSP) that includes general services and trauma care, child care, reproductive health services Minimum Initial Service Package (MISP), management of both communicable and non-communicable disease as well as outbreak response, especially preparedness activities and clinical management of sexual gender-based violence (SGBV). The project will strengthen the health systems through support to the functionality of 11 fixed Health Facilities (HFs) and 1 mobile team (that would work outside the 1st and 2nd zones of the HF), which were identified in collaboration with the health cluster and sub cluster, District Health Office (DHO) and the Governorate Health Offices (GHO) in Aden and Lahj, based on the gaps on the ground. SC will collaborate with the WHO through the Health cluster to receive support in form of IEHKs.

The Action will integrate with the other sectors such as WASH and Nutrition currently being implemented in the locations, funded by other donors. The health units will refer to the nutrition unit in the Primary Health Center (PHC) and also ensure that all children with malnutrition and with minor illnesses are managed with appropriate treatment or referred to the higher level. The reproductive health (RH) unit of the PHC will also ensure that mothers that come to the nutrition center are aware of RH services available at the health facilities. Integrated WASH components will focus on clean water supply, communicable disease control, improvement of the water systems within the HFs, and enhancing proper community hygiene practices to reduce disease spread and resultant mortalities. 

Outreach activities will be implemented, and health workers will work within the 1st and 2nd zone of the targeted HF catchment population and to reduce gaps and delays in getting essential life-saving services to vulnerable people, especially women and girls. The mobile team will work outside the 5 km radius (outside the 1st and 2nd zones) of the catchment HF to avoid overlap with the outreach activities of the health workers. 

At the community and HF level, health education will be provided to enhance beneficiaries&#x2019; knowledge, attitude and behaviors related to child health, reproductive health and prompt care seeking. Below are details of the HFs to be supported and their catchment populations.

Aden: Dar-Sad District (Dar Saad, Allohom, Alemad amp Albasateen HF). 1 mobile team  will cover the remote areas in all HFs in Dar Saad (Al-Damana, Gholel, Al-Rawda, Al-Yarmok, Dar Mansor, AlDawgen, AlDemah, Al-Hffer, Block Zero, AlFalahen, amp BerFadel villages and neighborhood)
Lahj: Tuban district (Haran Daian, Alshaqaa, Al-Waht Hospital, Abder Bader, Al Fuish, amp Albithara HFs)
Lahj: Almaqatirah District (AL-Sumain HF) 

Project target number:
142,803 (34,171 Men, 79,734 Women, 14,404 Boys, 14,494 Girls) host community and 13,136 IDPs (being 30% of the total 43,860 IDP community) will directly benefit from this Action with 3,796 under 1 (1860 Boys, 1936 Girls) receiving Penta3 vaccination. The total population in the target areas is 180,763.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Development and Quality</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Mohammed.Alshamaa@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Alshamaa Mohammed</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awards Management and Business Development</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>Sajjad.Yousaf@savethechildren.org</telephone>
   <email>Sajjad Yousaf</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aden</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.84865928 45.00201169</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lahj</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.96593663 44.41733354</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-31">914959.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-31">84921.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14772">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-31">999880.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304481093">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-05">399952.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304957586">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-26">599928.21</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
