<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/SHNFI/O/14614</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shelter  NFIs Assistance for IDPs in Dhamar Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemeni Red Crescent Society as has an excellent reputation among stakeholders amp authorities, it has established on 1970, under Presidential Decree no. 51 amp officially become recognized National NGO performing humanitarian activities with compassion. Its 22 branch in 22 Gov. in Yemen worked separately to consolidate the Basic Principles of the (IFRC) International Red Cross amp Red Crescent Movement bringing 7 vital elements (Humanity, Impartiality Neutrality, Independence, Voluntary Service, Unity and Universal). It mainly work to embody human values, spread noble message of humanity amp support State during crises resulting from disasters amp armed conflicts. Which aid, relief amp assistance is without discrimination or bias bringing protection of life, health and ensure respect for human beings. YRC has excellent access to all places even frontline districts where such privilege promote project success. In addition, YRC has an extensive experience in Shelter/NFIs activities in which will reflect positively during project implementation.
After almost 5 years of conflict, and despite all efforts to stop displacement, hunger and disease, the situation in Yemen remains catastrophic and continues to be the worst man-made humanitarian crisis in the world which has torn Yemeni nation apart and set back the standard of living by decades. Shelter/NFI situation deteriorated as a result of increased conflict and shift of frontlines, deterioration of economy including reduction of local currency. Also, extraordinary increases in goods prices in local markets including household items amp shelter materials. Affected population situation continue to deteriorate where growing number of humanitarian needs must be addressed. Targets are 1500 NFIs amp 600 rent will be provided for most vulnerable of 80% IDP amp 15.8 % host households.  
Dhamar Gov surrounded by Ibb, Hudaydah, Al Bayda Governorates where IDPs approach it looking for several humanitarian assistance most importantly shelter, security and food. Lots of farms business creating chances of employment more likely rather than other governorates. The project targeting 3 districts (Jahran, Jabal Ash Sharq and Utmah) where IDP households are living in Hosting Site amp private settings taking into account families who are at risk to leave because of the inability to continue hosting them.
The Gap Analysis for HPF 2nd SA 2019 shows that IDP families in these three districts in huge need of Non-Food items amp Rental Subsidies. The Guidelines of the Alternative to Camps in Yemen in June 2018, gave Ladder of options to target IDP households, 1st category Camps that facilitate the identification of people with specific needs and the delivery of services to them, yet camps limit rights and freedom of movement and reduce the chances to merge with host community. Project will distribute NFIs for targeted IDPs in hosting sites. Another alternative form: many of IDPs have settled peacefully outside of camps in both rural and urban areas, living on land or in housing that they rent or with host families, where project will assist them rental subsidies. Each step in the ladder option provided in the Guidelines are considered to respond to IDP needs whether it is implemented in IDP hosting sites or in private-settings inside host communities. Project will target 15.8 % of the most vulnerable of host community members in both of NFIs amp Rental Subsidies in the way to mitigate sufferance and most importantly to merge between IDPs amp host community. Training amp awareness sessions considering segregation between gender amp age categories of (women, girls, men and boys) will improve performance amp ultimately for the effectiveness of humanitarian assistance in meeting the needs of those affected, especially the most vulnerable ones.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Red Crescent Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Red Crescent Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abdullah Saleh ALAZAP</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Projects Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>777188863</telephone>
   <email>a.azap@yemenredcrescent.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Ahmad HANASH</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>777293834</telephone>
   <email>m.hanash@yemenredcrescent.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waleed Abdullah ALMUHYYA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>713604040</telephone>
   <email>waleed.muhyya@yemenredcrescent.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dhamar</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.50737016 44.42760976</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">758463.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14614">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">758463.08</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Red Crescent Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304437113/114">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-16">227538.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Red Crescent Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304736261-62">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-15">227538.92</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Red Crescent Society</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
