<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/SHNFI/NGO/14746</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFIs Response to the Vulnerable People in Hajjah Governorate (Aslem, Bani Qais and Hajjah City Districts).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposed project is aimed at providing emergency shelter and NFIs assistance to the most vulnerable IDP households (75%) living in the IDP hosting sites and host communities and host community members (25%) in Hajjah (Aslem, Bani Qais, and Hajjah City districts) governorate. The project is designed under the 2nd standard allocation 2019 with a focus on the first line of efforts covering the high priority gaps in first line response in IDPs collective sites and areas hosting a large number of IDPs as relevant to the cluster and allocation strategy and also within SDF&apos;s capacity, experiences and access. SDF will ensure that all men, women, boys and girls living in IDPs hosting sites and in adjacent host communities have access to basic services of NFIs, ES and rental subsidies of needed HHs. To respond to the needs assessed and identified in the targeted areas, the SDF is planning to target 2100 vulnerable IDP HHs in 21 IDP settlements through the implementation of life-saving and life-sustaining activities: 1- Distributing 1800 ES and NFIs (300 NFIs in Aslem, 600 ES kits in Aslem, 300 NFIs in Bani Qais, 300 ES kits in Bani Qais and 300 NFIs in Hajjah City) and 2- Provision of rental subsidies for 300 HHs in Hajjah City. The ES will be provided for 900 HHs in the targeted districts the ESK will be provided to 900 HHs who are in acute need for such assistance in the targeted areas and who meet the criteria identified and agreed with the cluster where the SDF will procure the needed items based on the standard specifications agreed with the cluster. The SDF will ensure active follow up on delivery timeframes, materials quality and transportation throughout the procurement cycle as well as sufficient warehousing in place and that transportation contracting allows for required flexibility in delivery locations. 
Another life-saving modality is focused on the provision of rental subsidies for 300 vulnerable HHs in Hajjah City to ensure access to a safe shelter for an extended period to ensure a life-sustaining shelter response. To manage these interventions effectively, SDF will determine eligible target groups by an in-depth assessment and agreed criteria and also ensure that the assessment will assess the average rent costs to avoid creating inflation of rent amounts in the targeted locations. In fact, SDF conducted a needs assessment to effectively identify the Shelter and NFI needs in the targeted areas and to enable the SDF team to plan distributions effectively and ensure targeted delivery of results based on identified needs. SDF will undertake a PDM for gathering information on the efficiency of the assistance provided of which it will reinforce accountability, confirming if the ES and NFI items have reached the intended beneficiaries and help assess beneficiary satisfaction with the distribution and the materials received. Prior to this, SDF will set up distribution points where all target groups (men, women, boys and girls) will have equal access to the services and assistance and ensure causing no harm and a priority will be given to the safety and dignity of the targeted HHs. To that end, the SDF will benefit from its strong expertise and experts in running NFIs and ES kits interventions in Sana&apos;a, Amanat Al Asimah, Dhamar, Albaydha and Rada&apos;a governorates provided to the vulnerable IDP households. Furthermore, SDF had signed agreements with Al Kuraimi and Al Amal banks to manage cash transfer, ensuring gender equity and protection mainstreaming among target groups. At last, the foundation will at best seek to coordinate with the Shelter and NFIs and CCCM clusters and relevant local authorities to promote an integrated response in the IDP hosting sites included in the target areas and ensure that gaps and needs are adequately addressed. This can be also achieved through other projects and activities SDF is running in the targeted areas to complement the proposed services with other needed support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ala&apos;a Aldeen Almahdi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>771811156</telephone>
   <email>alaa.almahdi@sdfyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-27">803484.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14746">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-27">803484.4</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304412261">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-03">241045.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304773152">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-27">241045.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304940964">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-05">320013.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Development Foundation</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
