<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/Education/NGO/14640</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Education Services for hard-hit Schools in Bajil District in Al-Hodeidah Governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is in line with the 2nd Allocation Strategy 2019. Basic education services will be delivered to the most affected by the deteriorated economy and humanitarian situations in Al-Hodeidah in Bajil District, which is one of the high priority areas for this humanitarian allocation. Besides, our education project embraces several activities that all aim at fixing the poor humanitarian situation of some governmental schools in Al-Hodeidah. In addition, in response to the strategy&#x2019;s instructions, coordination has been well-established with the Education Cluster who eventually gave the green light to AGF to go ahead in proposing the project.

The intervention targets seven governmental schools in Bajil educating both of the host communities and IDPs in the area. The schools&#x2019; names and areas are as ensues: 14th October Primary School in Al-Sulaimaniah, Al-Fatah Primary School in Deer Dahrah, Al-Fatah High-School in Al-Hejari, Al-Noor High-School in Al-Qomriah, Al-Iaz Bin Abdullslam in Al-Mhadiah, Al-Nser in Deer Al-Qumal, and Al-Tasaheeh High-School in Albbahah. Based on the field investigation and data gotten from the Office of education and the headmasters of the seven schools, it is expected that 5333 students of both genders, boys amp girls, and of both communities, host amp IDPs and 162 teachers , will benefit from this intervention.

Before kicking off any activities, necessary coordination will be maintained with all stakeholders including the governmental authorities at the central level in Sana&apos;a and the local level in Al-Hodeidah by getting all required permits and relevant data. Only then, the project team will start to work in the locations of the project immediately.

The first activity is a construction of 13 semi-permanent classrooms in the seven schools of the seven aforementioned. There will be also rehabilitation of 78 classrooms in all the seven schools. The rehabilitation will include providing the classrooms fans, windows, doors, paint, lights, pens, and whiteboards.

As an indispensable component to complete the activity of rehabilitation and building of classrooms, solar-powered systems will be implemented at the seven schools so fans, lights, and microphones and speakers of the morning assembly and other electric school devices can be operated.

Another activity of pivot importance is the rehabilitation of school fences. Fences will be rehabilitated in two schools with 160 meters long to protect the schools&apos; properties and their classrooms.

Some vital WASH activities will take place in this intervention, as well. 14 latrines will be built in three schools at a ratio of 7 latrines for girls and 7 latrines for boys. Each of the seven schools will be provided by two water tanks per school, i.e. 14 water tanks in all schools. The water tanks will be used for providing the latrines of schools with water. Also, filters will be added to some of those tanks so students can use water to drink.

Teachers will get considerable attention, as well. They will receive monthly allowances of 50$ per teacher for eight months in sequence. Lists of beneficiaries will be verified carefully before the transferring starts. AGF&apos;s project team will make sure that only eligible teachers characterized by being well-committed to attendance and teaching throughout the eight months are those who receive the allowances.

In addition to the above, the teacher at the seven schools will be trained on pedagogy and how to mitigate the psychological effect of conflict on students.

GAM and protection criteria will be applied to all the activities of the project. People of different ages and social statuses of both genders will be made sure to be incorporated in the intervention. Sex- and age-disaggregated data has been collected and analyzed to tailor assistance to the needs and interests of the different gender and age groups this will help in reducing and mitigating gender-based violence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Girls Foundation for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Girls Foundation for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intisar Al-Adhi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chairwomen</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967733277110</telephone>
   <email>allgirls1@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">289813.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">119895.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1110014639">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-25">9467.86</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Girls Foundation for Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14640">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">409708.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Girls Foundation for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304437111/112">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-16">163883.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Girls Foundation for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304957706">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-30">122912.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Girls Foundation for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305098715">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-21">122912.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">All Girls Foundation for Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
