<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/FSAC/INGO/14577</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency livelihoods assistance for crisis affected vulnerable population  in Taiz (Ma&apos;afer and Shamaiteen) and Lahj (Almilah)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will enhance the productive assets, income and livelihoods of most vulnerable 6,100 households or 42,700 individuals (9289 men, 8540 women, 12810 boys, and 12061 girls) in Al Milah district of Lahj Governorate and Ash Shamyateen and Al Maafer Districts of Taiz Governorate. The districts are among the most conflict affected food insecure districts classified in IPC 4 by the 2018 Yemen IPC analysis. The conflict has resulted in the destruction of livelihoods and income of many households in the districts who mainly depend on agricultural activities. FSAC&#x2019;s recent analysis show that there is a critical gap in livelihoods response in all three districts. Only 14590 individuals (6.5%) out of the 2019 FSAC YHRP target of 221760 individuals have so far received livelihoods in the three districts. 

Oxfam&#x2019;s recent rapid needs assessments show that many vulnerable households in the targeted sub-districts of the target districts depend on agricultural livelihoods and lack agricultural support and and income to meet food needs in lean season to restart agricultural activities. Livelihoods and wellbeing deteriorated after conflict due to lack of grazing for animals, drought and the high price of fodder in the market. Income level decline due to fuel scarcity, lack of livelihood opportunities, deprecation of Yemeni Riyal, high prices of commodities and lack of support as many families left their major livelihood. They are relying on different coping strategies as eating less preferred food, borrowing and limiting portion of meal, sell assets. The project proposes cash plus agricultural support (seeds, tools and training) to 5180 highly vulnerable agricultural dependent households at high risk of becoming acutely food insecure. In addition, a total 920 vulnerable household&#x2019;s dependant on income from agriculture labour workforce in Taiz will participate in the Food for Asset (FFA) activities for three months to meet their 80% of the recommended minimum food basket. The FFA will also contribute to rehabilitating community assets needed for agricultural activities and prevention of flood risks in targeted villages.

The beneficiaries targeted for livelihoods will be supported with cash  for a period of 3 month to cover 50% of the minimum food baskets and agricultural inputs (seeds, tools and training). The cash support will be provided during the lean season or onset of agricultural season. The beneficiaries will only qualify for both cash and agricultural inputs support if they prepare their farming fields for planting. Oxfam will collaborate and work with the Ministry of Agriculture use their technical recommendations and standards to design and implement the agricultural support. 
Oxfam&#x2019;s recent monitoring shows that there are functional local markets in the targeted districts for basic commodities and targeted communities usually prefer to receive basic humanitarian assistance in cash rather than in kind. However, Oxfam will conduct a rapid feasibility and market assessment in the target districts to understand agricultural markets and provide support either in kind or in vouchers depending on market situation and target men and women beneficiaries&#x2019; preference. 
Oxfam has been currently operational in all target districts and has a lot of experience and capacity to implement the proposed livelihoods support. Its experience in livelihoods support and good working relationship with local authorities and target communities would help to implement the project with the required level. The implementation process will be supported by a local partner in Taiz, (Coalition of Humanitarian Relief (CHR) In addition, Oxfam will closely work with Social Fund for Development to plan and implement FFA activities on needs basis in designing and implementing FFA. 
Oxfam has systems and procedures for managing potential risks of the project (security, financial, mis use of funds, etc) while implementing the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Rusk</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>739133655</telephone>
   <email>SRusk1@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Khalid Ahmed</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funding Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>737892181</telephone>
   <email>kawadh@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lahj</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.96593663 44.41733354</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-06">1839207.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-06">660792.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14577">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-06">2500000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304487185">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-10">1000000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304919192">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-24">750000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
