<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA1/WASH/NGO/11906</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH Response for the New IDPs in Abs District, Hajja Governorate, Parameter 3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In continuation of ADO&apos;s commitments to those IDPs in their collective sites in Abs district- Hajjah governorate in the field of WASH since the beginning of the displacement in 2015 and so far.
And due to the escalation of war and conflict in the areas adjacent to the Abs district, which continue to generate new waves of displacement from the districts of Hayran, Mustaba, Haradh and Midi, as well as from the area of Abs district adjacent to Hayran district (e.g.Bani Hassan sub-district and others), as well as IDPs from Hodeidah and Sa&apos;ada governorates, And Through this project, ADO committed as usual to response to the Sanitation and Hygiene needs of those new IDPs through the minimum service package of sanitation and Hygiene as first line response which will include : 
1- Construction of 1600 latrines, 
2- Distribution of 1600 basic HKs
3- Train 30 Community volunteers on hygiene promotion
4- Provide hygiene promotion for 1600 IDPs HHs
5- Community led cleaning campaign as a contribution to reduce the potential outbreak diseases. (12810IDPs+ 19470 HCs)

ADO targeting by this project the 15 prioritized IDPs sites in Abs district in close coordination with the proposed health and nutrition interventions. 
Gender and age groups are identified 12810 IDPs(2784 men, 2776 women, 3667 boys and 3583 girls) and 19470 of host communities by  as well as those with special needs (disables), In the construction of latrines, it will be taken into account that these latrines should meet the needs of all gender and age groups and provide adequate protection to women through the safe location and distance and the possibility of closing tightly and safety of using even at nights, and a suitable seating chairs in those latrines would be provided for disabled who can not use the latrines normally, and also ADO always take into account the protection mainstreaming and GBV trends (e.g. dimensions and specifications of those latrines in terms of appropriate height, ventilation and light to make it easy to use for all defecation and personal hygiene purposes).
Women&apos;s needs are also taken into consideration when selecting the type and sizes of HKs provided to those IDPs.
30 members community volunteers will be elected for hygiene promotion messages (50% of them will be women to conduct the Hygiene promotion for women either through house-to-house awareness or through group). Beneficiaries Selection criteria always give priority to Female headed HHs, disabled...etc.
By Integration of  WASH intervention and Health and Nutrition for those IDPs an effective contribution to reduce the famine risks will be ensured.
Since 2015 till now ADO has successfully implemented so many WASH intervention to the IDPs in Hajja and Hodeidah governorates (Abs dist , Al-Hali dist..etc). ADO has experts civil engineers and experienced WASH team including designing, planning, implementation and monitoring, and ADO has the most effective access in those targeted locations of displacement in Abs district.
ADO has contributed to establish an effective coordination mechanism with NAMCHA and working agencies/organization in the field through a weekly coordination meeting that held mostly in ADO abs office and offices of other INGOs in Abs city, through this weekly coordination meeting a full coordination is ensured in addition to ad-hoc meeting once needed, ADO is in continuous coordination with Oxfam and Hodeidah WASH sub-cluster in respect of WASH intervention, and through that coordination ADO committed to fulfill the gap of Sanitation and Hygiene needs for the IDPs in Abs district, a part of the gap have been covered by ADO through the recent ended project implemented in 2018 and funded by YHF, MEAL will be ensured through MEAL department

Conflict Escalating in those targeted sites is the main potential risks and in close coordination with the UNOCHA, NAMCHA and community leaders once a such conflict happen a contingency plan would be put in place</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jameel Alzabidi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programs Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>777093386</telephone>
   <email>jameelalzabidi@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="17">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hajjah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.27488061 43.11225315</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-04">477971.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="1107489448">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-31">846.37</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-11906">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-04">477971.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303924878">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-12">238985.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304171428">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-29">238985.57</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
