<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/WASH/NGO/14608</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing  Water, sanitation and hygiene Services in the most affected IDPs hosting sites  (Alazrakeen&#x2013;Alreqqah -Darwan) in Hamdan district Sana&#x2019;a governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project will be in-lines with HRP Strategies in fulfillment SO2 and WASH cluster Objectives in 1st line , YGUSSWP is proposing a 10 months WASH project to respond to WASH gaps and needs of IDPs in the following  IDPs Sites (Alazrakeen&#x2013;Alreqqah -Dawran) in Hamdan district Sana&#x2019;a GOV .
The project aims to contribute to providing the safe water,sanitation,hygiene services and Provision of adequate and appropriate hygiene items, community engagement for hygiene awareness, and capacity building of community volunteers in the targeted areas.
total of BNFs from the project are 2301 (622 men, 598 women, 552 boys and 529 girls).

The WASH activities include: conducting water quality tests of the water sources to target IDPs sites, providing access to safe and chlorination water to 2301 BNFs by trucking water to safe water point in the IDPs sites , design and construct 48 shared household latrines which are dryable and un prone to floods,  for 1008 beneficiaries (272 men, 262women,242boys and 232girls) this activity will be conducted by cash4work  modality and conducting rehabilitation/desludging 22 latrine for 66 HHs which will be conducted by cash for work modality in Alazrakeen &#x2013; Alreqqah -Dawran IDPs sites, 6 Cleaning campaigns will be implemented in Alazrakeen &#x2013; Alreqqah -Dawran IDPs a team will be assigned to clean the solid waste in the camp and carry out cleaning campaigns on a regular basis and encourage the community to get rid of solid waste, the modality of (CfW) will be conducted , Distribution of consumable hygiene kits for 353 HHs for three times in the project ,Train and building capcity of CHPs and  chlorine tester and chlorine adder ) from the same IDPs sites in hygiene promotion and community engagement approaches , and conducting 90 awareness session on hygiene promotion and community engagement by CHPs. 
The intervention aims to alleviate women amp children&apos;s suffering who are responsible for fetching water used for drinking amp other domestic uses. Women will have more time for taking care of their children amp family members in the time spent fetching water for their HHs. School-age children will have the opportunity to join classes amp get an education instead of spend time fetching water. 
The project also aims to provide protection and safety  for women and girls by providing safe, close latrines,  Considerate the privacy and gender from previous risk that have exposed them to the GBV risk due to Shortage of  latrines  , invalidity and lack of privacy, YGUSSWP will work in participation of women and girls  and people with disabilities participate in the selection of the latrines&apos; location and represent them as community hygiene promotors CHPs and chlorine tester and chlorine adder )
The risks that we may face are 
Bureaucratic impediments interference with humanitarian work 
Increase the number of IDPs and flow of people from other nearby area from IDPs camps  to get hygiene kits  whenever they hear about any organization distribution
YGUSSWP  has faced many similar challenges in the field amp has gathered learnt lessons from previous interventions. YGUSSWP holds the capacity to solve these challenges amp mitigate the risks through proper coordination with all stakeholders and local authorities and NAMCHA also community participation in the project activities  
and Strengths community hygiene promotion to the near areas besides the camps
YGUSSWP is currently working in Sana&#x2019;a governorate in WASH, Shelter, and Protection, so we are familiar with the terrain amp surroundings, amp have a great deal of experience in dealing with the local stakeholders.Our access to Hamdan  is never restricted due to our diligent implementation amp coordination with all stakeholders.We have a team of elite WASH experts in designing amp implementing WASH interventions who will thoroughly contribute to improving the quality of the deliverables.  
YGUSSWP has considered the project activity costs by designing activities link.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen General Union of Sociologists</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen General Union of Sociologists</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Refat Hassan</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head OF YGUSSWP</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>777806007</telephone>
   <email>Yuoswp@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="23">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sana&apos;a</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.12394358 44.78727759</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-27">287601.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14608">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-27">287601.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen General Union of Sociologists</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304415463">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-03">115040.62</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen General Union of Sociologists</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304647659">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-19">86280.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen General Union of Sociologists</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304737276">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-17">86280.47</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen General Union of Sociologists</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
