<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA1/WASH/INGO/11905</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency WASH assistance to famine risk population in Musaymir of Lahaj, As Safra and Monabbih districts of Saada under Parameter 1.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">28,900 most vulnerable individuals at famine risk in Severe Acute Malnutrition (SAM) prevalence community, (20,500 (As Shafra 8,500, Monnabbih 12,000, Sadaa ) amp 8,400 individuals in Musaymir of Lahj) are targeted in this proposition.

The actions proposed under this project seeks to provide improved access to the water supply through fixed-term emergency water trucking, water points, rehabilitation of Water Supply System (WSS), operational support (fuel) to strategic WSS to increase water production, amp spare parts amp training to Water Management Committees (WMC) to sustain the services.. Water quality surveillance will be used to monitor amp evaluate the approaches in safe water chain. Improve Environmental sanitation through the provision of latrines, repair amp desludging, operational support to sanitation systems, environmental cleaning campaign. Community engagement amp hygiene promotion will be enhanced by maintaining trained community health volunteer, provision basic amp consumable kits. To avoid any negative impacts on women amp children, the project will ensure that gender amp protection lenses are mainstreamed throughout the project. Oxfam&#x2019;s gender amp protection staff are well trained amp will conduct training at partner amp field levels, focusing on men, women, boys amp girls within community committee members amp beneficiaries. The project team also will make sure that there is a gender-balanced in the formation of Water Management Committee (WMC) amp Community Health Volunteers (CHVs) amp how each member should be protected amp their rights be respected. Gender participation, role, an economic power relation, social participation, needs prioritization always focused on conducting different assessments including need assessment, baseline, Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM), During Distribution Monitoring (DDM) amp End line survey. During data collection, sex amp disaggregated household data also prioritized in each project analysis purpose. The technical design will also incorporate the protection aspects into account amp all WASH facilities are accessible amp provide security amp protection particularly to women, girls, boys amp people with disability. Hence, four principles of accessibility (easy to reach, easy to enter, easy to move amp easy to use) will be integrated into all WASH technical design. Oxfam through its local NGOs partner (WEDYAN) in Al Musaymir District -Lahj governorate amp Abna Sa&apos;ada Association (ASADSC) in Monabbih of Sa&#x2019;adah governorate while Oxfam will directly implement in As Safra district with integrated humanitarian response to reach 30,500 women, men, boys amp girls in the Integrated Food Security Phase Classifciation (IPC) 4 amp above through water supply, sanitation amp hygiene promotion. Integration of food security will be ensured through the adoption of a nutrition-focused approached by WFP that will be developed in collaboration with nutrition expert institutions such as IMC amp OCHA through their local partner amp district health offices to ensure that targeting of the most vulnerable households. Partners will also closely work with district health offices, Education offices, a general authority of rural water supply (GARWSP) amp Cleaning Fund in the targeted locations. To address the underlying causes of malnutrition, public health promotion (PHP) team of NGO partner will work closely with community health volunteers (CHVs), health workers from district health offices, amp humanitarian partners in the location amp will ensure cross-referral of the identified malnourished cases. Gender would be the key to the proposed intervention amp will be mainstreamed in WASH assistance through WMC amp CHVs pieces of training. Under WASH assistance, the market feasibility assessment will capture the gender roles amp relationships including the barriers experienced by both males amp females.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wedyan - Lahj</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Rusk</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>739133655</telephone>
   <email>srusk1@oxfam.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lahj</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.96593663 44.41733354</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="22">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sa&apos;ada</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>17.25112185 43.50274965</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-25">408165.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-25">585838.07</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="24003458682021">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-07-23">27124.58</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-11905">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-25">994003.93</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303962729">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-02">795203.14</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304913938">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-17">198800.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OXFAM GB</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
