<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/FSAC/NGO/14607</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provide Livelihood support for  highly vulnerable families in  Aldahi district- Hodaidah governorate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the planned period of 12  months (just 9 month would be costed under this grant, and the other 3 month will be non- costed &quot; 2 months for coordination at the beginning and 1 at the end of project  for closing ), and In line  with the FSAC&apos;s objectives to increase access to food for highly vulnerable families across the country, ADO aims to provide Livelihood  support  for 950 (1197 men, 1463 women, 1796 girls, 2194 boy) of highly vulnerable agricultural  dependent families in  Ad Dahi district- Al hudaidah governora through provision  Cash+ and agriculture input.The proposed  activities under this project aim to cover gaps in first-line responses using key approaches and modalities endorsed by the FSAC.
In response to the gap,  and based on  RNA, and rapid Market assessment (report draft attached)  result , ADO planning  to  Provide Livelihood support  to severely food insecure households in  one sub- district (Aljalabah Alolia)  of Ad Dahi district and the activity will be  as following : 
              - distribute Cash+ 950 agriculture kits (cereal kits, and tools) for 950 of highly agriculture  dependent families ( the selection of Livelihood kits based on the beneficiaries preferring,and rain seasonal calendar  ).
              -Conduct baseline for compare at the end of project and  End-line to measure the impact of the project.
              -The Cash+ will distribute  3 Consecutive months to targeted 950 HHs  and will distribute combines with the agriculture  inputs to address the financial barrier  which faced the targeted beneficiaries, and enabling them to meet their immediate needs  before harvest the crops, So The same beneficiaries in targeted sub- district will received Cash+ cereal kits as both to insure the  impact- full  of intervention.
- ADO will be conduct a curate food security assessment at the beginning of project to be as baseline for the  intervention, and measuring impact. The project will implement directly by ADO, ADO has strong presence in Al Hudaidah  and long experience of delivering  this intervention.
- This grant will enable  ADO to expand its humanitarian assistance.
- ADO will insure alignment of planned activities under this project with the concepts of protection and gender mainstreaming while providing humanitarian assistance using very clear and specific mechanisms that could be easily monitored and measured, in addition to demonstrating its &#x2019;accountability towards beneficiaries&#x2019; rights during designing, implementing and evaluating this project through adhering to the AAP framework for respective clusters. 
The management of this project will be carried out by high professional central and field staff who abide by internal code of conduct which is aligned with humanitarian principles.
ADO MEAL unit will fulfill effectively the tasks of MampE as per the designed plan to ensure the timeliness and quality of implementation throughout the project duration using innovative tailored MampE concepts, modalities and tools at the central and field levels including active community engagement( community Livelihood committees) through the tool of feedback mechanism.
ADO identify Some of potential  risks they may face the project are - Lose the harvest season due to delay the project permeation and clearance from Supreme council (SC), ADO established a fit work plan to avoid this high potential risk, and  suggested 3 ms for coordination and this based on the rain seasonal calendar in Adahi district,- Environmental Risks for the agriculture intervention: ADO will manage this by working closely with local Agriculture office, and Use good agricultural practices to limit environmental risk.-Lack Technical Capacity of targeting beneficiaries: This will be mitigated by conducting a TOT training for 20 community Livelihood committee prepare the land&quot;see upload risk amp mitigation Doc&quot;
The financial management of the project will be carried out by financial ampaccounting department at the main offic</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aisha Thawab</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>777448700</telephone>
   <email>aishaaltook@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohannad Al-Mekhlafi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Compliance and risk Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>775555072</telephone>
   <email>malmekhlafi.sanaa@absyemen.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-30">468651.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14607">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-30">468651.98</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304415461">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-07">187460.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
