<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/Education-WASH/INGO/14542</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Education and WASH response for conflict affected population in Hodeidah governorate.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed integrated interventions are in line with YHF Second Standard Allocation Strategy covering priority gaps under the first and second line responses. In addition, the proposed interventions are in line with the prioritized funding gaps of the Education and WASH clusters in Hodeidah. The proposed WASH interventions will improve access to adequate and safe water, sanitation facilities and hygiene information for vulnerable conflict-affected men, women, boys, and girls in Az-zuhra district - Hodeidah governorate. The overall outcome of the project will be that the target beneficiaries living conditions are improved. Under the WASH component, the main gap identified was lack of safe and adequate water plus poor hygiene practices lead to disease outbreak like cholera and dengue fever, thus, the project will focus on rehabilitation of water supply systems including installation of chlorine dosing pump. Provision of latrines and HP activities to enhance good hygiene practices, support in solid waste management activities to ensure clean and safe environment and ultimately to improve the public health in Az-zuhura district. Over 10,000 vulnerable communities and IDPs (2300 men, 2600 women, 2400 boys and 2700 girls) will benefit from this wash project in the community. NRC WASH team will support the education team with technical expertise in addressing WASH needs in schools rehabilitation/construction of latrines. The NRC teams will work together to extend water connections to schools to enable children have access to safe water for drinking and other sanitation purposes to improve the learning environment in schools as per INEE minimum standards for Access and Learnto reach locations where we couldn&#x2019;t reach it with the existing grants. 
Under the Education component (to be implemented in both Az zuhra and As Sukhnah districts), students will be provided with school bags containing notebooks and other essential scholastic materials, while teachers will be provided with teachers&#x2019; kits with basic teaching/learning materials to use in delivering lessons, and recording learner attendance and assessment. Schools will be supported with the construction of Temporary Learning Space (TLS)/classrooms to provide additional learning space to address the challenge of overcrowding that has kept many children out of school in the project locations. WASH facilities in schools will be rehabilitated to improve the hygiene and sanitation of the school environment Schools will be supported to staff the extra classes created (TLSs) and a monthly teacher incentive/allowance to cover transport for volunteer teachers will be paid. Selection criteria for teachers to befit from this will be jointly developed and agreed upon with school and Education NRC will advocate for prioritization of qualified teachers among the IDP population. Teachers&#x2019; capacity will be strengthened through training in Psycho-social support (PSS), to enable them to support children&#x2019;s well-being. Context-appropriate recreational kits for use by children in play will be provided while classrooms will be provided with student desks. Students lacking crucial civil documents will be provided with necessary information on civil documentation and assisted to acquire birth certificates, where necessary for them to get enrolled in school. Lastly, the integrated WASH and Education intervention will enable access to quality protective education for these children by addressing a range of barriers that currently deter enrollment and retention of children in schools in the target locations. Over all 14,496 (7,148 males, 7,348 females) beneficiaries will be reached with the integrated intervention in Az Zahrah district.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Christopher Mzembe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programme</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 736 003 398</telephone>
   <email>christopher.mzembe@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohamed Abdi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 738 401 702</telephone>
   <email>mohamed.abdi@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Timothy Muia</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+967 737 892 545</telephone>
   <email>timothy.muia@nrc.no</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="74" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="26" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">737263.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">365601.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14542">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">1102865.06</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304453155">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-21">882292.05</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian Refugee Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
