<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA1/Nutrition/INGO/11974</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency nutrition community-based assistant to most affected population (SA1 Parameter 12) in 1 district (Qatabah) in Al Dhale&apos;e and 2 districts (Mukha  Dhoubab) in Taiz Governorates.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on 2019 YHF SA1 published to help cover key gaps in the existing operation and support the scale-up of activities in highly vulnerable communities, given priority to high impact projects in districts classified as IPC 4 and above, especially 45 districts with pockets of populations in IPC phase 5 and facing catastrophic conditions
HA has access for most targeted area&#x2019;s prioritized under parameter 1amp2 In particular to identify, prevent and treat malnutrition, HA coordinated with nutrition cluster that endorsed HA to provide emergency nutrition community assistance in 3 of 45 priority districts by supporting 15 HFs, deploy 3 MTs and establish outreach network
The designed project proposed to ensure expanding high nutrition impact in targeted 3 district classified as IPC 4 and above and scaling up nutrition intervention in the targets and IDP hosting sites in Al Mukha district, the project will contribute to objectives identified by nutrition in 1 districts in Adhlee&#x2019;e (Qatabah) and 2 districts in Taiz (Mukha amp Dhoubab), these will be achieved by ensuring adequate nutrition access for 66,105 affected people.
The proposed project will support 12 HFs in Adhlee&#x2019;e -Qatabah district (Al Meqbab HU, Halif HU, Qarourah HU, Shakhab HU, Bit Alneham HU, Alatabat HU, Shalil HU, Azab HU, Alrahbah HU, Rebat Alsalami HU, AlQadam HU, Dhe-Lehas HU) and 2 Mobile team, while 3 HFs will be supported in Taiz-Mukha district (Aljoumah HU, Alzuhari HU, Alkudehah HU) and 1 mobile team will be operated for Mukha and Dhoubab districts.
The proposed intervention will span across
1.	Support 15 HFs to manage CMAM (SAM/MAM) and deploy 3 MTs to provide CMAM treatment for malnutrition.
2.	Establish 15 IYCF corners in HFs with focus on CU5 (Boy Girl) and PLW
3.	Prevent malnutrition by establish nutrition community wide intervention to be a key output for CMAM approach, 100 of CHVs network will be established to prevent most vulnerable group (CU5ampPLW) form becoming malnutrition through conducting ongoing mass screening community mobilization home visit active case finding referral defaulter tracing awareness session, also to ensure community participation through CHVs recruitment, represent different vulnerable beneficiary types and minimize exclusion, gender and take into consideration differences in gender and age requirements
4.	Capacity building for HFs and MTs staff in the 3 targeted districts
5.	ensure solid communication among HFs, MTs and CHVs to enhance complementary intervention
HA confirmed by WFP to receive MAM supplies for proposed project to be used for treatment of CU5 and PLW, WFP will deliver the supplies for HA districts warehouse while HA deliver the supplies to HFs and Mobile team on weekly and monthly bases.
A potential risk might be occurring such insecurity situation, delay in signing the sub agreement with MoPIC, but HA already coordinated with MoPIC and related authorities and got acceptance to operate in targets areas
HA is duly registered in MOPICampNAMCHA. HA actively participates in the relevant coordination for at all levels including Humanitarian Country Team (HCT), Emergency Response Group and in Nutrition, Health, WASH, Shelter and FSL clusters. HA actively participated in the design of HNO and YHRP. At field level,HA coordinates with NGOs implementing similar Health and Nutrition interventions and timely reporting to relevant cluster and authorities, bilaterally or through the clusters, and collaborates with authorities
HA has a program expert&#x2019;s team who already implemented successfully health, nutrition, shelter, FSL projects ..etc  in cooperation with clusters
Proposed project will be implemented by HA itself and will ensure participation of target community particularly women during assessment, implementation and monitoring
HA will maintain effective coordination mechanism with Local authority, NAMCHA, health and nutrition cluster and other actors in the target areas to ensure smooth implmentation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mohammed Radman</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Deputy HoM/Programmes Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967 771887454</telephone>
   <email>mohammed.radman@humanappeal.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="30">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Dhale&apos;e</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.85996808 44.67423913</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="9" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-22">675873.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-22">272949.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-11974">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-22">948822.81</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303965255">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-05-02">379529.12</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="99299.23">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-09">99299.23</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Appeal</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
