<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/Health/NGO/14627</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improvement of Health Care Service for people in four  priority districts (  Hays,   Al Khawkhah, Al Mawasit and AlMasrakh  )in Taiz and Al Hudaydah governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through this project Abs Organization (ADO) will respond to prioritized, assessed, unmet health needs or gaps in primary health service provision, to reduce morbidity and mortality of vulnerable girls, boys, women, and men in the targeted areas. ADO will contribute towards the humanitarian needs outlined in the YHRP, 2019 through a focus on Health Minimum Service Package. The proposed intervention is aligned with Health Cluster Humanitarian Strategy objectives for Yemen 2019.
This project aims to improve access to primary health care services, including consultation, reproductive health, referral of critical cases and building capacity HWs and CHVs. Due to high heath needs, this project will also focus on improving access of quality life&#xAC;saving services to vulnerable women and children, and maintain provision of essential primary health care services by ensuring that 71,915 both IDPs and host community benefit from the following activities in Taiz governorate (Mataran health center in Al Mawaset district, Wateer health center in Al Mesrakh district), and in Al Hudaydah governorate (Al Khukha new health center in Al Khukhah district, Hays rural hospital in Hays district ) where the health system in these health facilities has been damaged and non-functional due to the ongoing conflict. 
All over the proposed project duration 12 months, the proposed Heath activities of this project will be  as follows: 
1-	Rehabilitation will be for 3 health facilities (2 Health Centers and one hospital), and provision of medicines to all 4 HFs, and provide solar system (Wateer HC, Alkawkah HC)
  2- Provision of Primary and Secondary health care (OPD and ER).
  3- Provision of Reproductive health (Antenatal care, Postnatal care and deliveries) services. 
  4- Vaccination for children (EPI).
  5- Referral services (transportation cost) for 150 cases based on identified criteria.
  6- Training HWs: 30 HWs will be selected in coordination with GHO and DHO (12 health workers in Hays hospital, 6 Al Khukha, 6 Al-Misrakh, and 6 Al Mawaset districts) and 25 CHVs.
The project will also maintain ADO&#x2019;s health response capacity to act as &#x201C;First Responders&#x201D; in these area as it has community acceptance that leads to significant access and smooth provisions of project activities. Since 2015, ADO&#x2019;s focus has been delivering health services and emergency responses in most conflict affected areas, responding to population displacement, epidemiological diseases outbreaks and restoring health services to vulnerable communities. This project will enable ADO to continue supporting life-saving, health care services and response activities as well as other disease outbreaks and reduce morbidity and mortality. This project also aims to support the Ministry of Health and other relevant authorities in emergency response capacity, training local male and female health workers to respond to health needs and providing training in consultation, outbreak response, referral cases, deliver health services, reporting systems, and awareness of various health gender needs based on current needs. ADO has coordinated with WHO to provide medication kits for this project, while extra medication that are not included in these kits ADO will procure them through the project cost. 
ADO will ensure alignment of planned activities under this project with the concepts of protection and gender mainstreaming while providing humanitarian assistance. The project through the MEAL team will monitoring and evaluation overseeing implementation process in each area. The MEAL staff will be responsible for supporting the collection, analysis and prepare monthly progress reports that provide a summary of planned activities for month, progress to date and plans for the upcoming month. In addition, team will be using innovative tailored MampE concepts, modalities and tools throughout the project and engage community through the tool of feedback mechanism.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aisha Thawab</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967-777448700</telephone>
   <email>aishaaltook@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Hudaydah</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.00062889 43.04031959</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="15">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taizz</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.39753802 43.68772167</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-24">357235.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14627">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-24">357235.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304412258">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-27">142894.01</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305032999">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-24">164271.32</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abs Development for Women  Children</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
