<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM-19/3420/SA2/Protection/INGO/14721</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated emergency protection response for the most vulnerable conflict-affected people in Lahj  (Mudaraba wa Al-Ara) and Aden (Dar Sa&apos;ad)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS is seeking to sustain 2 community centers established under the 1st standard allocation in 2018: 1 in Dar Sa&#x2019;ad (Aden) and 1 in Ras Al-Ara (Lahj). 
The project will support protection sector coordination in South-Yemen by covering the role of co-coordinator for the Protection sub-cluster in Aden gain a better understanding of critical protection risks and needs, promoting the role of community and survivors/beneficiaries in providing information and analysis for programming and advocacy provide individual case management (ICM) services for PoCs with acute and ongoing protection needs &#x2013; focus on CP, GBV and PwSN provide collective PSS for adults (men and women) and children aimed at enhanced family resilience and community solidarity enhance community based protection mechanisms and community resilience by enrolling community outreach volunteers run livelihoods/skills training that permit the social-economic integration of women/girls at risk and GBV survivors and lastly run awareness raising and information sharing on protection related services and issues. Meanwhile the centers provide also an opportunity for integration of services with other sectors running ad hoc and regularly recurring activities related to for example WASH, health and nutrition and CP.
INTERSOS is looking for 12 months funding, being able to work directly as centers were already established. 
The ICM package comprises: identification, psycho-social first aid (PSFA), psychosocial counseling (PSC), and internal and external referrals for specialized services, in addition to follow-up and case closure). Internal referral within the project for specialize services include: legal assistance, cash for protection and livelihoods. Cash for protection is an integral part of the assistance package for case under ICM, conditional to risk assessment and ensuring that cash assistance will contribute to direct protection outcome. Integration with other sectors is covered: INTERSOS run mobile health and nutrition services under DG ECHO funding, and the mobile team is visiting weekly the CC while for Ras Al-Ara INTERSOS is exploring complementary services for HampN via WHO funding (INTERSOS) and/or IOM.
INTERSOS ensures outreach through a network of community outreach volunteers (COVs) supporting the protection staff at the CC with identification, referral, follow-up and community engagement (bridge between community and centers). While the project will not include protection monitoring, as this is covered under UNHCR programming in the targeted governorates and the 2 actions complement each other, but the team will monthly conduct a few FGDs to zoom in on some protection trends and permit more in-depth analysis, in addition to permitting rapid protection assessments (RPA) where needed. However, overall the outreach is in function of service delivery.
Also, protection related trends and issues will be reported by COVs to activity coordinators and the verification and information collection will be done by protection monitors working under UNHCR grant. During the past year &#x2013; while implementing previous project &#x2013; INTERSOS developed excellent relations with local stakeholders, demonstrated its ability to deliver, with effective access and presence in the targeted area and long-term experience in the protection sector, in particular for integrated individual case management (since 2008 in Yemen) and community center modality.
Finally, to complete INTERSOS wishes to include in the project the continuation of the protection cluster co-coordinator positions coverage. 
The approximate budget that INTERSOS is looking for is just below 1 million US$, for 9,456 direct beneficiaries (without double counting) for an estimate of 70% IDPs and 30% HC, and 24% men, 46% women and 15% boys and 15% girls.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evelyn Lernout</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>00967 (0) 715 555 001</telephone>
   <email>yemen@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="24">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aden</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.84865928 45.00201169</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lahj</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.96593663 44.41733354</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">999996.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304756917">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-10-01">23532.86</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="YEM64-14721">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">999996.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304437100/101">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-16">799996.88</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304756917-918">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-10-09">199999.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-YEM64-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
