<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-693</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reconstruction and Development Assistance to Afghanistan - DACAAR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the programme is to contribute to equitable and sustainable livelihoods of rural Afghans with particular emphasis on vulnerable groups. The main target group is internally displaced people, returnees and vulnerable rural host communities. Special focus is given to female-headed households.

The current programme phase (2014-2016) focuses on activities in 4 thematic areas: Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH), Natural Resource Management (NRM), Small Scale Enterprise Development (SSED) and Women&#xBF;s Empowerment (WE).

For WASH, the objective is to improve capacity of stakeholders in the WASH sector. Main activities include training of 330 individuals of government, NGOs, the private sector and other stakeholders in WASH. Other activities include awareness-raising, action research, national learning exchanges and ground water surveys.

With NRM, the objective is to improve livelihoods though management of natural resources. Main activities include provision of inputs and practical training of 1,440 for increased agricultural production and of 520 community members for livestock, poultry and honey production. Other activities include construction of irrigation structures, mobilisation of communities and analysis of disaster risks.

SSED aims to improve income and livelihoods on a sustainable basis. Activities include technical training of 140 producer association members and training of 140 producer association members in business plan development, marketing and enterprise procurement, accounts and bookkeeping;and providing vocational skills training to another 72 vulnerable persons.

For WE, the objective is improved life quality, social and political influence and respect for women&#xBF;s rights. Activities include establishment of 4 Women Resource Centres (WRCs), support to 11 existing WRCs, mobilization of 2,000 women to become members of WRCs and mobilization of 90 local communities on general understanding of WE issues.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.N.336.b.1.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1996-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="16050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid for basic social services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-15789" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-16593" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-22261" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-24810" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-25551" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-2643" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-3138" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-693-686" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
