<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285822</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Sector Cooperation on Food Safety Between Denmark and Mexico Phase I.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Sector Cooperation on Food Safety is a peer-to-peer cooperation  between the Danish Veterinary and Food Administration and the Mexican National Agro-Alimentary Health, Safety and Quality Service. The cooperation will strengthen animal and public health, food safety and improve prevention of African Swine Fever and Antimicrobial Resistance.

A Strategic Sector Cooperation (SSC) is a partnership aiming at improving sector framework conditions in a partner country. The initiative is a flexible and adaptive instrument for exchanging experiences, learning and capacity building, which builds on a consolidated strong relationship and trust between the involved authorities. The commitment to finance the Danish authorities&#x2019; participation is sequenced in phas-es; an inception phase of approximately one year resulting in a project document; followed by phase one, two and &#x2013;if need be &#x2013; a phase three during which the cooperation is deepened and developed. All SSC partnerships are supported by a sector advisor at the embassy, who impel progress and stir the partnership in the direction agreed upon.

Annually, the SSC projects deliver a report on project progress and results achieved. Progress on selected outputs are displayed in openaid.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Strategic Sector Cooperation on Food aims to strengthen animal health, food safety, and public health including through improving the preparedness of the veterinary services in the handling of exotic diseases in Mexico through:

-Strengthened surveillance, improved capacity to develop and maintain contingency plans, improved diagnosis and handling of outbreaks;
-Sustainable and responsible use of veterinary medicine, including antibiotics including a first draft of a national plan to combat AMR;
-Improved traceability systems, updated meat and hygiene provisions, and strengthened monitoring of toxic contaminants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2018 - 14792</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000116</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285822-34362" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
