<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286740</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">#TogetherWeCanEndTorture IRCT 2022-24</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IRCT Strategy 2022 - 2024 - #TogetherWeCanEndTorture

Rehabilitation of torture survivors, documenting and investigating torture and ensuring that traumatised survivors can effectively participate in legal processes that concern their torture experience and speak up against torture.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1 - Healing: Torture Survivors receive the best possible support to rebuild their lives and have more space to make their voices heard:
&#x2022;	IRCT member capacity improved to provide rehabilitation through use of Global Rehabilitation Standards to over 50,000 torture survivors, of whom at least 50% are women, annually worldwide;
&#x2022;	Survivors&#x2019; rehabilitation improved through IRCT members integrating livelihood support into rehabilitation;
&#x2022;	Survivor agency improved through IRCT members engaging survivors through provision of safe and inclusive spaces.

Outcome 2 - Justice: States improve their laws, policies and practice on justice, reparation, and prevention of torture:
&#x2022;	IRCT forensic evidence and expert opinions contribute to increased State accountability and justice for survivors through public exposure of violations, strategic litigation, public advocacy;
&#x2022;	Global, regional, and national anti-torture laws, policies and mechanisms are improved based on IRCT advocacy;
&#x2022;	Civil society actors and state institutions have capacity, tools and resources to be effective and influential in the fight against torture;
&#x2022;	IRCT is a strong and ethical organisation in the anti-torture ecosystem.

Justification for support:
&#x2022;	The fight against torture is an important part of Denmark&#x2019;s efforts to protect and promote human rights as well as a priority in the new Development Cooperation Strategy;
&#x2022;	Torture is still practised in more than 100 countries and its impact is felt in every place there is a survivor. IRCT&#x2019;s members have a unique knowledge of rehabilitation gained through decades of clinical practice and human rights advocacy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2022 - 697</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2022000034</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286740-35501" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
