<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285125</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2019 &#x2013; Promoting Economic Growth and Nutrition through Fruit Processing in Ethiopia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">High-quality jobs and income opportunities created in production, processing, distribution, and sales of dried fruit products; income boosted; and at-risk populations have access to safe, nutritious and affordable snacks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">High-quality jobs and income opportunities created in production, processing, distribution, and sales of dried fruit products; income boosted; and at-risk populations have access to safe, nutritious and affordable snacks.
This project is implemented by the partnership consortium led by GAIN and Arla Food Ingredients, with Addis Ababa University, Africa Juice Tibilia, Confederation of Danish industry, Raya Horti Farm, Selam Tsehay Roschli Industrial &amp;  Agricultural Engineering and Theday Agro Industry. The project aims to unleash the potential of Ethiopia&#x2019;s papaya value chain by developing, testing and demonstrating a model for a new value chain for fruit processing. The project will create decent jobs and income generating opportunities for smallholder farmers, skilled and semi-skilled workers in processing, distribution and retail. This will be achieved by developing sustainable business models that include environmentally-friendly processing techniques. This project will help to reduce post-harvest losses and produce an innovative, high value-add, nutritious and affordable snack, thereby contributing to healthier, more diverse diets. Curricula for vocational training of skilled and semi-skilled workers will be developed and made available through training of trainers at public and private institutions.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and you</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019-30702</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019001179</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285125-34023" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
