<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286366</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Formulation Mission, including light touch review on existing program, The Danish Gulf of Guinea Maritime Security Program phase 3, 2022-2026 - Ghana</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of the LTR is to assess the progress of the ongoing engagements under the Gulf of Guinea maritime security program ongoing phase II. The LTR will gather lessons learned including factors, which enhanced or hindered the implementation of project activities and gauge progress made towards the achievement of outcomes in the context of the Danish maritime security engagements in the Gulf of Guinea. The LTR will also assess good practices and the ability of implementing partners to deliver on project results and adapt to changes during project implementation. Finally, the LTR will provide recommendations, which in return will inform the formulation of the Maritime Security Program phase III, 2022-2026.
The purpose of the Formulation is for the Consultant to conduct a formulation mission to the region, physical or virtual pending the development of the Covid-19 pandemic. The final product is the development of a Project Document (PD) detailing the broader Gulf of Guinea maritime security framework, including Peace and Stabilisation Engagement Documents (PSED&#x2019;s) for each of the engagements under the Danish Gulf of Guinea Maritime Security Program phase III, 2022-2026. The PD, PSED&#x2019;s and relevant annexes are to be quality assured by the MFA program committee and undergo a follow-up MFA technical appraisal. Finally, they will be approved by the Steering Committee for the Danish Peace and Stabilisation Fund in Q4 of 2021.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 - 4012</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021000124</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="15210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Security system management and reform</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286366-35027" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
