<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286115</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Covid-19 III hj&#xE6;lpepakke - kapitalindskud til IFU til investering i African Guarantee Fund</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Micro, small and medium enterprises (MSME) form the backbone of most African economies in terms of innovation, entrepreneurship, job creation and contribution to GDP, but the potential of the sector is severely constraint by inadequate access to finance. In 2019 the International Finance Corporation (IFC) estimated that more than half of the estimated 44 million African formal MSMEs lack the required finance to operate and grow their business. The Covid-19 crises is expected to further challenge the MSME sector, because the MSME have limited liquid assets to withstand declining economic activities and will quickly face a credit crunch as local banks tighten credit conditions. The African Guarantee Fund (AF) would be an optimal institution to support to mitigate the negative impact of the Covid-19 crises for banks financing the SME sector. AGF has a broad regional outreach and operate with more than 160 financial institutions involved in SME lending in 37 African economies.


In 2016 AGF developed a special Green Guarantee Facility in cooperation with NDF in order to promote green investments, demonstrate results and develop markets. An additional NDF capital contribution for this purpose was provided in 2018. Preliminary experience with the Green Guarantee activities is also promising. Green guarantees, which already constitutes 11% of the entire guarantee portfolio, have mainly been allocated to SME investments in off-grid solar energy (mainly roof top) and hydro power. More than 175,000 households have been connected with clean energy, and a significant reduction in greenhouse gas emission has been obtained. IFU will complement the capital contribution of DKK 60 mio. with own funds and totally invest USD 20 mio. in AGF.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The immediate objectives of the capital contribution are:
Stabilisation and recovery of SMEs and PFIs in Africa following the Covid-19 crises, and scaling market penetration of AGF&#x2019;s green guarantees to promote SME-led green investments across Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 11635</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000319</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="240" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Banking &amp; Financial Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286115-34670" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
