<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skills development, social dialogue and decent jobs for young Tanzanians</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of the DE is to contribute to the development of employable young people with vocational skills and decent jobs in Tanzania.

The long-term systematic change to be realized through the DE interventions is more employable young people with vocational skills and decent jobs from a more flexible and responsive TVET system that addresses demands of a dynamic labour market. As a result hereof, Tanzanian industries and value chains will gain improved access to the technological know-how and skills required in the labour market. Specifically, the DE intends to bring about more skilled, reskilled and upskilled workers with mechanical and electrical competencies to address the demands from , regional and local markets for sustainable (and green) solutions, primarily within the agro-industry. A key achievement will be that social partners play a central role in promoting demand-driven TVET with apprenticeships in companies and dual theory/practice learning in TVET institutions. The objective of the DE will be achieved through three outcomes: 

1) Improved demand-driven TVET system with social partners promoting TVET training that accommodate current and future skills needed, 

2) Companies and workers contribute to a modernized learning environment in agro-industries with flexible work-based learning (for apprentices and teachers), and 

3) Skilled young people and workers are competent with mechanical and electrical skills in demand by private agro-companies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286160-34735" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
