<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286109</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2020 &#x2013; Safe Water for All: A new partnership for growth in Bangladesh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">60% of people in Bangladesh do not have access to safe drinking water. Around 35 million people live in coastal districts where drinking water is heavily contaminated and industrial pollution also affects the populations in the industrial areas around Dhaka. As the access to water is controlled and can be expensive, there is an overall high demand for affordable safe water. The Covid-19 pandemic has furthermore impacted jobs and livelihoods in Bangladesh, in particular short-term employment in the informal sector. At the height of the pandemic in 2020, 72% of the people were unemployed.
The Safe Water for All project, involving a partnership between BRAC,  Grundfos, and Hydro Industries Ltd., aims to create a commercially viable business model for cleaning industrial effluent and to ensure safe drinking water in Bangladesh. This dual aim will be achieved through the installation of Water Treatment Plants and Effluent Treatment Plants, both of which will work towards SDG 8 by creating jobs in the water sector.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and youth. Outcome 2: Increased income opportunities from improved market linkages. Outcome 3: Additional capital raised (investment leverage).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project&#x2019;s development objective is to create inclusive and sustainable economic growth, increased income through improved and new jobs in water treatment and distribution (SDGs 1 and 8), and to increase access to safe and affordable drinking water for people in Bangladesh (SDG6) - supporting with economic recovery from Covid-19. The business objective is for Hydro and Grundfos to enter &amp; scale the Bangladesh safe water market and create a commercially viable business partnership model (SDG9) for cleaning industrial effluent (SDG12), reducing harmful impacts of effluent on people (SD3), providing safe drinking water (SDG6), and creating jobs (SDG8).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 42136</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000467</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water supply and sanitation - large systems</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286109-34727" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
