<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286106</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2020 - Solidaridad, Nigeria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aquaculture Development Project, Nigeria. (ADPN)

The ADPN aims to create sustainable business in the aquaculture value chain for smallholder fish farmers especially for women and youth in Ijebu Ode, Ogun State, Southwest Nigeria. The project will achieve this through capacity building on aquaculture Best Management Practices (BMP), modern fish farming techniques and education for improved output while reducing pollution along the value chain. The ADPN also will develop an online education, trading and farm management platform to provide easy access to education, BMP, access to an open and transparent market, and a tailor-made farm management software for easy operations, monitoring and decision making. The intervention would lead to creating decent/green jobs as well as creating
opportunities for economic growth and empowerment for this target group.
SDG 8: &#x2018;Decent work and economic growth&#x2019; Our physical education and training (E&amp;T) programs will improve the skills of smallholder fish farmers in Ogun State, thereby improving production capacity and income potential. We expect the outcome of this E&amp;T will create new jobs opportunities for at least 5000 people in the local community. The project would directly target 1,300 fish farmers; 1,700 farm workers and 2,760 indirect workers in the Ijebu-Ode community and further reach out to +50.000 indirect beneficiaries through the e-learning platform. It is designed in PPP model to ensure the long term sustainability of the Project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31381" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fishery education/training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286106-34759" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
