<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285955</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DKI / DUF - Ungdomshus i Kyiv, Ukraine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development goal is to establish a Ukrainian-Danish youth house with sustainable democratic structures and values as well as youth representation in order to support democratic youth organisations and youth participation in society and to strengthen relations between youth in Ukraine and Denmark.
With the Ukrainian-Danish Youth House (hereinafter, the House) we envision a user-driven hub for democratic activism. The House will serve as a democratic and inclusive framework, where a diversity of youth organisations and young women and men can practice democracy and youth influence. The House will support youth partnerships by building capacity to promote youth rights, giving skills to organise democratically and actively participate in society. Accordingly, we will develop a House, which may host central activities itself, focused on capacity building of its user groups, strengthening youth participation and being a channel for the exchange of young Danish and Ukrainian women and men. The house will be fitted4 and developed to meet these aims as well as to be an open platform for its users, both formal and informal youth groups, to conduct activities for democratic change and strengthened youth participation in Ukraine.
Thus, this project is contributing to the purpose of the youth pool of the Danish Neighbourhood Programme by supporting cooperation between Ukrainian and Danish youth and promoting active participation</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 17736</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000182</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285955-34457" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
