<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286099</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 15th replenishment of the African Development Fund</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The African Development Bank Group&#x2019;s independent evaluation unit publishes its &#x2018;Annual Development Effectiveness Review&#x2019; (ADER) on an annual basis. The review assesses Bank performance against targets in the Bank&#x2019;s result measurement framework. The &#x2018;Strategy for Denmark&#x2019;s Engagement with the African Development Bank 2020-2024&#x2019; sets out the most relevant indicators in relation to Danish priorities, cf. below. 
Based on the Bank&#x2019;s ADER 2021, measured against corresponding results from ADER 2020, the following results can be reported in relation to select Danish priorities* &#x2013; both for all African countries and for ADF (African Development Fund) countries only.

&#x2022;	DK priority climate change and green growth: Improvements over baseline regarding &#x2018;access to electricity&#x2019; as well as &#x2018;installed renewable capacity&#x2019; (cf. Table 1 in ADER 2021), while &#x2018;Access to safely managed drinking water services&#x2019; deteriorated (cf. Table 9 in ADER 2021 and ADER 2020).
Compared to 2019, where 54 percent of the population in all African countries had &#x2018;access to electricity&#x2019;, the score in 2020 remained the same at 54 percent. Meanwhile, access to electricity in ADF countries increased from 37 percent in 2019 to 42 percent in 2020. 
&#x2018;Installed renewable capacity&#x2019; increased from 43 GW in 2019 to 46 GW in 2020, and from 23 GW to 24GW in ADF countries. 
&#x2018;Access to safely managed drinking water services&#x2019; has deteriorated from a baseline of 72, and remained at 66 percent both in 2019 and 2020 in all African countries, and at 56 percent both in 2019 and 2020 in ADF countries. 

&#x2022;	DK priority inclusive development and job creation for youth: Improvements over baseline and vis-&#xE0;-vis 2019 regarding &#x2018;population living below the poverty line&#x2019;, while &#x2018;youth unemployment rate&#x2019; remained stable and the corresponding rate for &#x2018;young women&#x2019; deteriorated (cf. Table 9 in ADER 2021 and Table 9 in ADER 2020). 
&#x2018;Population living below the poverty line&#x2019; decreased from 40 percent in 2019 to 34 percent in 2020 in all A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The African Development Fund is the Bank Group&#x2019;s provider of concessional lending and grant financing. The ADF contributes to poverty reduction and economic and social sustainable development by financing projects and reforms and providing technical assistance and capacity building in low-income African countries that are not eligible to borrow from the AfDB. 

The 15th replenishment of the ADF (2020-2022)  will focus on two strategic pillars: the first is to develop quality and sustainable infrastructure that provides impetus for job-creating private sector investments, and which promotes sustainable development. The second is on human, governance and institutional capacity development to enable people to participate in, and benefit from, job creation opportunities for inclusive growth. The two pillars will be anchored around the crosscutting themes of gender, climate change, governance and private sector development to foster inclusive growth and strengthen resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 - 11357</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000347</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multilateral Cooperation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>MUS@um.dk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Asiatisk Plads 2, 1448 K&#xF8;benhavn K, Denmark</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286099-34657" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
