<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286083</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Telling the Real Story Information Campaign</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective of the information campaign is two-fold; a) Awareness raising activities in the Horn of Africa and Sudan on the risks of onward irregular movement and, b) Provide information on available services in countries of first asylum and opportunities for regular movement, when available.

With support of the Government of Denmark the project&#x2019;s core awareness raising activities can:
&#x2022;	Continue providing truthful and trustworthy testimonials by members of the diaspora in Europe and elsewhere, as this proved to be the most powerful tool to maintain and reinforce a critical intra-community discourse on the dangers of &#x201C;Tahriib&#x201D; (i.e. the journey to Europe);
&#x2022;	Widen and deepen the direct involvement of the community and refugee members by actively bringing on board teams of refugee volunteers, who will engage directly with the target populations and see to the sustainability of the project;
&#x2022;	Keep reframing the narrative on life in Europe, debunking myths and providing trustworthy information on entitlements to protection and of the economic and social realities of everyday life in close cooperation with the respective diaspora, including in Denmark;
&#x2022;	Counter the narrative of smugglers and traffickers, expose their methods and undermine their credibility;
&#x2022;	Provide information on complementary pathways should they be made available in the countries of first asylum; and
&#x2022;	Continue to promote intra-community dialogue on risks and opportunities.

UNHCR launched the awareness raising campaign, Telling the Real Story (TRS) , in 2015, as part of a multi-country initiative aimed at providing truthful and trustworthy information to refugees and other persons of concern in mixed flows. The purpose was to empower target audiences (asylum-seekers, refugees and other people on the move) to make informed decisions about their future, their immediate courses of action, and the risks associated with their choices; decisions based on facts rather than on smugglers&#x2019; and traf</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15190" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitation of orderly, safe, regular and responsible migration and mobility</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286083-34637" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of refugees, asylum seekers and persons of concern engaged through awareness raising activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of refugees, asylum seelers and persons of concern engaged through awareness raising activities. 

Baseline: May 2020: 81,050 refugees and persons of concern reached in outreach activities
11 million reached through social media.

Target: Dec 2021: 125,350 refugees and persons of concern reached through outreach activities
12 million reached through social media.</narrative>
   </description>
   <reference code="269069" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of refugees, asylum seekers and persons of concern engaged through awareness raising activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of refugees, asylum seelers and persons of concern engaged through awareness raising activities. 

Baseline: May 2020: 81,050 refugees and persons of concern reached in outreach activities
11 million reached through social media.

Target: Dec 2021: 125,350 refugees and persons of concern reached through outreach activities
12 million reached through social media.</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
