<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286099</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 15th replenishment of the African Development Fund</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADF-15 will focus on two strategic pillars: the first is to develop quality and sustainable infrastructure that provides impetus for job-creating private sector investments, and which promotes sustainable development. The second is on human, governance and institutional capacity development to enable people to participate in, and benefit from, job creation opportunities for inclusive growth. The two pillars will be anchored around the crosscutting themes of gender, climate change, governance and private sector development to foster inclusive growth and strengthen resilience. The ADF contributes to the realization of all the 17 SDGs. In view of the ADF comparative advantages in the multilateral development architecture, Denmark considers the following six SDG&#x2019;s particularly pertinent for the ADF during the coming strategy period: 1. No poverty; 6. Clean water; 7. Sustainable energy; 8. Decent jobs and economic growth; 10. Reduced inequalities; 13. Climate Action</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The African Development Fund is the Bank Group&#x2019;s provider of concessional lending and grant financing. The ADF contributes to poverty reduction and economic and social sustainable development by financing projects and reforms and providing technical assistance and capacity building in low-income African countries that are not eligible to borrow from the AfDB. 

The 15th replenishment of the ADF (2020-2022)  will focus on two strategic pillars: the first is to develop quality and sustainable infrastructure that provides impetus for job-creating private sector investments, and which promotes sustainable development. The second is on human, governance and institutional capacity development to enable people to participate in, and benefit from, job creation opportunities for inclusive growth. The two pillars will be anchored around the crosscutting themes of gender, climate change, governance and private sector development to foster inclusive growth and strengthen resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 - 11357</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000347</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286099-34657" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
