<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285143</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2019 &#x2013; Solar cooling for reduced food loss, job and income opportunities among smallholders in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is estimated that one-third of Kenya&#x2019;s post-harvest seafood is lost before it can be sold and safely consumed with loss of income for small-scale fishers as a consequence. Two obstacles must be overcome to solve this problem: First, many small-scale fishers are unbanked and do not have access to credit to invest in cold storage equipment. Secondly, only 30% of the Kenyan population have access to reliable electricity. Thus, the Solar for Cooling project, led by the partnership between WWF, X-Solar and WWF Kenya, aims to close the gap between off-grid energy and small-scale fishers&#x2019; need for refrigeration solutions. This is done by bringing together partners who can provide energy-efficient, environmentally friendly and tailored solar refrigeration systems.
In close collaboration, these commercial partners will expand the supply chain for off-grid energy and refrigeration in coastal Kenya. By expanding these supply chains, and by maturing the market demand and building capacity of small-scale fishers, the project will help to unleash the economic potential of small-scale fishing. This will contribute to the development objective which is to stimulate sustainable economic growth in selected coastal regions of Kenya. Expected key results include a reduction in post-catch losses and an increased average price for fish with higher revenue for small-scale fishers as result.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting:</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To stimulate sustainable economic growth in selected coastal regions of Kenya</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019-30904</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019001184</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285143-34029" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
