<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285140</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2019 &#x2013; Creating a Sustainable Circular Economy for Plastic Waste in Vietnam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recycling Plastic waste is a profitable and equitable venture for everyone involved</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The long-term vision for this project is to cultivate plastic waste recycling as a profitable venture for everyone involved in the value chain&#x2014;particularly for local waste collectors and small recycling business owners&#x2014;while reducing the flow of plastic waste into natural environments in coastal cities of Vietnam.
iDE is uniquely situated to lead the pursuit of this vision as the implementing partner in this project. iDE has pioneered market-based development and inclusive market ecosystem creation for over 30 years with deep experience in human centered design, supply chain strengthening, and product and service-delivery innovation. To complement our strengths, iDE has assembled a team of two commercial partners that share our vision and are ready to pursue it, including: (1) Oceanworks is our international commercial partner and it is a US-based company that hosts a platform built to drive recycled plastic offtake and reduce demand for new virgin plastic. Their expansive and growing range of recycled resins, textiles, and products from committed independent suppliers is sold to brands and manufacturers globally. (2) Evergreen Social Ventures is our local commercial partner and is a technology provider for low-grade plastic processing and production of materials and products made from recycled low-grade plastic.
By strengthening a sustainable and desirable market for recycled plastic, the project will help to ensure that informal waste collectors and their families have long-lasting livelihood improvements and that ocean-bound plastic will become obsolete.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme leve</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019-30665</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019001183</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business &amp; Other Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285140-34028" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
