<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286379</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine-Denmark Energy Partnership Programme (UDEPP, 2021-2026)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme focuses on reducing CO2 emissions by developing long-term energy planning through annual Ukraine Energy Outlooks and on strengthening Ukraine&apos;s energy efficiency and district heating by utilizing surplus heat and by modernizing its district heating network. The Ukraine Energy Outlook will provide guidance on how Ukraine can achieve its climate goals of carbon neutrality by 2050 and phase out of coal by 2040.

The Danish Energy Agency is implementing partner and will continue its close partnership with the Ministry of Energy of Ukraine (developed during the previous phase) and start cooperation with a new partner, the Ministry for Communities and Territories Development, within the area of district heating. This follows a great Ukrainian interest in the Danish district heating system. 

Energy experts from the Danish Energy Agency will contribute with advice, technical assistance and peer-to-peer learning in several areas. This includes energy efficiency in industry, strategic energy planning and long-term modelling of scenarios that can show pathways to a green transformation of Ukraine&apos;s energy system with focus on renewable energy and energy efficiency. 

The collaboration will focus on strengthening the environment for sustainable energy solutions and technologies based on Danish expertise and technical assistance, as well as opening up opportunities for companies working with green energy. 

The overall goal of the support is: &#x201C;Ukraine realizes its Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) goals and achieves SDG7 and SDG13 targets&#x201D;.

The intended impact is: &#x201C;Reduced greenhouse gas emissions and improved security of supply, though improved system planning, market development and increased sustainable energy and district heating modernization&#x201D;.

The objective is that: &#x201C;The enabling environment for investment in sustainable energy and district heating is strengthened, assisting Ukraine in achieving its energy efficiency, renewable energy, a</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 24972</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021000163</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="231" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy Policy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286379-35075" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
