<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-285988</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sekundering af S&#xF8;ren Liborius SL til EEAS Stratcom</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The seconded national expert will, in co-operation with the Stratcom team, support EUs external policies by;

- Support Eastern Neighbourhood partner countries in developing their capacities and policy frameworks on disinformation and foreign manipulative interference;

- Work closely with especially Ukraine and Georgia on their efforts to increase resilience and capabilities;

- Support an enabling environment for other external policies and programmes of the Union in close collaboration with the Commission, notably Support Group Ukraine

- Contribute to the EU&#x2019;s proactive communications in the Eastern Neighbourhood through engagement with relevant media actors, e.g. Russian language media in Ukraine.

- Contribute to supporting media in the Eastern Neighbourhood through developing and maintaining existing networks of journalists and media-related NGOs; Ref. Ares(2020)1816035 - 30/03/2020

- Contribute to the further development of the EUvsDisinfo online products with analysis of media narratives in relations to conflicts, political trends and the foreign policy agenda in Ukraine and other Eastern Partnership countries;

- Raise awareness of disinformation as well as the wider media situation in the Eastern Neighbourhood through, i.a., appearing on expert panels, giving background briefs to journalists and speaking in public at related research and awareness raising events;

- Liaise with relevant colleagues in delegations, other EU institutions, Member States as well as international organisations, such as NATO and OSCE;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-285988-34511" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
