<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286112</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2020 &#x2013; Fair Recycling: an inclusive and formalised plastic recycling ecosystem in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the major challenges in Kenya&#x2019;s waste and recycling sector is that the urban waste is either not collected and recycled at all, or it is collected by waste pickers who are perceived as outcasts and live in poverty, under poor working conditions, without any options to escape. At the same time, the 500.000 registered refugees, hosted by Kenya, generally face substantial barriers to access employment opportunities. The low income of waste pickers and the plastic waste challenge in areas hosting refugees are closely connected. Both are a result of low-value chain efficiency, limited value addition and a lack of formal organisation.
The Danish Refugee Council (DRC), in partnership with Unilever and Mr Green, aim to integrate informal and marginalised waste pickers and refugees in Kenya, to a formalised plastics recycling value chain. By implementing innovative and financially sustainable impact-interventions in the value chain, the &#x201C;Fair Recycling&#x201D; project will contribute to safer working conditions, increased income and decent jobs, and drive the tranisition to a localised circular plastic economy.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: Increased employment (decent jobs) for women, men and youth. Outcome 2: Increased income opportunities from improved market linkages. Outcome 3: Additional capital raised (investment leverage).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the project is to improve the lives of waste pickers in Kenya and reduce the country&#x2019;s environmental challenges with respect to plastic waste in a financially sustainable way.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 42139</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000464</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waste management/disposal</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="140" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Supply &amp; Sanitation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286112-34724" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
