<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-284188</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to C40 Business Plan 2020-2024</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accelerating climate action in large cities in developing countries</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through a strategic partnership with C40, Denmark can lend relevant expertise from local presence and decades of working on the ground in developing and transition countries while C40 can share expertise from longstanding collaboration with and across cities. This exchange has already proven valuable during the formulation process of the present programme, which coincided with key milestones in the preparation of the C40 Business Plan 2021-2024 . The MFA helped advance C40 thinking in particular with respect to adaptation and resilience, results framework and monitoring, systematic approach to ODA traceability in budget, spend and accounts, and models for delivery of technical support at large scale for accelerated implementation in cities in developing countries. The Danish grant aims to support C40 in the accelerated implementation and close collaboration is foreseen throughout the implementation of the business plan, through e.g. active engagement of relevant Danish embassies, secondment at senior technical level, and continued strategic dialogue.
The focus will be on C40 member cities in the global South in low income and lower middle-income countries in Africa and Asia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-284188-33934" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-284188-34127" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-284188-34467" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Action by C40 cities leads to increased resilience through tackling climate emergency and a green transition, including recovery from the COVID-19 crisis, and is also an opportunity to improve the lives and prospects of everyone, everywhere.</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="271056" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
