<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286202</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to AmplifyChange 2021-23 - Strengthening Civil Society Advocacy for SRHR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AmplifyChange is a civil society support mechanism for strengthening voices for sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) in developing countries. Improvement of sexual and reproductive health and rights for women, and girls and marginalised groups is a key focus. AmplifyChange mandate as set out in its Articles of Association, limits its operations to support to civil society in &#x2019;ODA-eligible&#x2019; countries. AmplifyChange operates a challenge funds for financial support to civil society in developing countries, provides technical assistance for organisational strengthening to recipient of funds, and is a knowledge hub for SRHR-advocacy. 

Denmark played a key role together with the Netherlands and Packard Foundation in establishing the multi-donor SRHR fund, which was launched in 2014 as AmplifyChange. The fund was established as a response to an identified gap in funding of civil society&#x2019;s work on advancing SRHR, in particular organisations in developing countries, a funding gap, which was identified by a Danish review in 2012 and later reconfirmed in a review by the Netherlands. 

AmplifyChange is a well-known advocate for improved policy and action on the most neglected SRHR issues. It is a unique entity being a challenge fund with its focus on advocacy for SRHR through support to civil society in developing countries, having a specific focus on &#x2018;hard to reach&#x2019; areas, and with a capacity to manage a large number of grantees. AmplifyChange has a good track-record in reaching &#x2018;hard to fund&#x2019; areas (geographically as well as subject wise). Its inclusive approach and capacity building activities has ensured support for a diverse range of civil society groups, including those who have never previously received support for their SRHR advocacy efforts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 22871</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000383</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286202-34772" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
