<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286618</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rights-based Border Management in the Silk Routes Countries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to implement sustainable, rights-based, border management practices in Iraq and Pakistan towards increasing border management and security and reducing irregular migration. The project thus aims to 1) support Federal Investigation Agency (FIA) of Pakistan to increase institutional and operational capacity in combatting irregular migration, and enhancing border and migration management and 2) enhance border management in Iraq by strengthening the capacities of border management institutions for planning the border control and reaction to crisis situations based on risk analysis.

The proposed action focuses on two countries of the Silk Routes region; Pakistan, as a major transit country for migration from Afghanistan, as well as a major host country for Afghan refugees and as a country of origin for regular and irregular migration itself; and Iraq, as a country of origin for regular and irregular migration, but also a host country for migrant labour such as from Bangladesh, and most recently as the source of emerging new irregular migration routes towards the EU via Belarus.
Given the widespread economic, political and physical conditions now present throughout the region that may push already highly vulnerable groups towards risky migration attempts, special focus on actions that prevent migration related crimes is needed to prevent these vulnerable groups from falling prey to organised crime groups seeking their exploitation. Furthermore, border authorities have a duty to predict and manage crisis and unpredicted mass influxes in a secure and efficient manner while respecting the human rights of migrants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 - 34883</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2022000022</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286618-35333" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
