<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286081</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark&#x2019;s contribution to HURIDOCS project on co-creating the future of digital investigations with human rights defenders</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HURIDOCS (Human Rights Information and Documentation Services) is an NGO that helps human rights groups gather, organise and use information to create positive change in the world. Founded in 1982, HURIDOCS has developed methodologies and software tools that make it easier not only to manage collections of evidence, law and research, but also to analyze them for insights.
This project aims at a growing need for human rights defenders (HRDs) that engage in efforts to advance accountability and justice: a state-of-the-art software tool that helps them record, manage and analyse human rights violations in a way that is easily adaptable to local contexts, while protecting sensitive data on sources and victims. The need for such a tool is timely, as existing alternatives have reached their end of life, just as threats against the digital resilience of HRDs are increasing, and the amount of potential information that HRDs can leverage is growing exponentially. HURIDOCS will be to cooperate with partners on the ground in Cameroon, China, Egypt, The Gambia, Iraq, Mali, Mexico, Myanmar, North Korea, Palestine, Philippines, Sri Lanka, Turkey and Ukraine.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286081-34627" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286081-35050" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">HRD investigations supported by software tools demonstrably lead to:
- Perpetrators being held to account to deter future violations;
- Achieve justice for victims through reparations, memorialisation, policy change, brought about by institutions that are open to all;
- Collective memory of the past brings societies to heal and grow into a better future.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </description>
   <reference code="269807" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">HRD investigations supported by software tools demonstrably lead to:
- Perpetrators being held to account to deter future violations;
- Achieve justice for victims through reparations, memorialisation, policy change, brought about by institutions that are open to all;
- Collective memory of the past brings societies to heal and grow into a better future.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2020">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The baseline is highly dependant on context - in some of the locations, formal national and international (transitional) justice efforts are already under way, in others, not. Nonetheless, common understanding exists that documentation, memorialisation and preservation efforts are key  for a future possibility of justice, healing and growth.

Target (2022): 
- At least 10 Organisations using the software tool report that it significantly aids their efforts in furthering at least one of the impact indicators.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
