<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286113</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DMDP 2020 - Organic growth: Taking Afghanistan&#x2019;s certified saffron value chain to scale</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Premium quality organic saffron creates new farm and job income opportunities, especially for women, through a stronger export market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Saffron is a global, climate-resilient, gender-sensitive and high-value export commodity. The Afghan saffron export market is the third-largest in the world, holding 8.8% of global volume, and the saffron exports business is growing bigger by the year. With the right investment and marketing, Afghanistan is positioned to become a major player in the global market for saffron. Hand in Hand, and its commercial partner Conflictfood, aim to establish and scale the first-ever line of certified organic saffron produced and processed in Afghanistan.
Sustainable production of saffron answers three major challenges in Afghanistan. Firstly, it is a legal alternative to the cultivation of opium poppy fueled by lack of livelihood and income opportunities. Secondly, saffron is climate-resilient as it does not require heavy irrigation. It is therefore an ideal crop for the climate change scenarios for Afghanistan, which include increased frequency and intensity of drought. Lastly, the saffron value chain requires labour-intensive post-harvest processing. It is therefore an engine of rural job creation, especially for women and youth who often engage in these activities. The project will contribute to improved livelihoods and unlock new markets, by responding to the growing international demand and by recognising the climate-resilient and labour-intensive nature of saffron.
The Danida Market Development Partnerships programme (DMDP) is designed to support commercially oriented partnerships for sustainable market development in developing countries. In addition to reporting on individually determined outputs and outcomes, all DMDP projects report on five key programme indicators. These five indicators are the same for the whole project portfolio, enabling strategic and programme level monitoring, and aggregation of results.
At the programme level, three key outcomes which are related to three of the five key programme indicators, have been chosen for results reporting: Outcome 1: I</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 - 42140</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020000463</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="311" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286113-34723" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
