<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286079</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution to the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) 2020-2024</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Danish contribution to IUCN&apos;s monitored on the basis of IUCN&apos;s
own performance reporting. The latest report can be found at the following link:</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Danish engagement with IUCN has the overarching purpose of supporting IUCN&#x2019;s Programme 2021-24 in realising its call to action by all IUCN&#x2019;s Members, scientific network and Secretariat to mobilise collectively on delivering a clear and demonstrable contribution to the SDGs, the post-2020 global biodiversity framework and the Paris Agreement in developing countries.

Follwoing this purpuse, the objective of the development cooperation is support to IUCN&#x2019;s global thematic and regional programmes to achieve their intended results for people, land, water, oceans, and climate, especially on climate adaptation, improved access to water resources, gender equality, and rights and inclusion of indigenous peoples.

The support consists of DKK 80 million in four tranches, divided in DKK 40 million in overall core support for IUCN&#x2019;s 2021-24 Strategic Programme Nature 2030 &#x2013; One Nature, One Future, and DKK 40 million in programmatic support for Nature 2030&#x2019;s programmatic areas of Danish priority, namely: Equity in access to water resources, climate adaptation through nature-based solutions (NbS), and gender responsiveness and indigenous peoples.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286079-34449" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286079-34662" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286079-35164" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286079-35165" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target P1 Fully realised rights, roles, obligations and responsibilities to ensure just and inclusive conservation and sustainable use of nature
Impact Indicators
? SDG 1.4.2 Proportion of total adult population with secure tenure rights to land, (a) with legally recognised documentation, and (b) who perceive their rights to land as secure, by sex 
and type of tenure 
? SDG 15.6.1. Number of countries that have adopted legislative, administrative and policy frameworks to ensure fair and equitable sharing of benefits</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272867" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target P2. Equitable and effective governance of natural resources at all levels to benefit people and nature 
Impact Indicators 
? SDG 15.6.1. Number of countries that have adopted legislative, administrative and policy frameworks to ensure fair and equitable sharing of benefits (this one should be under this 
impact)
? SDG 16.7.2 Proportion of population who believe decision making is inclusive and responsive, by sex, age, disability and population group</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272868" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target P3 Enhanced realisation and enforcement of the environmental rule of law
Impact Indicators None suggested</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272875" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target L1. Ecosystems are retained and restored, species are conserved and recovered, and key biodiversity areas are safeguarded
Impact Indicators 
? SDG 15.5.1 Red List Index (terrestrial species) 
? SDG 15.1.2. Proportion of important sites for terrestrial biodiversity that are covered by protected areas, by ecosystem type</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272881" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target L2. Thriving production landscapes are sustainable, and nature&#x2019;s value and benefits are safeguarded in the long term.
Impact Indicators 
? SDG 15.2.1. Progress towards sustainable forest management 
? SDG 15.3.1. Proportion of land that is degraded over total land area</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272886" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target L3. Nature and people thrive in cities while delivering solutions for urban challenges and a sustainable ecological footprint
Impact Indicators NONE</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272895" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target W1. The loss of freshwater species and decline of freshwater ecosystem health is halted, and restoration initiated.
Impact indicators 
? SDG 15.5.1. Red List Index (freshwater species)
? SDG 15.1.2. Proportion of important sites for freshwater biodiversity that are covered by protected areas, by ecosystem type</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272898" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target W2. Equitable access to water resources and all associated ecosystem services are secured.
Impact Indicators 
? SDG 6.4.2. Level of water stress: freshwater withdrawal as a proportion of available freshwater resources 
? SDG 6.6.1. Change in the extent of water-related ecosystems over time</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272903" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target W3. Water governance, law and investment decisions address the multiple values of nature and incorporate biodiversity knowledge.
Impact Indicators
? SDG 6.5.1. Degree of integrated water resources management implementation (0-100) 
? SDG 6. b.1. Proportion of local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272906" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target O1. The loss of marine species and decline of marine ecosystem integrity is halted, and restoration initiated.
Impact indicators 
? SDG 15.5.1. Red List Index (marine species)
? SDG 14.5.1. Coverage of protected areas in relation to marine areas</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272909" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact Target O2. Uses of marine natural resources generate overall positive biodiversity outcomes and sustain livelihood benefits for coastal communities.
Impact Indicators 
? SDG 14.4.1 Proportion of fish stocks within biologically sustainable levels
? SDG 14.6.1 Degree of implementation of international instruments aiming to combat illegal, unreported and unregulated fishing</narrative>
   </title>
   <reference code="272914" vocabulary="99"></reference>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
