<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286304</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark&apos;s contribution to the 19th replenishment of the International Development Association (IDA19)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the latest updated version of the World Bank Group Corporate Scorecards (source 1-3), The World Bank Annual Report 2020 (source 4) alongside the Danish organisational strategy for the World Bank (source 5), the following results can be noted in relation the Danish priorities:

&#x2022;	Concerning target 1 of &#x201C;ending extreme poverty&#x201D;, extreme poverty has continued its decline. Compared to the 2011 baseline outlined in the organisational strategy (source 5:10), where 13,5% of the population lived on less than USD 1.90 a day, the most recent scorecard updates shows a decrease to 9.2 % in 2017 (source 1: see section on goals). For the most recent regional updates regarding extreme poverty, see Table 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13 in source 4. 

&#x2022;	In relation to target 2 on &#x2018;promoting shared prosperity&#x2019;, the income growth for the 40 percent poorest in each country serves as an indicator. Compared to the 2011 baseline outlined in the organisational strategy, the growth rate has decreased from 3.6 % in 2011 (source 5:10), to 1.9 % in 2019 (source 1 see section on goals).

&#x2022;	Regarding target 3 on CO2eq emissions reductions per year, improvements have been made compared to the FY15-17 baseline. In 2011, the emissions reductions reached app. 15 million CO2eq/year (source 5:10), whereas the latest Corporate Scorecard update shows a 157 million CO2eq/year emissions reduction in FY19-FY21 (source 2: see section on Resilience). For the most recent regional updates regarding CO2 emissions, see Table 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13 in source 4.

&#x2022;	With reference to target 4, on client feedback on WB effectiveness and the impact on development results improvements can be measured vis-&#xE0;-vis the FY13 baseline. In 2013 the WB scored a 6.9 out (source 5:10) of 10 whereas in 2020 a 7.4 score was measured (source 3: see section on Supporting Clients To Achieve Development Results). 

The Danish motivation for supporting IDA19 is to support ending extreme poverty in the world&#x2019;s poorest countries, stren</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Under the overarching theme of &quot;Ten Years to 2030: Growth, People, and Resilience,&quot; IDA19 supports the world&#x2019;s poorest and most vulnerable countries to implement country-driven solutions that are people-centered, boost economic growth, and bolster resilience to climate shocks and natural disasters.  

IDA19 focuses on five special themes: (i) climate change; (ii) fragility, conflict and violence; (iii) gender; (iv) governance and institutions; and (v) jobs and economic transformation. IDA19 also incorporates four cross-cutting issues: debt, disability, human capital, and technology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 - 11401</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021000050</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2026-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>NA</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unallocated / Unspecified</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286304-34942" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
