<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286143</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnerships for a Tolerant Inclusive Bangladesh (PTIB) Second phase, 2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project funding under the 2020 LGA frame is with the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) is to contribute to a more tolerant and inclusive Bangladesh. It aims to deliver the result of &#x2018;&#x2018;A community of more knowledgeable and active citizens, civil society groups, and policymakers who better understand and are more committed to promoting diversity, inclusion, and tolerance in Bangladesh&#x2019;&#x2019;. The project focuses on research to better understand the nature of disinformation, hate speech, and violent extremism in Bangladesh. It uses a data-driven and iterative process in citizen engagement activities. It also supports coordination, cooperation, and interaction with the Government. The project has three outcomes:
&#x2022;	Output 1 &#x2013; Research Facility: Improved knowledge, understanding, and insights into the drivers of conflict, violence, and extremism and build capacity to analyse the sources and nature of disinformation, exclusion, and intolerance in Bangladesh. 
&#x2022;	Output 2 &#x2013; Citizen Engagement: Expanded diversity in the messages, messengers, and use of available media in promoting inclusivity and tolerance in Bangladeshi communities through online and offline engagement activities.
&#x2022;	Output 3 &#x2013; Government Engagement: Promote active coordination, cooperation, and interaction with the Government of Bangladesh to inform their efforts to strengthen inclusivity and tolerance and prevent violent extremism.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1900-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286143-34707" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
