<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-286367</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Formulation of engagement in North Africa: Health projects in Morocco and Tunisia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of an overall ambition to strengthen Denmark&#x2019;s bilateral relations with countries in North Africa, the Danish Government plans to allocate DKK 50 million annually for four years projects with the purpose of promoting social and economic development in Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia and Egypt, cf. Finance Act account &#xA7;06.32.01.23.

In 2021 DKK 50 million will be allocated for two different projects with thematic focus on the health sector in relation to the COVID-19 pandemic. The projects and partnerships will be new for Danida, though the concrete engagements will build on existing initiatives and previous experiences.
The first project &#x2018;Promoting women and girls&#x2019; leadership in the socio-economic and health response to COVID-19 in Tunisia&#x2019; is implemented by UNDP (lead), UNWOMEN and WHO. This project builds on the results and scale-up initiatives of three existing programmes currently being implemented by UN WOMEN, and UNDP and WHO.

The second project &#x2018;Ensuring the continuity of essential primary healthcare services for the most vulnerable population and developing prevention and hygiene measures during the COVID-19 pandemic&#x2019; in Morocco is implemented by UNFPA. This project is based on a pilot project implemented by UNFPA in Morocco.

The objective of the assignment is to produce two appraisal reports as part of the standard quality assurance process, cf. Danida&#x2019;s Aid Management Guidelines. The reports shall assess the proposed projects based on the project document submitted by the partners and its annexes. Furthermore, the appraisal reports shall assess the capacity and relevance of the partner organisations in relation to the proposed project objectives and activities. The appraisal reports shall provide relevant recommendations for the MFA and the implementing partners as appropriate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 - 15676</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021000116</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-286367-35021" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
