<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="CHF" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-CH-6600422994-6-CH-FDJP-66004229946-PROJECT- GB100100</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-CH-6600422994-6" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Economic Forum Geneva</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From policy design to field implementation: Fostering deforestation-free cattle ranching in Madre de Dios, Peru.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Peru, deforestation and climate change are linked: Agriculture is the country&#x2019;s leading driver of deforestation and about 45% of its greenhouse gas emissions come from land use, land-use change, and forestry. The national government has demonstrated its willingness to halt deforestation by adopting forest and climate goals and designing strategies and enacting policies such as its ambitious  NDC  which identifies the implementation of silvopastoral systems  (SPS)  as a  key measure for  GHG  emission reduction. In Madre de Dios (MDD), one of the most biodiverse regions in the Peruvian Amazon, expansion of low-tech, extensive cattle farming is the main cause of deforestation and environmental degradation; however, several actions are being taken to tackle GHG emissions. This project will bridge the gap between planning and action in support of low carbon,  deforestation-free silvopastoral cattle ranching.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcomes of the Funded Activity:

1. Implementation of low-carbon, deforestation-free cattle farming in Madre de Dios. 

Outputs of the Funded Activity:

2. Knowledge package for d-free cattle ranching developed and disseminated 

3.MuLti-stakeholders,  through the Technical  Livestock  Roundtable of  Madre de  Dios  (TLR-MDD),  provide inputs to solve finance bottlenecks for d-free cattle ranching in Madre de Dios.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1102909" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Climate Change Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (BEIS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-CHC-1081247" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WWF-UK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XI-PB-CH-6600422994-6" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Economic Forum Geneva</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-06-14"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-05-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-14">80000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
