<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-3.2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" secondary-reporter="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan(INBAR)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STANDARDS AND CERTIFICATION MECHANISM DEVELOPED</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Five products standard were drafted in Ethiopia on the bamboo curtain, bamboo charcoal, bamboo flooring for interior, bamboo structure, and vocabulary related to bamboo and bamboo products. The drafted standards were submitted to Ethiopian National Standards Committee for approval.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The following bamboo standards were developed, the country-specific details as mentioned below: 
Ethiopia: Bamboo Standards published by EBS on dated  06-01-2021 (First edition); ES 6416:2021: Design of Bamboo Structures; ES 6417:2021: Preservation of bamboo art 1: for construction purpose;ES 6418:2021: Preservation of bamboo-part- 2: for non-construction purpose; ES 6419-2021: Preservation of Timber - Code of practice; ES 6420-2021: Specification for water-soluble type wood Preservative; ES 6421-2021: Specification for water-soluble type wood preservatives Copper-Chrome-Arsenal (CCA)wood preservative; ES 6422-2021: Specification for water-soluble type wood preservatives Copper-Chrome-Boron (CCB) wood preservative
Kenya: Bamboo Standards published vide Gazette Notification No. 8585 of 20th August 2021 the following standards: KS 2929:2021: Kenya Standards &#x2013;General technical requirement for bamboo-culm furniture (first edition); and KS 2930:2021: Kenya Standards &#x2013;General requirement for flooring (first edition
Uganda: Bamboo Standards published in 2021  developed: UNBS/TC 20: Bamboo structural design with the Uganda National Bureau of Standards; and ISO 19624: Bamboo structures &#x2014; Grading of bamboo culms &#x2014; Basic principles and procedures. The Soil Association Certification Limited a UK-based agency has been engaged for FSC certification on bamboo forest (1000 - 2000 hectare), the groundwork initiated</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The target is to develop ten product and process standards; one Voluntary Guideline Standard (VGS); one FSC certified bamboo forest (1000 hectare); Three workshops + one CIDCA/MOFCOM workshop: 100 people trained (70M/30W).

In continuation of the Phase I of the programme, five national standards were developed by three national standard agencies. The Phase II of the programme is closely working with different working groups and technical committees to finalise the national standards. Under INBAR&#x2019;s Intra-Africa and SSTC grant, two (2) task forces have been established: Taskforce on Bamboo for Renewable Energy (TFB4RE) and Taskforce on Sustainable Bamboo Management (TFSBM). Task Force on Sustainable Bamboo Management: A task force consisting of 30 (25M/5F) experts from 15 countries was established. A chairperson and manager were selected to lead. Two working agendas have been identified and accepted for the development of two Voluntary Guideline Standards (VGS) namely (1) Step by Step Guide on the use of Bamboo for FLR and (2) Guideline for certification of forest and planted bamboo. Routine virtual meeting and preparation of VGS are ongoing. Two calls for interested consultants to 1) develop VGS for the certification of natural and establishment of bamboo plantations, and 2) develop VGS Step-by-Step for Forest Landscape Restoration (FLR) with bamboo have also been drafted and pending action. Task Force on Bamboo for Renewable Energy: A taskforce consisting of 21 (13/8F) experts from 12 countries including the selection of taskforce chairperson and manager has been finalised. The task force has identified three working items for the development of three VGS: (1) bamboo charcoal, (2) design of charcoal kiln and (3) bamboo bio-energy commoditization. Routine virtual meeting and preparation of VGS is ongoing. A draft of one VGS: design of charcoal kiln prepared and submitted to taskforce for review and finalisation. 

FSC forest certification: The programme team is closely working with EEFCCC and identified 1000ha bamboo forest for FSC certification. A joint visit was done with the EEFCCC to identify the forest area, as a result 1000 ha of bamboo project area selected in Kafa zone, Adiyo, SNNPR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopian Standard Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2" crs-channel-code="10000" role="3" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Center for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Bureau of Standards</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="3.2" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda National Bureau of Standards</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bamboo and Rattan Organisation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Programme</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selim Reza</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251930562676</telephone>
   <email>selim@inbar.int</email>
   <website>http://www.inbar.int/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Regional Office INBAR</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="34">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo product standards</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo product standards</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="33">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo product standards</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="12" percentage="50" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo products standards development for the national and international markets.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="17" percentage="50" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China being the global leader in bamboo, provide technical support and standards on bamboo products and processes for adoption</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="8"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="50"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
