<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-2.4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" secondary-reporter="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan(INBAR)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">QUANTIFYING E. AFRICA REGION BAMBOO CARBON SINKS AND ECOSYSTEM SERVICES; AND ESTABLISHING MECHANISMS TO FINANCE CARBON PROJECTS IN EAST AFRICA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target is to establish Bamboo carbon credit project; one environmental research plot; one report and journal paper; 2 capacity building training (50 researchers). 

The programme team initiated the activities for setting up bamboo carbon credit project as well as setting up bamboo environmental metrics research plot. Several virtual meetings and discussions were held with Zhejiang Agriculture and Forestry University (ZAFU) and Face the Future on mechanisms to quantity the bamboo carbon sinks as well as carbon credit trading.  Furthermore, a project identification note for establishing a bamboo carbon project site has been prepared based on field visits  to Parabongo Sub County, Agago District in East Acholi Sub-Region, Uganda. The Eco-Ways(U)Ltd and Kalongo Integrated Environmental Protection Association (KIEPA) a community-based organization were identified as local partner to set up a bamboo carbon project.

The programme is working closely with KEFRI to develop a Bamboo Allometric and Hydrology Research plot in Gede, Coast Region. The aim of the research was to assess the growth and performance of different bamboo species in the coastal agro-ecological zone in Kenya;determine the comparative rainfall water-use efficiencies of indigenous and exotic bamboo species in the research plot; investigate the long-term effects of growing different bamboo species on soil quality and carbon stocks; and evaluate the efficacy of bamboo plantations in conserving soil and water (runoff and sedimentation). The programme organised two virtual workshops with the participation of Indian Institute of Soil and Water Conservation (IISWC) scientists and KEFRI scientists to devise the methodology for RBD research plot in Kenya for bamboo soil water research.

The quantification of carbon sinks and field work and documentation for establishment of carbon credit project in Uganda and physical establishment of environmental research plot will happen in year 2 of the programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.4" role="3" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indian institute of soil and water conservation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.4" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Environment and Forest Research Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="2.4" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Forest Authority, Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bamboo and Rattan Organization</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Programme</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selim Reza</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Programme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251930562676</telephone>
   <email>selim@inbar.int</email>
   <website>http://www.inbar.int/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Regional Office INBAR</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo carbon project in Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bamboo research on soil and water in Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="13" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="8"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="50"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
