<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XI-PB-402-1.4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XI-PB-402" secondary-reporter="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Network for Bamboo and Rattan(INBAR)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT OF NEW MARKET ORIENTED PRODUCTS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Age-wise property test report of three bamboo species published; two bamboo bio-energy conversion technology + business model demonstrated; One new bamboo product composite developed; and LCA study on bamboo biomass conversion technology published. 

The programme in collaboration with ICBR finalised the protocol for sample collection for undertaking the age-wise property-machine compatibility-product testing. Three predominant species in east Africa namely Yushaniaalpina or Oldeaniaalpina, Oxytenantheraabyssinica, Dendrocalamus asper werefinalised for sample collection. The samples of OldeaniaalpinaandOxytenantheraabyssinica will be collected from Ethiopia and samples from Dendrocalamus asper will be collected from Kenya and a 20 feet container will be sent to China for age-wise property testing (physical, mechanical, chemical and anatomical) as well as for machine and product compatibility. The bamboo sample collection, processing, shipment and testing will be undertaken during year 2 of the programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the quarter(October-December2021) one full container of bamboo(two species highland and low land) has been sent to China for trial and testing for the new product verticals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The sample collected for age-wise property test report of 2 species in Ethiopia and sent to China for property, machine, and product A full container of bamboo of two predominant species from Ethiopia was collected from Amhara; Benisangul Gumuz; Sidama, and SNPPR regions. Collecting the sample, the Chinese national standard GB/T 15780-1995 &#x2018;Testing methods for physical and mechanical properties of bamboos&#x2019; and Chinese industry standards of construction JGT 199-2007 &#x2018;Testing methods for physical and mechanical properties of bamboo used in building&#x2019;, the samples of each bamboo species have been strict as followed: The bamboo samples were collected in the most representative bamboo producing areas, the age of bamboo should be 2-4 years; the DBH measured at 1.5 meter&#x2019;s height and the chosen sample is larger than 50 mm and collected 6 samples out of the 20 bamboos for the final test.  The chosen samples are healthy, have no defect or damage in appearance, and identified mother clumps. Each culm is cut into 3 pieces; marked and numbered sequentially. Further, it has been split in half and then oven-dried at about 60 degrees to an MC of about 7-12% and stored in a dry area. The sample was packed and the shipment was completed. The Ethiopia Environment and Forest Research Institute(EFRI) has been provided all logistic support for drying and storing. The Ethiopia Biodiversity Authority has provided all necessary support for clearance for shipment of the Bamboo in China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.4" crs-channel-code="10000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Environment and Forest Research Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.4" crs-channel-code="10000" role="1" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Center for Bamboo and Rattan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="1.4" crs-channel-code="10000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Forest Reearch Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On programme progress and implementation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global  Programme</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Selim Reza</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Porgramme Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251930562676</telephone>
   <email>selim@inbar.int</email>
   <website>http://www.inbar.int/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">East Africa Regional Office INBAR, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="2"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New market-oriented new product development.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="50">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New market-oriented product development</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme implemented in Ethiopia and Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-region>
  <sector code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New market-oriented product development for SME and industrial growth for poverty reduction and employment generation.</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="8"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="50"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
