<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41188664-CAOM-SST-SM</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41188664" type="INGO">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Sanitation Marketing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x93;Due to the lack of developed sanitation facilities most Cambodian villagers use the open defecation method.  This results in untreated human waste near homes. The lack of sanitation facilities in rural areas contributes to Cambodia&apos;s under-five mortality rate being among the highest in Asia. This project aims to improve rural sanitation by marketing unsubsidized toilets.  Sor Sor Trung promotes this idea through a social enterprise approach. The organization works to establish local sanitation agents within communities.  This innovation will spread the demand for such positions and will raise income for families as well. The project will train local entrepreneurs - small businessmen - how to build good and affordable latrines  called The Easy Latrine. In addition to building the latrine structure itself this training will involve many different construction efforts including the production of toilet rings and cement slabs.  Working hand in hand with the community sanitation agents will take models of the latrines into villages.  In addition to marketing promoting and selling the finished product at village meetings and door to door the sanitation agents will also offer education concerning proper sanitation and hygiene.  The Easy Latrine will be offered to households at an affordable price.  Families can purchase the Easy Latrine in cash or on an installment basis with little interest involved.&#x93;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sor Sor trung</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End Planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@ics.nl</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+310333030250</telephone>
   <email>info@ics.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smallepad 32, 3811 MG Amersfoort, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="250" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Business and Other Services&quot;</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">10583</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">40778</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
