<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41188664-TAME-SOLAR</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41188664" type="INGO">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meatu Solar Energy Enterprise</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;The Meatu Solar Enterprises project aims at enabling rural communities in Meatu district to access and use electricity through solar energy. Meatu district has a great potential for using solar energy with an average of eight hours of sun daily, but currently this potential is barely being used because of insufficient local awareness and capacities. Providing areas that are far from the national electricity grid with access to solar energy brings communities a wide range of advantages to improve economic activities and household wellbeing, for example by enabling (non-kerosine) lighting and mobile phones usage. This project will pursue three strategies to improve access to solar energy: 1. Investing in the establishment of solar enterprises will allow for the delivery of solar equipment to households and small local businesses through local markets. 2. By strengthening the infrastructure for installation and maintenance, the community&#x92;s capacity to operate the solar systems will be enhanced. 3) Setting up village savings and loans schemes will provide communities with the financial services that allow them to make the necessary investments in solar equipment.   The project builds upon a pilot project that is successfully being implemented in Meatu district since 2009. It scales up the activities and provide more households and local businesses with access to solar energy. The sustainability of results will be enhanced trough a refined social business approach. ICS will support the establishment and capacity enhancement of local solar enterprises, run by women and youth groups, that supply the community with solar panels and accessories on credit. By creating a local market for solar equipment and services, the project strengthens the capacity of communities to achieve positive social change in an entrepreneurial way. By facilitating the establishment of financial services, the project will enable community members to make their own investments and sustain the results of the project after ICS&#x92; involvement. &quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS Tanzania</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End Actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@ics.nl</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+310333030250</telephone>
   <email>info@ics.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smallepad 32, 3811 MG Amersfoort, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Government and civil society, general&quot;</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">13000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">10692</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
