<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41188664-TASI-ORMAME</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41188664" type="INGO">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Orkonerai Mass Media Ltd.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Orkonerei Mass Media Ltd - ORMAME-  is a company that has been in operations since 2009 following its formation to address sustainability in provision of media services among pastoralists&#x92; communities in Northern Tanzania. Its core activities are community radio broadcasting, and video production/documentation. The objective was  - and still remains - to advocate pastoralists interest against marginalization in development processes. It is the duty of the radio to promote social cohesion and raise awareness and stir up involvement and participation of the Pastoralists&#x92; Community in policy, legal, economic and environmental conservation processes. ORMAME remains the only Pastoralists&#x92; Community media company in Northern Tanzania. It has been quite successful in raising awareness in the community and especially in stimulating an urge for people to seek for information. The use of Maa Language is providing an opportunity for most People, who do not understand the conventional languages used in most media outlets  -radio, TV and prints- to be informed. As a result, over the years, ORMAME  - especially its radio broadcasting service has encouraged high enrollment to both primary and secondary schools for many pastoralists&#x92; children. It has also helped in coordinating and organizing local economic development initiatives and facilitated community participation, inclusion and engagement in a wide range of community development issues.&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ORMAME</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-07-01" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End Actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@ics.nl</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+310333030250</telephone>
   <email>info@ics.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smallepad 32, 3811 MG Amersfoort, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Government and civil society, general&quot;</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">50823</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">50823</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
