<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41188664-CAOM-SKYE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41188664" type="INGO">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Society of Khmer Youth entrepreneurs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x93;Unemployment is high among Cambodias youth - due in part to a low level of education - although younger youth are more likely to be literate - 84% - than older youth - 76.3%. By gender more young women have reached primary levels of schooling. But young men are more likely to have had a secondary education. One factor contributing to this gender disparity is the lack of secondary schools in rural areas and the reluctance of many families to send their daughters to urban centres for education . One of the challenges in engaging the youth to become active participants in creating change in their society is in maximizing the participation of out-of-school youths (OSY) in rural communities. OSYs tend to migrate to urban areas in search for employment. In addition to this their degree of participation is limited by their knowledge and skills brought about by lack of basic education and life skills. The problems faced by children and youth are all interrelated. Rural poverty diminishes their likelihood of obtaining and completing basic education. The rural poor who migrate to the cities for work tend to be homeless and unemployed. Thus they are more likely to turn to criminal behaviours or take risky and exploitative employment. Through SKYE Cambodian youth are given relevant vocational and life skills training opportunities that will equip them to explore create and participate in social enterprise opportunities within their communit. Thus breaking the cycle of poverty which they find themselves in. By establishing the Society of Khmer Youth Entrepreneurs (SKYE) youth are given a stronger voice in the society and they will not just be a statistics representing the population. By SKYE opportunities for youth are opened in their own communities reducing the possibility of risky migration.&#x93;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS Cambodia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Donations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rotary Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End Planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@ics.nl</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+310333030250</telephone>
   <email>info@ics.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smallepad 32, 3811 MG Amersfoort, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Government and civil society, general&quot;</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">106555</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">51601</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
