<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41188664-ASIA-SP</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41188664" type="INGO">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Skillful Parenting Cambodia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x93;A safe and stable home environment is of great importance in allowing children to develop into positive adults. Unfortunately this is not always the case for many rural children in Cambodia. The absence of information means that parents in rural areas of Cambodia are often not aware of the impact of education on their children. Parents pass on to children what they themselves learned and in doing so do not always follow the best examples. In addition there are often underlying family problems present. ICS has developed Skillful Parenting courses in which parents can learn about parenting skills working in groups. Subjects like self-worth and affirmation conflict control within the family positive discipline and child protection are covered. Parents are also made aware about the usefulness of saving money family budgeting and setting financial priorities jointly within the family. The parents learn together and support each other in developing know-how and skills concerning parenting. Violence against women and children is a big problem in Cambodia and this aspect receives special attention in the Cambodian Skillful Parenting program. On top of the subjects noted above coaches and teachers spend time talking about respectful gender-equal and non-violent relationships between fathers and mothers and  between parent and child.&#x94;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DGIS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICS Cambodia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End Planned</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start Actual</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">info@ics.nl</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>+310333030250</telephone>
   <email>info@ics.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smallepad 32, 3811 MG Amersfoort, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Government and civil society, general&quot;</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">26667</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-12-31">27147</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
