<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="14" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/13859" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-KHSI-KZ-14-13859</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional Consultancy for Children under 3 and children with disabilities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institutional consultancy on supporting the Ministry of Health and Social Development of the Republic of Kazakhstan in strategic and evidence-based planning (roadmap) of developing integrated family oriented social and health services for children under three and children with disabilities of pre-school age within the transformed care system.

	Specific objectives will consist of the following:

1.	To provide the technical assistance to the Ministry of Health and Social Development in strengthening the gender disaggregated data management system (monitoring and analyses) on current state of children of 0-7 age in risk of being abandoned or without parental care, including children with disabilities, their families and communities in line with internationally recognized indicators for children in formal care and data collected in selected regions.
2.	To provide the technical assistance to the Ministry of Health and Social Development and the Akimats in selected regions in elaborating and implementing of a test roadmap for development of services within the transformed operation of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities into modern form of family oriented care, including budgetary consideration. 
3.	To provide the technical advice to the Ministry of Health and Social Development on the good experience in transforming the infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities and provide a feedback to the draft strategies they included into the statute on the infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1. Strengthening the gender disaggregated data management system (monitoring and analysis) on current state of children of 0-7 age in risk of being abandoned or without parental care, including children with disabilities.
The following activities will be done:

&#x2022;	Desk review of the international experiences and lessons learned during the   transforming of institutions and the development of community-based social care services  for children of 0-7 age at risk of being abandoned or without parental care, including children with disabilities;
&#x2022;	Desk review of the Kazakhstan legal framework regarding social protection and social assistance of children from 0 to 7 in risk to be abandoned or without parental care, including those with disabilities;
&#x2022;	Conducting a desk review of the available data on children of 0-7 age at risk of being abandoned or without parental care, including children with disabilities;
&#x2022;	Desk revue of existing social care services for children from 0 to 7, including those with disabilities and the level of coverage of children in needs with those services;
&#x2022;	Identification of the  profiles of children in infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities;
&#x2022;	Setting up the baseline indicators for the modernization process and effective functioning of new services in selected locations; 
&#x2022;	Visiting the service sites in Kazakhstan, including the statutory services, the family support services and the family substitutive services in order to understand better the both: social protection system of children from 0 to 7, including children with disabilities and  referral mechanism;
&#x2022;	Technical discussion with the representatives of the National and regional departments of statistics regarding the data collected on both: children from 0 to 3 in risk to be abandoned and children with disabilities up to age 7. Identification of solutions for  collecting the disaggregated data by age and by gender; 
&#x2022;	Technical discussion with the main stakeholders (MoHSD, MES, MLSPF, local authorities (department of social protection, department of health and department of education), civil society and UNICEF) on implementing and assessing the modernization process at the level of the infant homes for children of 0-3 age and medical social facilities for children with disabilities; and regarding the development of the integrated and different types of social care services for vulnerable families and children at risk, especially in support of mothers with babies 0-3 age and with disabilities.

Objective 2. Elaboration and implementation of a test roadmap for development of services within the transformed operation of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities into modern form of family oriented care, including budgetary consideration. The following activities will be done:

&#x2022;	Drafting in consultation with relevant stakeholders a roadmap for development of modernized services. The roadmap will include  the following compartments: 
a.	the situational analysis of the social protection system for  children form 0-7, including those with disabilities in Kazakhstan; 
b.	the situational analysis of the existing services  for children from 0-7, including those  developed within the transformed operation of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities within Astana and in one region to be determined;
c.	the strategic plan (rational, vision, goals, objectives, activities) for  development of services within the transformed operation of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities into modern form of family oriented;
d.	the institutional framework changes  needed  for development of services within the transformed operation of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities into modern form of family oriented;
e.	 the  M&amp;amp;E mechanism of the road map, including: the performance indicators, the  long term and short term results,  the establishment of M&amp;amp;E system for the road map;
f.	Costing and financing of the road map. The road map will take into consideration the referrals to other sectors for assistance (social benefits, housing and employment, access to day care and other professional aid services for families and children)

&#x2022;	Discussion of the draft road map of modernized services and of the action plan for the next 12 months within the transformed operation of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities from Astana and region to be determined. 
&#x2022;	Defining the need in technical support and advice for the implementation of the 12 months action plan and preparation of the new TOR for the additional consultancies.
&#x2022;	Identifying  the training needs of current infant home and medical social facilities for children with disabilities staff; and 
&#x2022;	Developing a brief Staff Re-training Needs Plan for the regions, suggesting the type of educational packages/modules that should be developed in the future to offer possibilities to current infant home and medical social facilities for children with disabilities staff to re-train and acquire skills to provide alternative type of services in local communities.

Objective 3. To provide technical advice to the Ministry of Health and Social Development on the good experience in transforming the infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities and provide a feedback to the draft strategies and standards they included into the statute on the infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities.

&#x2022;	Advising the working group in the MoHSD on the infant home and medical social facilities for children with disabilities transformation, planning and implementation process;
&#x2022;	Provide feedback to the MoHSD to the draft strategies, standards and plan they included  into the statute of the infant home and medical social facilities for children with disabilities statutes;
&#x2022;	Presentation of the first draft &#x201C;roadmap for modernization of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities&#x201D; to the central and local government, civil society and NGOs for comments and suggestions;
&#x2022;	Improvement of the first draft roadmap based on the suggestions and comments and finalization of the final draft.
&#x2022;	Finalization of the final draft of the &#x201C;roadmap for modernization of infant homes and medical social facilities for children with disabilities&#x201D; for the national scale up among other regions of the country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">children</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government of Kazakhstan</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-25-1813977" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keystone Human Services International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="KHSI-KZ-14-13859" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="43170768" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-25-1813977">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keystone Human Services International</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-25" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-20" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keystone Human Services International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ludmila Malcoci, Ph.D</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <email>lmalcoci@keystonehumanservices.org</email>
   <website>http://keystonehumanservices.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="gn_1538317">
   <location-id code="1538317" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Astana (city)</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Astana (city), Kazakhstan (admin level 1)</narrative>
   </description>
   <administrative code="1538317" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>51.13333 71.43333</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADM1"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="14" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-20">67316</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total project budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNICEF</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="US-EIN-25-1813977">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keystone Human Services International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
