<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-18/DDA-3379/SA2/WASH/INGO/9622</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lifesaving Emergency WASH Response to displaced IDPs and host communities in 2017/2018 in Lagahidha, dawe serar and Rayitu districts of  Bale zone of Oromia region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed intervention will provide life-saving WASH services assistance to 5,964 households (HH) (46,578 individuals) internally displaced persons and local host community) impacted by man-made and  natural disasters (drought, floods, and other natural hazards), and conflict, and who are in critical need of emergency WASH and non-food items (NFI) in Ethiopia. 

Natural disasters and conflict are recurrent phenomena in most parts of Ethiopia. These disasters are major causes of displacement for large numbers of people and result in loss of human life and assets, disruption of livelihoods and damage to basic services and infrastructure. According to the DTM (Displacement Tracking Matrix) Round 10, conducted nationwide in April 2018, a total of 274,765 HH representing 1,613,436 individuals, are in a situation of internal displacement in various regions of Ethiopia. The highest rates of displacement are reported in Somali (46.3%), Oromia (43%), Tigray (4%), Afar (3.4%), Gambella (0.9%), Dire Dawa (0.9%), Addis Ababa (0.7%), Amhara (0.5%), and Hareri (0.3%) regions respectively. The primary drivers of displacement across the country include conflict (67%), drought (31%) and other factors including flash floods (2%). Of the total displaced 51 % are women and 49 % are male.   

Starting from the mid of April 2018, new conflict between Guji and Gedeo zones of Oromia and SNNP regions led to the displacement of over 642,152 IDPs in Gedeo zone of SNNPR region and 176,098 IDPs in West Guji zone of Oromia region. In Gedeo, IDPs are dispersed across Bule (38,459 IDPs in one site), Dilla Zuria (12,751 IDPs living with host communities), Gedeb (306,572 IDPs in three sites), Kochere (82,423 IDPs living with host communities), Wonago (32,784), Yirgachefe (106,832 IDPs in four sites) woredas and Dilla Town (62,511 IDPs in one &#x201C;collective&#x201D; type center). In West Guji, some 176,098 IDPs remain in Abaya (9,377 IDPs), Birbirsa Kojowa (9,767 IDPs), Bule Hora (15,330 IDPs), Gelana (43,224 IDPs), Hambela Wamena (29,086 IDPs) and Kercha (69,264 IDPs) woredas. This is the second large-scale wave of violence that has hit the area since April 2018 &#x2013; where at least 274,548 people were initially displaced in Gedeo and some 84,000 people in West Guji. Around 33% of the IDPs in West Guji are ethnic Gedeos. Within the first two weeks of displacement, the Oromia and SNNP regional authorities agreed to facilitate the return of all the IDPs to their respec&#xAC;tive areas of origin by end of April, and to provide assistance in areas of return. Most of the IDPs are living with host communities. The Government, local community and humanitarian partners including IRC provided some assistance. However, the responses so far are very limited compared to the needs.  On the other hand, IRC has also identified critical gaps in Bale IDPs sites where our interventions are currently on going but probably end at end of July 2018 due to limited resources mobilized for the Gedeo-Guji conflict.

The project will be implemented through direct intervention by the IRC by identifying the gaps in three IDPs districts of the Bale zone and coordinating with other agencies including UNICEF and government organizations in the WASH Cluster members. 

This project aims to address critical gaps of WASH services needs in IDPs sites and host communities through rehabilitation of Water schemes, emergency water tracking, Distribution of Water treatment Chemicals, dignity kits, WAH NFIs and improving the sanitation and hygiene practices in IDPs sites establishment of one surface water treatment site at one of the IDP site for water tracking to support the water need of IDPs during drought  and host community needs and improve the water quality monitoring of the government partners. The current situations in IDPs sites is worsening due to the depletion of rain in the area and shortage of budget sources. The current IRC intervention in Lagahidha and Dawe Serar will be end at the end of this</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marijana Simic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251116630479</telephone>
   <email>Marijana.Simic@rescue.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-22">301125.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-22">298636.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-9622">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-22">599761.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303516875">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">479809.43</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304097767">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-12">91785.51</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Rescue Committee INC</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
