<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-18/DDA-3379/RA1/NFI/ES/INGO/10963</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter/NFI Emergency Response in Deder and Babile Woredas of East Hararghe Zone, Oromia Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRS and its longstanding partner, the Ethiopian Catholic Church and Social Development Coordinating Office of Hararghe (ECC-SDCOH) will implement the Emergency Shelter/NFI Emergency Response in East Hararghe, targeting populations affected by internal displacement due to civil conflict. The civil conflict has resulted in complex movements of Somali and Oromo people and due to unrest and fears amongst ethnic Oromos living in Djibouti. These events have resulted in this destruction of basic infrastructure in borderland communities with over 144,000 displaced. The woredas are still characterized by turbulence, and the number of IDPs is still increasing, leading to a shortage of housing across the area.

The project will target 1,030 vulnerable IDP households (5,150 individuals), in Deder and Babile woredas. The project will provide transitional shelter to 1,030 households in the woredas and support another 135 households in Babile and Deder with non-food items(NFI), either in-kind or in-cash. In consultation with EHF/OCHA, the scope of the shelter construction may be expanded to also address the extensive IDP needs across the region and the country.

Given the scale of the response, diverse needs of the IDPs, and varying amounts of available land, three types of shelters will be constructed:

Individual transitional shelter (Type 1):
The 3m by 5m transitional shelter with and eucalyptus structure frame, CGI sheet covered roof and walls has a lockable door and one closable windows, and internal partition. CRS/ECC-SDCOH worked with beneficiary communities, through focus group discussions, shelter re-design and construction pilots to better understand local preferences. Families with more than eight members will be considered as two HH units. (Please see Annex 1 for design)

Partition cubicle with elevated platform (Type 2):
The 4m by 3m cubicle with 2m high partition has a eucalyptus frame and CGI sheet for wall and door. This space has a covered living space of 17.4m2 including the elevated platform area which will serve as sleeping area, and underneath will serve as storage space for beneficiary&#x2019; personal belongings. Type 2 shelters are intended to decongest overcrowding inside existing collective centers. (Please see Annex 2 for design)

One-block, 20 units transitional shelter (Type 3):
Type 3 transitional shelter is constructed in a row of 10 transitional shelters, back to back for a total of 20 transitional shelters for one block. The 3m by 5m transitional shelter has a eucalyptus structure frame, CGI sheet covered roof and wall (partition and external wall), a lockable door and one closable window. This shelter design is adapted to informal settlement compound where number of household exceeded the space covered living area for individual transitional shelter. In most cases, displaced people in informal compound belongs to one clan. (Please see Annex 3 for design)

To improve the sustainability of shelter construction, CRS/ECC-SDCOH will provide 10 construction techniques and skills trainings for 150 IDPs, and engage a Housing, Land, and Property Officer to ensure that land agreements are developed for both the safety of the landlords and IDPs.  

In addition, CRS/ECC-SDCOH will provide NFIs per cluster standards or cash transfers in accordance with Sphere standards and with guidance from the inter-agency Ethiopia Cash Working Group CRS/ECC-SDCOH to provide a one-time unconditional cash transfer of with a value of $163/ household for the purchase of NFIs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopian Catholic Church and Social Development Coordinating Office of Hararghe (ECC-SDCOH)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zemede Zewdie</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Programs</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911507305</telephone>
   <email>zemede.zewdie@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-12-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-19">23066.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-19">175745.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-04-29">0</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-10963">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-19">198812.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303752864">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">198812.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
