<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH-18/DDA-3379/RA1/WASH/INGO/10205</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Emergency Response in Babile Woreda of East Harraghe Zone, Oromia Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The WASH Emergency Response in East Hararghe will target populations affected by twin crises of drought and IDP displacement due to civil conflict. The drought is part of a long-term trend in the region that is witnessing more frequent and longer duration droughts in recent years. The civil conflict has resulted in displacement of both Somali and Oromo people with some destruction of basic infrastructure in borderland communities. With the current conflicts, in Babile woreda alone, over 55,984 (male 27,427 and female 28,557) people have been displaced from Dere Arba, berkele, Gemechu, Abdulkadir, Lekole and Tulo Haro Kebeles. The woreda is still under a state of unrest and the influx is increasing. The people are settled in  
1.	Medresa and Haromaya university research camp (2 sites) with total people of 15,598
2.	Mission compound and Woreda administration (2 sites) with total of 12,346 
3.	Primary and high school (2 sites) with a total of 12,900 and
4.	The host community with total of 15,140 people in Dere arba,Tulu Haro, Berkele, Gemechu, Abdulkadir, and Lekole Kebeles
The influx of IDPs has increased the stress on existing water facilities, as they are now serving both host communities and displaced populations in Babile. The influx has also worsened environmental sanitation problems, particular excreta management, which puts host and IDP populations at elevated risk of infectious acute watery diarrhea.  Most people are displaced from the above kebeles and existing schemes are damaged and needs rehabilitation.
The proposed project will improve access to water supply, improve environmental sanitation and hygiene behaviors for at risk populations in Babile.  CRS and its longstanding partner, the Ethiopian Catholic Church and Social Development Coordinating office of Hararghe (ECC-SDCOH) will engage with woreda officials and local community leaders while also mobilizing the health Development Army and Health Extension Workers.The proposed project will target a population of 25,659 people, including both IDP and host communities in Babile woreda of East Hararghe. CRS and ECC-SDCOH will implementin locations in which both organizations have an active current presence through the USAID-Food for Peace funded Development Food Security Activity (DFSA). 
The project aims to work
1.	Distribute water through water trucking for IDPs in the Medresa and Haromaya IDP camp (15,598 IDPs) for 45 days followed by installation of 10 m3 Roto and distribution of water points, five distribution point at each camp. 
2.	Distribute 93,588 water chemicals (Sachet) for 3120 HHs of IDPS in Babile town
3.	 Drill three new shallow wells, one at Bishan Babile and two at Tulu Haro (Weltei and Hassan sites) for IDPs in the host community and host community.
4.	  Rehabilitation of nine existing shallow wells by replacing damaged hand pumps with new afridave pumps at, Berkele (Sali, Omer and Jango sites), Gemechu (Ali, Weday and Rewbere sites), Abdulkadir (Sela site), Lekole (Haji site) and Tulu Haro (Weltei site) for IDPS in the host community and host community. 
5.	The drilling and rehabilitation of boreholes will address the 15,140 IDPs in the host community.
6.	Additionally, the project will replace the generator of a scheme at Dere Arba Kebele for IDPs and Host community.
7.	 Once the three new wells and 10 rehabilitated wells are completed, the project will provide management training to local WASH Committees.
As part of a hygiene promotion campaign the WASH response will also raise general awareness of the targeted 30,738 individuals through campaigns and hygiene promotion events. Targeted distribution of point of use water treatment chemicals and hygiene kits (soap, buckets, wash basin, jerrycans) will go to families who are considered most at risk of AWD due to their water source and excreta management facilities. The hygiene promotion campaign and distributions will be implemented through the HDA/HEW network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECC-SDCOH Hararghe Catholic Secretariete</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zemede Abebe</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Program</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+251911507305</telephone>
   <email>zemede.zewdie@crs.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ET04">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oromia</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.50798643 38.76521270</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-01">124329.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-01">248658.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="2400278360">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-06">38856.42</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="ETH53-10205">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-01">372987.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303647117">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-07">372987.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Relief Services</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-ETH53-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
