<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=MAL/12/01/MAL" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-103486-1486-2015-MYS177</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Jobs Malaysia Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will take a tripartite approach to provide ILO constituents and national stakeholders, including the Ministry of Energy, Green Technology and Water (KeTTHA) in Malaysia, with a clearer understanding of the prevalence of green jobs across the economy and sectors, promote an exchange of information and social dialogue on green jobs policies and identify possible entry points for further green job creation. The study will assess the economy-employment and economy-environment linkages at the national level and map existing green jobs in the Malaysian labour market. Through the building and use of a Green Dynamic Social Accounting Matrix (DYSAM) via expansions and extension, the employment and environmental impacts of environment driven policies in Malaysia will be simulated. Several modelling scenarios will be conducted with a view to generating new socio-economic data at the national level on employment (green jobs), income distribution, and CO2 emissions. The purpose of this study is to provide an estimate of the number of green jobs, the level of economic activity that is dependent on the environment in Malaysia and the employment impact of environment related policies. It supports wider efforts by governments, employers and trade unions to promote sustainable development in a resource scarce and climate-challenged world. A steering committee will be established with representatives from ILO, relevant ministries including the Ministry of Energy, Green Technology and Water (KeTTHA), the social partners (MEF, MTUC), international consultants and academia to guide and monitor the implementation of the project. The results of the study will show statistically the links between environmental policies and the economy and the impacts on employment. It will also involve the evaluation of the socio-economic impacts of environment driven policies with a view to preparing the ground for green skills anticipation in key sectors of the Malaysian economy. A practical pilot on skills development will be conducted through the application and implementation of the 11 occupational skills standards in selected sectors and enterprises. The results of the pilot will allow for revising and finalizing these occupational standards for future training on green skills and developing the testing and certification mechanisms. These standards will be published and disseminated as the first official set of green skills national occupational standards for Malaysia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="MY">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="MY" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="MY" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">177645</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="MAL/12/01/MAL-2015-MYS177 - Increased engagement by employers&apos; and workers&apos; organizations in future skills development and national employment policy-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">177645</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia, Ministry of Human Resources, Social Security Organization</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="MAL/12/01/MAL-2015-MYS177 - Increased engagement by employers&apos; and workers&apos; organizations in future skills development and national employment policy">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">177645</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=MAL/12/01/MAL">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Green Jobs Malaysia Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
