<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=BRA/14/02/JTI" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105008-306542-2015-BRA126</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ARISE II: Programme to Reduce the Worst Forms of Child Labour in Tobacco Producing Communities in Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of project Strategy Based on the lessons learned from the first phase, it has become clear that to further the sustainable reduction in child labour in family farming, and consolidate the results obtained during the first phase of implementation, a number of issues need to be addressed at the state and national levels, where new public policies must be developed and implemented. From 2015 onwards, it will be possible to build national strategies for facing child labour in family farming, through actions that integrate Federal and State Governments and workers&#x2019; and employers&#x2019; organizations. Working at this level will also increase the scope and impact of the project and produce results which goes beyond the target municipalities and communities of the ARISE programme, while at the same time ensuring its visibility and credibility. Efficient advocacy actions are at the center of the national and regional dialogue, awareness and mobilization policy. Central to the project in this regard is the planning and organization of processes of dialogue aimed at the elaboration, approval and implementation of laws and public policies to improve education and work in communities where there is family farming. These actions will be developed at three different levels: &#x2022; Civil Society - Partner identification and mobilization - Participation and dialogue with networks - Mobilization &#x2022; Executive Power, Legislative Power and Judiciary Power - Mapping and identification of organs and key actors in the decision-making process - Preparation and planning for the contact with public authorities - Dialogue and the proposal of new laws and public policies &#x2022; Awareness of opinion leaders using media - Creation of effective messages - Identification of different means of communication and partners In this new phase, the ILO will invest in National and State policies to regulate, with the help of the Federal and State Government, on two different fronts: education and work. New regulations in these areas are fundamental to strengthen the school-to-work transition in rural areas. The access to quality and contextualized education, development of relevant vocational training and learning activities are essential in the context of eliminating child labour in rural areas. (i) Education Today&#x2019;s education model is not suitable for rural areas, and thus do not contribute to the school-to-work transition in this environment in an optimal manner. A central element of the project strategy is therefore to engage all stakeholders in a constructive process of dialogue towards a better and more relevant rural school. The ILO will promote the establishment of a dialogue on the model of &#x201C;Pedagogy of Alternation&#x201D;, and to further develop this model which is already implemented on a pilot basis in the Southern region, but which has never been fully developed and implemented as an alternative for rural children, due to administrative en legal hurdles. Additionally the project, as implemented through the ILO component, will engage in a dialogue with the Federal Government and key stakeholders on the adjustments in the educational programs (including contents and curricula) to better suit rural schools and realities than they do today. Also the proposal for a full time school will be studied in depth and depending on the results of the analysis will be targeted for dialogue and proposals for legislative change as needed. (ii) Employment In order to contribute to the eradication of child labour in family farming areas, it is necessary to invest efforts in safe vocational training activities for teenagers aged between 14 and 17 years old, comparative to what is already taking place in urban areas. Among the challenges is that work in agriculture is inherently seen as hazardous, and by Brazilian law, all work related to the growing of tobacco is prohibited for anyone under the age of 18, there is therefore currently no real decent work options for rural youth of 16-1</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="BR">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="BR" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="BR" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">167354</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="BRA/14/02/JTI-2015-BRA126 - Implementaci&#xF3;n de pol&#xED;ticas p&#xFA;blicas y acciones sociales para eliminar el trabajo infantil fortalecidas, con especial atenci&#xF3;n a sus peores formas-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">167354</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Japan Tobacco International SA</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="BRA/14/02/JTI-2015-BRA126 - Implementaci&#xF3;n de pol&#xED;ticas p&#xFA;blicas y acciones sociales para eliminar el trabajo infantil fortalecidas, con especial atenci&#xF3;n a sus peores formas">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">167354</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16064" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=BRA/14/02/JTI">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: ARISE II: Programme to Reduce the Worst Forms of Child Labour in Tobacco Producing Communities in Brazil</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
