<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=INS/11/50/IDA" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-103133-1311-2015-IDN127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RACBP Partner Agency Costs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project INS/11/50/IDA is for the ILO&apos;s administration and supervision of the contribution for the project Rural Access and Capacity Building Nias Islands (INS/09/02/IDA), of which the summary is provided below: The Multi-Donor Fund for Aceh and North Sumatra (MDFANS) is funding two coordinated and conceptually linked projects for the Nias Islands, each with a budget of US$ 10 million. The two projects are administratively independent. Nias-RACBP focuses on the improvement of the strategic rural transport network in the three economic/agricultural clusters in Nias Islands that are targeted by Nias-LEDP (Nias Islands Livelihoods and Economic Development Project). In accordance with MDFANS&#x2019; mandate, activities that will be undertaken by Nias-RACBP will contribute to post-disaster economic recovery and poverty alleviation for the communities of Nias Islands that were affected by the tsunami and the earthquake. Nias-RACBP will be implemented through a Fiscal Agency Agreement between the World Bank and the ILO. The Project Development Objective (PDO) of Nias-RACBP is for residents of the participating districts to utilize improved rural transport infrastructure and services and to benefit from enhanced access to economic and social services and facilities. RACBP&#x2019;s two main components, that will be implemented in an integrated way, are: Construction: The main activity is the improvement of strategic rural access roads, covering the construction of about 80 kilometers of light trafficked, &#x2018;all-weather access&#x2019; district roads (3 meter wide) and rural pathways (1.5 meter wide), and the construction of 1,000 running meters of stream crossings and small bridges. Design specifications will reflect the need to minimize the long-term (10-15 years) maintenance requirements. Local resource-based approaches will be used and it is estimated that the construction activities will generate 200,000 worker-days of short-term employment. In addition, a small cultural heritage sub-component is included, aiming at contributing to the preservation of Nias&#x2019; public cultural heritage assets, through small infrastructure works in the economic clusters where Nias-RACBP will be implemented. Training and Capacity Building: This component aims at enhancing the capacity of the involved local government agencies at district and sub-district level (Public Works Department and District Planning Offices), small-scale contractors, their staff, potential future supervisors, local communities and ILO&#x2019;s own newly recruited local project staff, in the planning and delivery of investments in the rural roads network. The main delivery modality will be through on-the-job training and mentorship.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-10-26" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="ID">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="ID" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="ID" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">30183</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="INS/11/50/IDA-2015-IDN127 - Optimized employment outcomes of public and community investments-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">30183</value>
   <provider-org ref="44000">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank, International Development Association</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="INS/11/50/IDA-2015-IDN127 - Optimized employment outcomes of public and community investments">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">30183</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=INS/11/50/IDA">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: RACBP Partner Agency Costs</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
