<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=EGY/11/07/EGY" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-103459-383560-2015-EGY104</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transition to Employment:Career Guidance for Youth and Job Creation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will contribute to the development of the institutional capacity framework of public employment services. It will support a more effective and quicker transition from school to work, leading to more and better jobs for job seekers, mainly young people. To achieve this end the project will build upon a package of integrated initiatives to mobilize public employment offices, education institutions, youth associations, training providers, workers&#x2019; and employers associations and the media in selected areas. At the same time, the project intends to build on the achievements and experience of recent programmes aimed at upgrading Egypt&#x2019;s PES network. The project will also establish links with ongoing major initiatives and UN projects to upgrade Egypt&#x2019;s education and training systems. The ILO project is designed to provide all necessary information on career guidance and labour market to young people, building upon various entry points of relevant stakeholders, under the leadership of the Ministry of Manpower and Migration. It should be ensured that public employment services offices play a better role in helping young people find a decent job, thus changing the previous view of the operation of these offices. This project will establish linkages with relevant stakeholders like the Ministry of Education, youth associations, vocational training providers, workers&#x2019; and employers&#x2019; associations, and civil society; to guarantee provision of the most appropriate channels of service delivery and its sustainability after project completion. The overall Development objective of the project is that it is expected to contribute to reducing the high unemployment rate among youth, by facilitating the transition from school to work and allowing young women and men to find more and better jobs. Special emphasis will be placed on women and the disabled. The project is expected to achieve this objective through close coordination with the Ministry of Manpower and Migration and its Public Employment Services network, together with relevant stakeholders .Objective 1: Ten Pilot Youth Employment Units will have been established inside 10 PES offices and the capacity of the staff enhanced through an intensive capacity building training programme to equip them to be able to operate the PES offices and further deliver career guidance, job counseling services, job search skills and life skills to youth job seekers. PES will be more visible and utilized by youth and enterprises in selected areas. Objective 2: Youth in selected areas will have a more and better understanding of the labour market and how it functions, job opportunities available, and life skills needed in the labour market, to allow them to make better career planning and education / training choices. Objective 3: PES will be more involved in job creation schemes made with potential enterprises in project sites to promote job insertion and apprenticeship agreements to employ / train youth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="EG">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="EG" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="EG" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">426026</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="EGY/11/07/EGY-2015-EGY104 - Effective and inclusive labour market institutions that support the implementation of wage policies and the provision of employment services are reviewed, developed and strengthened-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">426026</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Italian Egyptian Debt for Development Swap Program</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EGY/11/07/EGY-2015-EGY104 - Effective and inclusive labour market institutions that support the implementation of wage policies and the provision of employment services are reviewed, developed and strengthened">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">426026</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="16020" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=EGY/11/07/EGY">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Transition to Employment:Career Guidance for Youth and Job Creation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
