<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" linked-data-uri="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/32/UNP" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41302-105388-512568-2015-CHN251</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnership for Action on Green Economy (PAGE) - Phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Partnership for Action on Green Economy (PAGE) is a 7-year programme responding to the Rio+20&#x2019;s call for the UN system to support countries interested in pursuing green economy policies. It deploys the joint expertise of five UN agencies &#x2013; ILO, UNDP, UNEP, UNIDO, and UNITAR &#x2013; to assist countries in their efforts to embark on green economy pathways. During PAGE phase II a total of eight countries will receive support, including Peru, Mongolia, Senegal, Ghana, Burkina Faso, Mauritius, South Africa and China (at provincial level). Based on the idea of triggering the required change at policy level and, more broadly, supporting countries in creating enabling conditions that catalyse the transformative change towards an Inclusive Green Economy, PAGE has identified four strategic intervention areas: (i) national economic and development planning, (ii) selected thematic and sectoral policies, individual and institutional capacity building at national and global level and (iv) knowledge creation at global level. Although phase II work plan and budget conclude by 30 June 2016, it is expected that PAGE will continue in the following years. The project&#x2019;s vision is the equitable and sustainable transformation of national economic structures in up to 30 countries over a period of 7 years. Based on the idea of triggering the required change at policy level and, more broadly, supporting countries in creating enabling conditions that catalyse the transformative change towards an Inclusive Green Economy, PAGE has identified four strategic intervention areas: i. National economic and development planning processes: PAGE supports countries to integrate and reinforce inclusive green economy (IGE) into their national economic and development planning processes. ii. Selected sectoral/thematic policy analysis and subsequent policy reforms: PAGE provides on-going advisory support to countries as they design and advance sectoral and/or thematic policies, strategies and plans. Because of the critical importance of investment as a driver in the system of transformation, PAGE mobilizes IGE financing partners such as UNCT, donors, IFIs and the private sector. iii. Capacity development of key individuals and institutions for IGE action at the national and international level: PAGE strengthens national institutional capacities to participate, contribute, and implement in the overall process at the country level; it develops tailored training programmes that respond to national priorities and creates global leadership and training opportunities to communicate to a wider audience and multiply effects. iv. Knowledge creation for IGE action: PAGE generates and shares IGE knowledge products through North-South-South collaboration to encourage more understanding and engagement globally in the IGE processes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41302" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Labour Organization (ILO)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARDEV</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>PARDEV@ilo.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ilo.org/pardev/lang--en/index.htm</website>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="CN">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="CN" vocabulary="A4"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
   </name>
   <administrative code="CN" level="0" vocabulary="A4"></administrative>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
  </location>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-03"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2522</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/32/UNP-2015-CHN251 - Labour market information system improved to provide employment quality related data-2">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-03">2522</value>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-41116">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Environment Programme</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="GLO/15/32/UNP-2015-CHN251 - Labour market information system improved to provide employment quality related data">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-03">2522</value>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="91010" vocabulary="1"></sector>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://www.ilo.org/DevelopmentCooperationDashboard/#project_symbol=GLO/15/32/UNP">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development Cooperation Dashboard Project Page: Partnership for Action on Green Economy (PAGE) - Phase II</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
