<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>PH-SEC-CN200340507-FGG3</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="PH-SEC-CN200340507" secondary-reporter="1" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Samdhana Institute</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fair, Green and Global Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Fair, Green and Global Alliance (FGG) aims to increase the power and decision-making influence of organised, mobilised and informed civil society, especially women, to advance fair and green trade and value chains. FGG believes that poverty, inequality and exclusion are caused by power asymmetries. We see the unprecedented power of capital over people and planet as the primary obstacle impeding realisation of fair and green trade and value chains. The FGG programme focuses on recalibrating power within the global architecture of trade and value chains by amplifying the voices of targeted rights-holders &#x2013;  small producers and traders, workers, fishers, rural and Indigenous peoples, religious and ethnic minorities, and migrants, especially the women and youth among them &#x2013; who are practising, claiming or defending human rights and fair and green economic practices, and/or whose rights are being ignored, threatened or violated by corporations and/or governments. We aim to transform social relations so that these rights-holders&#x2019; voices are heard and heeded. FGG&#x2019;s eight members (ActionAid, Both ENDS, Clean Clothes Campaign, IT for Change, Milieudefensie/Friends of the Earth International/Friends of the Earth Europe, Samdhana Institute, SOMO and the Transnational Institute) cooperate with some 1000+ partners and allies in our many worldwide networks to strengthen collective capacities to advance a common vision of fair and green trade and value chains.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41210098" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Both ENDS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="PH-SEC-CN200340507" role="2" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Samdhana Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="PH-SEC-CN200340507" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Samdhana Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2025-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Samdhana Institute</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>erwin@samdhana.org</email>
   <website>http://www.samdhana.org/</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="8"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="LA" percentage="15"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="5"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="45"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="7"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">508045</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">508045</value>
  </budget>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-7-PPR-4000004332" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">agenda-setting, momentum-building and increased support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors (government, private sector, other) who put FGG policy/practice recommendations on their agendas (e.g. meetings, debates, media coverage)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="17"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021, the GTRA (local agrarian reform task force) in Indonesia conducted for the first time a  dialogue with the indigenous communities of Rhepang Muaif which raised both parties&#x2019; determination to pursue recognition and protection of their territory. Samdhana organised the Menoken di Tabi that invited the GTRA to participate. The GTRA will lead in the tenure right assessment in Jayapura Regency; the GTRA held an MOU or a joint commitment to collaborate on the acceleration of the indigenous peoples land  rights  recognition and official registration . 

In 2021, officials from 3 agencies: National Commission on Indigenous Peoples (NCIP) &#x2013; Region 10, Department of Agrarian Reform (DAR), and Department of Environment and Natural Resources (DENR) &#x2013; Region 10 addressed the concerns and petitions of Indigenous Menuvu community in southern  part of Bukidnon Province to resolve several overlapping tenurial instruments particularly on Ancestral Domain claim: integrated social forestry issued by the DENR; and Certificate of Land Ownership Award issued by the DAR. These offices provided various information that was requested by the community which was necessary for them to build up their case, and agreed to conduct further investigation and dialogues.  Samdhana contributed to this by providing mobilisation support to community partners.

In 2021, key actors in the Philippines expressed increased interest in  IPLCs issues and challenges during and after the national Fork-to-Farm dialogues and the partnership meetings, as the following below: 

The Department of Agriculture (DA) official expressed to support smallholder farmers, especially to indigenous communities, and identified areas of collaboration such as training needs analysis and starter kits for demo farm and product development, capacity development (seed bank, marketing), and financing.

The Climate Change Commission (CCC) representative remained open to having follow-up discussions and publicly suggested the idea of learning exchanges between the Commission and IP communities so that the government can enhance its understanding of how IP practices actually address climate change.

A Researcher, official representative from the Food and Nutrition Research Institute (FNRI) of the Department of Science and Technology (DOST) acknowledged that the food system issues have to be addressed and traditional food systems are important if we want to have a sustainable and healthy food production. In a follow-up discussion about this they expressed interest in exploring how this office can help the partner IPLCs.

A dean from a state university, during the public webinar and in a follow-up meeting after the Fork-to-Farm dialogue expressed interest in  future opportunities for collaboration such as providing scholarships to IP youth studying in Food Science and Technology, and research collaborations on community commodities. Samdhana is building up linkages to academe in provinces with high Indigenous populace for future collaborations, and increase the pool of institutions that can provide technical support to IPLCs.

In August 2021, the Deputy for Entrepreneurship of the Ministry of Cooperatives and Small-Medium Enterprises in Indonesia attended the online local  and national Fork-to-Farm dialogues organized by Samdhana. She expressed support during the dialogue to have  collaboration of rural and urban groups for agricultural and food production, especially to address the needs in the time of the pandemic (link to the zoom webinar). She helped to provide useful information to youth entrepreneurs in healthy food production and reference letters, for the latter&#x2019;s legal registration. The  key actor was also keen to have follow up discussions to engage all Samdhana programs particularly on agricultural and food production and livelihood.  

In 2021, because of the increased knowledge and capacities of local farmers to sustain agroecology practices and demonstrate this through their farmer group, a  town legislative councilor in Misamis Oriental, Philippines offered to support the organic farmers in the future marketing of their organic products, specifically offering them with a space at the town market  to display organic products. This response from the Councilor was after he learned about the self start-up initiatives and visited the local organic farmers group, whose members had increased, especially with the support from the FGG small grant. The progress of the local farmers helped to convince the Town Councilor on the potential of organic farming, which was being introduced to the town by an Agro-Ecology organization years before.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">agenda-setting, momentum-building and increased support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4x</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the recommendation a key actor puts on its agenda aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">agenda-setting, momentum-building and increased support</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">4g</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the recommendation a key actor puts on its agenda aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021, through Samdhana&#x2019;s urgent action grant for COVID response that was coursed through a partner CSO working in East Kalimantan, the Indonesia&#x2019;s Ministry of Health increased allocation of vaccines for indigenous communitiesm not only in Apokayan (a place) but also in other remote areas like West Kalimantan, Maluku and Mentawai in Sumatra. The timing of the grant triggered discussions on the need to improve government health services especially for IP communities

In 2021, the village-level local government unit (LGU) in Misamis Oriental, Philippines formally recognised the indigenous Higaonon women&#x2019;s group, giving their organisation more access to programs offered by the government. They also recognised that the Higaonon group is not involved in communist-related activities, which the Local Government Unit is wary of (because of the aggressive red-tagging policy of the government) FGG and Samdhana supported the community&#x2019;s mobilisations and conducted courtesy visit to the LGU to present our project and programs that supported the women&#x2019;s group. (g)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021, the Governor of Bengkulu in Indonesia issued recommendations for resolving land use rights conflicts. This is the result of farmers&#x2019; lobbying, and the recommendation is to establish a GTRA to resolve land conflicts in the district, with the GTRA mandated to resolve the PT land use rights conflict immediately. Samdhana supported the farmer union&#x2019;s work through grants.

In 2021, at least four key actors: Municipal local government unit, barangay (village) local government unit in  Misamis Oriental, NCIP offices, and Provincial &amp; Municipal IPMRs, convened and co-organized a dialogue between the Tribal Council and  private land sellers and/or buyers to resolve the arising land conflicts. They organized this upon the request of the Tribal Council, and in recognition that the tribe has ownership of the land  and has the right to regulate the entry of businesses that intend to operate  within the domain. Concrete steps were addressed for each specific case represented by the private individuals who attended the dialogue. The presence of the Local Government Units (LGU) are crucial as most non-IPs defer to the LGU authorities, while the presence of the NCIP, as the main mediating body is also vital.  This dialogue is a result of the tribe&#x2019;s continuous engagement with these agencies for their rights to be recognised as enshrined in the IPRA. Samdhana supported the community leaders&#x2019; gatherings and mobilisations. 

In 2021, the Head of Jayapura Regency, Papua Province in Indonesia publicly called for the protection and development of Jayapura and Yotoro Hill. This is a result of his participation in the Menoken di Tabi, a community gathering, and knowledge exchange facilitated by Samdhana in coordination with other local organisations. The GTMA had a MOU or joint commitment in GTRA for the first time in Papua Province; that will raised both parties determination to pursue a recognition and protection of their territory.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Cx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Cg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Cx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">C</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments increasing democratic decision-making</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Cg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target for 2021</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021, the National Human Rights Commission (KomNas HAM) in Indonesia supported the research and documentation of human rights violations of the Orang Rimba caused and/or resulting from the entry of the oil company, in cooperation with the local CSO that is supporting the Orang Rimba group. KomNas HAM was part of the research and documentation team. Samdhana contributed to this by providing a grant to the local CSO.

In 2021, local and provincial government units attended the conflict resolution process of the Menuvu community as support to the petitions from the IP community and through the IPMRs L &amp; A at the village legislative council.  This resulted in the contractor company paying the equivalent penalty for destroying parts of a sacred body of water during the construction of a government road project. Samdhana contributed to this by providing mobilisation support to the community.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Dx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target for 2021</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Dg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target for 2021</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Dx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">D</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments regulating the private sector</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Dg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6F</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No  result yet for this indicator</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5F</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No result yet for this indicator</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Fx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No result yet for this sub- indicator</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Fg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No result yet for this sub - indicator</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Fx</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No result yet for this indicator</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">F</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Fg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No result yet for this indicator</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6SCS1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of laws, policies and norms, implemented for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target for 2021</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCS</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">governments, government-backed agencies, donors, private sector actors increasing policy space and support for fair and green practices</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6SCS2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of laws, policies and norms/attitudes, blocked, adopted, improved for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No target for 2021</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># instances in which key actors adopt and/or implement FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># key actors who support and/or promote FGG policy/practice recommendations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Ex</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">6Eg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the adopted and/or implemented policies/practices by key actors contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Ex</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a key actor aims to contribute to expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">E</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">private sector actors respecting human rights and the environment</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">5Eg</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of instances in which the supported and/or promoted recommendation by a partner aims to contribute to gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Process</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">process</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">l</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">learning sessions organised by FGG members and partner organisations</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Learning was a continuous process internally and externally throughout the year. Internally, Samdhana was able to hold sessions with all Program teams to learn how our work aligns with the FGG Theory of Change, and how the language of trade and value chains translate to or link with Samdhana&#x2019;s areas of work. We reflected on how Samdhana is supporting Partners, and how Partners lobby and advocate. The orientations provided by the Coordination Team assisted us in determining the outcomes of our support and groundwork. Through these discussions and reflections on our roles and those of our Partners, we, particularly the Philippines team, were able to recognize that government agencies play an important role in the work. Learning sessions and one-on-one online meetings with new partners, especially those from Cambodia and Myanmar, deepened staff members&apos; understanding of context and analysis on key issues such as tenure and resource governance. Part of the internal learning is equipping the staff through a four-part workshop on Mental Health and Psycho-social Support (MHPSS) was designed to address internal staff needs following a year-long personal and professional struggle with the COVID-19 pandemic. This was done in recognition of the fact that, while Samdhana was able to work exceptionally well during the pandemic, staff were also vulnerable to the mental stress and anxiety that the pandemic generally caused. Externally, Samdhana staff and Partners continue a dynamic exchange of lessons and insights in our engagement with them. &#x201C;Menoken&#x201D; was an avenue for building interpersonal relationships beyond work or project-related concerns; it fostered exchange of personal stories especially those that motivate people to protect the environment, stand up for their rights and promote their cultures. It provided experiential learning through exchange of products, local culinary arts and crafts. The several sessions on strategic planning or visioning and problem analysis/ assessment with community partners were also avenues to learn of their context and history, their assessment and tactics to address their problems and what they aspire for. With indigenous partners, staff are continuously learning and re-calibrating our use of terms to adopt the local language, and encourage the community to put forth their own model of governance, and not limit it to only what is common today in structures of people organizations or State government. We were also challenged to learn how to maximize communications, especially for IPLC youth who are internet- and gadget-savvy and we continue to explore the online platforms that will be useful for us.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Process</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">process</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">g</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">lines of work in which FGG members and partners build upon gender analysis and incorporate gender justice in their strategy</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff in the Philippines-Mekong operations had an orientation on the Gender Equity and Social Inclusion (GESI) framework to further mainstream it across the programs, especially in the context of tenure rights. During the sessions, Staff realized that we have been putting less emphasis on probing the gender situation at the community level. One example is that we do not actively disaggregate statistics, like how many women actually control the land or resources within their collective ancestral domain. One resolution was for the team to prepare better probing questions to surface the gender situation or specific needs of peoples with different abilities. Staff have been practicing basic gender sensitivity, and we improved on those practices. One is ensuring that there is women-to-women facilitation of community discussions and planning activities. We have observed and believe that community women are more free to voice out their concerns when there are no men present. Thus, several female staff are usually designated to handle these sessions. We are more conscious in logistics preparation and program design to increase accessibility and participation for persons with different needs. We also encourage this same consciousness to community partners when they are organizing their own activities. During one Samdhana team discussion, the issue of GESI in conflict resolution was raised, and it was acknowledged that very few of the staff have formal training on conflict resolution, even while we deal with many conflicts in the line of work.

Organisational strengthening of different Indigenous peoples organisations within ancestral domains take into account the important role of women and youth in decision-making processes. Part of Samdhana&#x2019;s work is ensuring that women and youth formations within the ancestral domains are supported. In 2021, this was done by facilitating visioning and planning workshops and learning sessions on leadership and women&#x2019;s rights. This resulted in the women and youth formations&#x2019; increased confidence to articulate their vision and aspirations for their own development within their domains&#x2019; decision-making structures.Samdhana recognises the important role of women as producers of healthy food in the community, and as such, has been providing platforms where they can freely express and exercise their agency in terms of contributing to the meeting the needs of the family. The Fork-to-Farm local and global dialogues engaged with women where they showcased their knowledge, skills and challenges as producers in the community. Women-led livelihood initiatives are also being supported through trainings (turmeric processing, weaving, etc.) and networking and exchanging products (Menoken di Tabi). For this year, we increased our effort to be more inclusive to deaf people by incorporating an American Sign Language interpretation during the webinar-dialogue series on food systems.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Process</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">process</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">o</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">the extent to and ways in which FGG involves local groups in the design and implementation of the FGG programme</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through the FGG support, we started to widen our reach in the Lower Mekong region, in particular by reaching out to new local CSO partners in Cambodia, Thailand, Myanmar and Laos. FGG support was provided through small grantsmaking to these partners, and as such, all projects have been planned and determined by the Partner themselves. We consult with proponents and facilitate that proposals will be improved so that their ideas will be expressed in a clearer manner on the paper proposal. Design of capacity building activities are usually based on needs expressed by community partners, such as the need for crafting their strategic plan or providing a financial literacy training. We hold feedback sessions with community partners and leaders to assess project activities that had been conducted. Communication lines to Samdhana staff are open and this increases the access of community partners to Samdhana where there is open and timely exchange of information that also help us to make informed decisions in relation to the implementation. For the Regional Youth Menoken, we created the youth working groups and allowed each team to design their own program, with minimum guidance from Samdhana; thus the youth were the ones who identified the topics that were shared and discussed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs included in the FGG programme</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="46"></target>
     <actual value="97">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors that lobby and advocate for improved policies and practices in trade and value chains and advance fair and green practices based on capacities mutually developed</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
     <actual value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021, the farmer&#x2019;s union from Bengkulu, Indonesia (1) used their capacity to produce evidence (land parcel maps and land management plans) to support efforts to claim their cultivated land through the country&#x2019;s agrarian reform, and with this strengthened capacity they were able to submit their developed land parcel maps and land management plan to the Ministry of Agrarian Affairs and Spatial Planning/National Land Agency (ATR/BPN) through the Bengkulu Province Agrarian Reform Task Force (GTRA). Samdhana supported this initiative through a small grant which facilitated and supported the farmer union&#x2019;s network on the legalisation of farmer&#x2019;s managed lands specifically on land use rights.

In 2021, one IP community in Cambodia (1) who received training and technical advice from a partner CSO used their strengthened capacity to effectively assert their prior rights to the communal land versus the private company and to enable the community to engage with three ministries (Ministry of Rural Development, Ministry of Interior, and Ministry of Land) relevant in granting communal land titles. It also helped the community to present their research output as evidence against the private company to the central government. Samdhana supported this through small grants to the CSO that provided the trainings and technical support.

In 2021, a local organisation in Indonesia (1) used its strengthened knowledge on evidence building and lobbying for land conflict resolution by conducting a research on the historical marginalisation to a Palm Oil Company of Orang Rimba&#x2019;s IPs becoming displaced in Jambi Province. This case will be presented in the Agrarian Reform (GTRA) summit to find permanent solution for these semi-nomad communities in the upland as well as for the sea nomad. Samdhana supported this initiative through a small grant coursed through a partner CSO that conducted an assessment research in preparation for mediation between the IP community and the palm oil company. 

In 2021, one IP partner (1) in the Philippines with strengthened organisational capacities become more proactive in submitting community resolutions and initiating dialogues with government agencies on issues of overlapping tenurial instruments within their ancestral domain. Samdhana contributed to this change by facilitating linkages with other individual partners and networks, communications support and supporting their IPS (Indigenous Political Structure) gatherings and mobilisations. 
In 2021, one IP partner (1) in the Philippines with strengthened organisational capacities from the trainings and especially on the refresher course on IP mandatory representation and Free, Prior, and Informed Consent successfully lobby with the Barangay (village) and Provincial Local government units their complaint against a construction company for implementing a road construction project without a proper process to seek FPIC and submitted letters and petitions to the Department of Agrarian Reform (DAR) to question list of beneficiaries that were granted with Certificate of Land Ownership (CLOA) to &#x201C;redistribute&#x201D; the lands that were within their government &#x2013; recognised ancestral domain. Samdhana contributed to this by supporting mobilisations of the community and by facilitating linkages with other individual partners and networks, communications support and supporting their IPS (Indigenous Political Structure) gatherings. The IP partner also used its strengthened communication and advocacy skills on traditional food systems during the national and global dialogue and have participated in the State of the Indigenous Peoples Address were they raised their concerns particularly on tenurial insecurity. 

In September 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) used their increased knowledge in asserting their cultural governance to challenge the entry of migrants inside their domain, and to assert their right to regulate the entry of and requirement of FPIC for corporate businesses that will operate in their ancestral domain. Through their unified Indigenous Political Structure (IPS) the tribe continuously engaged the government agencies responsible, which resulted into a dialogue between ancestral domain leaders and private land sellers and/or buyers within their territory. The tribe asserted their right that ancestral domain lands cannot be sold to other private individuals or companies; and that businesses and corporations need to adhere to the FPIC process. Samdhana continues to support this Partner for their gatherings and mobilisations, and provides guidance/ mentoring, inputs on the IPRA and resource management laws, linkage to other agencies, and facilitate other capacity development or learning exchange opportunities. The IP partner also raised their issues and concerns on tenurial insecurity during the State of the Indigenous Peoples Address in July 2021. 

In 2021, a partner from the Philippines (1) used its strengthened knowledge to communicate their struggle against land grabbing through video documentation, which was then presented in a multi-sectoral webinar that helped to highlight the struggles of IPs against private companies and development aggression during a COP26 side-event. Samdhana provided technical support for video production and facilitated the IPLC&#x2019;s participation to the event.

In 2021, because of the gained knowledge and increased awareness on planning and organisational management, the members of a farmers&#x2019; cooperative in Southeast Asia   (1) documented and created their forest restoration roadmap as basis for a multistakeholder cooperation and community-based governance for rattan production. Samdhana supported the cooperative through a grant to a local NGO for them to promote a multi &#x2013; stakeholder cooperation and community-based management for sustainable forest rattan production.   The local NGO facilitated capacity building activities such as budgeting, work plans, and business plans to strengthen the cooperative&apos;s capacity. They also facilitated the cooperative&apos;s connection with other stakeholders.

In November 2021, 4  IPLC farmers, youth, and practitioners in Indonesia and Philippines  (1 &#x2013; Indonesia, 1 &#x2013; Laos and 2  &#x2013; Philippines) used its strengthened communication and advocacy skills to share with national and international partners about their identity, traditional food systems, culture and practices during the local and global dialogues conducted in partnership with Fork-to-Farm Network. Samdhana provided technical support on video production and facilitated the IPLCs&#x2019; participation to the event.

 In 2021, a partner in Southern Bukidnon, Philippines (1), which represented at least 5 sub-tribes of the Arumanon Menuvu tribe, submitted a petition letter to the Office of the Senate President to express their position on vaccination. They are also able to provide more timely responses and correspondence to local and national government agencies as a result of their increased communications capacities. Samdhana provided digital tools and training to IPLCs. The partner was able to raised their concerns during the State of the Indigenous Peoples Address in July 2021.  

In July 2021, four  partner IPLCs in the Philippines (4) raised their issues and concerns on: mining, agribusiness, armed conflict dams, and tenurial security and identified their electoral agenda for the 2022 national elections, and produced a formal declaration of calls and commitments on their rights assertion and protection. Samdhana supported the partner NGO that organised the event through a grant.

 In 2021, one IP community in Southern Bukidnon, Philippines (1), successfully asserted their traditional/ culture-based selection process over the political manoeuvring of local politicians who do not recognize Indigenous peoples rights, for the selection of the Indigenous Peoples Mandatory Representative (IPMR) to the local legislative council. The traditional selection process  involved the discernment and nomination of clan members and Elders, that gives genuine legitimacy and mandate to the IPMR. This assertion is a result of their increased understanding of their rights to participation in governance. Samdhana supported their meetings and mobilisation.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="14"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2x</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors with strengthened capacities contributing to and/or relevant for lobby and advocacy aiming at expanding/defending civic space</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors with strengthened capacities for lobbying and advocacy</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="89">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021, a farmer&#x2019;s union in Mukomuko Regency in Bengkulu, Indonesia (1) strengthened its capacity to produce evidence (land parcel maps and land management plan) to support efforts to reclaim their cultivated land through the country&#x2019;s agrarian reform program. Samdhana supported this initiative through a grant to a local NGO (1), which facilitated and supported the farmer union&#x2019;s work.

In 2021, an Indigenous community in Preah Vihear, Cambodia (1) strengthened its capacity to establish its organisational formation and legal identity. Youth from the community also strengthened their capacity in data collection through participatory action research on overlapping claims with a private land concession. The technical advice on what information the community should produce to effectively assert their prior rights to the communal land versus the private company enabled the community to engage with ministries relevant in granting communal land titles. Samdhana&#x2019;s grant support to a local NGO (1) helped in building the community&#x2019;s capacities

In 2021, an IPLC community in Indonesia (1) increased their capacity for evidence-building and lobbying for land conflict resolution with a palm oil company. Samdhana supported this initiative through a small grant coursed through a partner CSO (1) that conducted an assessment research in preparation for mediation between the IP community and the palm oil company.

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened their organisational capacity by developing a 5-year strategic plan and learning how to develop proposals through workshops facilitated by Samdhana. Leaders from this community also increased their knowledge about the roles and functions of the Indigenous Peoples Mandatory Representative (IPMR) and the related skills for draft local ordinances and resolutions, and on the Free, Prior and Informed Consent (FPIC) through a training and refresher course organised by Samdhana. (x)

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened its organisational capacity by developing a 5-year strategic plan as well as the capacity to develop proposals with support from trainings and workshops facilitated by Samdhana. This IPLC has also participated in a policy analysis and agenda-setting exercise at the State of the Indigenous Peoples Address (SIPA) co-organised by Samdhana with a partner NGO. (x)

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened its organisational capacity by developing a 5-year strategic plan as well as their capacity to develop proposals with support from trainings and workshops facilitated by Samdhana.

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened its organisational capacity by developing a 5-year strategic plan with support from trainings organised by Samdhana. (g)

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened its organisational capacity by developing a 5-year strategic plan with support from trainings organised by Samdhana. They also participated in promoting their traditional food systems and agroecology practices, which enhanced their capacity to articulate these practices. Samdhana provided technical assistance on video production to IPLCs and facilitated national dialogues to connect them with other communities, government institutions, academe and other CSOs. (g) This IPLC also participated in a policy analysis and agenda-setting exercise at the State of the Indigenous Peoples Address (SIPA) co-organised by Samdhana with a partner NGO. (x)

In 2021, two IP partner in the Philippines (2) strengthened their capacity to develop proposals through proposal writeshops facilitated by Samdhana. One of these IPLCs is a women&#x2019;s group focused on improving IP women&#x2019;s participation in the management of the community&#x2019;s ancestral domain. (1g) These IP partners have become more confident in articulating their vision and aspirations for their own development within their domain&apos;s decision-making structures, which has helped to address the dominant patriarchal decision-making process within IPLCs in both traditional structures and organisations. 

In 2021, one women&#x2019;s group in the Philippines (1) strengthened its capacity to develop proposals through a writeshop facilitated by Samdhana. The group also strengthened its capacity to revive traditional organic cotton growing and weaving by documenting the IP community&#x2019;s history and creative process of design and weaving with Samdhana&#x2019;s facilitation and linkaging with a capacity development provider. (g)

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened their project management skills through a project financial management training facilitated by Samdhana.

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened its project management skills through a project financial management training facilitated by Samdhana. Members of this group, primarily youth, increased their knowledge on human rights, IP rights and leadership through trainings organised by Samdhana.

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) increased knowledge on human rights, IP rights, gender and leadership through a training organised by Samdhana. (g)

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened its organisational capacity by developing guidelines for its Indigenous Political Structure with technical guidance and mobilisation support from Samdhana.

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) strengthened their capacity to communicate their struggle against land grabbing and harassment spurred by tourism investment through a video documentation. Samdhana provided technical support for video production to IPLCs and facilitated national dialogues to connect them with other communities, government institutions, academe and other CSOs.

In 2021, a social forestry farmers&#x2019; cooperative in Indonesia (1) strengthened its capacities on managing forests for conservation and resource use, specifically on planning and organisational management, forest conservation, business planning, and value-added production of rattan products. Samdhana supported this cooperative through a grant to a local NGO (1) that facilitated the trainings and activities.

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) increased their knowledge and capacities on agroecology practices by establishing an &#x201C;agro-ecommunity&#x201D; farm. Samdhana supported this community through small grants.

In 2021, one IP partner in the Philippines (1) increased their knowledge and capacities on agroecology practices by establishing an &#x201C;agro-ecommunity&#x201D; farm. They also enhanced their capacity to articulate and promote traditional food systems and agroecology practices. Samdhana supported the community through trainings and technical assistance on video production. Further, this IPLC has participated in a policy analysis and agenda-setting exercise at the State of the Indigenous Peoples Address (SIPA) co-organised by Samdhana with a partner NGO.

From July to November 2021, ten partner IPLCs and CSOs from the Philippines and Laos, and three partners from Indonesia (13) enhanced their capacity to articulate and promote traditional food systems and agroecology practices. Their experiences emphasised the role of women and youth in securing food for the home, community and future generations. Samdhana provided technical assistance on video production to IPLCs and facilitated national dialogues to connect them with other communities, government institutions, academe and other CSOs. (g) Of these, IPLCs and CSOs, six partners from Indonesia, Laos and the Philippines increased their confidence in sharing with national and international partners about their identity, traditional food systems, culture and practices, during the global dialogues at the Fork-to-Farm side-event of the UNFCCC&#x2019;s COP26 in Glasgow, Scotland conducted in partnership with the Fork-to-Farm Network last November 2021. Samdhana facilitated the organisations&#x2019; participation to the event. (g)

In 2021, three (3) IP partners in the Philippines increased their capacities to communicate more effectively using digital tools and the internet. This enables them to access and participate in conversations and decision-making spaces that have now shifted to online platforms, especially in this time of pandemic. Samdhana provided digital tools and training to IPLCs. (x)

In 2021, an environmental legal policy CSO in the Philippines (1) strengthened their policy research and analysis expertise, for advancing Indigenous peoples rights beyond the Indigenous Peoples Rights Act (IPRA). Samdhana exchanges information or collaborates with this CSO for policy development and lobbying or environmental and Indigenous issues.  This research will contribute in strengthening their lobby and advocacy work as well as Samdhana will also benefit from the research results for our environmental protection and IP rights work. FGG support was provided through a grant to the CSO.

Through Samdhana&#x2019;s grant support in 2021, one CSO and its five consortium members (6) working on environmental issues in the Philippines underwent institutional development, i.e., conducting organisational assessments within the consortium, revisiting their strategic plan, and facilitating proposal development workshops.  This organisational assessment/ capacity review aims to sustain their momentum in lobbying and advocating on palm oil plantations and mining issues, and local climate change policies, and update their strategy in line with the analysis of the global, national, and local situations. Samdhana also provided guidance on the organisations&#x2019; review of their strategic plan, by sharing our insights, approaches and lessons based on our grounded work with IP partners, support during the pandemic, and conducting partner discussions that help us align towards similar goals.

In 2021, eight partners (8), where six are women-led, in Papua, Indonesia strengthened their capacities in marketing and networking for their community-based products and livelihoods development. (6g) This is important for Papuan women to increase their control over natural resources.

In 2021, one CSO partner in Laos (1) increased its capacity by jointly developing and reviewing a training module with Samdhana on forest protection and gender equity. (g)

CONFIDENTIAL: Through Samdhana&#x2019;s urgent action grant to one CSO partner in Southeast Asia (1), environmental activists that were prosecuted for speaking out against environmental issues in the country were supported. As getting prosecuted translates to restricting activists and their families economically, families were provided with one-time support when the activists were detained and charged. (x)

CONFIDENTIAL: In 2021, one partner CSO in Southeast Asia was able to strengthen their constituency with local CSOs through the urgent action grant they received from Samdhana This support enabled them to continue their work with other local organizations and provide them with communication support to continue engaging throughout the conflict situation, and to support internally displaced persons (IDPs) who were also affected by COVID-19.The CSO Partner served as main contact of Samdhana during the height of the civil war crisis, and provided us with important information and local insight into the struggle, and helped Samdhana to identify what were the priority needs of local CSOs to weather out the pandemic and the civil war at the same time. 

In 2021, eleven partners in Indonesia (11) increased their capacities on conflict resolution and Gender Equality and Social Inclusion (GESI) in a training organised by Samdhana. It covered topics on perception of conflict, common types of land-based conflict, roots and levels. The training integrated GESI and the intersection of issues that lead to conflict and increase women&#x2019;s vulnerability. (g) 

In 2021, one recently organized CSO partner in Laos (1) received a grant and facilitation support from Samdhana that enabled them to train youth volunteers for community development work. The youth were trained on personal development topics such as Self Understanding, Volunteerism, Community Facilitation, Youth Leadership for Development, and on community organizing work, such as Problem Analysis, and Problem-solving. This contributes to building local human resources who are trained in critical thinking, moulded to recognise and respect community rights and address community needs and problems, such as villagers&#x2019; loss of access or control to their forest and agricultural lands, lack of livelihoods, and environmental problems. (x)

In 2021, twenty-seven youth groups, including individuals with different abilities/diffables in the Philippines and Indonesia (27) increased their representation in national discussions and cross-country exchange on access to natural resources and livelihoods. Samdhana contributed funds and provided technical assistance to the youth working groups in conceptualizing and organizing this event, which focused on tenurial rights, tenure security, and the roles and capacities of the youth, especially of young women in Indigenous governance and natural resources management.(g) The exchanges gave recognition to women-led local enterprises, such as the diffable coffee barista, and to youth initiatives, such as &#x2018;kampung kembali&#x2019; (generally translated as returning to the villages), a growing movement in Indonesia where Indigenous youth who had migrated to the cities are consciously moving back to their villages and reviving their indigenous cultures and values. The organizing of this event led to the creation of an inter-province Indigenous youth working group, and also the formal creation of a territory-wide (composed of four municipalities/ towns) Indigenous youth network in the Philippines. In the youth formations (Philippines), there are almost equal number of young women to young men, which is a significant difference from current Tribal Councils wherein mostly men are the recognized authorities and leaders (g). 

In July 2021, one CSO partner in the Philippines facilitated the State of Indigenous Peoples Address (SIPA 2021) which is a national gathering of Indigenous Peoples where  five Indigenous partner communities/ organizations (5 ) increased their participation in policy analysis and agenda setting. SIPA served as an alternative avenue for presenting the national plight of the Indigenous Peoples, which was completely left out in the Philippine President&#x2019;s State of the Nation Address (SONA) 2021. Through this, more than 80 indigenous leaders and representatives were able to voice out their situations, pressing issues and concerns that have not been given attention by the current government administration. Samdhana supported the activity through a grant, and facilitating the participation of the eight partners, including translation support during the actual exchanges. (x)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">strengthened capacities</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2g</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># targeted civil society actors with strengthened capacities relevant to advance gender justice</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2021"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
     <actual value="57">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No need for a narrative</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2025-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2025-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
