<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-08215619-201210000-9001160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org>Kadaster International</reporting-org>
  <title>Access to Reliable Geo Information for Sustainable Development in Bhutan</title>
  <description>The project aims to bring major stakeholders together and to develop human and organisational capacity so that the activities can be harmonised and standardised for the efficient maintenance and timely delivery and use of Geo-information for sustainable (socio-economic) development of the country.

The main objective of this proposal is to enhance access to reliable geo-information for sustainable development in Bhutan. Fast and reliable information provision and efficient land use planning benefits social and economic development of Bhutan. A joint National Strategy and plan will positively influence strategic plans of the involved institutions and vice-versa. Data sharing and dissemination amongst major stakeholders improves efficiency and accuracy. It is therefore essential to improve the cooperation of all stakeholders on geo-information provision and management and to develop organisational and human capacities. In developing a joint strategy the program might become a regions best practice for location based governmental services.

By sharing geo-information amongst major service providers and users in the sector, this project is expected to support the policies of Gross National Happiness (GNH) for social, economic and environmental development for the Bhutanese people.</description>
  <participating-org>University of Twente, Faculty of Geo-Info. and Earth Observation (ITC) &#x2013; the Netherlands</participating-org>
  <participating-org>VU University Amsterdam, Department of Spatial Economics (VU) &#x2013; the Netherlands</participating-org>
  <other-identifier>MAG14BT01</other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date>1 year and 5 months</activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-08-01" type="START-ACTUAL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="KADASTER.INTERNATIONAL@KADASTER.NL">
   <organisation>Kadaster International</organisation>
   <person-name>Suzanne Valkman</person-name>
   <job-title>Regional Manager Asia</job-title>
   <telephone>+31881833051</telephone>
   <email>suzanne.valkman@kadaster.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.kadaster.nl/web/artikel/klantenserviceartikel/Kadaster-International-department.htm</website>
   <website>http://www.rvo.nl/subsidies-regelingen/projecten/reliable-geo-information-sustainable-development-bhutan</website>
   <mailing-address>Postbus 9046
7300 GH Apeldoorn</mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15140" percentage="100" vocabulary="DAC"></sector>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-02-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR">290000</value>
  </budget>
  <result type="2">
   <title>The main objective of this proposal is to enhance cooperation between the Netherlands and Bhutan.
The specific project purpose is to enhance access to reliable geo-information for major stakeholders in Bhutan.

The approach is Learning through Exchange (LE). By exchanging knowledge between the Netherlands and Bhutan in the field of Geo-Information we aim to develop human and organisational capacity so that the activities can be harmonised and standardised for the efficient maintenance and timely delivery and use of Geo-information for sustainable (socioeconomic) development of the country.</title>
   <description>1. Improving governance amongst major service providers in geo-information; 
a.	Formation of a &#x2018;Golden Triangle&#x2019; composed of the National Land Commission (NLC), the Municipality of Thimphu and the Ministry of Works and Human Settlement (MWHS). 
b.	Development of a national strategic policy and plan for the use of geo-information in Bhutan by the Golden Triangle in cooperation with major end users particularly the Bhutan Power Corporation.
2. Capacity development in the field of Geo-information science for the Golden Triangle and major end-users particularly the Bhutan Power Corporation (BPC); 
3. Improved use of geo-information amongst major service providers and end-users particularly Bhutan Power Corporation (BPC). 
2. Capacity development in the field of Geo-information science for the Golden Triangle and major end-users particularly the Bhutan Power Corporation (BPC); 
3. Improved use of geo-information amongst major service providers and end-users particularly Bhutan Power Corporation (BPC).</description>
  </result>
  <activity-website>http://geo.gov.bt/</activity-website>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
