<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-08215619-201210000-9001142</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org>Kadaster International</reporting-org>
  <title>Capacity Development Bangladesh Department of Land Records and Surveys (DLRS), Ministry of Land Bangladesh</title>
  <description>A well functioning and up to date system of (in)formal land registration and cadastre is a critical factor in ensuring legal certainty to both owners and government; it stimulates investment and economic growth and prevents conflicts, loss of capital (and lives), and expensive long lasting court cases. 
The government of Bangladesh understands this but it&#x2019;s not easy to organise and maintain a comprehensive system. Six mayor criteria need to be addressed: 
i)	laws and legislation are in place and can be enforced; 
ii)	transparent and accountable intergovernmental cooperation; 
iii)	spatial data infrastructure and technology is up to date and easy to use;
iv)	sufficient resources (financial, human capital, technological) to maintain the system; 
v)	effective procedures for land(use) and property registration and administration are in place  and the system can easily adapt to technological and societal changes; 
vi)	adequate capacity (knowledge, skills and experience) of officials in the sector to collect, organise and maintain data and register rights; 

Especially in the area&#x2019;s of spatial data and ownership reality is constantly changing and the sector needs to be able to quickly adapt to those changes. An outdated system of land(use) and property registration is worthless. 

For transformation of the land registration system the sector first needs to enhance its intergovernmental collaboration and build capacity of management and staff. In Bangladesh three ministries are responsible for land registration: Ministry of Land (Land records), Ministry of Defence (Topography), en Ministry of Law (Records of Rights), the fourth key-stakeholders are local governments. Intergovernmental cooperation is not easy and one ministry needs to take the lead to initialise change. The ministry of Lands, department of Land Records and Surveys is the prime target group since all information needs to pass and clear this department. To develop capacities of staff an initial study visit of 15 persons of DLRS to Kadaster, ITC and DLG would be the first step after which a follow-up workshop in Dhaka combined with the establishment of a peer-group (Dutch experts and DLRS experts) will provide the necessary backup for capacity development.</description>
  <participating-org>ITC, University of Twente</participating-org>
  <activity-status>Additional budget for the second phase of the project is confirmed.</activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="END-ACTUAL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>Kadaster International</organisation>
   <person-name>Christelle van den Berg</person-name>
   <job-title>Project Manager</job-title>
   <telephone>+(31) 6 50 61 39 81</telephone>
   <email>christelle.vandenberg@kadaster.nl</email>
   <website>www.kadaster.nl</website>
   <mailing-address>P.O. Box 9046, 7300 GH Apeldoorn, The Netherlands</mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope>Bangladesh</activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>N/A</name>
   <location-type>Dhaka</location-type>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">Land Registry/ Land Administration</sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR">15782</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR">170000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
