<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-08215619-201210000-9001183</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org>Kadaster International</reporting-org>
  <title>Cadastral Formalisation in Colombia</title>
  <description>The Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Development (MADR) and the Geographical Institute Agustin Codazzi (IGAC) use innovative approaches to land administration in Colombia. Both organisations expressed their interest in working together with ITC and Kadaster to share knowledge on new concepts, methods and technologies, and to jointly develop new knowledge on &#x201C;fit for purpose&#x201D; land administration.</description>
  <participating-org>Geographical Institute Agustin Codazzi (IGAC)</participating-org>
  <participating-org>ITC, Univerity of Twente</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Development (MADR)</participating-org>
  <participating-org>Superintendencia de Notariado y Registro</participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date>Inception / fact finding mission was carried out in October 6-9, 2014 in Bogota, Colombia.</activity-date>
  <contact-info type="CADASTRE, LAND REGISTRY AND MAPPING AGENCY OF THE NETHERLANDS">
   <organisation>Kadaster International</organisation>
   <person-name>Mathilde Molendijk</person-name>
   <job-title>Manager Latin America</job-title>
   <telephone>+31 (0)88 183 31 10</telephone>
   <email>kadaster.international@kadaster.nl</email>
   <website>http://www.kadaster.nl/web/english/International-relations.htm</website>
   <mailing-address>Cadastre, Land Registry and Mapping Agency

P.O. Box 9046, 7300 GH Apeldoorn, the Netherlands
Hofstraat 110, 7311 KZ Apeldoorn, 
the Netherlands</mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope>The project consists of three work visits of ITC and Kadaster to Colombia. During the first work visit, employees of MADR and IGAC will be trained in new concepts of land administration; in methods and technology for Spatial Data Infrastructures; and the Dutch team will participate in the formalisation fieldwork of MADR in order to assist writing the Terms of Reference for the capacity building programme of MADR (project results 1 and 3 of the project, planned for March 2015).  In the second work visit, a joint pilot study will be carried out and evaluated, based on a prototype of mobile, participatory technologies for spatial data collection based on the fit for purpose approach to land administration. This serves as a &#x201C;proof of concept&#x201D; to what extend cheap and fast methods and techniques could be used for fit for purpose land administration. Can these methods and techniques help in establishing a rapid inventory of the land ownership situation in an area, including the identification of the nature of conflicts in that area? Recommendations will be formulated (technical advice on project results 2 and 4, planned for June / July 2015).  In the third and last visit, the project will be evaluated with the counterpart organisations, and the results will be presented at a high level end conference (project result 5, planned for October / November 2015). If possible, a Study Visit of MADR and IGAC to the Netherlands will be organised, after the first work visit of the Dutch team to Colombia. Finances to cover the costs of the Study Visit on both the Colombian side (tickets) and Dutch side (e.g. DSA for the visitors and allocation of hours) still have to be found.</activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region percentage="100" vocabulary="1">Colombia</recipient-region>
  <location>
   <name>Colombia</name>
   <administrative vocabulary="1">Colombia</administrative>
   <coordinates latitude="4.740675384778373" longitude="-432.94921875"></coordinates>
   <location-type code="ADM1"></location-type>
  </location>
  <sector code="LAND ADMINISTRATION" percentage="100" vocabulary="RO"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-02-29"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR">150000</value>
  </budget>
  <result type="1">
   <title>&#x2022; Result A Inception, Management, Monitoring 
&#x2022; Result 1 Methods and Technology for Spatial Data Infrastructures (SDI) 
&#x2022; Result 2 Technical advisory on mobile technologies, based on one pilot area
&#x2022; Result 3 Training (Concepts and fieldwork) 
&#x2022; Result 4 Technical advisory on participatory data collection, based on one pilot area.
&#x2022; Result 5 Evaluation and end conference</title>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
