<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2009091211</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;NGO Support / HIV and Aids Project &quot;&quot;The Good Samaritan&quot;&quot; Malawi&quot;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The long term objective of the project is to contribute to the reduction of the spread of HIV and stigmatization of infected and affected people. The main focus is to reduce stigmatization and discrimination of PLHA. The overall objectives of the Good Sama
ritan HIV programme (GSP) is to strengthen the involvement of churches in the response to HIV by enabling people and organisations to: ?Get knowledge about HIV and AIDS and risky behaviour, Encourage VCT and sexual education, Eradicate stigma and condemnat
ion, Restore PLHA&apos;s human rights dignity and equality and, To renew churches and local congregations&apos; social responsibility. The programme has two main target groups: influental people and opinion leaders with the capacity to act as facilitators and traine
rs, and people who are particularly vulnerable to HIV: youth women PLHA and married persons. The strategy is based on information education and communication with a focus on behavioural change communication and to work with individuals and communities thro
ugh sharing and providing supportive and enabling environments. The implementation is based on a two tier strategy: (i) advocacy sensitisation and mobilisation of community and religious leaders, and (ii) cascade training of trainers to reach local congreg
ations and communities. The training uses the workshop as a platform to facilitate inter-action sharing and reflection to promote change in attitudes and behaviour. The programme also encourages the formation of local groups for mutual support and action.G
ender equality is embedded in training materials and teachings and project staff. Implementing Bible Societies will be further trained on gender issues. Human dignity is one the key elements in the Good Samaritan program. Project is implemented within nati
onal HIV coordinating structures that include governmental HIV coordination religious network and local communities.The direct beneficiaries include PLHIV and non-infected people. Special emphasis is put on women and youth aim is also try to better address
 PVDs.The key project activities include four kind of workshops: sensitization for various leaders training of trainees (ToT) decentralized workshops (DWs) Follow up (FU) Take Charge youth program (TC) and annual capacity building workshops for project sta
ff (Joint Program Review / JPR and anglophone capacity building workshop).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish Bible Society</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-10" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">94650</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">93500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">84150</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">94650</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
