<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2013130117</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Palliative Care in Ilembula Lutheran Hospital</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at strengthening Home Based Care and Palliative Care (HBC+PC) already existing in connection to Ilembula Lutheran Hospital. Overall objective is to improve quality of life of people living with HIV/AIDS and other chronic illnesses and disa
bilities as well as to work towards HBC+PC becoming well established part of local healthcare schemes. Immediate objectives are improvement of quality of treatment through training and education of staff and volunteers ensuring adequate resources for conti
nuation of HBC+PC as well as increasing awareness about palliative care and the positive impact that it can have in people&apos;s lives. Mr Bryceson Mbilinyi started small scale home visiting already in 1993 after having completed 4-months Clinical Pastoral Edu
cation (CPE) at KCMC. In 1997 he attended course in Primary Healthcare. In 2003 nurse Aida Mtega joined the work after having received HBC Provider training for 3 wks. In 2004 both attended the African Palliative Care Association (APCA) inaugural meeting. 
In 2003-2010 there was a project &apos;Continuum of Care for People Living with HIV/AIDS in Tanzania (CHAT)&apos; managed by ELCT Headquarters in Arusha. This project helped to establish Ilembula Palliative Care headed by Aida Mtega as its coordinator. The project i
ntegrated elements of both Palliative and Home Based Care in the care of HIV/AIDS patients. It also recognized the need of HBC+PC of other patient groups that were suffering from cancer and other chronic debilitating conditions such as heart failure COPD d
iabetes mellitus physical disability etc. There are 53 village based volunteers now working in the HBC+PC team. By WHO palliative care is recognised as essential part of controlling cancer and other life-threatening illnesses. It can be provided relatively
 simply and inexpensively in different levels of health care system. APCA was established after a meeting in Cape Town in -02 of 28 palliative care trainers from across Africa incl. TZ. It produced the Cape Town Declaration: palliative care and pain and sy
mptom control are a human right for every adult and child with life-limiting illnesses. Such care should be incorporated into national health care strategies making it accessible and affordable for all in Africa. This project aims at securing and strengthe
ning the on-going work in Ilembula. Continuation and spread into new areas of the project will be planned during this initial year of partnership between FCMS and Ilembula HBC+PC team.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomen kristillinen laakariseura ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">40910</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">40910</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
