<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2013130160</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transitional Demobilization and Reintegration Programme in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The TDRP was launched in the second half of 2009 with the ultimate strategic objective of enhancing the prospects for stabilization and recovery in the Great Lakes Region. It has three specific objectives: to provide financial and technical support, to exp
and demobilization and reintegration coverage and to facilitate dialogue information exchange and learning.The TDRP is funded through a multi-donor trust fund managed by the World Bank covering grants to national programs sub-projects regional activities a
nd the management of the TDRP. The trust fund amounts to US$ 33.71 million and as of March 20th 2013 total disbursements stand at US$ 21.8 million.The extension which this programme is responding of the TDRP would continue the demand driven geographical ex
pansion of program activities away from traditional TDRP countries to emerging centers of conflict in West Africa the Sahel and Horn of Africa along with the two Sudan&apos;s where there has been and will continue to be a demand for TDRP expertise. Currently th
e needs in these Fragile and Conflict Affect States (FCS) and transnational areas are receiving renewed attention often with more African regional and continental leadership than has been the case in the recent past. This presents an opportunity for the Wo
rld Bank and TDRP donors to enable African leadership through the application of TDRP operational technical and knowledge management expertise and the cross-border analytical and operational perspectives in critical and emerging fragile and conflict affect
ed areas. Particularly the regional approach of the TDRP (built on the preceding MDRP) can be of strategic value when addressing the drivers of conflict and developing and implement a new approach to peace building and stabilization.The programme has been 
successful in its goals to reintegrate to society hundreds of thousands of ex-combatants. Various examples have been reported during the project about how ex-military groups have been successfully integrated back to socieatal activities after handing over 
the weapons and negotiating about their status in the community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44000" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank (WB)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-13" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">500000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">500000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
