<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2012000080</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving reading and writing skills in primary education in Maputo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Mozambique the level of writing and reading skills is low. There are many reasons for this: they do not have enough schoolbooks the infrastructure and teachers&apos; teaching skills are insufficient and parents do not understand the importance of education. 
Even though the state of Mozambique has paid effort to develop the educational sector for example by constructing school buildings and training teachers the development does not materialize immediately.The direct objective of the project is to improve writ
ing and reading skills of the 1st and 2nd grade pupils in six schools in Maputo area. This will be reached by following activities:1) Procuring schoolbooks and other important materials for teaching 2) Training teachers and thus improving the quality of te
aching3) Increasing the attendance of the pupils in the schools by increasing the knowledge of the parents on the importance of education4) Establishing a favorable reading and writing atmosphere in the schools 5) Establishing advocacy work and lobbying to
 affect the quality of education in Mozambique The direct beneficiaries of the project are  1st and 2nd grade pupils of the project schools and  teachers.During the project already existing infrastructures will be supported for example the professional ski
lls and learning materials will be increased. Cross-cutting objectives of the development policy of Finland will be taken into account in project activities in the following:Environmental sustainabilityThe materials needed in project will be bought from Mo
zambique and books will be protected by plastic covers. In teacher trainings and storytelling groups themes related to environment will be discussed. Gender equality: The beneficiaries of the project are both female and male. Parents will be informed about
 the children?s right for education especially the girls. Teachers will be trained how to take account both sexes in education.Reduction of inequality:The whole project aims at the reduction of inequality by education.Human rights will also be taken accoun
t especially the right for education. Education will affect the realization of other human rights such as the right to employment and a sufficient level of live. The project has been planned together with the beneficiaries and stakeholders and thus their p
ossibility to tell their opinions has been secured.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomen ylioppilaskuntien liitto (SYL) ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">62527</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">68083</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">65418</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">62527</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
