<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2012000270</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing religious violence in Myanmar: An inter-faith approach</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Religious violence is on the rise in Myanmar. Left unchecked it has the potential to spread rapidly and with tragic effects on both the lives and livelihoods of many thousands of people predominantly Muslims. The impact on the reform process could be signi
ficant also. Despite very public calls for restraint and tolerance from President U Thein Sein himself faith in the Government amongst those outside the core Burman majority has fallen to its lowest levels since the country embarked on the transition to de
mocracy. Fear and insecurity is pervasive amongst ethnic and religious minorities. The worst of the violence has been felt in Rakhine State where the long persecuted Rohingyapeople have endured what Human Rights Watch (HRW) unhesitatingly called ethnic cle
ansing. But the violence has not stopped at the State border. It has swept into central Myanmar leaving deadand displaced in Meikhtila Oakkan and even Yangon. Less destructive than the devastation in Rakhine these latest attacks may nevertheless prove even
 more ominous for the future of Myanmar. The source of the problem in Rakhine was never religion specifically but rather an explosive cocktail of land identity and conflicting historical narratives. This is not true of the more recent attacks. Anti-Muslim 
sentiment is spreading. No single project and no single organisation particularly a foreign one can hope to resolve problems as complex and deeply rooted as these. Yet many working in common cause can make a difference. This proposal outlines PACTA&apos;s contr
ibution in partnership with others: a project which serves to catalyse and support a network of inter-faith leaders at all levels, a project which harnesses the strength influence and authority of religious figures to promote reconciliation, a project whic
h discreetly and gradually encourages political consensus at the very heart of the problem -RakhineState. PACTA&apos;s program comprises two main parallel but complementary strands of work. First a broader focus working at a national level on inter-faith reconc
iliation. For this strand PACTA will be working in close partnership with and in support of the Myanmar Inter-Faith Network on AIDS (MINA).  Second a more specific process of building trust between Rakhine and Rohingya leaderships. In this strand our work 
will be undertaken mostly but not exclusively with political parties from both communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Pacta Finland ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">50000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">50000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
