<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2010100154</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indigenous rights and culture in Adivasi forest communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The new Tribal Forests Rights Act gives indigenous tribes the right to exploit local forests in a sustainable manner. The execution of the law has however been incomplete. The project aims to facilitate the execution in manner that secures the tribal way o
f life.Industrial development and globalization mines and old forest laws and policies are further pushing them to the margins of existence threatening their sustainable livelihood their traditional subsistence- and shifting cultivation minor forest produc
e collection herbal practices and bamboo-work. In some areas they are even under threat of being uprooted/evicted or displaced from their indigenous homes and habitats. Indian government has set up institutions (like Baiga Development Authority) and specia
l budgetary provisions to take care of PTGs and to address their declining population growth literacy below 5% and remote and isolated habitation etc. But due to top-down policies non-transparency in functioning and governmental inertia these measures have
 hardly made change in the situation. Forest Rights Act has potential to provide also for PTGs (among other tribes) tenurial security and autonomy barrier free MFP collection habitat rights and other community rights but it has not yet been adequately impl
emented. The intended continuation project aims to support and capacitate 4 PTGs of Chhattisgarh (and MP) to organise themselves to secure their rights and to strengthen their communities. PTG forums workshops trainings and advocacy strengthen their unity 
and make them aware about their basic rights.  It supports the possibilities of the PTG-communities to defend their traditional forest habitat and community rights their means of subsistence and traditional occupations and their rights to drinking water ed
ucation and health care. Project aims to ensure bottom-up planning and to bring transparency in the functioning of PTGs-Development Authorities.  By audio-visual and written documentation campaigning and dissemination of survey findings and newsletters the
 project makes wider audience aware of the situation of the PTGs and creates national and international pressure to get their rights implemented compliant to the international commitments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emmaus Aurinkotehdas ry EMAUR</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">33231</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">33231</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
