<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2012000431</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transfer Pricing Seminar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tax Justice Network (TJN) co-hosts with Kepa and Agenda Participation 2000 a two day seminar on Transfer Pricing to be held on October 3-4 2013 in Dar es Salaam Tanzania. The event is follow-up to the  transfer pricing seminar organized in Helsinki. In add
ition a more general public event will be organized on June 15. Participants will discuss issues related to transfer pricing/transfer mispricing and the harmful impact of transfer mispricing on government revenue especially in the context of extractive ind
ustries and exploitation of natural resources in developing countries. Losses to developing countries from transfer mispricing have been estimated at US$ 160 billion of tax revenue annually. The seminar will present alternatives to the current transfer pri
cing rules. Combating transfer mispricing is one way to promote developing countries&apos; domestic resource mobilization . It supports the achievement of the objectives stated in Finland&apos;s development policy program and realizes the commitment to support inter
national actions combating tax evasion and illicit capital flows while promoting the development of international norms and guidelines and strenthening corporate social responsibility. Supporting the transfer pricing seminar is also in line with the priori
ties set in the Finland&apos;s country strategy for Tanzania (good governance and equitable access to public services sustainable management of natural resources and inclusive green growth) and it is complements other interventions supported by Finland and embe
ds synergies with the operations carried out by the Institute of African Leadership for Sustainable Development (Uongozi Institute). TJN is a network of NGO&apos;s specialized in international taxation focusing - among other issues - on transfer pricing of mult
inational corporations. The network undertakes research and advocacy and has a membership of 80 organizations in 30 countries. Finnish Kepa ry is a member of TJN and its Tanzania office is in charge of seminar arrangements together with TJN in particular o
f linking the Finnish participants to the event and relation with the Finnish media. Agenda Participation 2000 is a Tanzanian NGO focused on promoting democracy and good governance. The event is expected to bring together experts researchers tax authoritie
s civil society and private sector representatives. Finnish support will enable wide  participation of developing countries&apos; representatives and other high level experts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="3" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-03-05" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">129877</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-09-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">129877</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">129877</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
