<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2012000309</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building for Mongolian deaf people by empowering their NGOs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at inclusion of deaf people in Mongolian society. There are 3 problems to help deaf people to have more opportunities to access the society and claim their human rights:1. The NGOs that are working on all inclusion of deaf people in societ
y are weak and need to be empowered to do a better job then they will be capable of doing. Most NGOs started from an ideology to help deaf people on one or two aspects of inclusion like helping to find employment or with legal issues but they don&apos;t have ma
nagement knowledge or skills and mostly lack of money and staff. They are all members of the Mongolian Deaf Federation (MNFD) and could have a stronger voice in the Mongolian society when they work more as a team and join forces. By training them as a team
 in the project centre on different management issues they will have more opportunities to development services for deaf people and be better heard when they stand up for the rights of the Deaf.2. The Deaf in the different areas of Mongolia have developed 
their own sign language in daily life which is limited by the way of this development. The second partner organization in this project the Mongolian Association of Sign Language Interpreters (MASLI) is now developing a National Standard for sign language w
hich will be ready at the end of 2012 with signs that will be a bit different for groups of deaf people in the country and new signs that will extend their learning and communication possibilities. It is very important that deaf people learn that standard 
and we want to use the existing structure of NGOs for the Deaf to make the standard for sign language accessible for deaf people all over the country.3. The third problem is the lack of interpreters in sign language and the lack of knowledge about communic
ation with deaf people among the hearing community which makes it very difficult for deaf people to access justice enter legal commitments participate in regular education information in general and all other human rights. By training volunteers from the N
GOs to become interpreters and by including governmental organizations in the advocacy about communication with deaf people this situation will be improved.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evankelisluterilainen Lahetysyhdistys Ky</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">76754</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">69463</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">76754</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
