<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2009091295</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NGO Support / Village empowerment in Bijoliya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Village Community Empowerment Phase II continues the awareness and advocacy work with underprivileged Scheduled Castes and Scheduled Tribes in the rural communities of Bijoliya Rajasthan. The project objectives are in unision with Millennium Development Go
als and Development Policies of Finland and India. The project is implemented in cooperation with the Student Union of the University of Jyvaskyla (JYY) and Bal Rashmi Society (BRS). The long-term development objectives are to empower different levels of p
oor and backward communities and to improve their living conditions by increasing the awareness of the importance of health education and civil society. The project aims at reducing morbidity and infant mortality rates increasing enrolment in education enh
ancing family incomes raising the self-esteem of women and supporting government workers to become more responsible in their duties. Particularly the communities are encouraged to take an active role in matters affecting their lives and in their own develo
pment in order to achieve appropriate and sustainable outcomes. The project also carries out an in-depth study on child marriage in the Bijoliya region. The direct beneficiaries of the project are women children and youth whereas men and communities as a w
hole are mostly indirect beneficiaries.The main activities through which the objectives are accomplished are Village Planning Exercises and Community Meetings Women&apos;s Youth&apos;s and Adolescent Girls&apos; Groups Income Generation Loan Programme Orientation of Chil
d Development Centres&apos; Workers Educational Support to Children Information Centres and Training of Village Youth Volunteers. The project also continues to work with Members of Local Governance and Service Providers to strengthen collaboration between gover
nment workers and beneficiaries. The project develops old structures such as existing health and education services and therefore it does not create new institutions. In order to make the progress coherent Village Community Empowerment Phase II covers all 
the 115 villages and 24 hamlets of the Bijoliya Block.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Student Union of Jyvaskyla University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-10" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">44414</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">45241</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">44885</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">44414</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
