<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2013130081</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening sustainable livelihoods in 12 villages in Malawi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to contribute to solving of a crucial development problem in Malawi - insufficient food security - by enhancing sustainable livelihood in 12 villages in Mangochi region (Lungwena area). Sustainable livelihood is understood as a combination
 of nutritionally ecologically socially and economically sustainable agriculture and other sustainable sources of income.  This 3-year project has two immediate objectives: 1) Nutritional food security of rural families improved. 2) Capacity of Pemphero or
ganisation strengthened .The cross-cutting development policy objectives form an integral part of the project as: - girls and women are special groups among the beneficiaries (gender equality)- as are other marginalised groups such as aids-orphans old and 
disabled persons (decreasing inequality) - enhanced agricultural methods are ecologically sound and climate sensitive (enhancement of climate sustainability).   The project is not creating new structures as its key elements are already part of Pemphero&apos;s w
ork. However due to lack of resources and limited possibilities to capacity strengthening the organisation has asked for external support in order to better strengthen sustainable livelihoods in the target area and to make its own capacity firmer.   The ma
in beneficiary groups are: 1) persons in the 12 target villages who participate in the collective farming and their families 2) groups who benefit from the production of collective farming (marginalised women children and especially girls elderly and some 
disabled persons as well)3) Pemphero as an organization and its activists who get their capacity strengthened. The objectives will mainly be achieved by following activities: a) Training local families on plant varieties agricultural methods recycling prod
ucing manure healthy nutrition crop storage food conserving cooking methods feeding habits multiple use of local foods home economics and marketing of the local products. b) Purchasing tools (e.g. ploughs) seeds seedlings plants sacks kitchen ware computer
s mobiles, c) Deepening Pemphero activists&apos; knowledge on ecologically sound agriculture and nutritionally balanced food basket and on their working environment by strengthening their capacity to network with other civil society actors and to contact local 
authorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Coalition for Research and Action for Social Justice and Human Dignity</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31165" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">10000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
