<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2013130127</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Girls&apos; and Boys&apos; Literacy and Learning Skills in Uganda Through Innovative Child Rights Based Technical Solutions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project being planned aims to enhance Ugandan children?s learning competences and ability to learn to read. This will in turn provide them life skills to participate as equal members of society by developing innovative human rights based technical solu
tions. The project will be implemented by UNICEF Finland NMI Makerere University and UNICEF Uganda. Innovative technical solutions learning games such as GraphoGame? will be developed into a child rights based and socio-culturally appropriate that allows c
hildren to learn read. Positive messages will be included to advocate girls? rights and environmental protection.  Sustainable model for dissemination will be sought to target especially remote and poor regions and the most vulnerable groups in rural Ugand
a. All cooperation will be based on human rights inclusion to ensure that the possible project will reach those people who are most in need of learning aids specifically the poorest children women and children with learning difficulties The project will co
nsist of two components. The 1st component?s expected result is a comprehensive analysis consisting information on: 1.) Socio-cultural and economic conditions affecting access to education and abilities to learn. 2.) Problem analysis providing information 
on problems related to introduction of technical learning tools,3.) Gender roles in the communities, 4.) Beneficiary/rights holder analysis including identification of vulnerable groups, 5.) Identification and definition of duty bearers including the gaps 
and capacities, 6.) Perceptions and attitudes towards use of technology with links to gender, 7.) Information on local languages and ethnic groups. 8.) Infrastructure and technology analysis. 9.) Definitions institutional factors and financial resources. 1
0.) Requirements by natural environment. The analysis will be conducted by two African female Researchers and will be based on interviews in 5-10 diverse villages and a desk study. The second component&apos;s expected result is the project proposal done in part
icipatory spirit. Planning is based on the analysis produced by the 1st component. It will be done in two workshops organised in Uganda e-mail correspondence and Skype conferences. The proposal will be submitted to the donor on 31 May 2014. The beneficiari
es of the project will be school children that include orphans and children with disabilities teachers illiterate women project partners and the donor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Children&apos;s Fund (UNICEF) Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">33276</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">33276</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
