<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2009091257</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NGO Support / Mediation and gender based violence</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The absence of women from peace negotiations and insufficient expertise on gender-based violence (GBV) in peace mediation teams limit the success of peace processes. In 2010 CMI and the West Africa Network for Peacebuilding (WANEP) joined forces to develop
 policy guidance and recommendations on how to address questions of gender-based violence more effectively in all stages of peace processes from the pre-conflict period to peace mediation and the post-conflict phase.The continuation project builds on the w
ork of the project&apos;s first phase accepted for funding by the Finnish Ministry for Foreign Affairs for 2011-2012. Through the collection and comparative analysis of experiences from West African conflicts and peace mediation processes most notably those of 
Liberia and Cote d?Ivoire the original project has focused on increasing professional practice in addressing gender-based violence (GBV). The project brings its key findings to a dialogue with ECOWAS as well as local and regional mediators in West Africa i
n order to increase their knowledge on GBV and to influence peace and mediation processes to become more gender-sensitive. A senior-level Advisory Board composed of experienced regional mediation and peacebuilding professionals supports the high-level advo
cacy and dissemination of the project results.The proposal at hand aims to strengthen and consolidate the work commenced in the first phase of the project by widening the scope of the project advocacy and by expanding the case studies with complementary re
search. While the advocacy of the first phase has focused on bringing the findings into a dialogue with ECOWAS the continuation project aims to advocate for a higher level of acknowledgement and acceptance for the need to address GBV not only within ECOWAS
 but also among other relevant international organizations active in West Africa (e.g. the African Union the United Nations and the European Union).Moreover thorough external and internal evaluations of the project will be carried out during the continuati
on period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Crisis Management Initiative (CMI) ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-10" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">260000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">260000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
