<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2013130063</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Cooperation Fund (LCF) in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the year 2008 Arid Lands Development Focus Kenya (ALDEF-K) partnering with Finish Embassy initiated a project that resulted in training of 40 paralegals in two divisions of Wajir district. The purpose of the project was to enable the marginalized commun
ities living in Wajir District to access justice enjoy their legal rights as well as access other development benefits.  The training of this group has raised great interest in the community regarding the subject of paralegals. The trained paralegals have 
already formed a network opened an office and are engaged in advocacy and awareness raising in the community. However due to the vastness of the County and the high number of the un served population the services offered by the few trained paralegals are n
ot adequate to cover the County. It is based on this that ALDEF K intends to scale up this project while addressing key challenges of human rights violations in the County. In essence the project seeks to build the capacity of 50 paralegals in Habaswein an
d Wajir South  districts in the County. The project is further expected to strengthen and consolidate the paralegal services in the larger Wajir County by nurturing and mentoring the once trained the paralegals will use their skills to help community membe
rs with legal issues. . As part of the practical training the trainees will get a chance to visit 4 existing paralegals network and offering paralegals services in the communities in the County. Once trained the paralegals will use their skills to help com
munity members with legal issues. The project expects the society to become more informed on legal issues. The training will use three basic training materials. These include the paralegal curriculum the paralegal manual and the Paralegal training Handbook
. Other legal materials may also be used to supplement the core training materials. As part of the practical training the trainees will get a chance to visit institutions for administration of justice. The trainees will visit the police stations the prison
 and the Magistrate court in Wajir. The training will be expected to take a total of one year. The trained paralegals will also network have grass root linkages and synergy. Since the trainees will be selected at the locational level they will elect divisi
onal representatives who will discuss issues from the locations and also link them to umbrella paralegal network at the district level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">120000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">120000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">120000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
