<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2013130546</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame agreement with NGO (SASK)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Transport corridors in West Africa. &quot;&quot;Through this project a regional collective agreement is negotiated for West African transport sector, covering all important transport corridors and the minimum terms and conditions of employment. The road transport s
ector has grown rapidly over the last few years due to economic globalisation in West Africa. Privatisation, deregulation and outsourcing have fragmented the company structures in the sector. This causes a rapid change in the employment contracts towards p
recarious employment such as temporary and short-term employment. For the employees in the sector this means a weakening in terms and conditions of employment, living standards and occupational safety as well as an increasingly hostile and anti-trade union
ism environment among employers. When lobbying becomes challenging the number of members decreases, which in turn leads to trade unions losing their influence in society. The project aims at strengthening trade unions? collective bargaining and thereby imp
roving the terms and conditions of employment. After the first phase of the project West African transport sector trade unions have negotiated regional collective agreements covering the minimum terms and conditions of employment in all the countries and a
re monitoring the implementation of the agreements. Furthermore, the recruitment and membership services have become more effective and the knowledge on interest representation has increased at workplaces (border, bus stops and truck rest stops). Beneficia
ries of this project are organisers, negotiators, officers and activists of the local trade unions. The rank and file members benefit from the project in the form of better terms and condition of employment. The project is implemented by transport sector g
lobal union International Transport Workers? Federation ITF.&quot;&quot; &quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, SASK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">40322</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
