<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2013-2009091235</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NGO Support / Mtukwao Participatory Media Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Tanzania the majority of the population lives in rural communities that earn their living by subsistence farming and often lack most basic services. Rural communities are however almost totally neglected by the urban-based mainstream media.The main obje
ctive of the Mtukwao Participatory Media Project is to raise discussion about issues that are important to the people in rural communities in the Mtwara and Lindi regions. Community media wants to offer people on the grassroots level a possibility to take 
part in the public debate about issues concerning their livelihoods about alternative ways of development and through this process a chance to find the best possible solutions to the development of their local areas in order to advance democracy human righ
ts and good governance.The project will support and develop the community media activities implemented by Mtukwao Community Media including a new community radio station Jamii FM Radio expected to be launched during 2012 before the end of the first phase o
f the project.The direct beneficiaries of the project are the hundreds of young community media journalists and members of rural radio groups taking part in the implementation and facilitation of the activities of Mtukwao Community Media. Thousands of peop
le will benefit from the project by joining the village discussions arranged as part of the community media productions. When people in the rural communities feel that their views are being listened to they are also more inclined to actively try to make an
 impact to their own living conditions. Among the direct beneficiaries are also all inhabitants within the coverage area of the new radio station (almost one million people) who can potentially listen to the radio broadcast of Jamii FM. When the participat
ory video documentaries are broadcasted on a national TV channel the whole population will belong to the beneficiaries.The key project activities include capacity building of young community media journalists the establishment of new Community Media Centre
s and rural radio groups promotion and marketing of the radio station networking with other community media operators and supporting the community media productions as well as the procurement of media equipment including the construction of an own radio tr
ansmission tower and support for buying a media van.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Viestinta ja kehitys-saatio Vikes</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-10" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">46750</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">46750</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">46750</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-01-01">46750</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
