<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-8764</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEF Societe de Transports et de Commerce Bogoya et Freres (STCBF)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY  OF  PROJECT  INFORMATION  (SPI)    Project Name	Burkina Faso - Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; de Transports et de Commerce Bogoya et Fr&#xE8;res (STCBF)    Region			Sub Saharan Africa    Sector			Transport    Project No			008764    Projected Board Date	February 22, 1998    Company Name	Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; de Transports et de Commerce Bogoya et Fr&#xE8;res(STCBF)     Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	Mr. Amad&#xE9; Bogoya Ou&#xE9;draogo, a Burkinab&#xE8; National, is the sponsor  of the project and the major shareholder with 75% of the shares.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The project is to acquire 15 reconditioned vehicles (2 petroleum tank trucks and 13 trailer trucks), and to build and operate a vehicle maintenance garage in Bobo-Dioulasso and a spare parts warehouse in Ouagadougou.  The companys fleet will consist of 22 trucks in total  (including the 7 existing tank trucks) to cover partly the national long haulage and international transportation markets between Burkina Faso and neighboring coastal countries.    Location of Project and Description of Site    	The project statutes are registered at Bobo-Dioulasso where the garage would be constructed.  Most project activities are in Ouagadougou, where the warehouse for spares would be constructed.  Plots have already been bought for both constructions in areas designated by local authorities for the concerned activities.    Project Cost Including Proposed IFC Investment    	Total project cost is estimated at US$1.1 million equivalent. ECOBANK-Burkina would provide loans of about US$0.6 million of which US$0.4 million would be guaranteed by IFC and US$0.2 million at ECOBANK-Burkinas own commercial risk.    Projects Development Impact:      	The project would help a major road transportation company in Burkina to improve and expand its facilities.  This would contribute to ameliorating the quality of the road transportation sector which is vital to the local economy, given its landlocked location.  The project would also help setting better transportation standards, which would encourage enhanced professionalism in the sector.    IFCs Role    	The proposed guarantee will help make possible the mobilization of  a local bank loan guaranteed by IFC on the basis of competitive market terms.  IFCs presence has helped the revision of the companys strategic focus which will concentrate only on goods transportation, excluding passenger transportation whose high costs have put a strain on the companys profitability.    Environmental Category and Issues    	The sponsor is implementing a management plan to prevent spills and thereby ground contamination.  All packaging and discarded oil materials will be properly disposed.  Domestic liquid effluents will be disposed in septic tanks.   Noise levels will be below the World Bank guidelines.  The sponsor will have a fire safety program in place.  Fire extinguishers will be installed at appropriate places. The employees will be trained on fire safety measures.  All employees will have annual medical checkups and    will be provided with and required to use the relevant personal protective equipment.  Based on its review of available information regarding potential environmental impacts and proposed mitigation measures, IFC concludes that, the proposed project is being designed to meet World bank guidelines.    Date SPI sent to PIC			January 22, 1998    This Summary of Project Information is prepared and distributed to the public in advance of consideration of the proposed transaction by the Corporations Board of Directors. &#xA0;It is provided for the purpose of enhancing the transparency of IFCs activities and should not be construed as presuming the outcome of IFC Board consideration.   For additional Information contact: &#xA0;Corporate Relations Unit - Telephone (202) 473-7711- facsimile:(202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; de Transports et de Commerce Bogoya et Fr&#xE9;res (STCBF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-8764" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-03-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="BF-Burkina Faso">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.5000000000 -1.6666700000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AE - Other (Including General Freight Trucking)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.36 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="912"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1999-03-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-03-15">360000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1999-03-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1999-03-15">360000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; de Transports et de Commerce Bogoya et Fr&#xE9;res (STCBF)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="912"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/8764/aef-societe-de-transports-et-de-commerce-bogoya-et-freres-stcbf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
