<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41160054-550477</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" secondary-reporter="0" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smart Healthcare Services for extreme-poor households</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh suffers from large disparities in most of the health indicators across social, economic, and demographic parameters. Rural population and the urban extreme poor (The urban extreme poor makes up one third of the nationwide urban population, living in slums, squatter settlements and city pavements) do not have proper access to essential healthcare services. Currently, 67% of the healthcare cost is being paid by general public, whereas global standard is below 32%. Only one hospital bed is allocated per 1667 people, and 34% of total posts in health sector are vacant due to scarcity of funds.
Municipalities and City Corporations under Ministry of Local Government, Rural Development and Co-operatives (MOLGRD&amp;C) are responsible for delivering Primary Health Care (PHC) services with technical guidance from Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (MOHFW). However, these public health services remain insufficient in terms of policy support and government financing which is reflected in the national budget allocation of 4.9% for the FY 2019-2020, which fails to meet the World Health Organization (WHO) standard of 15%.
The major barriers for extreme poor households in accessing healthcare services includes the cost of treatment and distance of healthcare facilities. According to the Bangladesh Urban Health Survey which covered 45,000 households across city corporations and other urban areas, only 13% of the population in city corporations have access to a governmental health facility within one kilometer. A significant barrier due to travel costs and also the loss of time compounded by long waiting times at overburdened facilities. This unfortunate circumstance has led to people foregoing treatment, avoiding formal healthcare facilities and opting for advice from the informal sectors which often includes retail drug shops. As a result, there is a high prevalence of non-communicable disease (NCDs), such as hypertension and diabetes, in slum areas. 

Sunamganj, one of the most underserved districts in Sylhet division, has a very high rate of maternal mortality of 425 deaths per 100,000 live births compared with the national average of 194. It has also been found that due to major barriers in accessing healthcare services, poor road connectivity, cost of treatment and distance, 89% of pregnant women have home deliveries assisted by non-medical birth attendants. Additionally, given the impact of frequent natural disasters like flooding, low-income communities of the district are highly vulnerable to different diseases and health risks.

Furthermore, a survey conducted with 700 extreme poor to middle income households has found that 87% families rely on overburdened public healthcare facilities and informal healthcare providers such as dispensaries and quacks for general healthcare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During project launch, we will undertake a mapping exercise to identify vulnerable communities whose healthcare needs are the highest. Once identified, the project will share the list with the municipality for their approval. Households comprising of reproductive women, lactating mothers, children and elderly will be given priority.

Direct Beneficiaries: Total Households- 800, Total Beneficiary- 3200, Reproductive age women (15-49 years)-1030, Pregnant and lactating women-64, Children under 05 - 388, Adolescent boys (10-19 years)-395, Adolescent girls (10-14 years)- 194, Elderly, over 60 years- 247, People with disability - 178

Indirect Beneficiary: People living in Sunamganj Sadar with a total population of 367,230 including people living in slums and squatters will benefit from an improved health system with improved quality of care in the long run.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To increase access to quality health care for extreme poor households through piloting a smartcard program.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Bangladesh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41160054" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sajida Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cordaid Global Office</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0) 70 &#x2013; 31 36 300</telephone>
   <email>info@cordaid.org</email>
   <website>https://www.cordaid.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grote Marktstraat 45, Den Haag, Zuid Holland, 2511 BH</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="0" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="BD">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
   </name>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <location ref="229111">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sylhet</narrative>
   </name>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
  </location>
  <sector code="12220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-04-01">119995</value>
  </budget>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Corporate Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of beneficiaries reached (HE)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people benefitting directly or indirectly from activities or services established/enabled/improved within a Cordaid Health project</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="HE0.01" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="BD"></location>
      <dimension name="Direct/ Indirect" value="Direct beneficiaries"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="BD"></location>
      <dimension name="Direct/ Indirect" value="Indirect beneficiaries"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3200"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Resilience</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project integrates climate risks in programming</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The integration of climate risks in programming includes an undertaking of concrete actions to reduce and/or mitigate risks related to climate change impact and disaster risks  ( for example droughts, erosion, salinization, flooding, etc.) 
The projects we refer to could be on the themes of health education, justice, security, disaster management, finance and livelihoods.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="CC1.03" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="BD"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Project Specific Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people referred within the health system</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of people that visited primary health facilities that were referred to hospitals (vertically and or horizontally)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="HE2.153" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-12-31" value="0" year="2021">
     <location ref="229111"></location>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0">
      <location ref="229111"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2240"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of Health Care Facilities using improved digital service delivery mechanisms</narrative>
    </title>
    <reference code="HE2.033" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3">
      <location ref="BD"></location>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
