<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2019000309</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of Energy Efficiency and Improvement of Environment Effects of Power Plants in Sri Lanka.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project begins with identifying (a) the CHP- type of power plants in Sri Lanka using various types of fuel oil (FO) and (b) also Boiler Power Plants managed to generate just electricity or heat or steam. We are especially looking for these power plants in 
use of manufacturing industries of Sri Lanka. This phase includes also the recognition of those power plants suitable for our technology knowhow and fuel additive.Project will run the pilot and demonstration phases in the selected power plants and using th
e fuel additive our company has developed and which we currently manufacture in Finland. Furthermore we are offering our own expertise and knowhow specially to improve the burning process of the power plants in question as well as supporting the recognitio
n and actions to cut any environmental effects due the imperfect burning process causing e.g. growing CO2 emission.These power plants are quite complex processes and testing the technology is mandatory for any further commercial actions.The pilot and demon
stration phase will also include a technology transfer of monitoring and measurement tools and technologies to improve the energy efficiency ratio of those power plants. These plants are mostly of older technology where improvements in both fuel consumptio
n efficiency and harmful emissions can be significant.For this project phase we are searching power plants among the Sri Lankan industries where energy (electricityheat steam) is produced with clearly older PP-technology. Typically these are power plants w
ith a higher impact of harmful environmental effects and with lower rate of efficiency in energy production.Within these power plants also the effect of energy efficiency and energy costs is more dramatic on the competitiveness of the whole company than th
eir competitors with more modern technology. In addition to improvements in the energy production process generally our fuel additive and knowhow will also reduce the production of oil and further cuts the consumption of fossil fuels and emissions. In addi
tion to the power industries we are researching similar power plants used e.g. in chemical industries and food production.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="61000" ref="NA" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turun Pari Oy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-02" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="LK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Sri Lanka"></location>
  <sector code="23183" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">34347</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">34347</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
