<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2018180067</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved access to livelihoods for young Gambian returnees and other vulnerable communities</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Palautettujen nuorten gambialaispakolaisten ammatillisten valmiuksien kehittamishanke</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to IOM conflict political upheavals ethnic tensions as well as environmental changes affect livelihoods creating displacement in Western Africa. Youth unemployment rate is 38.5% in Gambia and it has become a country with highest number of migrant
s per capita reaching Europe. During 2017 nearly 2500 Gambians were flown back from their escape stopover in Libya. In the nation of 2 million returnees re-integration poses a serious threat to the stability of Gambia.This proposed project seeks to increas
e sustainable income generating skills and subsequently to support the access to livelihoods opportunities of unemployed Gambian youths and women with special attention on returnees of the illegal migration from Libya Niger and Europe and also the youth de
portees from the USA. It will promote economic self-reliance and create a wide variety of opportunities through employability skills development job seeking and entrepreneurship. The project would specifically target the vulnerable ones in society such as 
returnees deportees school drop outs people living with disabilities (PLWDs) and young women.Through its advocacy the project will also work with local communities to combat the irregular migration as returnees are revealing their real-life experiences for
 their peers. Advocacy will also create a favorable environment for returnees and deportees to be reintegrated into the society without being stigmatized or shamed for their unsuccessful attempt in search of ?greener pastures?. All the elements of this pro
ject are aligned with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2250: Youth Peace + Security. The proposed action is also in line with the Finnish Development Policy also in Fragile States and the Civil Society Policy. Finland promotes sustainable livelih
oods decent work for all the status of women and highlights the civil society&apos;s role in this.The implementers are YMCA Finland and the Gambia YMCA who have been in close partnership for over 30 years and are experienced in the field. Refugee and migrant is
sues are YMCA&apos;s focus in all levels. World YMCA?s headquarters in Geneva have close ties with UN IOM and other global actors.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Kansainvalisen siirtolaisuusjarjeston (IOM) mukaan konfliktit poliittiset selkkaukset etniset jannitteet seka ympariston muutokset vaikuttavat elinkeinomahdollisuuksiin seka luovat pakolaisuutta ja laitonta siirtolaisuutta Lansi-Afrikassa. Nuorisotyottomyy
sprosentin ollessa 385 Gambiasta on lahtenyt maailman eniten siirtolaisia asukasta kohden suunnaten Eurooppaan. Vuoden 2017 aikana lahes 2500 gambialaista lennatettiin takaisin Libyasta. Palaavien haasteellinen integroituminen takaisin Gambiaan on todellin
en yhteiskuntarauhan uhka pienelle maalle.Tama hanke kehittaa kestavan toimeentulon hankintaan tarvittavia taitoja ja siten tukee nuorten gambialaisten tyollistymista. Hanke kohdennetaan erityisesti kaikkein heikommassa asemassa oleville: palautetuille nuo
rille naisille vammaisille koulupudokkaille seka tyottomille. Hanke edistaa taloudellista itsenaisyytta ja tarjoaa erilaisia mahdollisuuksia tyollisyys- tyonhaku- seka yrittajyystaitoja kehittamalla.Vaikuttamistyon avulla hanke pyrkii myos hillitsemaan lai
tonta maastamuuttoa. Palautetut nuoret jakavat tietoa omista traumatisoivista kokemuksistaan salakuljettajien matkassa ja Libyan pidatyskeskuksissa pyrkien oikomaan harhakuvitelmia kanssanuorten keskuudessa ? jotteivat muut toistaisi samoja virheita. Samal
la vaikuttamistyon tarkoitus on helpottaa palanneiden takaisinintegroitumista ja estaa leimautumista.Tassa tyossa YK:n paatoslauselma 2250: Nuoret rauha + turvallisuus on keskeinen tyokalu.Suomen kehityspoliittiset linjaukset kuten kansalaisyhteiskuntalinj
aus ja hauraissa valtioissa tyoskentelyn ohjeistus on huomioitu hankkeen suunnittelussa. Hanke tukee kestavia elinkeinoja ihmisarvoisia tyopaikkoja naisten aseman parantamista seka korostaa kansalaisyhteiskunnan roolia naissa.Hankkeen toteuttajia ovat Suom
en YMCA seka Gambian YMCA joiden kumppanuus on syntynyt yli 30 vuotta sitten. Molemmat toimijat ovat kokeneita seka kehitysyhteistyossa etta nuorten kouluttamisessa. Pakolais- ja siirtolaisuusteemat ovat fokuksessa YMCA:n agendalla kaikilla sen eri tasoill
a. YMCA:n Maailmanliitolla Genevessa on laheiset yhteydet YK-jarjestoihin IOM:n seka muihin keskeisiin kansainvalisiin toimijoihin.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomen Nuorten Miesten Kristillisten Yhd</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Suomen YMCA:n liitto ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2018180067" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is the main prio
rity area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">100000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">100000</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2018-2018180067" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
