<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2017170128</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trimble partner in Myanmar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is a precursor for a larger group of projects aimed at transferring Finnish know-how and technology for electric distribution networks to Myanmar. The electricity networks in Myanmar are in poor condition which is well characterized by the figu
re of Electric power transmission and distribution losses which is 28% of output compared to world average of 8%. Comprehensive and reliable electric distribution system is the cornerstone of modern society and efficiency of the network is a considerable e
nvironmental factor. This project focuses on next/phase project planning and identifying a local partner for delivering supporting and further developing information systems for electricity distribution.Trimble Solutions Oy has been developing and deliveri
ng information systems for electricity distribution since 1987. Trimble?s solutions are in use in more than 200 utilities in Europe and the US. Trimble has long experience in delivering demanding systems mainly with own resources and through subsidiaries. 
The goal in this project is to grow the capabilities of a local partner so that the partner can build and expand its business around services built on Trimble?s Finnish technology. For the utilities these system are critical tools so the support and additi
onal professional services need to be available locally and with short notice. Typically the systems include a maintenance contract that provides the partner with steady revenue for maintaining and developing resources.  The target model means a long-term 
partnership between the end customer Trimble and its partner.The larger group of projects targets to provide a development package containing services and Finnish technology and know-how with significant impact in developing the electricity distribution in
 Myanmar. The package will contain documenting the existing networks creating development plans renovating and building the networks as well as continuous operation. In all phases the local capabilities will be developed in order to ensure the sustainabili
ty of the improvements and further development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="61000" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trimble Solutions Oy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2017170128" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Myanmar"></location>
  <sector code="23630" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430664" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maittain kohdentamaton kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-region specific development cooperation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">98435.43</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
