<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2019000166</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RHESA - Regional Higher Education Services in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the RHESA -project is to apply the Finnish Regional Higher Education and Services model in Namibia and in this way support sustainable development in the country. The partners are in Namibia the University of Namibia (UNAM) and in Finland the Se
inajoki University of Applied Sciences (SeAMK).The main aim is to strenghten co-operation between UNAM and regional actors so that all of them are committed to follow the Finnish model of cooperation between higher education and local actors (cities towns 
authorities and enterprises) and implement the localized model in Namibia. The first phase in the project is to analyze an operating environment to evaluate previous education and education system in Namibia and to make an assessment concerning educational
 needs.The first Regional Higher Education and Services pilot takes place in UNAM Windhoek main Campus. The following possible regions for the experiments are the UNAM Neudam campus near Hosea Kutako airport and the UNAM e-Campus in Otjiwarongo in Central 
Namibia. Neudam will be an open campus also for international students and in Otjiwarongo the activities mainly concentrate on the education of women and young people who have dropped out from the education or who are in a situation of social exclusion. On
e important experience raised from the regional education experiments in Finland is the cooperation with the local enterprises. This has produced new activity in the already existing enterprises and also courage the students to start new startups. The flex
ibility and applicability of the regional higher education fastens the availability of new skillful workers for the local enterprises. Outcome of the project is a long-term partnership between UNAM and SeAMK aiming capacity building of students teachers re
gional actors and citizens. During the project the partners sign also a 10-year sustainable business partnership agreement. Gradually UNAM will take the responsibility in implementing the Regional Higher Education and Services model in Namibia. After the p
roject the role of SeAMK is quality assurance and continuous development of the model together with UNAM.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="61004" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seinajoen ammattikorkeakoulu Oy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Namibia"></location>
  <sector code="11420" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="NA" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">NA</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">10208</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">10208</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
