<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2019000109</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">APS in Nigeria and Tanzania</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this project is to establish in Nigeria and Tanzania joint ventures which will be in charge of the installation and maintenance of the structured cabling and network. The companies are responsible for the product sale as well. The experience ac
quired from Kenya will be used in the establishment of these two companies. Business models in Nigeria and Tanzania are identical and the operations of these establishing projects are similar to each other. Operations in Nigeria have proceeded a bit furthe
r than in Tanzania so the joint venture in Tanzania will be established some months later than the subsidiary in Nigeria. Closely knitted timetables make it possible to achieve both establishments as a part of this one mutual project.In this project AP Sol
utions Oy will execute background checks for the already identified partners. The company has done a lengthy research for finding suitable partners from many African countries. Potential partners have already been identified in both Nigeria and Tanzania an
d the background checks will be carried out as a part of this project.In the research work in this project the company will familiarize oneself with the preliminary information regarding Nigeria and Tanzania. AP Solutions Oy had ordered a market research r
egarding structured cabling market status from an outside consulting company (BSRIA Piero Russo). AP Solutions also has quality information from its network partners. In this project will be carried out a profound market information research regarding key 
business areas. One example of this research is to conduct a study to find out if a B2B E-commerce platform is a good way to operate in Africa.Also as a part of this project AP Solutions will develop a training-concept which will give vocational skills to 
local workers and enables the development of local expert teams to carry out installation projects. This training-concept can be used in other parts of Africa as well.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="61004" ref="61002-62" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AP Solutions Oy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-13" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Nigeria;Tanzania"></location>
  <sector code="22040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">55405</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">55405</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
