<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2009091298</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the quality of life through Biogas in Dausa Rajasthan India Phase III</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This four year project aims to contribute to a lower the level of poverty and reducing vulnerability in rural households in 100 villages in Dausa and Bandikui blocks in Dausa district (Rajasthan India). It is a continuation to the two phases implemented in
 2010-12 and 2014-16 which were also funded by UFF and the Ministry for Foreign Affairs Finland and implemented by HPPI. This third phase aims to consolidate the results achieved during the earlier phases as well as build and expand on them.The direct obje
ctive of the project is to improve the quality of life and climate change adaptation for rural households in Dausa district. The key results are:1) Improved access to affordable clean + green energy2) Improved status of women in the household3) Improved aw
areness and knowledge on latest techniques and benefits of livestock management and sustainable organic agriculture4) Increase in agriculture related income generation activitiesThe access to clean and green energy is enhanced by construction of 650 biogas
 plants. 1200 women from vulnerable sections of society are reached through Self-Help groups and empowered with financial literacy and better income generation skills. 1200 male farmers are reached through farmers clubs with trainings on livestock manageme
nt and sustainable organic agriculture. To ensure increase in agriculture related income generation activities the project connects the farmers to existing government schemes and establishes market linkages for ensuring better price for their produce.The p
roject takes a holistic approach tackling issues of poverty gender and energy. Families get access to clean energy from the biogas plants for cooking. Empowerment of women and improvement in quality of life are achieved through significantly reduced domest
ic work directly leading to improved health and time available to engage in productive activities. The use of bioslurry from the biogas plants as farm manure increases agricultural output and reduces expenditure on energy and chemical fertilizers/pesticide
s. Improved techniques in agriculture and livestock management leads to increases in yield and income and enhances climate adaptability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-8" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UFF Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2009091298" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-10" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="23210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">8000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
