<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2016160064</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public-Private-People: Joint and Inclusive Effort Against Tuberculosis in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project builds on the previous TB intervention implemented by LSV. However in order to increase effectiveness totally new strategies will be applied.TB continues to be an essential health problem in Somalia. The disease hasn&apos;t been beaten yet but rathe
r new problems emerge such as multi-drug resistant forms of TB resulting in much more complex treatment regimens and bigger danger to the population.LSV will continue to diagnose and treat TB patients in Hargeisa and Mogadishu. As a new strategy the privat
e sector health care providers (clinics and pharmacies) and local communities will be engaged in the effort in a systematic way in order to strengthen a holistic public-private-people partnership approach to tackling the disease. In addition collaboration 
with the local maternity and child health facility network will be strengthened. The overall objective is to contribute to the reduction of TB burden and suffering in Somalia. The immediate objectives of the project include 1) To increase TB awareness and 
participation of communities in TB control. 2) To increase TB awareness and participation of private practitioners and pharmacists in TB control in. 3) To diagnose and treat patients at two TB centers according to WHO&apos;s DOTS protocol. 4) To provide TB cult
ure services and drug susceptibility tests (DST) for suspected MDR cases.Regarding the cross-cutting themes the project will empower women and facilitate their access to TB services. In addition the project will reduce inequality by providing an access to 
TB services for internally displaced persons (IDPs). When it comes to climate proofing there are no negative impacts on environment. For example thanks to community DOTS there will be less daily traveling to TB Centers.The main project partners include NGO
 called PSR and National TB Programs (NTPs). LSV will strengthen their capacity in all the fields described above.The main beneficiaries include local people of Hargeisa Mogadishu and nomads living in nearby areas who have TB or belong to risk groups. The 
project will help the poorest of the poor. For example many cases are found among people who suffer from malnutrition.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-756" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Laakarin Sosialinen Vastuu ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2016160064" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="12263" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">26422</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
