<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2017170100</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amka Mwanamke (Woman Arise) Campaign in Response to Women&apos;s Land Rights</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Agricultural Modernization Association (TAMA) intends to implement a one year Amka Mwanamke Campaign project that aims at empowering marginalized women to secure land rights in Muleba District. The project seeks to promote positive change in polic
ies and customary laws those deprive women&apos;s rights to land ownership by 2018; to strengthen women&apos;s capacity to have voices and confidence to protect their rights to access own and have full control over land and other family resources; promote awareness 
and accountability among land owners local leaders and existing land councils on equitable distribution of land resources gender equity and equality by 2018. The need for this project is that In Tanzania laws that support women&apos;s rights to land ownership h
ave been enacted but a great milestone- does not bring all women to the end - customary practices regarding marriage and inheritance continue to discriminate heavily against women. The government and other development partners have been carrying out their 
roles to facilitate implementation of land policy and laws to ensure women&apos;s ownership of land but such roles need other joint efforts to collaboratively increase awareness and empower more women to fight for their rights hence this project.The expected de
velopment impact of this project is Women in Muleba District have access to and control over land. Project outcomes will be; increased capacity knowledge and skills among marginalized women on their rights to have access to and control over land; village a
nd Ward Land Councils are accountable and ensure equitable distribution of land resources for women; increased access to information education and communication services and materials for women about land distribution registration and land rights. Main ben
eficiaries in this project are women and the main implementing Agency is Tanzania Agricultural Modernization Association (TAMA). Why TAMA was chosen it&apos;s because the Land issue  and particularly women&apos;s land rights is a sensitive issue which needs support 
so that many women can enjoy their rights socially and economically as land is a basic resource from which human beings and almost other living creatures depend on for their living. For more information about TAMA click the following website: www.tama.or.t
z.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11000" ref="11000-1" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2017170100" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430662" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country-specific and regional development cooperation</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maa-ja aluekohtainen kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">8580</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
