<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2016160165</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksien kunnioittaminen suomalaisyritysten toiminnassa Intiassa</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Respecting human rights in the operations of Finnish companies&apos; operations in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tama Finnwatchin ja Cividepin yhteishanke edistaa sita etta Intiassa on tarjolla enemman ihmisarvoista tyota ja toimeentuloa erityisesti naisille. Taman pitkan aikavalin tavoitteen saavuttamiseksi tyoelaman perusoikeuksia turvaaminen niin lain kuin kaytann
onkin tasolla naisten oikeuksien toteutuminen tyopaikoilla seka tyontekijoiden voimaannuttaminen ja tyoehtoneuvotteluihin tahtaavan keskusteluyhteyden luominen tyontekijoiden ja yritysjohdon valille ovat hankkeen keskiossa.Jatkohankkeen tavoitteet saavutet
aan tutkimalla tyooloja Suomessa toimivien yritysten intialaisten tytartyhtioiden ja tavarantoimittajien tehtailla. Tutkimustulokset julkaistaan (vahintaan 2 raporttia 4 tutkimusartikkelia) ja kuluttajia (tavoitettavuus 15 milj.) mobilisoidaan vaatimaan yr
ityksilta lisaa vastuullisuutta. Yritysten kanssa kaydaan rakentavaa ja ratkaisukeskeista vuoropuhelua jonka kautta yrityksia kannustetaan ja tuetaan entista kattavamman ihmisoikeuksia koskevan huolellisuusvelvoitteen noudattamisessa (20 yritysta).Hankkeen
 paaasiallisia hyodynsaajia ovat tyontekijat em. tehtaissa. Hankkeen aikana koulutetaan vuosittain 100 tyontekijaa tyoelamanoikeuksista (yhteensa 400 joista 70% naisia daliteja tai alkuperaisvaestoihin kuuluvia henkiloita). Tyontekijoiden jarjestaytymisen 
mahdollistavan ilmapiirin luomiseksi myos tehtaiden johdolle jarjestetaan koulutusta yritysten ihmisoikeusvastuusta (2 koulutusta per vuosi). Tyontekijoita tuetaan myos kasvattamalla tyontekijoita tukevien ruohonjuurijarjestojen kapasiteettia (yhteensa 10 
tyopajaa).Projekti myos mobilisoi suomalaisia/eurooppalaisia yrityksia (10) vaikuttamaan Intiassa kaynnissa oleviin tyolainsaadannon uudistuksiin joiden pelataan merkittavasti heikentavan tyontekijoiden lakisaateisia oikeuksia. Jatkohankkeen aikana uusi pr
ojektikumppanimme valtion yhteishankintayksikko Hansel Oy osallistuu elektroniikka-alan yritysten kanssa kaytavaan vuoropuheluun.Jatkohanke tukee Cividepin verkostoitumista ruohonjuuritason jarjestojen ja ammattiliittojen kanssa seka kasvattaa sen kapasite
ettia tehda kenttatutkimusta ja projektinhallintataitoja.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This joint project between Finnwatch and Cividep contributes towards the creation of decent jobs and livelihood opportunities in India especially for women. To achieve this long-term goal protection of fundamental labour rights both in law and in practice 
in India is essential as are implementation of gender rights at workplace and enabling and empowering of workers themselves to negotiate better terms and conditions of work.Continuation project aims to achieve its objectives by conducting primary research 
into working conditions in the subsidiaries and suppliers? manufacturing units in India of companies operating in Finland. Research results are published (at least 2 reports 4 research articles) and consumers (reach at least 15 million) mobilised to demand
 more responsibility from the companies. Project partners will engage in constructive and solution-oriented dialogue with the companies encouraging and supporting them to increase and improve human rights due diligence in their operations (at least 20 comp
anies).Project?s main beneficiaries are workers in the above-mentioned manufacturing units. At least 100 workers will be reached through trainings in labour rights each year of the project (400 in total) 70% of whom will be women Dalits or indigenous peopl
e. In order to create an enabling environment for workers to organise training on business and human rights (BHR) is offered to the Indian managements of 2 such units each year. Workers are further supported through capacity-building workshops for their re
presentative grass-roots organisations (at least 10 in total).The project also mobilises Finnish/European companies (at least 10) to influence the ongoing labour reforms in India which are feared to considerably weaken the legal protection of labour rights
 in India. The continuation phase introduces a new project partner Hansel a Finnish state-owned limited company and the government&apos;s central purchasing body for the work done in the electronics sector.The project will strengthen Cividep&apos;s networks and coll
aboration with grass-roots NGOs and trade unions and its capacity to conduct field research and project management skills.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FinnWatch</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Finnwatch ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2016160165" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 2, PRIMARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Generating jobs, livelihood opportunities and well-being in a developing country is the main prio
rity area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights progressive</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Ihmisoikeuksia edistava</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 3, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving democracy in societies is a secondary priority area in this activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9999999" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Muut momentit</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other budget lines</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="PRIORITY AREA 1, SECONDARY" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/goals-and-principles-of-finland-s-development-policy#Priorities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the rights and status of women and girls is a secondary priority area in this 
activity</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">6362</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2018-2016160165" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
