<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2019000467</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EU REACH regulation capacity building for South East Asian export companies Phase 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project goal is to establish a subsidiary for providing consulting and education services about the EU REACH regulation. Additionally the intention is to conclude long-term agreements in order to carry out the overall concept in Vietnam.  Phase 2 is to cre
ate a multi-channel service system for small medium and large businesses. The commercial offer to medium and large companies is for those whose size and scale of production requires more in-depth consultation. This customer group Chementors manages by its 
own local staff.The Support Center for small and handicraft companies distributes free basic information about the entire REACH certification and guides the customer through the procedures for applying for a certificate. The goal is also to find partners t
o meet the needs of Support Center customers in certification. The Support Center strives to direct the companies to the partner&apos;s services while the partner relies on Chementors services. Small business advisory and guidance services are not commercially 
sustainable and must be based on external funding. As a completely new opportunity we are trying to develop new partnerships in the field of chemical waste management which have received a lot of inquiries (Hazardous Chemicals) as well as substitute substa
nces. There also seems to be demand for the compilation of safety data sheets in Vietnam with little supply available.The Support Center is likely to work with the PPP method where Chementors designs builds and operates the service and may be funded by gov
ernment / local government or ODA operators. The first discussions with the ministry have taken place which keeps the idea good. It is important to note that under the REACH Directive all non-EU suppliers must have a representative within the EU so that th
e service chain must extend from Vietnam to the EU. Chementors specializes in this service and Vietnamese partners can use Chementor services in the EU.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="61004" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chementors Oy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Vietnam"></location>
  <sector code="32130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="NA" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">NA</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">49696</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">49696</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
