<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2014140707</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening community-based protection in Torotorofotsy Ramsar wetland</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the continuation project phase the protection of the Torotorofotsy Ramsar Wetland will be intensified together with the local communities and environmental administration in the rainforest area of Madagascar. The wetland obtained official protection sta
tus during the previous project period in 2015 since it inhabits a significant diversity of endemic and endangered animal and plant species. The wetland is threatened by rice farming of the local and migrant people rapid population growth and a large mine 
close by. Torotorofotsy has an important role in preservation of biodiversity in preventing erosion and climate change and securing of regional water supply. In a long run the destruction of the wetland would hinder climate change adaptation and would dete
riorate food security of the local population. The main goal of the continuation project is to proceed with the community based conservation of the Ramsar wetland particularly from its buffer zone in a participatory way. The coordination of  wetland core a
rea conservation was assigned by the state to a Madagascan NGO Asity in 2015 and therefore this continuation project will concentrate on the buffer zone where our partner Mitsinjo operates. The needs of the growing population living around the wetland put 
constant pressure to the conservation of the core area the reason for which it is vital to support the beneficiaries living in the buffer zone with alternative income generation activities. With our partner organisation Mitsinjo we continue to promote the 
use of sustainable and diverse farming methods environmental education awareness raising and possibilities for alternative income generation activities. We support local democracy and grass-roots level advocacy work as well as advocate on a national level 
in order to impact the root causes of the challenges of Torotorofotsy wetland conservation. The main beneficiaries of the continuation project are the members of Mitsinjo local communities around Torotorofotsy schools and local and regional authorities. Th
e activities include workshops trainings events awareness raising advocacy work and networking.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomen Luonnonsuojeluliitto ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2014140707" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-27" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisjarjestojen kehitysyhteistyolle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">77300</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">77300</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">77300</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
