<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2014140579</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">F.a: Corporate engagement</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector engagement is a highly relevant field of work not only in view of the strong prioritization of the Finnish Development Policy on the role of private sector in development, but in terms of its concrete results.In the next four years, we will 
focus our efforts on engaging with private sector actors regarding Human Rights Due Diligence based on the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights (UNGPs). Specifically, we aim to work together especially regarding children in the supply chain o
r identifying particularly vulnerable segments in the supply chain workforce as well as in piloting innovative ways for stakeholder engagement and community dialogue in communities with potential business-related child right impacts.In summary, the 2018-20
21 Programme, Plan Finland&#x2019;s corporate engagement will: 1) Continue to establish multi-sector partnerships in order to enhance the realisation of child rights also in business operations; 2) Pilot innovative approaches in Human Rights Due Diligence and 3
) Advocate strongly with other child-centered organisations in Finland for enhanced regulation in regard business and human rights, especially Human Rights Due Diligence.The results of this work will be to find new working models together with private sect
or for businesses to respect child rights and gender equality in their business operations. The specific results to children and particularly girls will vary depending on partner and country of operations. The result for the advocacy work will be to increa
se public discussion on state responsibility to protect human rights in business operations, and strive for policy changes to support UN Guiding principles of business and human rights in Finland.The beneficiaries of this work are children, particularly gi
rls and their families who are impacted by business operations in developing countries. Key beneficiaries are also Finnish companies and their staff working on business and human rights due diligence.In seeking solutions to these complex problems, we have 
joined up the expertise of the corporate partners, Plan Finland as well as Plan Country Offices&#x2019; in-depth knowledge and understanding of child rights and the local corporate scene. The rich experience of Plan from various parts of the world, and a strong
 child rights and gender expertise, has proven to be attractive to many Finnish companies, as they tackle social responsibility issues in their supply chains</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan Suomi s&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Plan Suomi s&#xE4;&#xE4;ti&#xF6;</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2014140579" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <location ref="Global + Finland"></location>
  <sector code="25010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430668" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for NGOs</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Tuki kansalaisj&#xE4;rjest&#xF6;jen kehitysyhteisty&#xF6;lle</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/48132/human_rights_based_approach_in_finlands_development_cooperation___guidance">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="FI"></narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">3167.1</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="FI-3-2018-2014140579" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
