<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2019-2017170040</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the capacity of local partners of GoSol&apos;s pilots in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main goal of the project is to support the commercialization of SFCO technology in Kenya and prepare for further scale-up. Through World Vision?s (WV) support the process can be made faster and results more sustainable. WV will train local producer gro
ups and entrepreneurs and facilitate SFCO&apos;s engagement with different partners and stakeholders needed for the introduction testing manufacturing commercialization and scaling-up of SFCO technology. WV will also monitor and report the progress against the 
targets. WV will also support assessing the value chain for manufacturing the GoSol machines. The community based businesses and producer groups that SFCO is targeting as their partners and customers lack skills and assets needed to operate in a sustainabl
e way to be able to purchase the equipment or to work in different parts of the GoSol value chain. In this project we will develop a training module to answer these needs. The target beneficiaries that will be trained include women youth and disabled peopl
e. The training will also include strengthening financial skills and we will design suitable financial services to the target groups (credit savings schemes insurance). Market linkages will be created with traders and other customers as well as government 
funding schemes. These functions are crucial to ensure that the businesses will become viable and that the technology is continued to be used after the pilots end.  WV will also facilitate the contact of SFCO to community decision makers local government a
ctors and local businesses. The support and acceptance of these stakeholders is crucial and here WV?s existing working relationships are an asset. One part of the project is to test the technology in Kakuma refugee camp or host community in Turkana county.
 This is a new environment for SFCO and WV can support the company in entering the humanitarian ecosystem. Finally we will identify new target groups in Kenya for scaling-up and investigate the possibility to start piloting next in Uganda. Training modules
 and other tools developed and the learnings from this project can be used in the subsequent steps of the scale-up.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="22000-175" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomen World Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="FI-3-2018-2017170040" type="A3"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-18" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Kenya"></location>
  <sector code="23230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <tag code="2430664" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://um.fi/documents/35732/0/finlands-development-cooperation-appropriations-and-disbursements-1989-2019.pdf/fe42e62c-798c-359f-6180-e7e01fd9d89a?t=1588088517786">
   <narrative xml:lang="FI">Maittain kohdentamaton kehitysyhteistyo</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-region specific development cooperation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">46393</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
