<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5125003001-COD-15180</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senior Women Protection Advisor at UNJHRO 2017-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Senior r&#xE5;dgivare sexuellt v&#xE5;ld till UNJHRO 2017-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Insatsen best&#xE5;r av att bidra med en sekonderad person till UN Joint Human Rights Office (UNJHRO) p&#xE5; en senior P5 niv&#xE5; under 18 m&#xE5;nader. Detta ska m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra f&#xF6;r UNJHRO i Kinshasa att ge st&#xF6;d till implementeringen av handlingsplanen mot sexuellt v&#xE5;ld med FARDC (kongolesiska arm&#xE9;n) och personen ska leda arbetet med att implementera ett flertal FN resolutioner r&#xF6;rande konflikt relaterat sexuellt v&#xE5;ld.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Embassy is proposing another secondment of a senior women protection advisor to UNJHRO during the period December 2016 - March 2019. During this phase, he/she will lead the implementation of Security Council Resolutions 1820; 1888; 1960; 2106 and 2242 on Conflict-Related Sexual Violence (CRSV) in the Democratic Republic of Congo and support the implementation of the FARDCs (the Congolse Army) Action Plan against sexual violance. The seconded person will be recruited by UNJHRO. The secondment will contribute to the result &quot;Strengthened capacity to prevent and alleviate the consequences of sexual and gender based violance&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of the support to the Senior Women Protection Advisor is to advocate and support the government of DRC in reducing the levels of sexual violence by their armed forces and by other armed actors in the context of the armed conflict.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41313" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OHCHR/Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41313" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OHCHR/Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ending violence against women and girls</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.10" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.10 - 0 S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till information och skydda grundl&#xE4;ggande friheter, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning och internationella avtal.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.10 - Ensure public access to information and protect fundamental freedoms, in accordance with national legislation and international agreements.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.2 - Avskaffa alla former av v&#xE5;ld mot alla kvinnor och flickor i det offentliga och privata rummet, inklusive m&#xE4;nniskohandel, sexuellt utnyttjande och andra typer av exploatering.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.2 - Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other types of exploitation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">303862.5606264243</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">169881.8236214674</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">222218.5090789877</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">303862.5606264243</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">169881.8236214674</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">222218.5090789877</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-01">721979.430842</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">303862.5606264244</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-10-28">169881.8236214674</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">222218.5090789877</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">-193162.6776574287</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-28">193162.6776574287</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the start of the contribution, two SWPAs have left the post causing delays in the implementation. The second Senior Women Protection Advisor, SWPA, left the mission in December 2019 and a new recruited advisor was delayed due to many reasons, in particular the outbreak of the Covid-19 pandemic. The Deputy Director of the Joint Human Rights Office served as SWPA ad interim until the arrival of the new SWPA in November 2020 and thus ensured that the team could continue its work to reach the objectives. The new SWPA arrived in October 2020 and met with the embassy as soon as possible after mandatory quarantine and induction training.&#xA0;
Even though working in the office of the UNJHRO, the SWPA mandate is part of that of the SRSG on Sexual Violence in Conflict (SVC) to whom she directly reports. The main objective of this contribution is to work on conflict related sexual violence (CRSV).&#xA0;Key results of the SWPA during the implementation of this contribution until transferred to contribution 12906 as a component in the general support to the UNJHRO are the following.
The Security Council has mandated MONUSCO to establish Monitoring, Analysis and Reporting Arrangements (MARA) on conflict-related sexual violence, to engage with parties to the conflict for concrete time-bound commitments to comprehensively address CRSV and to support parties to the conflict to implement these commitments. CRSV data collection and analysis is conducted by the MARA Working Group, established in 2013, of which MONUSCO Sections and UN agencies are part. The SWPA has strengthened the work and coordination of the MARA working group and its analysis through the development in 2018 of a set of qualitative indicators, including classification of sexual violence types, modus operandi and location of attacks. The membership of the MARA was extended to include all civilian sections of Monusco, the Force Gender Focal Point, UNPOL, as well as all agencies. The meetings of the MARA were made regular and more efficient contributing to the identification of key priorities. The SWPA also strengthened the cooperation and coordination with humanitarian actors by participation in the Protection Cluster and Gender-Based Violence (GBV) Sub-Cluster.&#xA0;
Within Monusco, apart from strengthening the work and coordination of the MARA working group the SWPA participated in all decisions on support to the armed forces to ensure inclusion of CRSV prevention and response; provided support to all units of MONUSCO ensuring that the CSRV mandate is fully implemented by all thematic units; contributed by missions and work to the adoption of actions plans for the CRSV prevention and response.
The SWPA worked together with national authorities to develop the Addendum to the 2013 Joint Communiqu&#xE9; between the Government of the DRC and the United Nations against Sexual Violence in Conflict. During this work, the SWPA promoted and ensured the recommitment of the government to prevent and stop sexual violence in conflict. The SWPA was instrumental in organising the visit to the DRC of the SRSG SVC, who during her visit to the DRC appointed the First Lady to serve as a Global Champion for the Prevention of CRSV. The work by the SWPA led to the adoption of an action plan by the national police, the PNC, against sexual violence in December 2019. The armed forces, the FARDC, had already previously signed such an action plan. Promotion of the full implementation of the actions plans remains one of the main tasks of the SWPA.
In December 2019, the SWPA assisted Sweden in the planning and organisation of an event to commemorate the ten year&apos;s mandate of the SRSG SVC which coincided with the SRSG&apos;s visit to the DRC.&#xA0;
The SWPA continuously monitored and reported on CRSV and by this contributing to the Secretary General&apos;s annual reports on sexual violence in conflict, ensuring that these human rights violations were not forgotten or hidden. An information recording and analysis system was established in 2018 and progressively strengthened and refined to contribute to early warnings triggering Force patrolling and other deployments to key hotspots. The SWPA reports as well as early warnings&apos; assessments that the SWPA and her team contributed to lead to the mobilisation of support for timely response to CRSV such as protection missions, assistance to survivors of sexual violence, investigations of specific cases, and post-rape care in several locations of the DRC. One of these missions led to the adoption of an action plan providing guidance on effective multisectoral response. The action plan, the so called Shabunda Action Plan, has since been amended that seeks to build on the successes of the first plan and expand to other critical areas to respond to CRSV.
In 2018, the SWPA worked with the Monusco Protection of Civilians Advisor and the UNJHRO Deputy Director (who in 2020 acted as the SWPA a.i.) to develop a guidance document on Disarmament, Demobilisation and Reintegration (DDR) and protections, including key elements of CRSV prevention and response, which was shared with all Monusco field offices. In 2019, the SWPA supported the integration of conflict-related sexual violence prevention and response measures in Monusco&apos;s strategy on DDR. The SWPA will continue this, including support to transitional justice initiatives.
As a part of her mandate, the SWPA regularly engaged with parties to the conflict, including non-state armed actors. Together with the child protection section she ensured the integration of CRSV concerns in acts of commitments to stop the recruitment and use of child soldiers made by armed groups. This was pushed for also with FARDC and PNC to ensure that CRSV is prioritised in their human rights monitoring.
The SWPA ensured regular cooperation with the government (the previous as well as the one installed during the time of this contribution). She for example held regular meetings with the Special Advisor to the President on Youth, Gender and Violence against Women for follow up of the publication of the addendum to the joint communiqu&#xE9; and adopt a roadmap for its implementation; regularly met with provincial authorities, the FARDC, the PNC and CSOs following up allegations of CRSV by state agents; assisted in the development of training materials to the FARDC; and shared information with judicial authorities influencing the performance of judicial performances.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51250030" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1225000000" strategy-end-date="2019-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>DR Congo 2015-2019</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>DR Kongo 2015-2019</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
