<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5125003201-COD-72010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience through DRC Humanitarian Fund 2017-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Resiliens genom DRK Humanit&#xE4;ra Fonden 2017-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;d 2017-2019 f&#xF6;r resiliens och h&#xE5;llbara l&#xF6;sningar f&#xF6;r individer, hush&#xE5;llen och samh&#xE4;llen som har drabbats av humanit&#xE4;ra kriser i DRK genom Humanit&#xE4;ra Fondens standardallokering av medel i syftet att stimulera l&#xE4;nk mellan humanit&#xE4;r verksamhet och &#xE5;teruppbyggnad/utveckling, i enlighet med DRK:s humanit&#xE4;ra strategiska planer.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support in 2017-2019 to resilience and durable solutions for individuals, housholds and communities who have been affected by humanitarian crises in DRC, through the Humanitarian Fund&apos;s standard allocations in view of stimulating the link between humanitarian action and recovery/development in the frame of DRC&apos;s humanitarian response strategies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through its Standard Allocations to projects with up to 24 months implementation period, the DRC Country based Humanitarian Pooled Fund (CBPF) is strengthened in its work with supporting beneficiaries&apos; recovery and resilience among communities affected by humanitarian crises in different parts of DRC.
The longer term interventions add to shorter term interventions through emergency allocations and standard allocations for projects of shorter durations, funded through humanitarian funding from Sweden and other donors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.1 - Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.1 - St&#xE4;rka motst&#xE5;ndskraften mot och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatrelaterade faror och naturkatastrofer i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="13.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.3 - F&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra utbildningen, medvetenheten och den m&#xE4;nskliga och institutionella kapaciteten vad g&#xE4;ller begr&#xE4;nsning av klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarna, klimatanpassning, begr&#xE4;nsning av klimatf&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringarnas konsekvenser samt tidig varning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.3 - Improve education, awareness-raising and human and institutional capacity on climate change mitigation, adaptation, impact reduction and early warning.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="16.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.3 - Fr&#xE4;mja r&#xE4;ttss&#xE4;kerheten p&#xE5; nationell och internationell niv&#xE5; samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla lika tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttvisa f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.3 - Promote the rule of law at the national and international levels and ensure equal access to justice for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="17.17" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.1 - By 2030, end hunger and ensure access by all people, in particular the poor and people in vulnerable situations, including infants, to safe, nutritious and sufficient food all year round.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">2.1 - Senast 2030 avskaffa hunger och garantera alla m&#xE4;nniskor, i synnerhet de fattiga och m&#xE4;nniskor i utsatta situationer, inklusive sm&#xE5; barn, tillg&#xE5;ng till tillr&#xE4;ckligt med s&#xE4;ker och n&#xE4;ringsrik mat &#xE5;ret om.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.a - Genomf&#xF6;ra reformer f&#xF6;r att ge kvinnor lika r&#xE4;tt till ekonomiska resurser, m&#xF6;jlighet att &#xE4;ga och kontrollera mark och andra former av egendom samt tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, arv och naturresurser, i enlighet med nationell lagstiftning</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.a - Undertake reforms to give women equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to ownership and control over land and other forms of property, financial services, inheritance and natural resources, in accordance with national laws.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2340002.34000234</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2301390.0395839084</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">2340002.3400023393</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">2301390.039583909</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-31">7020007.020007</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-28">2340002.34000234</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-28">2301390.0395839084</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">2115081.5892723063</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The humanitarian pooled fund demonstrated significant results in providing humanitarian aid to address needs in the DRC throughout the activity period of the intervention. The added value of a multiyear grant like this contribution brought a number of interesting results with regard to management of the fund, adding a longer term perspective and raising the importance of resilience in strategic planning.
The activities implemented through the CBPF have mainly been linked to nine clusters as well as coordination, and respond to two main objectives of the humanitarian response: Immediate improvement of the living conditions of people affected by the crisis, with priority to the most vulnerable (SO1); and Protecting people affected by the humanitarian crisis and ensuring respect for their human rights (SO2).
Between 2016 and 2018, the CBPF more than doubled its received funding to just over 90 million USD, adding new donors and/or increased amounts from several donors. This can be partly seen in context of significant efforts of the Embassy to promote the CBPF as an important instrument for humanitarian assistance in the wider donor community. Sweden was also not the only country to provide multiyear funding throughout the contribution period, Belgium also provided multiyear funding in 2018-2019.
The addition of multiyear funding has allowed for certain very specific results with regard to developing processes and procedures. For example, the fund has improved its allocation procedures and now operates in line with global CBPF standards, with two modalities, standard allocations and emergency (reserve) allocations, where the former allows for longer project cycles of up to 24 months. A harmonized and simplified reporting format with 20 fixed indicators has been adopted internationally, including for the CBPF DRC, facilitating overview, identification of tendencies and comparison over time.
The monitoring and follow up function of the fund has been strengthened through the 2019 revision of the operational manual as well as an increase in monitoring staff. The number of projects that could be visited on a regular basis increased. The advisory board continues to advocate for strengthened monitoring and quality assurance of the pooled fund management team and staff.
In addition to contributed to improved processes and procedures the fund has demonstrated an increase in the number of resilience oriented projects that could be supported. By 2019, 42 multi-year projects were funded through the standard allocation. This is a direct result of the operational management revising its procedures and allowing longer term projects of up to 24 months. One example of a cluster who invested in resilience is the food security cluster where the DRC CBPF granted USD 8.5 million to assist the most vulnerable families through food assistance as well as to strengthen their resilience and improve food security in seven provinces (Haut-Katanga, Ituri, Kasai Central, Maniema, North Kivu, South Kivu, and Tanganyika).
Standard allocation projects have put a strong emphasis on promoting the participation of affected people, with a view to building their resilience. The OCHA led regional coordination fora (CRIO) in the South-East and Kasais regions have been requested to direct funding to areas where returns were expected, in the expectation that projects funded would build community resilience and capacity to integrate IDPs, returnees and other vulnerable people through a longer-term approach (18 to 24 months).
The fund engaged in a few cases of financial irregularities over the last couple of years of the implementation period. The Embassy&apos;s impression has been that quality and transparency in the handling of those matters was satisfactory. An HCT commissioned operational review of the entire humanitarian system in the DRC further contributed to strengthening the financial management systems and general follow up of suspected cases of irregularities.
While the follow up functions where improved and financial management procedures strengthened, the departure of the fund manager in 2019 resulted in a decrease in the quality of fund management. The advisory board faced some doubts on the transparency, sharing of information and regularity in consultation. This was especially true in the case of using the pooled fund resources to address Ebola needs even though Ebola was being responded to through parallel structures. The result of these discussions led to a decrease in funding in 2019 from 90 million to approximately 78 million USD. Sweden was among those reducing their contribution.
However, the CBPF has continued to be one of Sweden&apos;s most important instruments to support the humanitarian response and resilience building in a localised manner and the Embassy continued to advocate for systems strengthening and in 2019 the number of different donors to the fund was still high. Donors to the fund in 2019 included the UK, Sweden, Germany, Netherlands, Belgium, Ireland, Norway, Canada and Luxembourg. The 10.8 million USD provided by Sweden was the third largest contribution to the fund in 2019.
Examples of specific results over time include the following:
In 2017, the CBPF allocated USD 35.8 million to 43 projects implemented by 36 partners across the country throughout the year, making the DRC HF the fourth largest contributor to the 2017 Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP).
While DRC CBPF implementing partners planned to reach 2.45 million people in 2018, they actually reached 2.54 million, of which 1.42 million were women and girls. The DRC HF continued to demonstrate its commitment to the targets agreed through the Grand Bargain at the World Humanitarian Summit to support national and local actors. Of all funds allocated in 2018, 37 per cent went directly to national NGOs.
Through six allocations in 2019 amounting to USD 76.9 million, the Fund enabled 63 humanitarian partners to reach 1.6 million vulnerable people, including 58 per cent of women and girls, through the implementation of 102 projects in 2019.
The DRC suffers from chronic under development, weak governance and a lack of infrastructure which leads to extreme poverty and poor access to social services which in turn results in humanitarian consequences. In line with the resilience priorities under this contribution the DRC CBPF has made allocations to the logistics cluster to improve accessibility to communities.
For example, the DRC CBPF funded logistics projects totalling USD 4.3 million in 2018 and in $4.27 million in 2019 to have open inaccessible roads to facilitate the delivery of aid to vulnerable populations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51250032" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1225000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2019-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>DR Congo 2015-2019</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>DR Kongo 2015-2019</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
