<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5125000101-COD-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert DRC 2014-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">International Alert DRC 2014-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To promote women&#x2019;s civic, political and economic empowerment through knowledge, networking and advocacy in eastern DRC and in the Great Lakes region of Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">International Alerts (IA) projektf&#xF6;rslag &#x201C;Tushiriki wote&#x201D; syftar till att &#xF6;ka kvinnors civila, politiska och ekonomiska r&#xE4;ttigheter och egenmakt i &#xF6;stra DRK. Detta ska uppn&#xE5;s genom fyra resultat:

1.	M&#xE5;lgrupper i Nord- och SydKivu samt gr&#xE4;nsomr&#xE5;dena har st&#xF6;rre kunskap om j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsfr&#xE5;gor och kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter, samt agerar d&#xE4;refter.
2.	Kvinnor i Nord- och SydKivu samt gr&#xE4;nsomr&#xE5;dena har &#xF6;kad tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella resurser och kunskap om hur dessa oms&#xE4;tts i praktiken.
3.	Deltagande av kvinnor i samh&#xE4;llsdebatten och den politiska sf&#xE4;ren i Nord- och Syd Kivu samt gr&#xE4;nsomr&#xE5;dena har &#xF6;kat.
4.	&#xD6;kat f&#xF6;rtroende och samarbete om kvinnors ekonomiska egenmakt och deltagande i DRK och regionalt i Stora Sj&#xF6;omr&#xE5;det. 

IA &#xE4;mnar arbeta genom flera lokala implementeringsorganisationer fr&#xE5;n civila samh&#xE4;llet, vilka inkluderar s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l kvinnoorganisationer som mansn&#xE4;tverk. Organisationernas kapacitet kommer att st&#xE4;rkas och samarbete nationellt och regionalt uppmuntras. 

IA&#x2019;s f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringsteori &#xE4;r adekvat, d.v.s. IA presenterar v&#xE4;l underbyggda aktiviteter som f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas bidra till det &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;let. IA r&#xE4;knar med att skapa 24 dialoggrupper (best&#xE5;ende av 720 kvinnor och m&#xE4;n) och 8 studentgrupper (240 unga kvinnor och m&#xE4;n) samt n&#xE5; 200 personer fr&#xE5;n s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l gr&#xE4;srotsniv&#xE5; som politiska fora, 300 kvinnliga sm&#xE5;f&#xF6;retagare, 150 personer involverade i gr&#xE4;ns&#xF6;verskridande handel (tull, polis etc.), 40 handelskooperativ samt ett stort antal organisationer som arbetar f&#xF6;r kvinnors deltagande och ekonomiska egenmakt i DRK, Burundi och Rwanda. 

Projektet l&#xF6;per &#xF6;ver 48 m&#xE5;nader med start i juni 2014 och har en samlad budget om 71 000 000 SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">potential 1325/WEE intervention post WCP</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21038" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21038" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.5 - Ensure women&#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.5 - Tillf&#xF6;rs&#xE4;kra kvinnor fullt och faktiskt deltagande och lika m&#xF6;jligheter till ledarskap p&#xE5; alla beslutsniv&#xE5;er i det politiska, ekonomiska och offentliga livet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2186620.7962215194</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">3559014.390281518</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1753053.2343832175</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1946881.0108810107</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">2186620.7962215194</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">3559014.390281518</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1753053.2343832175</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1946881.0108810104</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-47315.0096764983</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-08-01">11172173.355296</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-09-28">2186620.7962215194</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-11-28">2372676.260187679</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-11-28">1753053.2343832175</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">1946881.0108810107</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">-47315.0392876405</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Alert&apos;s Tushiriki Wote program had a significant impact in both areas namely increasing women&apos;s political participation in decision-making positions and women&apos;s economic empowerment through cross-border trade in the Great Lakes Africa. Beneficiaries have become &quot;agents of change&quot;, despite general deterioration in the stability throughout the electoral process with many demonstrations and the security situation which started from 2015 until the end of the project in 2018.
Find below the summary of the direct beneficiaries of the project, covering the entire duration of the project:
- 34 community dialogue groups, composed of 25 to 30 people per group, with a total of 983 people, 369 men and 614 women;
- 14 student dialogue groups, composed of between 25 and 30 students per group, with a total of 350 people, 140 men and 210 women;
- 199 women candidates and 1 male representative of a woman candidate (105 in year 3 and 94 in year 4); 24 women and 10 male members of political parties in DRC ;
- 600 small-scale women cross-border traders doing trade across three border areas of Uvira-Gatumba, Goma-Gisenyi and Bukavu Cyangugu, 100 per site;
- 278 customs officials (DGDA, DGM, Hygiene border police, OCC) in DRC, Rwanda and Burundi (178 men and 100 women);
- 65 associations and cooperatives of cross-border traders;
- 14 organisations directly working with the project &#xA0;and and approximately 160 indirectly affected by the project through the Rien Sans Les Femmes campaign
- 175 men, spouses of women small-scale cross-border traders in Rwanda and Burundi, members of the dialogue group of women traders in Rubavu, Rusizi and Gatumba 90 male spouses of women small-scale cross-border traders in DRC, members of the spouse clubs in Goma, Bukavu and Uvira
Among the results achieved that this contribution has produced, we can mention the following:
The increase in incomes caused a change in attitudes among the women traders&#x2019; husbands and families. The women testified that they were treated with more consideration and respect after they had strengthened their economic abilities. This has allowed them to increase their participation in decision-making at the household level, especially in terms of resource allocation.
The percentage of women who send their children to school using funds they have generated as a result of their economic activity was 90% at the end of the project, compared to 68% at the beginning of the project. The number of women elected (and appointed) in the National Assembly, the Senate and the National Government remains more or less the same between the beginning and the end of the project; 8% at the beginning and 7.8% at the end. But in the election of December 2018, the number grows to 10% to provincial and 11 to the national legislative.
The indicator result shows the number of obstacles women candidates face in trying to get nominated and elected, and the fact that more work is needed to make changes at the structural level. The percentage of women participating in project activities who require family authorization to travel has decreased from 78% to 71%. Even though the percentage has decreased, it has not decreased significantly, which could be related to the fact that some concessions may seem more &quot;acceptable&quot; to men than others, for example, the sharing of tasks at home is sometimes perceived as being more acceptable than allowing women to move freely.
The percentage of women whose opinions were taken into account in family, community, association, political or church meetings has more than doubled from 40% at the beginning of the project to 91 % at the end. In addition, the percentage of housework shared between women / girls and men / boys has increased from 20.5% to 62%, and there has been a significant increase in the number of men agree that women can earn more than themselves in the household, from 59% at the start of the project to 87% at the end of the project.
The percentage of men and women who think that a man has the right to hit his wife for at least one of the following reasons (to refuse sex, to burn dinner, to move without permission, to earn more than he does or spend money without seeking the approval of her husband) has decreased from 44.5% to 16%. A high percentage of community dialogue group members report being able to marry their daughters or sons to different ethnic groups (from 11% to 26%).
Also, the percentage of small cross-border women traders who claim to have invited women traders from the neighbouring country to the last important ceremony in their family has increased from 31% to 67% and the percentage of small cross-border women traders who can buy goods on credit from merchants across the border has increased from 59% to 90%.
The percentage of cross-border small business women who report having improved their relationship with border agents has increased from 49% at the start of the project to 84% at the end. One beneficiary declares: &quot;Before we could not resist and would pay illegal taxes without knowing why; now we know and we can address the officials who hassle us.&#x201D; women traders report feeling self-confident, even with the authorities, and that community members recognize their position and a source of income.
Through this contribution, the advocacy efforts of the Rien Sans Les Femmes movement (RSLF) that means Nothing without women movement, proceeded to send a petition to the National Assembly and they collected more than two hundred thousand signatures. International Alert over RSLF contributed to the passing of Law No. 15/013 of 1 August 2015 on the implementation of women&apos;s rights and parity, which requires the Congolese government to become more accountable to its commitment to gender equality.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51250001" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1225000000" strategy-end-date="2019-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>DR Congo 2015-2019</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>DR Kongo 2015-2019</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
