<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10853A0101-COD-15153</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Media Support - Fondation Hirondelle 2017 - 2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Media in DRC via Fondation Hirondelle 2017 - 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Svenska ambassaden i Kinshasa kommer via Foundation Hirondelle st&#xF6;tta det kapacitetsbyggande programmet f&#xF6;r mediasektorn i Demokratiska Republiken Kongo (DRK). Insatsen har som m&#xE5;l att &#xF6;ka tillg&#xE4;ngligheten till tv- och radios&#xE4;ndningar med &#xF6;ppen och fri informationsspridning i provinserna Kinshasa, Nord-Kivu, Sud-Kivu, Kongo Central, Kwango, Kwilu, Mai-Ndombe and Haut-Katanga. Insatsen vill &#xE4;ven st&#xF6;tta kapacitetsbyggande aktiviteter f&#xF6;r de mediaakt&#xF6;rer som &#xE4;r engagerade i programmet.

Fondation Hirondelles insats str&#xE4;cker sig &#xF6;ver en 24-m&#xE5;nadsperiod, med en total budget p&#xE5; USD 1 986 555 motsvarande SEK 17 848 654 och d&#xE4;r Sverige finansierar 15 000 000 SEK av den totala budgeten.

Det &#xF6;vergripande f&#xF6;r insatsen &#xE4;r &#xF6;ka tillg&#xE4;ngligheten till kvalitativ media som g&#xF6;r att framf&#xF6;rallt kvinnor och unga kan bli aktivare deltagare i samh&#xE4;llsutvecklingen i DRK. Insatsen omfattar s&#xE5;v&#xE4;l spridande som producering av medialt material samt st&#xF6;d till utvalda media, framf&#xF6;rallt radiokanaler. 

Insatsen har tre f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade &#xF6;vergripande resultat:

1. &#xD6;kad kompetens hos partnerorganisationer vad g&#xE4;ller deras journalistiska- och mediala f&#xE4;rdigheter, fr&#xE4;mst vad g&#xE4;ller produktion och s&#xE4;ndning av lokala program med olika tema, anpassade till kvinnor och ungdomar.

2. St&#xE4;rka kompetens hos ledarskapet vid partnerorganisationerna och p&#xE5; s&#xE5; s&#xE4;tt &#xF6;ka organisatoriska kapacitet och h&#xE5;llbarhet.

3. &#xD6;kad och mer regelbunden inkomst f&#xF6;r mediala partnerorganisationer bland annat genom att &#xF6;ka partners f&#xE4;rdigheter inom marknad och management.

Instabilitet och of&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;gbarhet i det politiska och s&#xE4;kerhetsm&#xE4;ssiga l&#xE4;get i DRK g&#xF6;r det sv&#xE5;rt att f&#xF6;rutse sannolikheten att resultatm&#xE5;len ska kunna uppn&#xE5;s innan avtalsperiodens slut. Beredskap f&#xF6;r att justera projektuppl&#xE4;gg finns hos Foundation Hirondelle om detta skulle visa sig beh&#xF6;vas, t ex om ytterligare restriktioner f&#xF6;r media i DRK blir fallet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The contribution will support Foundation Hirondelle in capacity building for the media sector in the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC). The aim is to increase accessibility to television and radio broadcasts with open and free dissemination of information in the provinces Kinshasa, North Kivu, Sud-Kivu, Congo Central, Kwango, Kwilu, Mai-Ndombe and Haut-Katanga. The initiative will also support capacity-building activities for the media actors involved in the Project, foremost radio channels and some TV channels. 

The contribution will extend over 24 month and Fondation Hirondelle is the agreement partner to Sweden.  It has a total budget of USD 1 986 555, whereof the Embassy supports with 15 000 000 SEK. 

The overall goal of the contribution is to increase accessibility of information by spreading and producting media material. It is young people and women who are the main focus group in the initiative, this to increase their opportunities for active participation in society.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this intervention is to contribute to the consolidation of a democratic society in the DRC through the diversification and improvement of the media offer of general interest, especially for young people and women, during and after the electoral cycle.
The specific objective of this invervention is:
The Media content is produced and disseminated for the special attention of young people and women in the DRC to give them the information they need for better participation in public life; and
The Partner media are strengthened through structuring coordination and actions that enhance journalistic, editorial, managerial, and revenue-generating skills.
Revenue generation from institutional communication campaigns broadcast on the Fondation Hirondelle media network partners</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Hirondelle</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Hirondelle</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media and free flow of information</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">877500.8775008775</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">863021.2648439658</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">877500.8775008772</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">863021.2648439659</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-10">1755001.755001</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">877500.8775008775</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-11-28">863021.2648439658</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fondation Hirondelle (FH) is the recipient of a grant from SIDA for the period of September 2017 to September 2019, altogether with its network of media partners in the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), Fondation Hirondelle has been engaged in the mission of providing to young people and women in the DRC the information they need to participate more effectively in public life.
This was done under the project M&#xE9;dias Citoyens pour la participation des populations &#xE0; la Vie Publique (MCVP) which has as main objective: &#x201C;To contribute to the consolidation of a democratic society in the DRC through the diversification and improvement of the media offer of general interest, especially for young people and women, during and after the electoral cycle&#x201D;.
As highlighted by the external evaluation carried out as part of this grant, the FH has achieved the following in the past two years of this grant:
With regard to the first outcome of the project: &#x201C;Media contents are produced and broadcasted specially to youth and women in DRC, in order to provide them all necessary information for a greater participation in the public life&#x201D;, the indicators are more than satisfying, with an overall significant amount of people targeted who clearly indicate that the content produced was useful and met their expectation (90% of the persons interviewed during the final assessment), and they want or are likely to be more involved in public life (53% of the participants in the public debates; 95% listeners interviewed during the impact studies).
As summarized in the final project evaluation, &#x201C;the activities selected for this project are likely to contribute to the changes desired, including the democratization of the DRC. And answering the question about the extent to which this will happen, the study of project documentation and the evaluation&#x2019;s field work has presented a number of important areas where change is beginning to take place, both in relation to the increasing participation by women and youth in and around the election period, and through a budding assertiveness among women in general: &#x201C;when the woman interviewed can do this, there is no reason for me not to try/aim for the same&#x201D;.
Eight public live debates were organized and FH made a specific point to have them also organized in remote country areas, to make sure the most marginalized and isolated can also take the opportunity to express their views and being informed. As report stated during a debate in Matadi, &#x201C;Today, I decided to become an observer because I just got the information I didn&apos;t have before.&#x201D; As about audio-visual material produced and broadcasted, FH reached the total of 267 portrays; 264 chronicles; 68 magazines and 10 motion design video in 5 languages, which is 95% of what was planned.
Looking at the second outcome: &#x201C;Media partners are strengthened through structuring coordination and actions that improve journalistic, editorial, managerial and income-generation skills&#x201D;, a wide range of activities were carried out, towards two main results: the improvement of editorial capacities of the radios, and the improvement of their sustainability.
Regarding editorial capacities, FH didn&#x2019;t deliver a big number of training and workshops as they planned because financial resources where not well executed during the project. However, FH focused on the quality of these trainings, and particularly, on follow up support to trainees. 49 radios have seen their staff trained, and 72% of media partners who received editorial support (training and remote coaching) report that their journalists&apos; skills have been upgraded. Four editorial training session were organized during the project implimentation.
Regarding the whole radio partners sustainability, FH focused on technical training, technical remote support through a dedicated hotline, and management training. Four management and marketing training were organized targeting the staff of a total of 43 radios. A close follow up was provided including in the phase of setting up income generating activities. One of the major success is also that these trainings were done with local trainers previously trained by Fondation Hirondelle. These local trainers, being also themselves radio managers, were perfect in terms of embracing the specific challenges that local radios can met in terms of management, and to provide tailored counsel related to the context. 61 media outlets have received technical support, and a close coaching was provided for 28 radio managers.
More than these figures, 106 radios were embarked in the whole project, receiving broadcasting fees that helped them to fix daily issues (paying invoices, fixing equipment, etc) and then maintain their radios, and 97 of them received additional royalties provided from campaigns obtained and managed by Fondation Hirondelle from other development partners. In this light, a direct amount of 325&#xA0;086 USD has been directed to media partners during these project implementation, as broadcasting fees, as royalties from additional contracts obtained by Fondation Hirondelle, or as time involvement of correspondents in the project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10853" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1060202" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1225000000" strategy-end-date="2019-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>DR Congo 2015-2019</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>DR Kongo 2015-2019</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
