<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-32408</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palma Guinea</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business infrastructure development/Opening of Conakry as a travel destination: The Project will support the development of a  high-standard hotel, which will help Guinea&apos;&apos;s capital city  address growing demand for quality hotel accommodation driven by increasing business travel and the emerging conference activities sector. Furthermore, the availability of a high-quality hotel is expected to become a driver for more travel (both business and conference) to Conakry in its own right, contributing to the development of the city into a regional center.  Best practice transfer: The Project is expected to support transfer of best international business practices to Guinea, especially in such areas as (i) real estate development; (ii) hotel management; (iii) management of environmental, social life and fire safety issues; (iv) business ethics, transparency and integrity in dealing with employees, business partners, authorities and other stakeholders.   Employment generation: The investment will create significant local direct employment of about 400 and indirect employment in the supply value chain.  Linkages to the local economy: The Project hotel will seek to establish linkages with the local economy, specifically in such areas, as the supply of food products and the procurement of services (e.g. transportation).  Encouragement of investment activity in Guinea/Demonstration effect: The Project will have a demonstration effect by encouraging other international and regional players to pursue investment opportunities in Guinea as this IDA post-conflict country works to improve the business climate, facilitate greater foreign direct investment inflows and diversify its economy from the natural resource-based sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project comprises a greenfield development of a 280-room 5-star hotel in Conakry, Guinea (the Project). The Project is implemented by the Guinea-incorporated Palma Guin&#xE9;e S.A. (Palma Guinea). Fully owned by the Topaz Group of companies, Palma Guinea has been incorporated specifically to develop and own the Project hotel, which will be operated by Starwood Hotels &amp; Resorts Worldwide, Inc., under the Sheraton brand. The purpose of the Project is to reduce imbalance between supply and demand for quality hotel accommodations in Conakry. At present, Guineas capital has no 5-star hotels. This gap in the hospitality market has been hindering travel to Conakry and slowing down the citys development into an important national and regional business destination. The Project hotel is expected to help change this situation and to become an important part of Conakrys business infrastructure.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALMA GUINEE SA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-32408" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-17" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALMA GUINEE Conakry  Guinee, Immeuble Yero Makan Cisse Sis Au Carrefour Constantin, Commune De Matam, BP 3290. Palma Guinea will make available for the public this ESRS and Action Plan in French, at the local building site in Conakry and publish an advertisement about the ESRS and Action Plan in a local newspaper&apos;&apos;&apos;&apos;.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sammy Chortimal, Owners Representative  mailto:sammy@hospitalitysolutionshk.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guinea</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="GN-Guinea">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project hotel will be located on a seafront greenfield site in Kipe, a district of Conakry, Guineas capital. The site of the future hotel is adjacent to residential and business areas and has a convenient access to the citys major transport arteries.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.8333300000 -10.6666700000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="7211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U-AA - City and Business Hotel</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $15.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-17"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-17">15000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-04-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-04-17">15000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PALMA GUINEE SA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/32408/palma-guinea">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/32408/palma-guinea">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
