<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-31067</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Simandou III</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic transformation for Guinea: At full production the Simandou iron ore project will be the largest mining and commercial project in the country and will make a large direct positive contribution to Guinea&apos;&apos;s economy for decades. Annual taxes and royalties to the Government of Guinea have the potential, at full production and after tax holiday, to exceed US$1 billion p.a. (subject to iron ore prices) and will directly employ over 4,000 Guineans.  Infrastructure development:  The Simandou infrastructure, particularly the rail, will open up the east of the country to new private sector development opportunities. Simfer has committed to the provision of a multi-use/multi-user facility, which will include passenger rail services.  The construction of the rail will also require the construction of a feeder road network along its alignment, further facilitating local movement and trade.    Emerging sustainable mining sector:  Guinea is an emerging iron ore producer and, based on its resource endowment, is expected to become one of the main global producers in the coming years. The Simandou iron ore project will be the first of several large projects and will set key benchmarks going forward in terms of standards of operation and E&amp;S management.  In addition, Simandou&apos;&apos;s infrastructure could in the future potentially be shared on a commercial basis with other emerging iron ore operations in the region.  Community development:  Simfer will spend a minimum of 0.25% of project revenues on socioeconomic activities in affected prefectures (particularly Beyla and Forecariah), including investments in electricity, roads, water and sanitation, communication, and health and education.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Simandou iron ore project is located in South-east Guinea, approximately 600km from the Guinean coast.  The current phase of the project (the Project or Simandou III) entails the completion of a Preliminary Engineering Assessment (PEA), Definitive Engineering (DE), early construction works and advance ordering of long lead items at an estimated expenditure of more than $3.5 billion over the next eighteen months, and culminating in the formal decision to proceed with the full development of the operation (Decision to Mine).  A large high grade iron ore resource has been delineated and is expected to support a 95Mtpa mining operation for over thirty years.  Development of the mining operation would include development of new rail and port infrastructure to export the ore.  This infrastructure component is expected to account for around two-thirds of the total cost of the Simandou iron ore project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RIO TINTO SIMFER SA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-31067" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-06-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Managing Director Simfer SA Immeuble KanKan, Cite Chemin de Fer BP 848, Conakry, Republique de Guinea  Tel: (+224) 62352445 or  (+33) 1 49046000 Email:  simandou.project@riotinto.com&#xA0; Website&#xA0;: www.riotintosimandou.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guinea</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="GN-Guinea">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Simandou concession area is located along 60km of the Simandou mountain range in South-eastern Guinea. The Simandou range is located in the prefectures of K&#xE9;rouan&#xE9;, Beyla and Macenta.  Simfer has established two camps in the area, Canga East, which is the major project base camp for exploration (the nearest village is Moribadou, about 7kms away), and an office and accommodation base in Kerouane, where it rents buildings within the existing town.  The Canga East camp is approximately 1,000km by road from the capital, Conakry.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>10.8333300000 -10.6666700000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BA - Iron (Pellets, etc.)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $150.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-06-28"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-28">150000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-06-28">150000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RIO TINTO SIMFER SA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/31067/simandou-iii">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
