<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/SA1/FSL/INGO/15513</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced access to emergency food production for IDPs and Vulnerable host communities in Yirol East County, Lakes State.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will support vulnerable Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) and host communities in IPC 4 in Yirol East County of Lakes State to improve their food security through provision of timely and appropriate inputs/kits (agricultural and fishing) and training in improved agronomic and fishing practices. Through this project, NPA will provide emergency assistance to save lives and avert total collapse of livelihoods in the target county of Yirol East. The provision of agricultural and fishing inputs/kits and subsequent training in agricultural production and fishing is expected to improve the food production of the target households thus improving their food security, supporting them to recover from crisis and placing them on an accelerated path to early recovery and resilience to acute shocks. 

NPA seeks to support 34,200 beneficiaries (5,700 households) with agricultural inputs and fishing kits during the main and dry seasons. During the Main Season Response (MSR) which will be implemented from June to August 2020, NPA will support 34,200 beneficiaries with inputs comprising of emergency cropping kits, vegetable kits, fishing kits and farming tools. The same beneficiaries will be supported with inputs comprising of vegetable and fishing kits and farming tools during the Dry Season Response (DSR) which will be implemented from November 2020 to February 2021. The kits will be provided by FAO through the FSL cluster. As advised by the cluster, the kits will be availed at Rumbek and NPA will transport them to the project locations in Yirol East.

Training on improved agronomic and fishing practices, including reducing post-harvest losses and cooking techniques will be provided to the targeted 5,700 household representatives prior to distribution of inputs and kits. The training will focus on improved methods of land preparation, planting, weeding, crop management, harvesting, post-harvest handling, seed sorting and selection and cooking techniques as well as on fish preservation, marketing and group dynamics. The knowledge gained from these trainings will improve the agricultural and fishing practices of the target HHs thus improving food production, addressing their immediate food security needs and building their resilience to future shocks. The provision of agricultural inputs and fishing kits and subsequent enhancement of agricultural production and fishing is expected to contribute to improvement of the Household Diversity Score (HDDS) and Food Consumption Score (FCS) of the target HHs.

NPA will employ a community-based beneficiary selection approach which will entail establishing a beneficiary targeting committee to lead the selection of eligible beneficiaries among the IDPs and host communities based on the agreed-on beneficiary selection criteria. Vulnerable households with severe food insecurity including female, child, disabled/chronically ill headed households persons living with or at risk of HIV/AIDS and survivors of Gender-Based Violence (GBV) will be targeted under this project. 

The target communities will be the prime movers of the implementation process through their continuous engagement in the project. NPA will facilitate the establishment and training of an all-inclusive project management committee which will take the leading role in the beneficiary selection. NPA will hold regular meetings with the project management committee and community members and conduct Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) to get their feedback on the project implementation. NPA will ensure that their feedback is incorporated in the implementation of this project and design of future projects. Further, to promote accountability to the affected populations, NPA will use the community-based complaints and feedback mechanism to provide a platform for beneficiaries&apos; active involvement in the project and avenues to voice any issues or concerns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian People&apos;s Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian People&apos;s Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-FSC-160791-2" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Pritchard</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 (0) 925 696 969</telephone>
   <email>GraPri918@npaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Caroline Muasya</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants and Reporting Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 922272743</telephone>
   <email>carmua152@npaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ekubazgi Fesshaye</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 924102333</telephone>
   <email>ekufes591@npaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU09">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lakes</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>6.60307990 29.97405340</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-25">130966.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-07-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-25">130352.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-15513">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-25">261318.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian People&apos;s Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304663776">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-07-07">261318.97</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Norwegian People&apos;s Aid</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
