<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA2/P/INGO/17614</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency integrated GBV/CP protection services in response to the floods in Ayod County</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Response to the floods severely affecting Jonglei State and specifically Ayod county, INTERSOS is proposing a six month protection intervention integrating GBV and CP protection response and targeting the most affected payams in the county. The intervention will operate in four different locations: Wau, Mogok, Panjiek and Ayod town and will support directly 4,400 beneficiaries by providing life-saving GBV CP services, as well as protection monitoring and awareness sessions on protection topics for 10,580 indirect beneficiaries in the four locations. Through this comprehensive approach combining both preventive and responsive activities it is expected the protective environment of 14,980 people in Ayod county will be strengthened.

Both GBV and CP component have one element of preventive action, in the form of CP protection monitoring, awareness and distribution of material assistance (cash assistance for GBV, tailored in-kind assistance for CP), as well as an element of responsive action including above all the provision of case management for GBV and CP, reunification services for UASC and PSS. To ensure the protective environment is enlarged, the establishment of one temporary WGFS in each location is foreseen. In this space women and girls, in small groups to ensure COVID19 measures are respected, will be able to find PSS collective activities and recreational ones. The distribution of PPE in these spaces will be done on a regular basis to reduce the likelihood of COVID19 contagion. For children, the PSS will be done mainly at home with the provision of tailored PSS emergency kit to ensure COVID19 measures are respected. This methodology also ensures children living within unreachable distance for WGFS have access to PSS and recreational activities. Within the PSS emergency kits, child friendly messages of COVID19 preventive measures and PFA will be included. 

Finally, the sustainability of the intervention as well as the access to all remote areas will be ensure by the component of capacity building within the community by the establishment and strengthening of community-based protection network in each locations that include elderly,  PwD and other vulnerable groups representative.  Additionally, men in the community will be involved to ensure the importance of protective environment both related to GBV and CP is understood and accepted by the community in general. This CBPN will on one hand support the identification of both GBV and CP cases, while at the same time strengthening the protective environment of the community by sharing messages on GBV and CP prevention as well as COVID19 protective measures. Additionally, on a monthly basis the CBPN will be supported to organize a monthly meeting where protection risks and solutions can be discussed. 

An overall of 4,400 beneficiaries (20 men, 2,200 women, 565 boys and 1,615 girls) will benefit directly from protection services. Specifically, 2200 women and 1,075 girls will receive GBV services including the provision of dignity kits, case management with PSS, cash support and referrals, and access to WGFS for PSS and recreational activities. Additionally, 565 boys and 565 girls will receive CP services including case management with access to tracing and reunification services and material assistance, and the provision of emergency PSS kits for home. Finally, the sustainability of both components will be ensure by the training of 48 men and 54 women both humanitarian staff and community members on different protection topics including case management, PSS and protection mainstreaming with a focus on the inclusion of PwD and other vulnerable groups.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-PRO-CPN-161106-2" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-PRO-GBV-160248-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stefano Antichi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission INTERSOS South Sudan</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211 923 133 819</telephone>
   <email>south.sudan@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">63981.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">236018.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-17614">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-04">300000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304822954">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-11">180000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305028819">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-20">120000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
