<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/SA1/FSL/NGO/15636</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency main and dry-season livelihood kits to 6600 vulnerable women, men, girls and boys headed households in Longochuk County, UpperNile State</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of January 2020 5.29 million People in South Sudan were estimated to be in crisis (IPC3) food insecurity or worse (IPC Analysis, February 2020) with Longochuk County being one of the severely affected counties. Longochuk County has been affected by complex disasters ranging from internal and external displacements, flooding, droughts and destruction of livelihoods and means of survival for the community. 
To reverse the they level of food insecurity situation and avert total collapse the livelihood of the most vulnerable persons in the County, CAFAD proposes two pronged emergency project covering main (rain) season and dry season response respectively to support 6600 Households with fast maturing, nutritious and quality crop and vegetable seeds, farming tools and fishing equipment. This is expected to benefit 39,600 persons estimating that each of the target household has 6 household members. CAFAD will also strive to ensure that the project reached minimum of 700 persons living with disability (PLWD), TB and HIV/AIDs supported through capacity building and livelihood support.
Information on desert locust will be disseminated at the training to enable the participants to scout for this pest imminent to adversely affect the cropping season of the sorghum, maize and sesame in Upper Nile. Efforts will be combined with the ministry of Agriculture and Food Security agaist this pest 
CAFAD plans to distribute fishing gear, quality Crop and vegetable seeds and farming tools (maloda and sickle) to vulnerable 6600 women, girls, boys and men on time at the onset of the rain and dry seasons in a timely manner before the onset of the rains for optimal performance of the crops to help close the cereal gap that nationally stands at 482,500 MT and 5MT at Longochuk County level. During the dry season response each beneficiary is expected to receive a combination of vegetable kit (Okra, onion, watermelon, amaranthus, eggplant, Tomato, collard and pumpkin seeds), farming tools (maloda and gunny bag) and a fishing kit (Monofilament, box of hooks and a pair of twine for making fishing net)
CAFAD will liaise with UNFAO for the timely release of the above inputs and transport them (within three days upon notification as per FAO SOP in relation to release orders) from Bor warehouses for further shipment to the distribution points in Udier and Mathiang by the logistic cluster via barge river transport.
For the purpose of project inception, CAFAD shall mobilize and sensitize the communities at County, Boma and payam level through their representatives women leaders, youth, payam administrators, commissioners and RRC to determine identification and beneficiary selection. Consultative meetings shall be carried out during inception, implementation and exit points of the project and reports submitted to relevant stakeholders. 
In collaboration with local authorities (RRC, payam administrators, boma heads) OCHA, FAO and other stakeholders CAFAD will identify and register the most vulnerable households in OCHA approved payams in Longochuk County (Wudier, Pamach, Malual, Longochuk, Guelguk and Dajo) in a format to be agreed between CAFAD and the local authorities and submitted to FSL secretariat and FAO for approval. 

During distribution, CAFAD shall provide technical information and guidance to the beneficiaries on best use of agriculture and fishing kits being distributed. This will cover handling of inputs provided with support of visual aids and captions with instructions. Also good agronomic practices, seed production and preservation techniques, post-harvest processing and store management, family nutrition with special emphasis on fo]od preparation, processing amp utilization will be covered in the trainings. 
CAFAD is committed to provide quality, accountable and dignified assistance captured under our profile with commitments which takes into account of the needs and aspirations of children, women men, people living with HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-FSC-160331-2" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elijah Mwangi</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211929354669</telephone>
   <email>cafad.southsudan.org@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Angelo Madhier</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Executive Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211924354235</telephone>
   <email>cd.cafad.org@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Simon Kuach</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Area Coordinator</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211924073222</telephone>
   <email>longochuk.cafad.org@gmail.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU20">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upper Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.88942020 32.71813750</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-06-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">142747.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">101196.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-15636">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-17">243943.31</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304656739">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-24">195154.65</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304915973">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-16">48788.66</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Aid for Fisheries and Agriculture Development</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
