<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD-20/HSS10/RA2/WASH/NGO/17629</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of live-saving equitable access to safe and adequate water, dignified Sanitation, and safe hygiene practices to mitigate WASH related GBV and health for the flood affected  population in Pibor</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps-CMC aims to provide timely, equitable access to safe and sufficient water, improved sanitation, and improving hygiene knowledge of the flood affected IDPs and most vulnerable host communities in Pibor, Lekuangole, and Verteth payams of Pibor County, Jonglei state through WASH emergency intervention incorporating the WASH cluster flood phases intervention to reduce WASH-related Gender Base Violence (GBV) and malnutrition through integrated lifesaving WASH activities mainstreaming protection, COVID 19 prevention, and strengthening beneficiaries copping mechanism and resilience through training of different groups of people in the community such as pump mechanics, Water management committee, Hygiene promoters, women groups, community leaders, integrated community-based protection network (CBPN) for protection mainstreaming, and the AAP focal persons. The project will target 15,000 direct, and indirect) beneficiaries facing IPC 3-5 and GAM rate of 20.8% customarily, the internally displaced population, most vulnerable flood affected host communities, and malnutrition patients with limited access to safe water supply, hygiene, sanitation practices and food insecurity, through supported coordination and complement of WASH gaps which current implementing partners in the targeted areas are limited to tackle through their interventions due to increase on the caseloads or inadequate integration. CMC purposes to address WASH gaps related to current flood in the villages of Pibor to tuckle assessed emergency needs to achieve Sphere standards, the core humanitarian standards/principles and the WASH cluster objectives, contributing to 2020 SSHF SA1 tackling the 1st and 2nd Humaniterian Respond Plan (HRP) WASH Cluster Objective. contributing to eradication of the IPC 3-4 in Pibor areas.

CMC targets most vulnerable flood affected population with a structured, effective programming to increase access to WASH services incorporating COVID 19 prevention measures to prevent and mitigate WASH-related diseases through 75% WASH- GBV, and 35% WASH in health to increase knowledge of appropriate hygiene practices to prevent and mitigate WASH-related diseases, incorporating the WASH cluster flood phase strategies and undertaking the following

 Repairing and rehabilitating and disinfecting 25 identified boreholes, measurable by WASH cluster standards for water supply.
 Selection and Training of 45 pump mechanics, 180 water management committees, 45 hygiene promoters, 40 water point attendances, the 60 food vendors, and the accountability to the affected population (AAP) focal persons deeply involved in the participatory monitoring and evaluation (MampE), and WASH mainstreaming in protection and health
 Conducting hygiene promotion through house-to-house, institutional hygiene promotion, focused group discussions, schools MHM sessions and public outreaches customized to incorporate COVID 19 risk practicing.
 Identification and registration of 2500 most vulnerable IDPs/host communities households targeted for the WASH NFIs, 600 women and girls for the menstrual hygiene kits.
 Distribution of the WASH non-food items, hygiene kits, menstrual hygiene kits, and IEC materials and garbage bins to 65 food vendors, installation of 10 hand-washing facilities and 5 garbage bins at the crowded locations, to improve household waste management system through cat-methods. 
 Conducting rapid monitoring and evaluation(MampE) through the CMC&#x2019; AAP incorporation methodologies and the Post Distribution monitoring.
 Repairing existing 15 sanitations facilities in the phase 3 of the WASH cluster at community level based on GBV risk mitigation analysis/Safety audits. To complement the existing WASH static intervention since CMC will only focus on flooding, putting the affected population at the center of the response through gender-sensitivity and people with special needs and reporting</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSSD20-WSH-160113-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wani James</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WASH Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+211911448743</telephone>
   <email>charitymissioncorps@outlook.com</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU06">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jonglei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>7.18196190 32.35609520</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSSD20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan 2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-11-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-02">86339.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-02">259019.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SSD19-17629">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-02">345358.79</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304825602">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-09">207215.27</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305016572">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-14">138143.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Charity Mission Corps</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SSD19-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
