<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41217404-PU011</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41217404" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increasing access</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the General Assembly adopted the 2030 Agenda in September 2015, focus has been on how to implement the 17 Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and their 169 global targets. While the UN will host a High Level Political Forum each year from 2016-19 to follow the process and keep track of progress, the task to realise the goals now sits with the national governments, not just in the global south but across the world. A broad variety of partnerships, platforms, associations and forums have formed during the past year to support the implementation processes, monitor governments and statistical bureaus, provide shadow reporting and additional data and develop national targets and indicators. A recent report counted that 198 legal partnerships have emerged 16 related to the SDG implementation in addition to more than 1,500 voluntary commitments. Among the relevant existing initiatives that work on SDG implementation on a global level, the following have a relevant connection to the PUF agenda on inclusivity and just and peaceful societies: &#xF0B7; The Open Government Partnership, a multilateral initiative that secures commitments from governments to promote transparency, empower citizens, fight corruption, and strengthen governance. &#xF0B7; The Transparency, Accountability and Participation (TAP) Network, a network of CSOs that works to ensure that open, inclusive, accountable and effective governance is at the heart of the 2030 Agenda, and that civil society is included as partners in the design, implementation and accountability of sustainable development policies, at all levels. &#xF0B7; The sub-branch of The World Federation of UN Associations (WFUNA), The 16+ Forum that engages Member States, CSOs, UN agencies and other stake &#xF0B7; Moreover, the Civil Society Platform for Peacebuilding and Statebuilding (CSPPS) is now looking at ways to reformulate the mission of their platform to move away from a narrow focus on peacebuilding and statebuilding in and among states sharing experiences of fragility, to engage with the Sustainable Development Agenda more broadly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="PU000" ref="NL-KVK-41217404" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="PUOOO" ref="NL-KVK-41217404" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <transaction ref="2017.3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-31">56695</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2017.4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-06-30">74791</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2017.8">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-09-30">26295</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2018.4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-31">133253</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2018.10">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-06-30">1072</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2018.13">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-30">28381</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2018.16">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">37553</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2019.4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-03-31">115117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="2019.10">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">7614</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2019.13">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-30">62790</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2019.16">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">10337</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2020.02">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-31">55111</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2020.08">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-30">59939</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2020.11">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-30">52436</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0" ref="2020.14">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">34421</value>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41217404-PU000" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased inclusion of civil society recommendations articulated through the GPPAC network in the global policy action</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) GPPAC continues to engage with relevant actors by creating various policy spaces to share GPPAC messaging from the 2020 Review written submissions that are reflective of the experiences of GPPAC Network in the Pacific and the Americas. 2) The GPPAC&apos;s COVID-19 statement was picked up by Canada and the EU in their statements to the PBC, and further led to the organizing an informal brown bag for local civil society and PBC Member States on shaping the PBC&apos;s COVID Response Strategy in Q2. 3) The informal PBC brownbag organised by GPPAC and LPI led to the invitation extended to Adan Kabelo from LPI-Somalia team to brief the Peacebuilding Commission on the socio-economic impact of COVID-19 and the proposed participation of Sharon Bhagwan Rolls in the PBC meeting on the Pacific; therefore, ensuring the presence of local civil society voices in the PBC deliberations. 4) The most recent version of the Community Engagement Guidelines includes a number of language and inputs from the GPPAC Network, including references to the VTC conducted in Mali and the case-study of peacebuilding work in Kyrgyzstan. Moreover, the draft document includes a section on recommendations for civil society that GPPAC co-drafted with the Quaker UN Office and workshopped with the New York Peacebuilding Group as an attempt to generate broader civil society ownership. 5) The invitation has been extended to GPPAC to coordinate the civil society launch of the CEG and the development of a pilot project for the CEG implementation as a result of the recognition of GPPAC&apos;s capacity to mobilise local civil society to engage in and support relevant processes. 6) The presentation of GPPAC-South Caucasus of the South Caucasus case-study conducted for the 2020 Peacebuilding Architecture Review has opened the space for GPPAC-South Caucasus to better engage with PDA of South Caucasus and engage with the OHCHR around protections for local peacebuilders. 7) The thematic consultation on the Triple Nexus in the Pacific has gained a lot of interest with the Permanent Mission of Australia to the UN, DPPA Regional Office for the Pacific and PDA-Fiji have both expressed interest in moving the conversation forward. 8) In the Americas, we have received great interest from UNDP Regional Desk in Panama, as well as from the Missions of Colombia and Peru (co-sponsors of the event) to continue formal engagement.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4 Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Awareness raising on peace and confidence building in the Caucasus</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12 videoblogs of peace activists and civic leaders from Georgia, Armenia, Abkhazia and South Ossetia about impact of COVID-19 on the peace process have been published. Three articles on peace and confidence building related to the war in Karabakh are publicized by GPPAC freelance press officers in Armenia and Azerbaijan https://www.civilnet.am/news/2020/12/29/Life-After-War/414722
 https://d9mc3ts4czbpr.cloudfront.net/ru/article/vybor-po-zhelaniyu-klienta/?ref=list-opinion
https://d9mc3ts4czbpr.cloudfront.net/ru/article/yuk-novaya-arhitektura-regionalnoj-bezopasnosti/?ref=list-opinion</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2. The networks develop civil society statements, strategies and internal procedures for the protection of human rights defenders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Start-up of a civil society organisations Working Group that cooperates with UN and other actors on Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) 16+</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">8 GPPAC members from Africa, Eastern Europe, Pacific, North America and EU actively participated in the SDG 16+ Forum in Sierra Leone, from 6 to 11 October. 2 GPPAC members gave a presentation on mediation&#x2019;s contribution to SDGs and community shadow reporting on national progress on SDGs. United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), Department of Political Affairs (DPA) and United Nations Peacebuilding Support Office (UN PBSO) and World Bank confirmed their interest in cooperating in future potential work on the implementation and operationalisation of the Pathways for Peace report. GPPAC hosted a workshop on SDGs and sustaining peace on 7th of October with 70 civil society representatives. GPPAC managed to achieve greater awareness among civil society organisations about SDGs and Sustaining peace and the start-up of an informal group of civil society organisations on SDG 16+ to jointly prepare for the United Nations High Level Political Forum (UN HLPF) meeting on SDGs in July 2019. GPPAC organised a follow-up informal roundtable of civil society organisations working on SDG 16+ alongside the Geneva Peace Week from 5 to 9 November 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.3. Networks and their members incorporate SDGs and WPS-related advocacy agendas in their respective and collective lobby and advocacy strategies.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Draft Handbook on developing National CSOs Networks</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A draft handbook on national networks was developed, to be finalised in 2020. The Global Secretariat has drafted a handbook for members seeking to build national networks. It includes lessons learned and suggestions from existing national GPPAC networks. The handbook also draws on academic research on civil society networks. The Handbook will be finalised following input from members, including GPPAC&#x2019;s newest national network in Tunisia.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In May 2019, the newly created &#x201C;Conflict Prevention team&#x201D; of the Netherlands Ministry of Defence (MinDef) approached GPPAC, as one of the only civil society organisations to brainstorm and give input to define the Ministry&#x2019;s role and mandate in conflict prevention, upon which they invited themselves to meet GPPAC with their team in The Hague.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A new relationship was established between GPPAC and this newly created team, that wants GPPAC to see it as its &#x201C;go-to&#x201D; contacts for further engagement. They reached out proactively to GPPAC, to help them define conflict prevention within the Ministry of Defence. The team and its mandate are still under development, and they are looking to mainstream the concepts of conflict prevention, Do no Harm and working on early warning within the MOD. GPPAC and PAX are so far the only CSOs the team involved in their formal discussions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukrainian NGO invited to organise a photo exhibition at the Romanian Parliament</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A photo exhibition of Ukrainian prisoners, organised by the NGO &quot;Bereginya&quot;, and accompanied by the performances of their mothers and wives, demonstrated the importance of an international solidarity platform to support their release. As a result of a roundtable organised by the GPPAC Eastern European regional network, and active work of Ukrainian diplomats, the &#x201C;Berehinya&#x201D; NGO was invited to organise a similar exhibition at the Romanian Parliament. This is important as Romania currently presides over the Council of the European Union.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society organisations (CSOs) and UN officials increasingly recognise the Prevention Platform (co-led by GPPAC&#x2019;s UN Liaison Office) as a go-to forum for civil society-UN dialogue at the UN level.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">An increasing number of CSO are approaching the Prevention Platform after the meetings to learn more and ask about how they can participate and/or support the Platform. UN officials are increasingly aware of the Prevention Platform and more quickly agree to serve as panellists during the events. Attendance of both CSOs and UN officials to Prevention Platform meetings has increased.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including RIGOs, Steering Groups, CS-UN Working Group)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community of practice on prevention via the Civil Society-UN Prevention Platform</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a co-facilitator of the CS-UN Prevention Platform, GPPAC works to enhance civil society and UN collective capacity to prevent conflicts. In Q3, work has continued and GPPAC increased local civil society voices in the NY policy dialogues and increased engagement with Member States by encouraging the adoption of a new working method for the Platform. After the first meeting of the discussion series on the evolution of prevention, the statement of GPPAC members from South Caucasus was widely followed-up on, including by DPPA and OHCHR, and referenced in many forthcoming dialogues by various participants of this meeting. 
GPPAC-QUNO as co-facilitators of the Platform continue to attend and provide technical capacity building sessions and share learning from the PDA project during the PDA inductions. We were able to further connect with the number of PDAs to continue the dialogue and facilitate future joint learning and action via two meetings, where GPPAC members from Lebanon, West Africa, Pacific, and Zimbabwe were able to speak and share their perspectives with the follow-up engagement with DPPA.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3. The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobilizing a joint community of practice on prevention via the Civil Society-UN Prevention Platform</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a co-facilitator of the CS-UN Prevention Platform, GPPAC works to enhance civil society and UN collective capacity to prevent conflicts. This includes:
1. The discussion series on prevention that brings together various stakeholders to identify good practices and lessons learned and coordinate joint action around prevention. 2. Engagement with Peace and Development Advisors aimed at enhancing their engagement with civil society on the ground. 3. Strategy discussions for the next strategic cycle of the Review.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Major Group on Children and Youth (UN MGCY) takes a political stance on 20 September 2019 on youth focused activities hosted by repressive governments, including the (OSGEY)-Prince Mohammed bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Foundation (MiSK) Youth Forum hosted by the Saudi government; inspired by GPPAC Youth, Peace and Security working group core member, Khaled Emam&#x2019;s recommendations to the UN MGCY</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a formal youth engagement platform of the UN, UN MGCY has leverage and credibility. In light of a widely circulated petition that highlights the normalization of human rights violations, restrictions on freedom of speech and press, and other concerns, the UN MGCY membership has requested the UN and other partners to distance themselves from the Forum.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4 Political space-DD3</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.1. Governmental and intergovernmental actors highlight and take up civil society positions about shrinking political space and repression in policy and decision making arenas in a timely and relevant manner</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sources of information: Khaled Emam, GPPAC Youth, Peace and Security working group core member</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sources of information: Khaled Emam, GPPAC Youth, Peace and Security working group core member</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Major Group on Children and Youth (UN MGCY) takes a political stance on 20 September 2019 on youth focused activities hosted by repressive governments, including the (OSGEY)-Prince Mohammed bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Foundation (MiSK) Youth Forum hosted by the Saudi government; inspired by GPPAC Youth, Peace and Security working group core member, Khaled Emam&#x2019;s recommendations to the UN MGCY</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a formal youth engagement platform of the UN, UN MGCY has leverage and credibility. In light of a widely circulated petition that highlights the normalization of human rights violations, restrictions on freedom of speech and press, and other concerns, the UN MGCY membership has requested the UN and other partners to distance themselves from the Forum.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened recognition of the role and expertise of GPPAC within the peacebuilding community</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a result of GPPAC&apos;s consolidated engagement around the 2020 Review through drafting written submission and mobilizing policy dialogues with various stakeholders, the recognition of GPPAC expertise has increased which was exemplified in 1) the invitations to participate in the Dutch, EU and AfP consultations for the 2020 Review, 2) increased engagement with PBSO around opening further policy opportunities, 3) partnership with the Canadian Mission to the UN, 4) the mobilization of support for the 2020 Review Consultation in Colombia resulted from GPPAC&apos;s consolidated effort to broaden engagement with Member States beyond the list of &quot;usual suspects&quot; (i.e., Colombia, Guatemala, Brazil, Mexico).; 5) increased reliance of PBSO on GPPAC&apos;s support in the implementation of CEG; 6) invitation to brief the Group of Friends on Sustaining Peace; 7) moderation of the climate e-consultation by UNDP and the invitation from UNDP to conduct a joint project on local infrastructures for peace; 8) invitation from the Human Security Trust Fund to apply for its outreach and advocacy grant; 9) expressed recognition of GPPAC as one of the key contributors to the 2020 Review (as reported by Member States to Louise Allen - a consultation for the PBC&apos;s Gender Strategy Review); 10) further partnership with Annika Soder and DHF around financing for peacebuilding project; 11) invitation from ForPeace to engage in e-consultation on infrastructures for peace.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened recognition of the role and expertise of GPPAC within the peacebuilding community.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a result of GPPAC&apos;s consolidated engagement around the 2020 Review through drafting written submission and mobilizing policy dialogues with various stakeholders, the recognition of GPPAC expertise has increased which was exemplified in 1) the personal invitations extended to the UN Liaison to participate in the Dutch, EU and AfP consultations for the 2020 Review, 2) increased engagement with PBSO around opening further policy opportunities, 3) partnership with the Canadian Mission to the UN, 4) mobilize support for the 2020 Review Consultation in Colombia resulted from GPPAC&apos;s consolidated effort to broaden engagement with Member States beyond the list of &quot;usual suspects&quot; (i.e., Colombia, Guatemala, Brazil, Mexico).; 5) increased reliance of PBSO on GPPAC&apos;s support in the implementation of CEG (UN System-wide Community Engagement Guidelines on Peacebuilding and Sustaining Peace).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4 Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC hosted a delegation of women peacebuilders during the UNSCR 1325 Week in October 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of its work advocating for increased space for civil society within UN processes, GPPAC hosted a delegation of women peacebuilders during the UNSCR 1325 Week in October 2017. These GPPAC members were able to participate in a number of meetings at the UN, including as speakers in &#x201C;The implementation of UNSCR 1325 in the OSCE Region&#x201D; held by the Mission of Austria to the United Nations, United Methodist Women (UMW), and World Federation of Ukrainian Women&#x2019;s Organizations (WFUWO)) and a Prevention Platform forum called &#x201C;Reflections on the Role of Women in the Prevention of Violent Conflict.&#x201D;</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3 The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">After GPPAC participation at UN New York, WANEP strengthens CSOs coalition on SDG16+ for SDG implementation by Ghana government</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the beginning of 2020 and as a follow up from its attendance at the High-Level Political Forum in New York in July 2019, GPPAC member WANEP joined the national coalitions of CSOs on SDG16+ working with the Ghana government on SDG planning and implementation. This offers GPPAC members to be involved in local implementation of SDG16+ and advocate at the national level for the key recommendations that came out of its country report on progress in Ghana towards SDG16+.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Guidance on how to undertake national level progress reviews on SDG 16+</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on experiences of national reviews undertaken by GPPAC members in Ghana and Cameroon with the support of the GPPAC global secretariat, GPPAC global secretariat developed a guidance note on how to undertake national level progress reviews on SDG 16+.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC member WAA enabled the localisation of SDG16+ in Cameroon</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By March 2020, GPPAC member WAA Cameroon had enhanced its capacity as an organisation and emerged as a leading civil society organization in advocating for the localization of SDG16+ in Cameroon. This was done by WAA broadening its strategic engagement from narrowly focusing on resolving violence against women issues to the broader inter-linking issues that promote peace and conflict prevention and address the root causes of gender-based violence.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Global Pedagogical Network - Joining in Reformation (GPENreformation) recognized GPPAC&#x2019;s Peace Education Working Group (PEWG)&#x2019;s Webinars series as a capacity building and innovative learning tool, and approached the PEWG in September 2019 with a request to collaborate on a project.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By viewing GPPAC PEWG&#x2019;s webinar series on GPPAC&#x2019;s website, GPENreformation learned about GPPAC. GPPAC has been approached to contribute to the project &#x2018;Peace Academy&#x2019; in Spring/Summer 2020 as leader in its conception or as a participating expert. The recognition of GPENreformation indicates an increase in visibility of GPPAC&#x2019;s PEWG work and experiences that are being shared through series of webinars in 2019.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Meeting of the Global Strategy Group in September to provide input for strategic planning.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO representatives of the Global Strategy Group provided input to operational plans of PuF Alliance for 2019, including on Preventing Violent Extremism and strategic priorities for the global thematic working groups of CSOs as part of the PuF Alliance.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility (DD5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.2. The networks and members develop internal procedures to strengthen internal (network) and external accountability and take steps to implement them.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment to Women&#x2019;s Leadership Peacebuilding</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Canadian permanent mission to the UN  co-sponsored GPPACs online event Committing to Women&#x2019;s Leadership in Peacebuilding - Bringing Women, Peace and Security and the UN Peacebuilding Architecture Closer Together held on 28 October 2020 and permanent missions Senior Policy Adviser (Peacebuilding) accepted to be a panelist during the event.Significance of the event was increased as perspectives of civil society organisations were shared alongside perspectives of a member state (Canada) which was current chair of the UNs Peacebuilding Commission.  Co-sponsorship contributes to the track record of GPPACs collaboration with Canada.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3. The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Dialogue on SDG 16+</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Center for Conflict Resolution (CECORE) in partnership with GPPAC conducted a study in June 2020 on the review of Uganda&#x2019;s progress in SDG16+ implementation. The study presented a number of key issues and recommendations that need to be addressed, the report indicates that &#x201C;&#x2026;the progress on peace and justice, Uganda&#x2019;s performance are stagnating &#x2013; meaning their scores on relevant indicators remains stagnant or increasing at a rate below 50 per cent of the growth rate needed to achieve the SDG by 2030&#x201D;. The main objective of the dialogue was therefore to discuss and identify means of how to ensure implementation and acceleration of the realization of SDG16+ in Uganda. The outputs of the dialogue were: 1) A task Force was set up to follow-up on the process of developing the National Peace Policy. The priorities are; Advocacy for national peace policy and Revitalization of National peace platform; Strengthening planning units to provide the required information, data collection tools; Creating awareness on SDG16, build on the secretariat strategy; Strengthening partnership; Localization of SDG 16. 2)The dialogue came up with 5 key priorities/messages to be incorporated in the planned national dialogue on SDGs by the government of Uganda. 3) The Office of the Prime Minister and Uganda Bureau of Statistics promised to share data collection templates and enhance joint collaboration with CSOs as a way of bridging the data gap in the peacebuilding field.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.1.  The networks and member organisations develop resources and expertise on relevant institutional stakeholders through the network</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Space for Civil Society engagement: PuF Alliance hosting and advocacy of 21 GPPAC members and CSO&#x2019;s from across the African continent: African Union - UN - World Bank - GPPAC - CSOs Roundtable in Addis, 7 September 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Discussions with the AU (Peace and Security Department), World Bank (Fragility Unit) and UNDP and PBSO on the &#x201C;Pathways for Peace&#x201D; report. Agreement with WB and UNDP to organize joint events in Asia and the Americas and GPPAC bringing together CSOs from across the respective regions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Draft Protection Protocol and support to 3 GPPAC members facing threats</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Draft protection protocol developed, to be finalised in 2020. It outlines the measures available to us to support GPPAC member organisations facing persecution or prosecution; steps to take to analyse each case and determine which measures should be taken; and preventative measures to avoid GPPAC members coming under scrutiny or threat because of their involvement with GPPAC. It will be finalised following consultations with organisations specialised in in protecting and enhancing civic space, and civil society activists facing threats. GS staff supported GPPAC members facing government / security threats in three cases. No details included for safety reasons.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chairmanship and membership in the New York Peacebuilding Group (NYPG)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During its chairmanship (December, 2019-March, 2020), GPPAC was able to revitalize the work of NYPG and increase the reputation of the NYPG by strengthening partnerships between the group and the key Member States and UN actors. This included the establishment of bi-monthly check-ins with a peacebuilding expert of Canada (the Chair of the Peacebuilding Commission) and regular briefings by the Peacebuilding Support Office (PBSO), including the March 2020 briefing update on the CEG from Henk-Jan Brinkman (Chief of Policy) and the May 2020 NYPG-PBSO Dialogue on the 2020 Report of the Secretary-General on peacebuilding and sustaining peace, where members shared the key messages from NYPG members to inform the Report.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4 Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the South Caucasian Regional Network</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the Regional Steering Group meeting held in Dubai in November 2019, South Caucasian Regional Network members agreed by consensus on a set of procedures and internal network documents for strengthening GPPAC network (including a Code of Ethics) in the region and acceptance of new members and that did not exist before. GPPAC network with new members will increase its potential, authority and credibility as a visible proponent of peace and conflict prevention initiatives.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC members in South Caucasus have elaborated 45 recommendations on regional conflict prevention and promoting human security</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the South-Caucasus Regional Steering Group meeting in Istanbul (November 2017) GPPAC members have elaborated 45 recommendations on regional conflict prevention and promoting human security, intended for advocacy towards state agencies, international and domestic donors as well as CSOs and media communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5 - 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.1 The networks and member organisations develop resources and expertise on relevant institutional stakeholders through the network</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">As a result of GPPAC&#x2019;s international advocacy visit in June 2019, young activists from Kyrgyzstan became more positive about the possibilities to make a change and influence decision-makers. One of the participants said: &quot;I enjoyed it a lot because we were taken very seriously and were told on numerous occasions that the opinions of us, children, matter!&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the advocacy visit to the Netherlands and Belgium, the young Kyrgyzstani boys and girls, participating in the project &#x201C;Cameras in Hands: transformation and empowerment of Kyrgyzstani boys and girls&#x201D; had an opportunity to meet with various (governmental) stakeholders and became more positive about the youth engagement with policymakers. They also discussed the continuation of the project and its activities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Global Working Group started national baselines on SDG implementation in Cameroon and Ghana and global advocacy interventions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the first quarter of 2019, GPPAC&#x2019;s Influencing Policy Working Group started developing 2 national baselines for national Sustainable Development Goals, measuring which actions have been taken and which frameworks are in place for the domestication of SDG16+. The work also resulted in 2 national policy briefs, and a global policy brief reflecting on what came out of this process and providing recommendations for areas of focus, data and ensuring an inclusive process. This process aims to influence national governments in Cameroon and Ghana in their priority setting of peacebuilding actions. The Working Group produced a joint global advocacy calendar and identified regional and global interventions, and ensured financial resources to pre-selected members to represent GPPAC and present their own work.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Media Section interviewed GPPAC&#x2019;s Youth, Peace, and Security Working Group co-Chair, Mr. Emam, during the ECOSOC Youth Forum in April 2019.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the forum, Khaled Emam (co-Chair of GPPAC Youth, Peace, and Security Working Group) received a request from the United Nations Media Section for an interview about his participation in the forum. Three interviews were conducted during which he spoke about the challenges youth faces in the Arab region, and the importance of networking and partnerships at the regional and international level to give young people a voice in decision-making. He also spoke about GPPAC, YPS WG, and the preparations for the High-Level Political Forum. GPPAC helped him attend the forum. Links for the interviews: - https://bit.ly/2IBFaVH - https://bit.ly/2VKwCQ1 - https://bit.ly/2KO8bA7</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Civil Society-UN Prevention Platform co-led by GPPAC held three meetings in the second quarter of 2018, that brought together civil society actors and key UN officials to discuss how to advance the prevention agenda.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Events were held on: the UN development reform; inclusivity in peace processes; and collaboration between UN and civil society on the prevention of violent extremism. GPPAC UN Liaison in coordination with the Quaker United Nations Office (QUNO) planned and moderated the event.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including RIGOs, Steering Groups, CS-UN Working Group)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/UNPPA joint program partners with civil society</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following from the Rigo conference in DC - a joint higher level delegation from UNDP (Sam Rizk) and UNPPA (Roselyn Akombe) together with 3 PDA&#x2019;s requested a meeting with GPPAC to discuss possible areas of cooperation. UNDP and UNDPPA indicated interest in partnering with GPPAC in country, regionally and globally. The Dutch MFA was present during these conversations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs and media of Georgia and Armenia touched upon and publicly discussed economic blocks and their influence to prevention of conflict</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first time CSOs and the media of Georgia and Armenia touched upon and publicly discussed the previously unexplored issues such as prevention of conflict in terms of new re-division and diversification of economic ties in the Region of South Caucasus, having thereby strengthened the capacity of civic actors to make their voice heard by decision makers. Attitudinal changes to the conflict prevention have been reflected in the policy papers, which was a product of compromises and consensus between the parties.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.1 The networks and member organisations develop resources and expertise on relevant institutional stakeholders through the network</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Online trainings on Improving Practice</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From April 2020 till December 2020, through the four online trainings &quot;Analysis, Intervention and Dialogue: Making Sense of Conflict in the Age of Pandemic&quot;, &quot;Human Security Basics: What Really Makes Us Secure When Confronting a Pandemic&quot;, &quot;Multi-Stakeholder Processes for Human Security&quot; and &quot;The Facilitation Toolkit: Exchanging Best Practices&quot;, the GPPAC Improving Practice members have acquired and significantly improved their internal and external capacities in conducting online trainings / workshops and applying online methodology. 
As a result of all the online knowledge exchange that the GPPAC Improving Practice Working Group conducted in 2020, the Group became a more professional group of experts. It developed internal capacities and built the internal dynamics within the group which led to founding active partnerships in the peacebuilding field. The Group signed the Memorandum of Understanding with the Nansen Academy from Norway to deliver jointly online trainings in the sphere of peacebuilding as well as partnership with Patrir.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.2. The networks and members develop internal procedures to strengthen internal (network) and external accountability and take steps to implement them</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC&#x2019;s Youth Policy to mainstream and implement youth strategies in civil society actions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From January to March 2019, GPPAC&#x2019;s Youth Peace and Security (YPS) Working Group has developed GPPAC&#x2019;s draft Youth Policy. The Youth Policy will define objectives and strategies for increasing the effectiveness of the GPPAC network in promoting and achieving meaningful youth participation in conflict prevention and peacebuilding. The policy provides a foundation and implementation strategy for mainstreaming youth throughout GPPAC&#x2019;s work and network structures. WG members were able to provide feedback throughout a two week window and online meetings. GPPAC YPS WG Co-Chair Eliska Jelinkova participated in the preparation of the GPPAC-ICRtoP-FES panel on 12 March 2019, and presented the speech during the panel itself. These advocacy interventions by the YPS Working Group are important steps for youth mainstreaming and implementation at GPPAC.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In June 2019, GPPAC produced two country reports on progress in Cameroon and Ghana towards SDG16+ on peaceful and inclusive societies, the policy brief &#x201C;Peaceful societies &#x2013; the orphaned SDG target?&#x201D; and a 2-page summary of key recommendations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">From March until June 2019, GPPAC, Women in Alternative Action Cameroon (WAA Cameroon) and Regional Secretariat West Africa Network for Peacebuilding (WANEP) conducted a research on progress in Cameroon and Ghana towards SDG16+ on peaceful and inclusive societies. As a result of the research GPPAC has published two reports on progress in Cameroon and Ghana towards SDG16+ on peaceful and inclusive societies. The reports offer a localized qualitative analysis of SDG 16+ progress and government &#x2013; CSO partnerships, and include specific findings and recommendations for each country. Further, GPPAC published a policy brief &#x201C;Peaceful societies &#x2013; the orphaned SDG target?&#x201D; and 2-page summary of key recommendations that capture key findings and recommendations to drive forward the peace agenda within the SDG goals. All printed four publications (400 copies of each) have been disseminated during different events and bilateral engagements at the High Level Political Forum in New York in July 2019. In July 2019 the four publications were shared with GPPAC members (sent to 400+ members) through the GPPAC update &#x201C;GPPAC calls for increased action on SDG16+&#x201D;, and was opened 171 times, which is double the open rate of an ordinary GPPAC Update. The potential outcomes that have been identified is that GPPAC South Asia region expressed their interest to conduct the same research next year. Another potential outcome is that that Regional Coordinator for GPPAC Eastern and Central Africa met with UNDP in Uganda in June 2019 during the Regional Steering Group Meeting. When seeing the country reports on Cameroon and Ghana, UNDP in Uganda said that they are interested to collaborate on undertaking the same research with GPPAC members in Uganda.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders 3.1.2 The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors &amp; institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">139 Civil Society Organizations Call for Immediate Protection of Civilians in Armed Conflict in Myanmar</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC - Southeast Asia issued a joint statement calling on the situation of Chin State in Burma/Myanmar following GPPAC partner local organization in Chin State expressing deep concerns about the current situation of armed conflict and its devastating impact on civilians. Between 9 March to 8 April, at least 28 civilians have been killed in Paletwa. 139 organisations endorsed the statement, and it was sent to regional and national (Myanmar) media and various policy actors (UN, ASEAN, government, CSOs).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2. The networks develop civil society statements, strategies and internal procedures for the protection of human rights defenders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A CSO representative from WANEP Mali spoke in a High-Level Event on Human Security at the UN in New York</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC GS and NY Liaison arranged for a civil society representative from WANEP Mali to speak in a High-Level Event on Human Security and its contribution to Agenda 2030 at the UN in New York.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.4. Political Space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks responsible for prevention, protection and justice (terms of engagement, ToR, consultation frameworks, CS focal points, MoUs]</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">invitation of GPPAC member IID to a regional High Level forum with ASEAN governmental representatives and leading academics</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Regional Secretariat for Southeast Asia (IID) engaged on various occasions with the Philippines Department of Foreign Affairs on ASEAN and the ASEAN Institute for Peace and Reconciliation (AIPR), and provided civil society a political platform on Peace and Security issues. This led to an invitation of IID to a regional High Level forum with ASEAN governmental representatives and leading academics in October 2017. The advocacy agenda is now to institutionalise (Memorandum of Understanding) the involvement of civil society on Peace and Security structurally.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.3 Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society- governmental/ intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#DD3 The ASEAN Intergovernmental Commission on Human Rights (AICHR) permanent representatives&#x2019; joint-statement on the Rohingya Crisis solicited input from the GPPAC Southeast Asia network</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Southeast Asia&#x2019;s Regional Secretariat held the &#x201C;1st Asian Peoples&#x2019; Regional Dialogue on Inter-Racial and Religious Solidarity: Addressing Racial and Religious Discrimination/Intolerance and the Rohingya Crisis&#x201D; dialogue on April 6-9 on board the Peace Boat. The recommendations brought forward during the meeting were presented in a follow-up meeting with the AICHR on April 10. Through the facilitation of Forum Asia, the inputs of GPPAC Southeast Asia members and partners were further solicited in the crafting of the AICHR permanent representatives&#x2019; joint-statement.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#DD3 - 3.4. Political space (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.1. Governmental and intergovernmental actors highlight and take up civil society positions about shrinking political space and repression in policy and decision making areas in a timely and relevant manner</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC and Quaker United Nations Office (QUNO) published the report &#x201C;Building Sustainable Peace - How inclusivity, partnerships and a reinforced UN Peacebuilding Architecture will support delivery&#x201D;.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC and QUNO co-wrote the report on Building Sustainable Peace in relation to the current UN Sustaining Peace resolutions and agenda. As a result of sharing the report, QUNO and GPPAC were asked to meet with the Assistant Secretary-General for Peacebuilding (ASG), Oscar Fernandez-Tarranco. At this meeting, the ASG suggested we work with the Peacebuilding Support Office (PBSO) on providing analysis of the High-Level Event on Sustaining Peace, to be held in New York from 24-25 April 2018. The report is available here: shorturl.at/bjr46.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.2. The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors &amp; institutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased advocacy capacity within GPPAC&#x2019;s Regional Secretariat for West Africa, West Africa Network for Peacebuilding (WANEP) due to their research on SDG 16 as part of a Voluntary National Review on UN SDG 16+ in Ghana during June 2019, and advocacy engagement at the High Level Political Forum (HLPF) in New York in July 2019.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC and WANEP have been working closely on the Voluntary National Review on UN SDG 16+ in Ghana and in preparation for the HLPF; as a result, WANEP gained a wider understanding of SDG 16+ and its implementation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC provided input into the draft international Security policy of the Netherlands</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC and the other 4 Strategic Partners of the Directorate Security and Rule of Law (DSH) of the Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MFA) provided input into the draft international Security policy of the Netherlands. The NGOs provided a Human Security lens to the international Security policy and MFA expressed their interest to take the NGOs&#x2019; points of view into account towards the final policy document.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2 - 3.4 Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.3. National, regional, and international bodies adopt civil society recommendations on inclusive, accountable transparent working methods and formal collaboration with relevant civil society representatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The GPPAC Gender Focal Point from Sri Lanka contributed as a speaker to the event &#x201C;Women Human Rights Defenders: Fighting the Closing Space!&#x201D; organised by the Dutch Gender Platform WO=MEN in The Hague on 19 April 2018.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC arranged for and prepared Visaka Dharmadasa (chair of the Association of War Affected Women in Sri Lanka) to participate effectively in the event. The participation of GPPAC&#x2019;s Gender Focal Point from Sri Lanka contributed to creating space for civil society and greater visibility of GPPAC and GPPAC&#x2019;s scope of work in The Netherlands.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders (DD5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.4. The network members collaborate in engaging relevant governments, RIGO, IGOs in policy events, delegations and initiatives.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC became active member of the &#x201C;NGO Working Group on Women, Peace and Security&#x201D;</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC became active member of the &#x201C;NGO Working Group on Women, Peace and Security&#x201D; in 2017. This paved the way to participate in the inner circle of the NGOs discussion on WPS issues and with UN actors. UN policy development on WPS can now be brought to GPPAC members with more frequency and intensity. Currently the future of the 16-days campaign is discussed and planned for the end-of-year campaign.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5 - 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3 The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="8"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working Group on regional and non-governmental organizations.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC continued operationalization of the RIGO Working Group and regional peacebuilding advocacy and deeper engagement in Latin America and the Caribbean (LAC). GPPAC was a speaker at the webinar &quot;Enhance Cooperation between the United Nations and Regional Organizations in the Promotion of International Peace and Security&quot; on 12 August 2020. GPPAC together with the Plataforma CIP&#xD3; and the Stimson Center co-organized a virtual expert discussion on &quot;Joining capacities to respond to regional crises: Calling on Latin America and the Caribbean&apos;s regional organisations?&quot; on Friday, 18 September 2020. The discussion took the format of a closed, off-the-record session that brings together regional stakeholders in the Americas and Caribbean, including regional organisations and multilateral arrangements, Member States, the UN, and civil society organisations to further understand some of the opportunities and challenges faced in making regional cooperation in LAC credible and effective. The summary of the discussion was further translated into a blog &quot;Regionalism in LAC in the era of COVID-19: Understanding the role and capacities of regional organizations&quot; published on GPPAC web-site.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased inclusion of civil society recommendations articulated through the GPPAC network in the global policy action</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC engaged with relevant actors by publishing policy resources and creating various policy spaces to share GPPAC messaging with the key actors of the 2020 Peacebuilding Architecture Review. As a result of this advocacy, we were able to inform the principal inputs into the formal phase of the 2020 Peacebuilding Architecture Review on the following topics: unlock the full potential of the Peacebuilding Commission,  promote local ownership, prioritize &#x201C;peace&#x201D; in efforts to achieve system-wide coherence, enhance partnerships with regional and subregional organizations, internalize WPS and YPS agendas, and focus on the impact of peacebuilding and sustaining peace in the field. The 2020 SG Report specifically highlights the GPPAC participatory video methodology project as an approach to youth empowerment towards playing key roles in identifying peacebuilding needs and to take them up with local authorities. GPPAC members were asked to brief the Peacebuilding Commission on the socio-economic impact of COVID-19 ensuring the presence of local civil society voices in the PBC deliberations. And last, the Community Engagement Guidelines includes a number of language and inputs from the GPPAC Network, including references to the VTC conducted in Mali and the case-study of peacebuilding work in Kyrgyzstan. Moreover, the document includes a section on recommendations for civil society that GPPAC co-drafted with the Quaker UN Office and workshopped with the New York Peacebuilding Group as an attempt to generate broader civil society ownership.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.1. Governmental and intergovernmental actors highlight and take up civil society positions about shrinking political space and repression in policy and decision making areas in a timely and relevant manner</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 27 June 2019, for the first time a member of the EU&#x2019;s Security Sector Reform (SSR) Taskforce (at the EEAS) approached GPPAC to provide expertise on community security to the Taskforce and invited GPPAC to take part in a workshop with partners, quoting GPPAC&#x2019;s track-record in this area.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC had tried for over a year to engage the SSR experts in the EEAS without success (non-responsive), and now a senior person at the Security and Defence Policy Division (Civilian CSDP) of the European External Action Service (EEAS) in Brussels offers GPPAC the opportunity to be part of discussions on Security Sector Reform. This official reached out as a result of speaking at a GPPAC policy dialogue as part of the WOSCAP project (2017) two years ago, which impressed on her GPPAC&#x2019;s track record in this area. The role of the EU&#x2019;s inter-service SSR task force is to ensure more effective thematic support from HQ to delegations and Common Security and Defence Policy missions. The Taskforce meeting / workshop is likely to take place in October 2019.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting Civil Society Partner Actions</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC has supported several GPPAC policy, advocacy and programming by conducting advocacy training, supporting members on their planned engagement and strategies for engaging the UN and regional organizations and broadening opportunities for policy input. IN Q3, regular preparatory sessions ahead of all global and regional engagements for GPPAC members. Resulted engagement of GPPAC around HLPF has led to the invitation by ForPeace to co-organize the discussion on an online consultation on the Establishment of Ministries or Departments and other National Infrastructures for Peace in October 2020. We supported our Cameroon partners in engaging with PDAs, which led GPPAC&#x2019;s Cameroon partner to become a lead facilitator of CS engagement with the UNCT. Last, we supported our MENA partners to advocate on Libya and Gender-SALW.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.4. The network members collaborate in engaging relevant governments, RIGO, IGOs in policy events, delegations and initiatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC hosts roundtable on the progress towards SDG16+</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC hosted a roundtable with the Dutch MFA, CSPPS and HiiL on the progress towards SDG 16+ implementation and next steps during the Knowledge Platform (KPSRL annual meeting on 10th of October). The roundtable was evaluated as &#x2018;excellent&#x2019; by participants and they indicated that they learned something new. GPPAC and CSPPS followed this conversation up with the Dutch MFA to seek support for the SDG localisation work and cooperation on specific countries</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC South East Asia led the crafting of a joint statement by 433 organisations for a human response to COVID19</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC members in South East Asia led the crafting of a joint statement titled &#x201C;Southeast Asian states should heed the call for a global ceasefire, ensure conflict sensitivity and human rights in responding to COVID19 crisis&#x201D;. This was signed by 433 organisations all over Southeast Asia, including a few individuals including 1996 Nobel Peace Prize co-awardee Jose Manuel Ramos-Horta, and was submitted to ASEAN offices, member-states, embassies, media, UN agencies and other relevant policy actors last March 30-April 1.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thematic Paper from S. Caucasus for UN 2020 Peacebuilding Architecture Review.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC network members provided input about coordinating national and regional efforts for peacebuilding architecture and conflict prevention for the thematic paper from S. Caucasus intended for the UN Secretary General&#x2019;s 2020 report. The paper gathered opinions of members of GPPAC S. Caucasus network as well as representatives of the civil sector from the secessionist regions of Abkhazia, South Ossetia and Nagorno-Karabakh. The paper contains views, concerns and suggestions about the UN role in settling the conflicts in S. Caucasus. The first and foremost significance is that members of GPPAC regional network from the secessionist regions took part in the preparation of the paper. It sends to the UN messages, concerns and recommendations from the prominent peace activists from the region about the role that UN could play in addressing the long- standing unresolved conflicts in the regions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC organises various round table meetings with UN, Netherlands, civil society organisations on Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and Sustaining Peace</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC organised regular meetings with key individuals and organisations in peacebuilding and conflict prevention during meetings and/or individual engagements: meeting with the United Nations Peacebuilding Fund (UNPBF) during their visit to the Netherlands (4th December), meeting with Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MFA) individuals working on SDGs, Sustaining Peace, United Nations Peacebuilding Support Office (UN PBSO) and joint program at the ministry on 10th of December, organization of a roundtable with CSOs working on SDG 16+ implementation (5th December).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including CS-UN Working Group).</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Women invited GPPACs gender focal point from Armenia to a seminar to strengthen the role of women in peace processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC participated in the high-level seminar Strengthening Women&#x2019;s Participation in Peace Processes, What Roles and Responsibilities for States? held in Rome, Italy, 3-4 December 2019. This was the first time that a gender expert from GPPACs network in the Caucasus that is not coming from a women&#x2019;s rights or women led CSO has been supported by UN Women. This indicates a more inclusive approach in who is supported as well as change of GPPACs credibility as an organisation working on gender equality and conflict prevention. This invitation resulted from the bilateral meeting held between GPPACs delegation at WPS week and UN Women at their headquarters in New York on 31 October 2019.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC invited to the Forum &#x2018;Localizing the 2030 Agenda: Building on What Works&#x2019;</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC participated in this forum to advocate for multistakeholder SDG implementation, involvement of civil society in the upcoming VNR processes and establish networks for cooperation in country as well as with UNDP, other NGOs and potential donors. It took place on 27-29 October 2019 in Banjul, Gambia. The Forum was organized in partnership with the Government of Gambia, the Senegalo-Gambia Permanent Secretariat, the UN Country Team in The Gambia, the UN Trust Fund for Human Security (UNTFHS), Humanity United and the International Peace Institute (IPI). It brought together 70 leaders from national and local governments, the UN system, local champions, entrepreneurs, youth and women organizations from C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire, The Gambia, Ghana, Guinea-Bissau, Guinea, Liberia, Senegal, and Sierra Leone, as well as regional entities and the international community.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC contributed to the 2020 Review of the UN Peacebuilding Architecture</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC prepared thematic submissions to the UN Secretary-General Report on Peacebuilding and Sustaining Peace on 1) regional peacebuilding; 2) lessons learned from Liberia and Papua New Guinea, 3) local perspectives on peacebuilding in South Caucasus. GPPAC and Life and Peace Institute hosted a civil society call for the 2020 Review on December 5, 2019 to share updates on the process from PBSO and facilitate information exchange between various actors. As a chair of the New York Peacebuilding Group, GPPAC worked to brainstorm ideas for a policy forum and connected with the Peacebuilding Commission incoming Chair, Canada, to strengthen the role of NYPG in the process.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Launch of the Papua New Guinea publication on Sustaining Peace and practice on September 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC previously worked and engaged with local GPPAC members in Liberia and Papua New Guinea. The publication is a result of an increased of practical understanding of UN peacebuilding and Sustaining Peace at the practical level. A roundtable discussed the results of the publication</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC produced overviews of Prevention Up Front activities and plans in focus countries for the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC produced five country one-pagers that summarise the planned Prevention Up Front (PUF) activities in Syria, The Philippines, Georgia, Ukraine and Mali, for 2018. These materials have been disseminated to inform the Dutch embassies in these countries and the relevant regional desks of the Dutch Ministry of Foreign Affairs. GPPAC also engaged with the MFA on the highlights of PUF in 2017 and produced an overview per region.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.2. The networks and members develop internal procedures to strengthen internal (network) and external accountability and take steps to implement them</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Held conversations with UN Department of Peacekeeping Operations (DPKO) to begin exploring concrete ways to partner on enhancing peacekeeping operations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC project staff was able to build upon initial conversations with UN Department of Peacekeeping Operations (DPKO) to begin exploring concrete ways to partner on enhancing peacekeeping operations&#x2019; engagement with civil society. As a result of these efforts, the UN Liaison was invited to be part of entire DPKO Heads of Civil Affairs workshop and conduct one session on civil society engagement (based on Human Security Handbook). This allowed staff to initiate relationships with heads of civil affairs from following missions: MONUSCO (DRC), UNMIL (Liberia), UNMISS (South Sudan), CAR, UNAMID (Darfur), UNOCI (Cote d&#x2019;Ivoire), MINUSMA (Mali), MINUSCA (CAR), UNFICYP (Cyprus). GPPAC was also asked to co-host an event with UN DPKO that explored ways in which peacekeeping missions can develop and implement civil society engagement strategies, some of the challenges they may face and best practices from the field in overcoming these hurdles to inclusion. A draft engagement strategy was subsequently developed in MINUSCA featuring recommendations from the discussion.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.3 Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.1. Network members engage in each other&#x2019;s policy arenas and coordinate their work through exchanges, joint statements and policy engagements</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">First GPPAC academic paper published on Civil-Military Synergy in EU External Action</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC published an academic paper for the first time as GPPAC. The paper titled &#x201C;Local Ownership, Inclusivity and Civil-Military Synergy in EU External Action: The Case of EU Support to Security Sector Reforms in Mali&#x201D; was published on November 2018 in the Journal for Regional Security, focusing on the EU, SSR, the case of Mali, and civil-military synergies. http://aseestant.ceon.rs/index.php/jouregsec/article/view/19428/pdf https://www.gppac.net/news/local-ownership-inclusivity-and-civil-military-synergy-eu-external-action</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions (DD4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.2. The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors &amp; institutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Facilitation of the New York Peacebuilding Group to organise engagement between CSOs and UN bodies</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC strengthened the Civil Society-UN Prevention Platform it co-facilitates with the Quaker United Nations Office (QUNO), holding advocacy meetings with a number of UN agencies, including Department of Political Affairs, UN Development Programme, UN Women and Department of Peacekeeping Operations, among others. Through these meetings, the Prevention Platform was able to establish itself as a go-to forum for holding honest conversations between UN and civil society on prevention, and was able to hold the only side-event to the &#x201C;High-Level Dialogue on the linkages between the 2030 Agenda and Sustaining Peace,&#x201D; which focused on how these synergies can be leveraged for prevention and hosted the first meeting between newly appointed Under Secretary-General and Senior Advisor on Policy, Ms. Ana Maria Men&#xE9;ndez, and civil society organizations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3 The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions (including working groups, coalitions, strategy documents)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened localization of the global agendas</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC supported operationalization and in implementation of global agendas at the local level. This includes strengthening linkages between local peacebuilders and regional and international multilateral partners, as well as bringing UN field actors into the discussions supported by GPPAC at the UN. This contributed to the transformation of dialogue and a better reflection of field perspectives in the UNHQ discourse.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthened advocacy capacity of GPPAC members</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC was able to create resources (publications that can be used for advocacy) and provide capacity building training specifically focused on the peacebuilding engagement, including policy support for the member in Kyrgyzstan (around the PBC on YPS), South Caucasus (around the CS-UN Prevention Platform meeting) and Lebanon (around DHF&apos;s 2020 Review Consultation for Lebanon). This allowed the GPPAC Network to 1) coherent messaging; 2) better quality of delivery; 3) stronger policy impact regarding YPS: spearheaded further discussion on the YPS Strategy for the PBC; re: South Caucasus: UNDPPA further increased its demand on PDAs to better engage with civil society &amp; OHCHR engaged with GPPAC members to further explore the point to the protections of local peacebuilders; regarding MENAPPAC, it ensures stronger advocacy engagement capacities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.1. The networks and member organisations develop resources and expertise on relevant institutional stakeholders through the network (incl. guidelines/manuals, information sheets, briefings, liaisons/resource persons..)</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC South East Asia co-led a joint statement on the Rohingya crisis</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC, Progressive Voice and Forum Asia have together written a joint statement on the Rohingya crisis entitled &#x201C;Myanmar Must Prioritize Protection of Civilians in Rakhine State, Address the Roots of the Conflict&#x201D;. The petition was signed by 122 organisations and 33 individuals, while endorsement continue to come. It has been circulated among different groups, embassies and government/regional/intergovernmental organisations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.2. The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors and institutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobilizing a joint community of practice on prevention via the Civil Society-UN Prevention Platform</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC, in partnership with QUNO and the Core Group, enhanced civil society and UN collective capacity to prevent conflicts by conducting the PDA induction, where it has shared critical good practices on engaging with local peacebuilders at the local level (capacity building) and facilitated 5 policy dialogues, where it has outlined the key opportunities on prevention, facilitated broader input from civil society into the work of the UN Office of the Secretary-General and the UN Department of Peacebuilding and Political Affairs. This included the Meeting with Ana Maria Menendez (January, 2020), the discussion on the evolution of Prevention (February, 2020), the discussion on gender transformative analysis in COVID-19 (April, 2020), the discussion on the role of youth in Prevention (April, 2020), the discussion on the capacity of mediation to respond to the evolving nature of conflict (June, 2020), the discussion on upstream prevention (July, 2020). GPPAC increased local civil society voices in the NY policy dialogues and increased engagement with Member States by encouraging the adoption of a new working method for the Platform - engaging more with Member States and local civil society (including where relevant via VTC). After the first meeting of the discussion series on the evolution of prevention, the statement of GPPAC members from South Caucasus was widely followed-up on, including by DPPA and OHCHR, and referenced in many forthcoming dialogues by various participants of this meeting. GPPAC brought partners from UNOY, WANEP, and ACCORD to participate in the discussions. GPPAC-QUNO as co-facilitators of the Platform continue to attend and provide technical capacity building sessions and share learning from the PDA project during the PDA inductions (the last one took place in March, 2020). In the follow-up from this session, we were able to further connect with the number of PDAs to continue the dialogue and facilitate future joint learning and action.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4 Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OAS formalizes its engagement with civil society working on peacebuilding and conflict prevention.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC&#x2019;s decade-long collaboration and engagement with the Organization of American States (OAS) is now formalised through the development of a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) between OAS and GPPAC in 2019. GPPAC members will now be able to represent GPPAC in the OAS General Assembly. GPPAC will also obtain a CSO Observer Status in the OAS, and be able to shape discussions relating to peace education, peace building and conflict prevention.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC revised Gender Policy has been approved and published online</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC&#x2019;s new Gender Policy has been finalised based on the input of GPPAC&#x2019;s main decision making body (the GPPAC International Steering Group) and is now published online.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development and eventual adoption of the youth policy within the GPPAC network has created a greater awareness of and interest to work with the Youth, Peace, and Security (YPS) agenda among GPPAC members during the months of April-July 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Greater awareness by the GPPAC network is demonstrated by: (1) new members who have recently joined the YPS Working Group (a member from Northeast Asia, 2 members from South Asia, a member from South Africa, 2 members from Central Asia) since the end of 2018; (2) &#x201C;youth&#x201D; is being reported as one out of three priorities by GPPAC members for the new strategic period; and (3) at least six regions (Northeast Asia, Southern Africa, Latin America and the Caribbean, Central Asia, Western Balkans, the Middle East and North Africa) reported on YPS in the last GPPAC International Steering Group meeting.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC became an active member of the global network on Prevention of Violent Extremism (PVE) and participation at international levels</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, GPPAC became an active member of the global network on Prevention of Violent Extremism (PVE). The GPPAC network asked the Global Secretariat to become more active on PVE. GPPAC and 3 members and 2 partners (RCSS, WANEP, UNOY and HSC, CSPS) participated in the Geneva conference on PVE (Global Project) and Vienna OSCE conference. In autumn, GPPAC and 8 Southeast Asian members took a leading role in discussions at the Manila conference on PVE. GPPAC had the first online meeting in September of the global Working Group on PVE with participation of 10 members.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD4 - 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3 The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC is active member of international initiatives on civic space and brought Defend Defenders to ECA members; support to 1 member facing repression from their government</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, GPPAC started implementing the priority area identified during the baseline analysis in 2016 in the 5 priority regions: space for civil society. As a consequence of the baseline analysis &#x201C;space for civil society&#x201D; had become the third priority goal to work on within the Prevention up Front Alliance. GPPAC developed a draft strategy on civic space that will be discussed in the Global Strategy Group and International Steering Group in 2018. GPPAC supported an individual member facing repression from their government. GPPAC is an active member of international working groups on civic space and brought Defend Defenders to the Regional Steering Group meeting in Kampala in September 2017 for a workshop of Central and East African members.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.2 - Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.2. The networks and members develop internal procedures to strengthen internal (network) and external accountability and take steps to implement them.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Better Peace&quot; website was officially launched and became one of the only go-to resources on the UN Peacebuilding Commission (PBC) and its work</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2017, the Better Peace website was officially launched and became one of the only go-to resources on the UN Peacebuilding Commission (PBC) and its work. Along with providing meeting summaries, which increased the transparency of the PBC&apos;s work to those outside New York, GPPAC was able to create space for briefings by relevant civil society representatives during PBC meetings through its advocacy and relationships. In 2017, these included meetings on: The Solomon Islands, Guinea-Bissau, Colombia, and Sri Lanka (featuring Jehan Perera from the GPPAC member organisation the National Peace Council of Sri Lanka). GPPAC along with other CSOs in New York advocated successfully for civil society representatives to be able to participate in the PBC&#x2019;s Annual Session in 2017.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 - 3.3 Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society- governmental/ intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including RIGOs Steering Groups, CS-UN Working Group)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigerian policy maker supports the implementation of UNSCR2250</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In December 2019, During the Nigeria Youth for Peace Forum, Honourable Olajuwon Olaosebikan of the Lagos State House of Assembly, the state legislative chamber, proclaimed the full support of the Lagos State legislature to youth, peace and development initiatives in the state. This is significant because the legislative arm of government which is primarily responsible for law- making in the state has a huge role to play in ensuring the domestication and implementation of both local and international policy frameworks including UNSCR2250. Prior to the forum, representatives of the legislative body who were engaged during mobilisation for the meeting confessed to their ignorance of the existence of UNSCR220 on Youth, Peace and Security. However, the event presented a platform for members to fully grasp the essence of the resolution and applicability at all levels in Nigeria.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political will to move forward with an Inclusive Transitional Government of National in South Sudan Unity</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In December 2019, the two principles in the South Sudan peace agreement, President Salva Kiir and Dr. Riek Machar, have demonstrated a political will towards fulfilling their commitment forming an Inclusive Transitional Government of National Unity by like accepting the face-to-face meetings and discussions of the way forward for peace in South Sudan. This positive change in behavior creates hope to end one of the most disastrous armed conflicts in the world today - and preventing the escalation of violence in South Sudan. The relevance of this outcome is related to the failure by the 2 principles to agree on a power-sharing government, which remains the main bottleneck to the realisation of the revitalised peace agreement in South Sudan. The positive move by the 2 principles therefore is a move towards restoring the hopes that have for long been shattered. GPPAC&#x2019;s contribution comes from hosting a meeting on the Development of recommendations for the implementation of the peace deal in South Sudan between Salva Kiir and Riek Machar. The activity attracted several high level and key influential actors and was follow-up by advocacy and lobby meetings with the African Union, IGAD, groups of diplomats like the TROIKA, members of the East African Community, leaders of neighbouring countries, National Pre-Transitional Committee, rally of civil society and government actors, among others.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of common GPPAC-East Central Africa priority areas and advocacy strategy for 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In February 2019, during the GPPAC-East Central Africa Regional Steering Group 2019 meeting, members of 19 member organisations developed a joint strategy on prioritised conflict prevention issues. The key advocacy areas for 2019 are trust and collaboration building between CSOs and government, capacity building of members and safety and protection, and fast-tracking specific peacebuilding initiatives/policies at national and regional level.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Publication of the Policy Brief &#x201C;Fostering Inclusion Builds Resilient Societies&#x201D; for advocacy on the Responsibility to Protect at the UN</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In March 2019, GPPAC in collaboration with Strategic Partnership (SP) Alliance partner &#x2018;International Coalition for the Responsibility to Protect&#x2019; (ICRtoP) and Friedrich Ebert Stiftung New York office published the policy brief on &#x201C;Fostering Inclusion Builds Resilient Societies&#x201D; and distributed it via social media and at a UN panel in New York. The policy brief summarised the conclusions of the Women, Peace and Security week&#x2019;s Panel discussion (hosted by the three organisations). It featured examples and recommendations from the 4 panelists from Uganda, Myanmar, West Africa and Palestine, and provides policy recommendations per target actor on participation of women in conflict and atrocity prevention. GPPAC and ICRtoP are part of the SP Alliance &#x201C;Prevention up Front&#x201D;.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN considers the UN-CSO Prevention Platform as the go-to platform to work on community engagement for peacebuilding.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In March 2019, the Prevention Platform was asked to join a UNDP-DPPA brownbag event on community engagement, in which GPPAC featured as a panelist. The event on peace and security reform also led to a request by UNDP-DPPA and other panelists to plan follow-up events. These outcomes further strengthened the Prevention Platform, enabling it to make stronger connections to more agencies with the UN. The platform in New York was initiated and being facilitated by GPPAC and QUNO.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC National Focal Point CEPO issued report on the implementation of the peace agreement in South Sudan</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In March 2020, CEPO (GPPAC Focal Point in South Sudan) issued the 1st status report on the observation of the R-ARCSS (Revitalized Agreement on the Resolution of Conflict in South Sudan) transitional period implementation. The report in part calls for: compliance with the provisions of the peace agreement implementation, disseminating the provisions of the peace agreement, Developing a political vision, putting in place financial systems for administering the transitional period, Providing adequate Funds for speeding up the unification of the forces in a professional manner, a checklist for fighting corruption, promoting transparency and human rights, among others. CEPO will be releasing monthly oversight observation reports.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC National Focal Point CEPO responding to the COVID 19 pandemic in South Sudan</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In March 2020, CEPO (GPPAC Focal Point in South in South Sudan) started developing the first COVID.19 national observatory report to guide the government of South Sudan and actors in responding to the pandemic. The first report calls for among others; transparency, protection of front line officers, being sensitive to the needs of internally displaced persons, use of non-stigmatizing language, capacity building, general awareness and respect of human rights.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SDG16+ in Uganda</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In May 2020, CECORE and GPPAC produced a report on the Review of Uganda&apos;s progress on SDG16+ - to complement Government efforts - ahead of its Voluntary National Review (VNR) report, presented to the UN High Level Political Forum 2020. The study focused on peaceful, just and inclusive societies and highlighted two key findings. First, Uganda has an enabling legal, policy and a comprehensive coordination framework for the SDGs overall. Second, although the government has made notable progress on a number of SDGs, progress on SDG16+ has stagnated. This is worrying because SDG16+ and achieving a peaceful Uganda is a key pre-requisite and central pillar for the realization of all the SDGs. The prevalence of violent conflicts, inequalities and injustices curtails the country&#x2019;s development aspirations and the achievement of the SDGs. To accelerate SDG 16+ progress, the study observes that peacebuilding and conflict prevention must be prioritized. This includes finalizing and passing a national Peace Policy, awareness raising on SDG 16+, greater participation of stakeholders to enhance accountability of duty bearers at local and national levels, capacitating relevant prevention and peacebuilding structures, and promoting the contextual localization of SDG 16+. Particular attention should be paid to human security as well as achieving gender equity, women&#x2019;s rights and engaging youth and other vulnerable groups as partners. The report was launched on July 6, 2020 during the online side event during the High Level Political Forum 2020 conference on Infrastructure for Peace in Africa - organized by GPPAC.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1 Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.2. The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors &amp; institutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Introduction of Regional Training on Conflict Transformation at the ASEAN Institute for Peace and Reconciliation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In November 2019, the ASEAN Institute for Peace and Reconciliation (ASEAN-IPR) permanent representative Amb. Artauli Tobing, seconded by the representatives from the ASEAN-IPR Secrretariat/Ministry of the Foreign Affairs of Indonesia and the Ministry of the Foreign Affairs of Malaysia, have verbally expressed their support in championing the proposal to make the Regional Training on Conflict Transformation and Peacebuilding as an organic program of the ASEAN-IPR, subject to some adjustments in the training design, particularly possible sensitivities in some ongoing peace processes, in order not to jeopardize inter-state relations of ASEAN member-states.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Peacebuilding Support Office (UNPBSO) to partner with GPPAC at the regional level</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In October - December 2019 tThe UN Peacebuilding Support Office (UNPBSO) indicated they wanted to partner with GPPAC at the regional level. This was a result of GPPAC&#x2019;s participation in the development of the Community Engagement Guidelines (CEG). While the CEG do not mention regional engagement, the process of the development of Guidelines has become a driver of building closer partnership between the UN and civil society in other contexts.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peacebuilding, Covid-19 and Human rights coordination committee in South Sudan</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In October 2020, South Sudan established a national Coordination Committee on the nexus between peacebuilding, COVID-19 and Human Rights which in turn has  appointed two Ambassadors; for UNSCR1325 and UNSCR 2250 to champion the localization of peace building, women and youth efforts in the country. During the GPPAC-CEPO workshop held in October 2020, one of the key recommendations to the government by the participant was to establish a mechanism called the national Coordination Committee on the nexus between peacebuilding, COVID-19 and Human Rights. 
The outcome is important because it is the first time the Government of South Sudan appreciated the need and put in place a national Coordination Committee on the nexus between peacebuilding, COVID-19 and Human Rights. It is also the first time the Government of South Sudan put in place an initiative of appointing the Ambassador for UNSRC 1325 in South Sudan and 2250.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.4. The network members collaborate in engaging relevant governments, RIGO, IGOs in policy events, delegations and initiatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Steering Group call</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In order to rebuild ISG sense of connection and ownership between meetings, held first ISG update call on 3 December</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">12 schools and 15 teachers apply newly developed Peace Education courses in Moldova and Transnistria</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the 2019 school year (September 2019 &#x2013; May 2020) increasing number of schools and teachers in Moldova (including the Transnistria region) are teaching the developed peace education courses &#x201C;Culture of Good Neighborhood&#x201D; / &#x201C;Living in peace and harmony&#x201C;. At least 12 new schools and 15 new teachers began to apply the developed Peace Education courses in their work (from the Dubasari, Stefan Voda, and other districts), and at least 1 additional school began teaching the &#x201C;Living in Peace and Harmony&#x201D; version of the peace education course in the Transnistria region. The number of children, studying this course, has reached approx. 4500 (including over 1500 children in schools of the Transnistrian region). It is a significant development because in Moldova there is an unresolved territorial dispute over the separatist region of Transnistria. For the long-term resolution of this and other societal issues it is important that children are educated in peace and tolerance.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD1" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC South Caucasus held six CSO dialogue meetings to create sustainable cooperation between Georgian, Armenian and Azerbaijani civic and media actors in conflict prevention.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the first dialogue (Armenia, 2-3 June 2018) participants discussed the regime change in Armenia and its impact on the existing conflict and on the economic dimensions of conflict prevention. In the second meeting (Azerbaijan, 18 June 2018) participants addressed how to respond to human rights violations leading to conflict, and decided to expand educational work and networking between CSOs working on human rights. The third discussion (Azerbaijan, 23-24 June 2018) was devoted to the role of peace journalists and social media. Here, the participants agreed to create a platform for exchange of experience and knowledge about proper coverage of conflict situations. This platform is significant because it is the first time there is established a floor of discussion where the civic sector (CSOs, media, pundits) of Azerbaijan, Armenia and Georgia have open discussion about competing economic alliances in the region.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2. Network members engage in each others&#x2019; policy arenas and coordinate their work through exchanges, joint statements and policy engagements</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Civil Society-UN Prevention Platform (co-led by GPPAC) held a meeting on 24 January 2018 on UN peace and security reforms that brought together civil society actors and key UN officials</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the meeting, it was discussed how UN peace and security reforms could advance conflict prevention. The event was planned and moderated by GPPAC and Quaker United Nations Office (QUNO).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3. The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation of the GPPAC Youth policy in the MENA region</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Introduction of the newly adopted Youth policy as well as the relevant parts of the YPS WG work plan for 2020 during a 3-day event in Lebanon. We provided 10 MENAPAC members with tools to implement the Youth policy in the region and we explored the roles, requests and challenges of the main YPS stakeholders (international and regional organisations, national Organization, youth lead organization). The sessions were conducted through practical exercises and a gender sensitive approach.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC and the Organization for American States signed a Memorandum of Understanding during the Regional Intergovernmental Organization (RIGO) conference on 20 September 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">It came as a result of GPPAC&#x2019;s previous engagement with the OAS. According to the OAS Secretary General, OAS &#x201C;recognizes GPPAC as a strategic advocate for civil society and regional organisations for the promotion of peace and democracy&#x201D;. GPPAC has an on-going collaboration with OAS for almost a decade. However, the nature of this collaboration was ad hoc, and centered around particular activities. In 2019, this collaboration was formal with the signing of a MoU between OAS and GPPAC.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contribution to the 4th Dutch National Action Plan on Women, Peace and Security</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Language on conflict prevention strengthened and improved in the text of the Forth Dutch National Action plan on Women, Peace and security final version dated 15 October 2020. The text includes multiple references to harmful gender roles and practices, human security, conflict sensitivity and relevance of engagement with local women&apos;s organisations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2. The networks develop civil society statements, strategies and internal procedures for the protection of human rights defenders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC South East Asia started new advocacy campaign on SDG16+</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Members throughout the GPPAC South East Asia and South Asia regions have recognised the potential of using SDG 16+ for their local peacebuilding and prevention work, including the SDGs in their plans and priorities for 2020. Representatives of these regions also participated in the SDG 16+ Forum in Dili in November 2019. This shows a better understanding and grasp of the SDG agenda by GPPAC members and the opportunities it offers to engage with UN and government entities. This is significant because such a global agenda can only become useful if local actors can translate it into a useful instrument on the ground. The recognition of the potential of SDG 16+ is the first step towards this.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recognition of GPPACs expertise on women peace and security</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NGO working group on Women peace and Security (WPS) proposed GPPACs Gender and Inclusivity specialist to speak on conflict prevention and WPS as a part of bigger delegation that presented the NGOWG on WPS Roadmap at the meeting of the NGOWG on WPS with high level meeting with DSG Amina Mohamed in October 2020.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3. The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC member H&#xE9;ritiers de la Justice called for a preventive and peaceful means of addressing electoral disputes in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On June 12, H&#xE9;ritiers de la Justice issued a statement calling for a change in approach as elective democracy remains under pressure in the DRC and noted that the nation is still not governed by those elected by the Congolese population. H&#xE9;ritiers de la Justice, in their latest Nota Bene newsletter, called upon international and national institutions to assist in the transition of power and hold those responsible for this &#x201C;miscarriage&#x201D; of justice accountable. H&#xE9;ritiers de la Justice also calls upon victims of electoral malpractices to pursue peaceful and legal means of redress; and on national and regional bodies, the African Union, and diplomatic missions to support a preventive and peaceful means of addressing electoral disputes in the DRC.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National consultative dialogue and Task Force on Child Marriage and Female Genital Mutilation</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On March 30, 2020, WAA Cameroon organized a National consultative dialogue with traditional and religious leaders, civil society and institutions on Child Marriage and Female Genital Mutilation. The dialogue brought together 33 participants. The traditional leaders came from all the 10 regions of the country. The dialogue emphasized the role of communities and religious leaders in ending harmful socio-cultural practices against women and girls; and increase of women&#x2019;s access to decision making and participation in peace processes. One of the key outputs was a task-force put together for religious and traditions leaders to work together to come up with community by-laws to empower women in the communities. The participants of the dialogue also signed an engagement to make efforts to push for gender equality in their communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Revitalisation of the council for the settlement of the Karabakh conflict in Azerbaijan.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On October 2-6 Azerbaijani youth peace activists organized thematic meetings on human security aspects of the Karabakh war and revitalized for this purpose a public council of experts for the settlement of the Karabakh conflict (Karabakh Council), composed of peace activists, pundits and CSOs.  Within the council, the Youth CSOs came out with several initiatives about building confidence between the conflicting parties and economic connectivity measures to relieve the aftermath of the war. The initiatives have been channeled to the official bodies through the officials who participated in the thematic meetings of the youth.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Call for a ceasefire in Nagorno-Karabakh</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On October 5, in its statement GPPAC called on the governments of Armenia and Azerbaijan for immediate ceasefire (http://iccn.ge/index.php?article_id=371&amp;clang=1).                          
ICCN and several CSOs with mandate of working on peace and confidence building urgently signed and issued a document &#x201C;APPEAL TO THE OSCE 12 OCTOBER 2020&#x201D; calling OSCE to pay greater attention to the sensitive issue and engage more proactively in the settlement of the armed conflict</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2. The networks develop civil society statements, strategies and internal procedures for the protection of human rights defenders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Algerian national delegation to the UN has promised to include young people and be accountable to them in the course of the preparation of the next Voluntary National Review (VNR) on the SDGs in response to GPPAC Youth, Peace and Security working group core member, Khaled Emam&#x2019;s, statement on behalf of the United Nations Major Group on Children and Youth (UN MGCY) about the Algerian VNR report on 17 July 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On behalf of UN MGCY, Khaled made a briefing on Algeria&apos;s VNR (Voluntary National Review) report on the implementation of the SDGs agenda. He focused on the need for Algeria to commit itself in allowing civil society institutions and relevant groups (including young people) to participate and contribute in the preparation of the VNR. The briefing also talked about the importance of respecting democracy and reforms towards justice as these were among the demands by the young protesters in Algeria.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strategic Engagement with the European Union on the Conflict in Mindanao, Philippines</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Representatives from the European Union&#x2019;s External Action Service &#x201C;PRISM&#x201D; department that deals with peacebuilding and conflict prevention reached out to GPPAC and its members to get their input for a strategy meeting Mindanao in the Philippines peace process. GPPAC also organised meetings in Fourth quarter of 2018 between EU representatives on Philippines, Myanmar and Mali that lead to further engagements in the field &amp; consultation of GPPAC&#x2019;s member in the Philippines for a strategy meeting.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including CS-UN Working Group)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO space at the Asia Europe People&apos;s Forum 12 held in Ghent, Belgium from 29 September until 1 October.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seven GPPAC CSO members from Southeast and Northeast Asia discussed the political and security situation in the Korean peninsula and the region, the recent positive developments, the way forward, and the role of civil society.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders (DD5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.2 The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors &amp; institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSOs participation in the UN Global Compact Leaders Summit 2018, UN New York, 24 September 2018.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Staff and CSOs from the GPPAC networks, Convened alongside the opening session of the United Nations General Assembly. The Leaders Summit brought together an international community of leaders from business, investor groups, government, the UN, and civil society for a multi-stakeholder stocktaking on progress towards the achievement of SDGs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mindanao PeaceWeavers Convenors Assembly</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Assembly facilitates communication with local civil society organisations especially those engaging the peace process. It offers a space for a wider discussion and engagement on the GRP-NDF peace process with Mindanao CSOs. The assembly agreed on a statement that called for the civil society to continually push conflict actors &#x201C;to affirm the primacy of peace process and for the cessation of hostilities in the communities; resume the formal talks and discuss substantive agenda; recognize meaningful participation of civil society and the conflict affected communities and work towards a just and peaceful political settlement&#x201D;.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Statement on the peace process in the Philippines</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Enabling Collaboration Working Group, which is accompanying the peace process in the Philippines, developed a statement from the WG calling for a renewal of ceasefire between the Philippine Government and the CPP-NPA-NDF as well as the veto/withdrawal of the Anti-Terrorism Act. https://gppac.net/news/gppac-statement-peace-process-philippines</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.2. The networks develop civil society statements, strategies and internal procedures for the protection of human rights defenders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Federation of United Nations Associations and GPPAC agreed to cooperate in the organisation of the SDG 16+ Forum to be held in Sierra Leone in 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Forum will bring together UN, Intergovernmental, Regional Organisations and civil society and having GPPAC members attend and present during the Forum.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthen GPPAC global civil society network on conflict prevention and implementation of accountability measures</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The GPPAC Regional Liaison Officers meeting was hold in The Hague, 20-22 November 2018. The meeting was aimed to develop capacity of 13 (10 women, 3 men) civil society representatives representatives on: monitoring &amp; evaluation, fundraising, networking of civil society organisations, CSO networking of international civil society organisations on lobby &amp; advocacy.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility (DD5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2.2. The networks and members develop internal procedures to strengthen internal (network) and external accountability and take steps to implement them.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC member WANEP invited to join the Ghana CSO Platform on SDGs</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ghana CSO Platform on SDGs has invited WANEP to join them and is in the process of adopting WANEP as one of its members in November-December 2019. In October and December WANEP has been regularly invited to participate in the platform&#x2019;s activities on the SG16+ goals. WANEP joining the CSO platform on SDGs is significant as it shows a formal recognition by the wider civil society community working on SDGs of the relevance of WANEP&#x2019;s experience in conflict prevention and peacebuilding and the added value of having a peacebuilding / prevention organisation cooperating with the government joining such a coalition/platform.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC was part of the organisational committee of the second Multistakeholder Forum on Women, Peace and Security</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The NGO Working Group on Women Peace and Security invited GPPAC to become part of the organisational committee of the second Multistakeholder Forum on Women, Peace and Security that took place on 28 October 2019 in collaboration of the NGO Working Group, Sweden and UN Women. This is significant because it reflects that GPPAC is seen as a relevant actor to shape the Multistakeholder Forum by proposing: agenda, format, participants and facilitators.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multistakeholder Forum</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project proposal to support Wilmington College in the USA, to lead the development of an Ohio Peace and Conflict Studies Network was awarded by GPPAC&#x2019;s Peace Education Working Group</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Ohio Peace and Conflict Studies Network initially comprising 18 colleges and universities has the potential to reach more than 50 institutions in Ohio that offer peace related programs and degrees.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 29 May 2019, during its meeting in Odessa, Ukraine, the GPPAC International Steering Group (ISG) approved GPPAC&#x2019;s Revised Gender Policy, including a new Gender Transformative approach that is seeking to address disbalance of power and harmful gender norms in conflict prevention.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Revised Gender policy strives to build a more inclusive approach of GPPAC to conflict prevention, and offers tools to measure it. It is written to inform next Strategic plan of GPPAC, it builds on the current achievements of the GPPAC network, needs of members and is informed by current developments in the international policies on Women, Peace and Security, Sustainable development and Sustaining Peace. Several ISG members felt that the Gender policy was too progressive but after a heated discussion the Gender policy was adopted in principle. This is an important change because it demonstrates the commitment of the GPPAC network to progressing gender equality in its work on conflict prevention.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3.2 - Civil society credibility: The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">By June 2019, after receiving trainings by a GPPAC member with the Human Security Handbook, the Command and Staff College of the Tanzania military shifted their approach from a purely military approach to handling conflicts and adopted an alternative peace approach by institutionalising peace education in their curriculum. To ensure this, the Command and Staff College has incorporated peace and conflict studies into their training curriculum &#x2013; now referred to as an alternative to war.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Staff College is a training institution of the Tanzanian military. The change in the approach of the Staff College and that of the Command is key in influencing the adoption of similar approaches in the rest of Tanzania and other countries in the GPPAC Eastern and Central African (ECA) region. This is because for the first time, an institution like the military has institutionalised a peaceful and pro-active approach &#x2013; as opposed to a traditional military approach. Since the college has students from other GPPAC-ECA countries like Uganda, Kenya, Burundi, and the DRC, there is great potential of trickling the institutionalisation of peace education within military institutions in other ECA countries.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD2" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN uses GPPAC input from 260 CSOs for UN Guidelines to engage with civil society worldwide</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN Working Group team for the creation of the UN Community Engagement Guideline uses the results of GPPAC&#x2019;s civil society survey. From February to March 2019, GPPAC had disseminated a survey through the GPPAC network and beyond to reach peacebuilding actors around the world. The questions focused on how civil society has interacted with the UN in the past, what could be done to improve it, and on what principles should guide the relationship moving forward. Over 260 civil society organizations participated to provide input into the UN Community Engagement Guidelines that are currently being drafted. Furthermore, the findings from the surveys have been reported back to various UN departments, so the recommendations will go beyond inclusion in the guidelines itself. As a result of the high level of response, this is likely one of the most consultative guidelines processes the UN has ever had.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance increases and diversifies access to political spaces and proactively supports CSOs affected by repression</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank selected GPPAC to present a panel at the Fragility Forum of March 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank has selected GPPAC, for the first time, to present a panel at the fragility Forum. It is a recognition to GPPAC&#x2019;s work regional intergovernmental organisations. The invitation was received on 23rd December 2019, the forum will take place on 2-3March 2020. GPPAC has been engaging with World Bank in a consistent manner in 2018 and 2019, especially after changing its policies towards conflict prevention. During the consultation on the FCV concept note, some of the feedback provided by GPPAC found its way into the consultation summary. The Fragility Forum will have a huge number of influential policy makers from very powerful and recognised institutions. The opportunity to present a panel which would showcase GPPAC&#x2019;s work and the capacity of our network, would be invaluable and help in achieving multiple other outcomes</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In May 2019, GPPAC adopted for the first time a Youth Policy to promote meaningful youth participation in all of its work</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Youth Policy developed by the GPPAC Youth, Peace, and Security Working Group defines objectives and strategies for increasing the effectiveness of the GPPAC network in promoting and achieving meaningful youth participation in conflict prevention and peacebuilding. It will provide a foundation and implementation strategy for mainstreaming youth throughout GPPAC&#x2019;s network structures and work.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Review of Aceh peace agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activity focused on reconstituting GPPAC network in Aceh through its focal point Achehnese Civil Society Task Force, by reviewing the implementation of the Law on Governing of Aceh based on the qualitative survey and focus group discussions with local stakeholders. 40 participants representing formal and non-formal institutions and individuals who had earlier engaged in the peace process and in the legislation of the LoGA bill have once again had a good opportunity to sit together and look back for a reflection on what was lacking in the LoGA implementation after 15 years of the Aceh peace agreement and what need to be done in the future. Around 30 resources persons from various distinguished sectors participated in the range of activities and provided their overviews on the LoGA implementation; 1 policy paper of analysis as review results on implementation of LoGA, as material for a hearing to influence policy makers to be produced by the Aceh Government, the Aceh People&apos;s Representative Council (DPRA) and the Central Government; 1 video documenting the activities, four sectoral FGDs and one dissemination event.; 1 Radio recordings of talk-shows on policy paper analysis; 1 Socialization content on YouTube Channel; 1 Advertorial contents published on local newspaper both online and printed</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2021-02-12" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Coalition of Civil Society Organisations working on the SDGs in Ghana was welcoming to the incorporation of GPPAC&#x2019;s Regional Secretariat for West Africa, West Africa Network for Peacebuilding (WANEP) into their coalition in July 2019.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The civil society organisations (CSO) coalition in Ghana is a key stakeholder in the implementation of SDG 16. The coalition produced a shadow report on SDG 16+ and managed to provide their input to the official Voluntary National Review report. Due to WANEP being part of GPPAC&#x2019;s delegation at the High-Level Political Forum in New York on July 2019, contacts were established between WANEP and the coordinator of the CSO coalition on SDG16, and WANEP is planning to join the coalition. This would lead to advancing the implementation of the SDGs, and related recommendations and joint advocacy efforts. It will also allow WANEP to closely collaborate with a main CSO platform working on SDG16 in Ghana.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">New working groups to strengthen the MENAPAC network</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The following working groups have been created: 1) An EWER working group 2) a working group on gender and arms in MENA to work on small arms and light weapons in the region, 3)the creation of a core group within MENAPPAC network to strengthen the network itself: consisting of youth with a gender balance.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD6" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-03-10" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In September 2019, GPPAC&#x2019;s main advisory body, the Global Steering Group (GSG), reviewed the first draft of our new Strategic Plan.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The input provided by the GSG will be used to formulate the second draft of the new Strategic Plan. Once completed, it will be shared with the GSG to check whether their input is accurately and fully reflected. The new Strategic Plan will then be shared with GPPAC&#x2019;s main decision making body, the International Steering Group (ISG), for their feedback.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC was invited to have one of its members give the keynote speech at the German Peacebuilding Forum organised by Fri-Ent.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The invitation came about as a follow-up from a Civil Society Platform for Peacebuilding and Statebuilding (CSPPS) meeting in April 2018 in which GPPAC actively participated, and in general from GPPAC&#x2019;s work on the Sustaining Peace agenda. Nina Tsikhistavi (Executive Director of the GPPAC member organisation, International Center on Conflict and Negotiation (ICCN) in the Caucasus) presented during the opening panel and was interviewed afterwards.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the second time since the adoption of 2250 in 2015, the United Nations Peacebuilding Commission (UN PBC) approached two young peacebuilders in July 2019 to brief the Commission on the current state of play with the Youth, Peace, and Security (YPS) agenda; among which was GPPAC&#x2019;s YPS Working Group member Khaled Emam.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The invitation to brief the UN PBC is significant to ensure its continued ownership of the YPS agenda. It is also rare for member states of the Commission to directly hear from young peacebuilders. Unfortunately, the briefing was cancelled due to political issues.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The GPPAC Southeast Asia network together with the ASEAN People&#x2019;s Advocacy (SAPA) and the Innovation for Change (I4C) &#x2013; East Asia, and the Asian Forum for Human Rights and Development (FORUM-ASIA), held the &#x201C;1st Asian Peoples&#x2019; Regional Dialogue on Inter-Racial and Religious Solidarity: Addressing Racial and Religious Discrimination/Intolerance and the Rohingya Crisis&#x201D; in April 2018 on board the Peace Boat.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this meeting was to provide a space and secure platform for representatives of communities faced by religious and racial intolerance, in order to document the stories of minority communities; and to develop core solidarity messages for and between these minority ethnic, racial and/or religious groups, including actions for people-to-people solidarity.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders (DD5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.2 The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors &amp; institutions</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society organisations have requested the GPPAC UN Liaison to participate in their events to share CSO perspectives with the UN/New York peacebuilding community.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The outcome was a result of the GPPAC UN Liaison Officer&#x2019;s participation in the UN High-Level Event on Sustaining Peace in April 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including RIGOs, Steering Groups, CS-UN Working Group).</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In May 2019, the ASEAN Institute for Peace and Reconciliation (A-IPR) Secretariat, the members of the A-IPR Advisory Board and the Ministry of the Foreign Affairs of Malaysia have verbally expressed their interest and openness to partner with GPPAC/Civil Society in sustaining a long-term project to build the capacity of ASEAN member-states and civil society actors on conflict transformation and peace mediation through joint-trainings.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The positive response came about after engagements by GPPAC South East Asia (SEA) Regional Secretariat and the Working Group on Regional Capacity Development, and a formal presentation on a proposal for a joint-Regional Training. This is important as it is the first formal presentation of a concrete joint-project with an ASEAN body from GPPAC Southeast Asia, and is the biggest joint-collaboration of members on a long-term and multi-faceted advocacy on a regional level. If and when the A-IPR formally agrees to do the joint training with GPPAC-SEA, this will open multiple doors and opportunities for GPPAC-SEA and its members.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the GPPAC Eastern European network meeting at the end of May 2019, for the first time the network members made a decision to proactively reach out to the youth-led civil society organisations and to take into account an age-balanced approach within the network in the future, particularly in the recruitment process of the new Regional Liaison Officer.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The response of the GPPAC Eastern European network will further strengthen the regional network and the implementation of the GPPAC Youth Policy.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Memorandum of Understanding was signed by GPPAC, Saferworld, Transparency, Accountability, and Participation (TAP) Network, and Civil Society Platform for Peacebuilding and Statebuilding (CSPPS) to establish the first of its kind SDG16+ localisation consortium on September 2019.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The signed Memorandum of Understanding was followed by a concept note for joint fundraising and establishment of the first of its kind SDG 16+ localisation consortium. The Memorandum of Understanding is a significant step towards a broader movement to achieve more sustained local progress towards peaceful, just and inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative model for social research in restrictive societies developed and tested in Belarus</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The study of local identities and their dependence on the nature and availability of information flows in eastern Belarus. On December 27, 2018 the report of the study was presented and discussed with civil society activists and journalists in the town of Orsha. This demonstrated a new model for conducting research in highly restrictive circumstances, developed by a diverse team of individuals from different backgrounds who have never cooperated before. This model is needed to address state control on any potentially sensitive research taking place in Belarus.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions (DD4)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.2. The networks with their members engage in action research, document case studies and produce joint position papers and policy briefs with particular attention to inclusivity on relevant actors &amp; institutions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">On 29 May 2019, the GPPAC International Steering Group agreed for the first time on a selection process,to ensure that each Regional Steering Group will initiate an open and democratic process for selecting regional secretariats and representatives.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There was previously no specification as to how regional representatives and regional secretariats are selected. The lack of a selection process lead to issues including: some Regional Representatives have remained the same ever since 2003; some regions appear not to have any kind of election process; and only a few regions holding open elections for the position of regional representative and/or regional secretariat. This agreement by the members of the International Steering Group allows the GPPAC Global Secretariat to ask the Regional Steering Groups to define their process (rather than the Regional Secretariat deciding how to do it on its own), and it will allow the Global Secretariat to check whether the process is followed.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.2. Civil society credibility</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance contributes to enhanced civil society credibility by strengthening its networks&apos; and members&apos; accountability, complementarities and internal procedures and practices</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD5" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-06-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)-Department of Political Affairs (DPA) Joint Programme on Peace and Development Advisors (PDAs) asked the Prevention Platform (co-led by GPPAC&#x2019;s UN Liaison Office) to arrange a meeting with civil society organisations to feed into the strategic review of PDAs.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This outcome was a result of continuous bilateral meetings between the Prevention Platform (led by GPPAC and the Quaker United Nations Office (QUNO)) and UN offices. The feedback from civil society made it into the final report on PDAs as part of the five-year strategic plan.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)-Department of Political Affairs (DPA) Joint Programme on Peace and Development Advisors (PDAs) will partner with the Prevention Platform (co-led by GPPAC&#x2019;s UN Liaison Office) on a project looking at how PDAs and civil society engage in country settings.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This outcome was a result of the successful input given by the Prevention Platform (led by GPPAC and the Quaker United Nations Office (QUNO)) to the strategic planning of the PDAs. The project will begin in the third quarter of 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including RIGOs, Steering Groups, CS-UN Working Group)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC established links with African Union (AU) representatives, and helped linking different networks of women mediators.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This output resulted from GPPAC Global Secretariat and GPPAC West Africa representatives presenting GPPAC&#x2019;s work to a women&#x2019;s mediator network linked to the African Union during a Clingendael training on negotiation and mediation on 19 April 2018. This established links with AU representatives and a network of women mediators in the Caucasus.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders (DD5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.3. The networks convene and participate in inclusive civil society strategy meetings, platforms and coalitions targeting key institutions (including working groups, coalitions, strategy documents)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The role of Regional International Organisations in conflict prevention</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three GPPAC regions (Latin America &amp; the Caribbean, Pacific and South Africa) have conducted a research on &#x201C;How could CSO-RIGO-UN partnerships support conflict prevention and sustaining peace work at the regional level?&#x201D;</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.4. The network members collaborate in engaging relevant governments, RIGO, IGOs in policy events, delegations and initiatives</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Translation of GPPAC&#x2019;s Human Security Handbook</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Translations of specific chapters of the Human Security Handbook into Russian, Georgian, Serbian and Arabic are complete. Translations enables wider use and dissemination of trainings by civil society worldwide through GPPAC&#x2019;s regional networks. This was supported and organised through the GPPAC Improving Practice Working Group in December 2018.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutions (DD5)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1.1. The networks and member organisations develop resources and expertise on relevant institutional stakeholders through the network (incl. guidelines/manuals, information sheets, briefings, liaisons/resource persons..)</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Major Group for Children and Youth (UN MGCY), the official UN youth participation channel, accepted GPPAC Youth, Peace and Security core group member, Khaled Emam, as a member on 14 August 2019. He is now a global focal point for Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) 16 at UNMGCY.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN MGCY is a formal engagement platform for young people in UN processes. They are often approached to gather young people&#x2019;s input, nominations for direct youth representation in policy processes, and to coordinate a youth civil society voice in UN agendas. Through his membership of MGCY as a focal point for SDG16, Khaled can make more sustainable and impactful contributions to global conversations on YPS and SDG16.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.1. Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Alliance enhances and mobilises civil society capacities to access and strategically engage relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD4" indicator-uri="http://helpdesk-opendata-minbuza.nl/dd-indicators/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-07-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two UN offices invited the UN-CSO Prevention Platform (co-facilitated by GPPAC) to conduct two trainings on civil society engagement in peacebuilding at UN level</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Offices (UN Department of Political Affairs (DPA) and the DPA-UN Development Programme (UNDP)) asked the Prevention Platform to provide training on civil society engagement. This led to GPPAC co-facilitating two trainings in February and March 2018 in New York. GPPAC and Quaker United Nations Office (QUNO) are co-facilitators of the Prevention Platform between UN and civil society organisations (CSOs) in New York.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including CS-UN Working Group)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Donors and member states such as the UK Department for International Development DFID and Canada are considering further supporting the local implementation of SDG 16+ with a peace focus. They indicated this during the High Level Political Forum on Sustainable Development (HLPF) in New York in July 2019 as a result of the continued, joint advocacy by a number of organisations involved in the Voices campaign, including during the Rome conference (May) and HLPF (July).</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Until now, SDG 16+ has either been supported at overall policy/political levels with a top-down approach, mostly on issues of access to justice or incidentally at member state levels for countries such as Sierra Leone. The indication that a number of donors, such as Canada, DFID or South Korea are considering supporting the localised implementation of SDG 16+ peacebuilding focused implementation is significant as it indicates a first step towards a) acknowledging both the importance of an focus on peaceful societies and b) the need to do this through the localisation of this agenda. GPPAC was an active member of the Voices Campaign, participated in the Rome conference on SDG 16+ preparing the main official messages on SDG 16 for the High Level Political Forum and co-drafted civil society demands formulated in Rome, which included a call for increased political and financial support for the peace agenda. GPPAC also brought 4 members and 3 GPPAC staff to New York for the HLPF and advocated for increased support with the campaign partners and on its own towards Canada and other member states. The SDG16+ event held on 11 July in New York at the International Peace Institute (IPI) offices where GPPAC member Women in Alternative Action (WAA) Cameroon participated was recognised as particularly successful in carrying over the message in a politically relevant and timely manner.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome: 3.4.1. Political Space</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Federation of UN Associations (WFUNA) provides space for local CSO in their yearly forum</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFUNA approached GPPAC to have a GPPAC member (Visaka Dharmadasa) as key-note speaker during their panel on reconciliation, agreed to support her attendance and for GPPAC to host a break-out session focusing on the inclusive localisation of SDG 16+. This is significant as it shows a change in behaviour of WFUNA. WFUNA now approaches GPPAC pro-actively to ensure participation by members and for GPPAC to co-shape the agenda.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intergovernmental and state actors systematically include civil society and adopt inclusive, transparent and accountable working methods</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC Strategic Input into the informal and formal stages of the 2020 Peacebuilding Architecture Review and the Secretary-General&apos;s Report on Peacebuilding and Sustaining Peace</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">We have been able to strengthen civil society engagement with UN actors and member states at all levels by providing space for local partners not only to directly engage with UN actors but also capitalize on opportunities to strengthen these connections moving forward. 

We have been able to ensure that civil society perspectives are reflected in the global policy on peacebuilding and sustaining peace by providing numerous inputs into the 2020 Peacebuilding Architecture Review and creating a policy space to further advance the recommendations.

We were able to strengthen the recognition of GPPAC expertise by the UN actors at all levels. Increased engagement of GPPAC in the 2020 Review process has led to invitation to participate as a speaker in the 2020 Review consultation organized by the Alliance for Peacebuilding, as a facilitator in the online consultation organized by Peace Direct, as a PBC eexpert for the PBC&apos;s internal assessment of thee implmentaiton of the Gender Strategy; as a speaker at High Level Event on COVID-19 and the role of Mental Health and Psychosocial Support in building resilience and sustaining social cohesion and peace organized by the Dutch MFA, as the only civil society speaker for the Group of Friends meeting on peacebuilding and Sustaining Peace; as a moderator in the UNDP e-consultation on Crisis, Conflict and Climate: From Immediate Humanitarian Response to Longer-Term Peace and Development Solutions. 

We were able to strengthen peacebuilding movement at the civil society level by re-vitalizing the work of the New York Peacebuilding Group and convening the 2020 Review civil society working group that mobilizes a learning space for civil society organizations inside and outside of New York to bring forces together to ensure appropriate joint input from civil society into the 2020 Review.

We were able to build the capacity of GPPAC members to engage in international advocacy by facilitating preparatory conversations with relevant colleagues ahead of the each global and regional meeting and conducted additional trainings in strategy setting in the MENA region.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4. Political space</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.4.2. Intergovernmental and state actors demonstrate a progression towards regular, systematic and inclusive involvement of civil society in their institutional frameworks.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="DD3" indicator-uri="http://tiny.cc/DDhelpdesk" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In May, GPPAC was co-leading author of the Rome Civil Society Declaration on SDG16+ together with TAP Network, Namati and Civil Society Platform for Peacebuilding (CSPPS).</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">With SDG16 being reviewed for the first time at the High-level Political Forum (HLPF) and the SDGs being reviewed for the first time at the SDGs Summit during the opening of the 74th United Nations General Assembly, 2019 marks an unprecedented opportunity to scale up our collective efforts towards SDG16+ implementation. To contribute to this, civil society organizations (CSOs) from around the world met in Rome, Italy on 26 May 2019 in the context of the SDG16 Conference (Rome Conference) after a series of in-depth consultations, convened by UNDESA, IDLO, and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Italy in preparation for the 2019 HLPF. 3 GPPAC members and 1 GPPAC staff actively participated in Rome from 26 until 29 of May. The resulting Civil Society outcome document &#x2013; Amplified Commitment and Partnerships for Accelerated Action: The Rome Civil Society Declaration on SDG16+ (Rome Declaration), endorsed by more than 130 civil society organizations, highlights key civil society priority areas, recommendations, and an urgent call-to-action to achieve the real transformative potential of SDG16+. GPPAC was co-leading writer of the Rome Civil Society Declaration on SDG16+. This advocacy initiative enabled us to further push for civil society role through a collective action in partnership with TAP Network, CSPPS, Namati and with other seven organisations involved in the Voice campaign &#x201C;Voices for SDG 16+: Stories of Global Action&#x201D;. This resulted in delivering the Civil Society Statement on Amplified Commitments and Partnerships for Accelerated Action: Rome Civil Society Declaration on SDG16+ at the UN High Level Political Forum 2019. GPPAC co-lead the writing of the statement. Civil Society called member states to commit to accelerate progress on SDG16+.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3.1.2</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In April 2019 a relationship and collaboration was established between GPPAC member Women in Alternative Action (WAA) Cameroon and the Cameroonian Government in the Voluntary National Review (VNR) of SDG implementation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women in Alternative Action (WAA) Cameroon did not have any engagements with its Government before the country research on SDG 16+ progress. In January 2019 GPPAC facilitated interactions between WAA Cameroon and relevant UNDP individuals in country. This led to further engagements with the UNDP lead for the VNR, as well as the SDG coordinator inside government, and a range of other stakeholders. WAA Cameroon for provided CSO inputs and key recommendations, based on its own national review, to the key VNR messages that government submitted to the UN. GPPAC supported writing and finalizing these key recommendations. After the civil society validation workshop in Cameroon held on 15 of May, which was attended by the government coordinator for SDGs, WAA Cameroon was invited for the first time to participate in the VNR technical committee set up by the government, and equally participated in the validation of the government VNR report.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 3.1 - Capacities for access to relevant institutional stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GPPAC UN Liaison attended the UN High-Level Event on Sustaining Peace in April 2018, and was asked to serve as a panellist at the event, &#x201C;Peacebuilding and Sustaining Peace: A debrief and discussion on next steps for civil society&#x201D;.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3. Alternative entry points (DD3)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3.4. The networks initiate and participate in civil society-governmental/intergovernmental working groups and exchange platforms (including RIGOs, Steering Groups, CS-UN Working Group)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-06-30"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
