<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012415-01-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Contributo all&#x2019;appello speciale 2021 del Comitato Internazionale della Croce Rossa &#x2013; CICR &#x2013; per lo Sminamento e la Disabilit&#xE0; in Mali</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il contributo della Cooperazione Italiana sostiene le attivit&#xE0; del Comitato Internazionale della Croce Rossa (CICR) in Mali, volte a favorire l&#x2019;accesso a servizi di riabilitazione fisica di qualit&#xE0; per le persone affette da disabilit&#xE0;, incluse quelle derivanti dai conflitti in atto nel Paese. Le attivit&#xE0; si concentreranno nella capitale Bamako e nelle regioni di Gao, Timbuktu, Mopti. In particolare, l&#x2019;iniziativa contribuir&#xE0; a rafforzare il settore della riabilitazione fisica, migliorando la qualit&#xE0; dei servizi offerti nei centri di riabilitazione fisica gestiti o supportati dal CICR, e la loro accessibilit&#xE0; e sostenibilit&#xE0;. Tali obiettivi saranno perseguiti i) fornendo ai 5 (cinque) centri di riabilitazione individuati le componenti prostetiche ed ortesiche necessarie, facilitando la gestione quotidiana dei servizi, oltre che supportando i pazienti provenienti dalle regioni pi&#xF9; remote per facilitare l&#x2019;accesso; ii) favorendo le iniziative a livello comunitario atte a promuovere i diritti e l&#x2019;inclusione delle persone affette da disabilit&#xE0;; iii) supportando il Ministero della Salute e dello Sviluppo Sociale nell&#x2019;espandere la formazione del personale qualificato all&#x2019;erogazione di tali servizi e nel migliorare la raccolta e l&#x2019;utilizzo dei dati onde consentire un graduale passaggio della gestione delle strutture al personale locale.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Italian Cooperation&#x2019;s financial contribution will support the activities implemented by the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) in Mali with the aim of improving the access to good-quality physical rehabilitation services to persons with disabilities, including those whose disabilities are conflict-related. The activities will target the capital city, Bamako, and the areas of Gao, Timbuktu, Mopti. Specifically, the initiative will contribute to strengthen the physical rehabilitation sector improving the quality of the services offered by the 5 (five) physical rehabilitation centres run or supported by the ICRC, their accessibility and sustainability. These objectives will be achieved i) providing the centres with the needed components for prostheses and orthoses, facilitating the daily management of the services, and supporting the access of patients from remote areas; ii) facilitating initiatives at community level promoting the rights and social inclusion of disabled people; iii) supporting health and social development ministry in expanding the pool of qualified personnel and in collecting and managing data helping a gradual handing over of the management of facilities to local staff</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21016" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21016" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="21016" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICRC - INTERNATIONAL COMMITTEE OF THE RED CROSS ALT</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012415/01/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-11-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ML" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.8" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve universal health coverage, including financial risk protection, access to quality essential health-care services and access to safe, effective, quality and affordable essential medicines and vaccines for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce inequality within and among countries</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B032" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-26">1000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICRC - INTERNATIONAL COMMITTEE OF THE RED CROSS ALT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-12-07">1000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2021</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ICRC - INTERNATIONAL COMMITTEE OF THE RED CROSS ALT</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
