<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-190378</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GGGI - Global Green Growth- development of adaptation and reduction strategies in developing countries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Denmark joined GGGI in 2011, and provided DKK 90 mill. during the 2011-2013 period. In 2014, Denmark renewed its engagement with GGGI and provided a contribution of DKK 90 mill. for the 2014-2016 period. Denmark&apos;s financial support is provided as a core contribution. The contribution is made available to help GGGI achieve its overall mandate and goals, rather than being available for specific elements of GGGI&apos;s work program.
GGGI&apos;s vision is that the world makes a paradigm shift to &apos;green growth&apos;, a model of economic growth that simultaneously achieves poverty reduction, job creation, social inclusion as well as environmental sustainability and resource security. GGGI&apos;s mission is to advance the practice and theory of green growth by helping to develop, implement and deepen understanding of green growth strategies. GGGI&apos;s vision and mission correspond well with the Denmark&apos;s strategic green growth priority. 
In 2014, GGGI adopted a strategic plan for 2015-2020, which operates with three main objectives: 
- strengthening national, sub-national, and local green growth plans;
- promoting green investment flows;
- knowledge sharing between countries on green growth.
In relation to developing and implementing GGGI&apos;s strategic plan, Denmark has set the following priorities: 1) Development of a focused and realistic strategic plan with a concrete results framework; 2) Poverty orientation; 3) Inclusiveness; 4) Consolidation of GGGI&apos;s activities; 5) Integration of GGGI&apos;s three work streams; 6) An organisational structure that is fit for purpose; 7) Implementation of financial and administrative policies, rules and procedures of international standards; 8) Influence at the global level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.G.13-2.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-190378-24682" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
