<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-210595</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Deliver 2013-2015 + 2014-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women Deliver (WD) is an international non-governmental organisation launched at a conference in London 2007. The organisation works on a global scale to gather political will and economic investments towards the realisation of MDG5 to reduce mortality among pregnant women and women giving birth as well as ensuring universal access to reproductive health. The base of the organisation is the commitments, partnerships and networks mobilised at the WD-conferences held in 2007, 2010 and 2013, and the focus is on fighting the numerous pregnancy-related deaths that each year contributes to around 287,000 deaths among women and girls. The organisation advocates that maternal health is both a human right and a prerequisite for sustainable development.
Denmark has supported WD since its establishment in 2007. The commitment for 2014-19 will, inter alia, contribute to the strategic preparations of the upcoming WD conference in Copenhagen in May 2016. The conference will revolve around the follow-up to the Post-2015 negotiations and focus on ways to operationalise the aims of the new development agenda in relation to possible SRHR commitments. The conference is expected to gather governments, UN organisations, civil society organisations and technical experts. 

WD is one of the leading advocacy organisations working on promoting the human rights of women and girls on a global scale with high impact. The organisation works actively to promote the ICPD commitments as well as the Danish priority of including SRHR in the Post-2015 development framework. 

Indicators include: 1) Gathering key actors in the field of SRHR for global conferences in 2016 and 2019; 2) Establishing a forum for strategic networks, including youth, for the promotion on SRHR; 3) Succesful advocacy on post-2015 agenda; 4) Engagement at the country level in select countries to promote SRHR, 5) Engagement of the private sector in the SRHR agenda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.N.151.FCI.1/2014-16045">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-210595-26124" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-210595-29409" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-210595-33352" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
