<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-187827</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Programme for Creative Industries in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Regional Programme for Creative Industries in Africa (2011-2013) aims to contribute to the development of the creative industries in Africa for economic growth and employment for youth by strengthening regional networks between -and improving capacity of- cultural entrepreneurs. It consists of the following 2 components.

1) African Music Festivals Network: The objective is to enhance collaborations between African music festivals, focusing on the mutual exchange of knowledge, know-how and artistic inspiration, and including support to artistic, technical, organisational, promotional and business activities of the festivals. 

During phase 1, the network of 17 African Music Festivals was established. Three open calls for inter-festival collaborative projects were conducted during phase 1 and 2 resulting in 15 approved projects focusing on artistic collaboration, technical capacity building, marketing and organisational and business development.

2) Contemporary Design Network in Africa: The objective is to contribute to the development of one of the fastest growing industry sectors in the global economy, and, through this contribution, enable the designers in Africa to make successful business out of good design and create room for commercialisation. 

The first phase of the programme was used for a participatory formulation of the Design Network, in order to determine the best way forward. Three successful workshops have been carried out in Burkina Faso, Swaziland and Southern Africa, in which designers discussed how to convert good design into good business.

The second phase of the program continues to develop the designers&apos; competencies through workshops and mutual exchange.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.Afrika.34-9.">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="16061" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Culture and recreation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-187827-24380" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-187827-25962" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
