<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-212023</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">St&#xF8;tte til civilsamfundsbaserede HIV/AIDS-indsatser for m&#xE6;nd som har sex med m&#xE6;nd i Afrika</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The International HIV/AIDS Alliance is a global alliance of nationally-based, independent civil society organisations with the objective of securing the human rights of all people affected by HIV/AIDS in low and middle income countries, with a particular emphasis on vulnerable and marginalised population groups. It is particularly concerned with the access to health services of groups exposed to stigmatisation and discrimination, such as commercial sex workers, men having sex with men etc. 

The Alliance was set up in 1993 to support communities in developing countries to play an active role in the global response to AIDS. It works through a network of over 35 so called linking organisations in the South. The overall objective of the organisation is to stop the spread of HIV and to end AIDS. It is pursued through actions to promote health and human rights via direct engagement with and through local communities.

Denmark has supported the Alliance since 1999. Denmark supports the International HIV/AIDS Alliance&apos;s work to increase access to HIV and reproductive health and rights information and services for men who have sex with men. The intervention focuses on four African countries: Uganda, Kenya, Tanzania and Zimbabwe and supports national civil society engagement and strengthening. Local partners and organisations are supported to carry out their work. The activities include supporting and strengthening civil society capacity to advocate the human rights of marginalized groups, raising awareness, creating the links between the communities and health services, training health care staff on meeting all patients without stigma and discrimination etc.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="104.C.122.1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-212023-26205" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
