<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-1-214729</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NATO-Russia cooperation, crime and counternarcotics in Central Asia, Afghanistan and Pakistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The regional program for peace and stability in the Afghanistan-Pakistan region has an emphasis on prevention and long-term stabilization. The goal is to build capacity in Afghanistan primarily in order to handle their own security and to support stabilization efforts in Pakistan and the region, and to support the regional reconciliation and dialogue. One of the three main components of the peace and stability framework is focused on capacity building for police, border security, law enforcement and counter-narcotics. 

The NATO-Russia Council (NRC) trust fund for the fight against drugs is based on the nations&apos; shared interest in fighting the threat of drug trafficking originating from Afghanistan. The Trust Fund was launched in 2006 and currently has 21 NRC participant-nations as well as Finland and Ukraine. UNODC is the implementing agency. DK has previously supported the Trust Fund with DKK 650,000 for the activities in 2011.

The Trust Fund&apos;s activities are targeted Afghanistan and transit countries in Central Asia and Pakistan, aiming to build local capacity to combat drugs through training of personnel from local law enforcement authorities. The training takes place partly in the region with the use of mobile training units staffed by teachers from NRC countries and the Danish contribution to the Trust Fund. It is stressed however that the Danish contribution will only be applied to the DAC activities of the project. At the end of 2013 it was decided to continue the support to the NRC in 2014 and 2015.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="DK-1" type="XM-DAC-3-1">
   <owner-org ref="46.H.1-6-0-2-19">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="DK-1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">XM-DAC-3-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="16063" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narcotics control</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="DK-1-214729-27003" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
