<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-206372</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NRREP: National Rural and Renewable Energy Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The National Rural and Renewable Energy Programme (NRREP) will support renewable energy in rural areas through renewable energy technologies such as, solar, micro hydro, biogas and improved cooking stoves. The objective is to reach 1.5 mio households with special focus gender equality and social inclusion.

NRREP has a clear emphasis on effectively reaching out to the more remote and poorest part of the country, it will apply demand led approaches actively involving beneficiaries in decision making, and support use of energy for productive purposes leading to income and employment increase in rural areas. 

Structure: the programme has two national partners and consists of three components. The Alternative Energy Promotion Centre (AEPC) is the executing agency for two of the components: Technical Suppoort Component and the Business Developmnt for Renewable Energy and Productive Energy Use Component. Central Renewable Energy Fund (CREF) is the other national partner and the establishment of the Fund is an independent component. NRREP is a single programme modality, which means that no other programmes within renewable energy in Nepal are to be funded outside NRREP to avoid duplication and lack of coordination.

The immediate objective of the Central Renewable Energy Fund Component is to institute the CREF as the core financial institution responsible for the effective delivery of subsidies and credit support to the renewable energy sector.

The immediate objective of the Technical Support Component is to accelerate renewable energy service delivery with better quality, comprising various technologies, to remote rural households, enterprises and communities, to benefit men and women from all social groups, leading to more equitable economic growth.

The immediate objective of the Business Development for Renewable Energy and Productive Energy Use Component is to contribute to an increase in income and employment generation potential for MSMEs in rural area.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.Nepal.802-300.KTM.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012001557</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-206372</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>Unk</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="231" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy Policy</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-206372-26284" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-206372-26303" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-206372-26304" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-206372-26305" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-206372-26306" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-206372-26307" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
