<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-209787</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Envelope 2012: South Africa - low carbon transition in the energy efficiency sector</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The energy sector program in South Africa aims to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by increasing the share of renewable energy (primarily wind) in the national energy mix. The focus is on the power sector, which accounts for 50% of South Africa&apos;s total greenhouse gas emissions. A small part of the program will focus on energy efficiency. South Africa is focused on contributing to reduce global warming, therefore the country is faced with significant investments in renewable energy. This places great demands on the capabilities in areas such as regulation and operation of the power system. Therefore, South Africa demands the skills and experience that Denmark has achieved through many years of commitment to renewable energy and energy efficiency.
The program consists of three components, which are developed based on consultation with key South African institutions and other donors. The activities under component one and three form an overall list, which will have to be conceptulised during the inception phase - including taking into account the activities of other donors:

1) Technical assistance to the South African Department of Energy Department of Energy (DoE )

2) further development of the South African wind atlas (mapping of wind resources in South Africa)

3 ) Technical assistance to the South African transmission system operator (TSO) and the state-owned Eskom (Electricity Supply Commission of South Africa ) for integration of renewable energy

The components will collectively and individually promote capacity building, development of renewable energy and emissions reduction in South Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.G.15-19.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012001288</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-209787</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-209787-26073" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
