<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-214052</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children - Upper Nile and Unity, South Sudan 2013</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The program was part of the larger integrated EiE, CPiE, WASH, multi-donor program that sought collectivelyto strengthen education and child resilience capacities among the refugees and host community in Maban County. This intervention increased access to inclusive, quality education in a protective learning environment for children and young people in Doro camp, Upper Nile, as well as strengthened community-based approaches and structures to prevent and respond to child abuse, exploitation, violence and neglect, increasing access to quality, appropriate and timely child protection and psychosocial services for vulnerable refugee and host community. 
The program supported the enrolment of 10297 primary school children and 3044 ALP learners across 5 primary schools. The activities supporting this include: constructing 42 classrooms (29 UNHCR, 13 DANIDA), rehabilitating 31 temporary learning spaces, training 172 teachers, providing urgent scholastic materials to 9918 children, school uniforms to 4000 children and raised awareness on protection of children to more than 11000 children and 280 community leaders. 
14 Child-Friendly Spaces were rehabilitated and supported, and over 4700 children attended. Fourteen Community Based Child Protection Network were established and members trained and supported to mobilize refugees and local authorities around children&#xBF;s protection and well-being. Over 264 vulnerable children (136 girls, 128 boys) received clothes, shelter as well as referral support for health care and nutrition provided by other actors. The program also established a Family Tracing and Reunification data base, trained 3 partners staff and 2 SCI case workers on FTR and has continued to utilize the standardized FTR tools to facilitate tracing and reunification of 768 Unaccompanied and Separated Children (289 girls, 479 boys). 
Despite a delayed project start date of 1 February due to final overall project approval, the expected results have been achieved</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012001474</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">46.H.7-4-149.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-214052</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="720" percentage="100" vocabulary="2" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-214052-26424" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
