<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-3-1-212431</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Horn of Africa - comp. 2: FAO and NGO consortium: support to resilience in Somalia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The support in sub-component 2.1 is to the FAO Somalia resilience programme, which is implemented as part of a joint UN resilience strategy in Somalia. FAO is the key partner in Somalia when it comes to supporting the food production aspects of food security and resilience. The programme is a longer-term agricultural development programme that builds strongly on and continues the many years of on-going short-term work on the part of FAO in Somalia. It is Somalia-wide but with the major part of the activities in south-central Somalia. The activities include: promoting household livelihood opportunities and diversifying within the food productive sectors; intensifying and extensifying food production at household level; support for the food production capacities of returnees; improved access to markets and market information and addressing value chains; basic technical services to build capacities in agricultural production/income-generation. 

The support in sub-component 2.2 is to the resilience programme of the SomReP NGO consortium. The programme is a commitment by several key NGOs to work together on building longer-term resilience in relation to the important food productive sectors. The NGOs involved have a range of different specific qualifications in relation to agricultural and pastoral production, and they complement the work being undertaken by FAO, being able to provide more direct support in areas where the UN organisations are less strongly represented. The SomReP programme is Somalia-wide with a focus on activities in the south-central parts of the country. Activities include: improving household capacities to undertake livelihood activities in relation to food productive sectors; protecting household assets during stress; enhancing risk and management capabilities at household and community level; securing effective management of vital natural resources; and strengthening local-level institutions for resilience building.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-3-1" role="1" type="10" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">104.C.175-2.</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A2">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2012001418</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="B1">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Denmark" type="A3">
   <owner-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DK-1-212431</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NA</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unk</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-212431-26228" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-212431-27440" type="2"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-3-1-212431-27441" type="2"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
