<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-NG.2019.13719</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">#CuerpoPol&#xED;tico - Conformaciones Perform&#xE1;ticas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by Venta Rota</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The current political and social context of Paraguay is difficult for minorities and particularly for LGBT+ people, as the country lacks a &#x201C;non-discrimination law&#x201D;. The country has witnessed a violent return to openly oppressive practices, both by the authorities and by conservative groups, as testified by the indictment last year of Bruno Comas, the main applicant for this project, as a direct result of his commitment to vocalizing the discrimination faced by LGBT+ people in Paraguay through his artistic work. The criminalization of Bruno&#x2019;s performance by the local authorities received significant attention in the local and international media, resulting also in an urgent appeal issued by Amnesty International.

Furthermore, as mentioned by the applicant and confirmed by independent advisors, there is little to no investment by the government in education focusing on the arts. As a result, young people in Paraguay are scarcely aware of the specificity of the Performing Arts as a discipline and, more in general, on the potential of the arts to produce political and social change.

The applicant&#x2019;s previous work and proposed project both contribute to addressing these two issues, by trying to bring discrimination towards minorities at the centre of the debate, and by creating a safe space where young artists, activists, and other participants can educate themselves on their political agency.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vena Rota is a platform for research and production focusing on the Performing Arts in Asunc&#xED;on, Py. As part of the project #EMERGER, Vena Rota will organize non-formal trainings, workshops, and public performances. The program will enable participants to collectively learn, reflect, and create around the concepts of corporeity and artistic performance as agents of social and political change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">_++Outputs++_: 1 training for the team of Vena Rota held by three of the guest trainers of the program; 6 theoretical/practical meetings for 20 participants enrolled in the program, aimed at reflecting on the body as a tool for the collective agency of artists and activists; 5 workshops of 3 days each, open to the public, held by Paraguayan and international guest trainers (30 participants for each workshop); 1 mid-project exhibition (10 artists, 50 to 80 visitors expected); 1 public performance (10 artists, expected audience of 80 to 120 people); 1 book (printed in 500 copies and distributed especially to educational institutions) and 6 videos of 8&#x2019; posted on Youtube.  

_++Outcomes++_: participants in the training program are more self-conscious and able to manage their own path as artists/activists; people, especially young people, have a safe space to reflect collectively on the political agency of their bodies and of their artistic work; the local artistic scene is enriched by the performances created as part of the training program. 

_++Impact++_: Paraguayan society is more just, open to diversity, and respectful of the rights of all people, including minorities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">artists, activists</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-NG.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8322" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-20" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>ngproposals@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603, 1017 CE Amsterdam</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-25.2637399 -57.575926</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-20"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-02-27"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-20">18814</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-07">18841</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988.NG.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8322/update/29030/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#CuerpoPolitico: Mostly on track and some changes</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8322/update/29031/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-related delay</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8322/update/29343/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Written and audiovisual materials launched online</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8322/Project_8322_current_image_2020-01-20_12.43.53.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-NG.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-06-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-06-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
