<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13860</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Documentary for Social Change</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Studies have suggested that the Tigray region of Ethiopia is particularly vulnerable to the adverse effects of climate change. In recent years, however, the region has boasted several exemplary land rehabilitation projects that have made significant progress in restoring degraded lands and improving food and water security. Despite this, the national media agenda does not consider the issue of the environment as a priority - a reason for this is in part due to a greater focus being placed on other socio-political issues but also due to a general lack of thorough environmental understanding among journalists in the region. This project aims to challenge that by ensuring stories, knowledge and skills from these indigenous conservation projects are shared and awareness is amplified by creating a pool of journalists, environmentalists, and students that are equipped to tell stories that can positively impact local communities through documentaries, blogs, and online campaigns.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Three journalists and professors from the Mekelle University hope to share the stories and knowledge gained from successful environmental conservation carried out by local farmers and environmentalists in the Tigray region. By training a team of journalists and journalism students to produce documentaries and short videos that engage with these case studies, the project looks to ensure the sustainability of their practices and educate their wider communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">_++Outputs++_

3 training sessions on environmental documentary production and environmental discourses. Reach: 10 professional journalists and 15 student journalists (of whom 10 will be females)

Four 25 minute documentary films and five short videos produced by the project coordinators and trainees which show exemplary accomplishments of local environmentalists.

Reach: 1000+ community members of four provinces in Tigray through screenings

Blog dedicated to environmental issues that will publish one article a week over the course of the year from regular contributions from writers, student-journalists, and professional journalists.

Bi-monthly commentaries on environment-related issues written by the project coordinators for local mainstream media over the course of the year.

_++Outcomes++_

Increased environmental awareness amongst local communities, including the efficiency of local knowledge and skills for environmental conservation.

Increased communication regarding environmental topics on online media platforms and both the blog and social channels.

_Impact _

In the long term this project hopes to foster new generation of journalists who are educated and prepared to take on environmental issues in their journalistic practice, making it a part of the dominant Ethiopian media discourse and ensuring local communities&#x2019; work is recognised and inspires others.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by Kibrom Berhane, Furtuna Kahsay &amp; Tesfagebriel Tekola</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">student and professional journalists, rural communities in the Tigray region</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8419" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.4935504 39.465738</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">15000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">15000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8419/Project_8419_current_image_2020-01-22_09.08.12.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x200B;</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
