<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-CER1.2019.13861</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safeguarding the collection of the Manuscript Library of the Sawani community</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by Bunkassa Beyrey Association</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities:

&#x2022; Risk and Damage Assessment of the Manuscripts.

&#x2022; Identifying and understanding the situation of the collection and other manuscripts in their direct context to ensure the effectiveness and immediate implementation of the manuscript rescue project.

&#x2022; Organization of the collection to prepare for an emergency situation and evacuation, including inventorying, cataloguing, cleaning, packaging, and proper storage. Also, improving the security situation of the library to protect it in the event of an attack.

&#x2022; Prospecting of the field to ensure long-term preservation of the manuscripts: engaging with the local community to raise awareness on the importance of the preservation of the manuscripts and to teach them about manuscript preservation, identifying the factors important for long-term preservation, and the establishment of a monitoring and evaluation committee for the project.

&#x2022; Training of 30 local experts to prepare for emergency situations and the scenario of the emergency evacuation.

&#x2022; Local network and capacity building workshop &#x2013; training of 30 manuscript owners and caretakers of the library on the preservation of their manuscripts, and to prepare for the potential evacuation.

&#x2022; Development of the Emergency Plan &#x2013; identification of methodology, planning and task division in case of emergency. Purchase of material.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Association Bunkassa Beyrey (pour la sauvegarde et la valorisation du patrimoine culturel) will safeguard the collection of the Manuscript Library of the Sawani community. The Sawani village is located in the Sinder community in the Tillab&#xE9;ri region of Niger (50km from the border with Mali) and its inhabitants came from Mali in 1810 as refugees. To the community, this is their first and most important library, consisting mostly of original manuscripts written by the local ulema. The manuscripts concern mostly their views on religion, social life and organization of the community and have great historic importance to the local community. The library is owned by the family of Iman Elhadji Oumarou Issifi de Sawani. It is now under threat of jihadists crossing the border from Mali and destroying villages and cultural heritage. The horrible crimes of the jihadists cause villagers to flee, leaving the manuscripts behind. The manuscripts are in such instances under great threat of destruction. Occasionally, there is other, inter-communal violence (mostly between Touaregs and other groups). Therefore, the Assocation aims to train the keepers of the library; purchase materials for quick evacuation; secure the premises; and set up an emergency plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-CER1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8791" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>14.6489525 2.1450245</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-15"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-15">22756</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-13">22756</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-CER1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8791/Project_8791_current_image_2020-12-08_12.27.32.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-CER1.2019" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-15"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x200B;</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2020"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-15"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">One: The collection of the Manuscript Library of the Sawani community.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
