<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-CER.Leadership</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CER Leadership Course 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">After the leadership module participants will:

&#xB7; be familiar with the basic principles of team building and leadership

&#xB7; be familiar with the basic principles of project planning and project management

&#xB7; be familiar with basic principle train-the trainer principles

&#xB7; have a better overview of the funding landscape and language used in applications

&#xB7; be able to identify and engage with (inter)national institutions and coordination mechanisms to align and strengthen cultural heritage initiatives locally

&#xB7; have developed concrete steps to implement their envisioned project

&#x200B;

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leadership for Cultural Heritage Stewards in Challenging Circumstances</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Working in areas of culture under threat Cultural Heritage professionals face unique challenges in managing projects, balancing both preservation in a variable environment and the dynamics of change in the community. They often lack the opportunity to develop leadership skills that will improve their ability to create more effective proposals and project management strategies, garnering more resources and partnerships. This leadership course will equip these emerging leaders with the tools and techniques needed to tackle these challenges and assist them in developing a professional network of colleagues dealing with the same issues. The Smithsonian Cultural Rescue Initiative and the Prince Claus Fund offer heritage stewards from its networks a high-quality leadership development program, customized for challenging scenarios caused by conflict or disaster and incorporating the kind of project development training available to leaders in the cultural sector.

This second edition will kick off with in-person training sessions in the Netherlands, where participants spend several days with a small group of peers learning together from a professor of Leadership Studies and an experienced international project development professional. Each participant brings a project idea on which they want to build a communication and management strategy and project implementation. The instructors devoted time to lecture, group exercises, and advice on participant&#x2019;s projects. Sessions are complemented by discussions with cultural heritage leaders, bringing classroom lessons to life and providing networking opportunities. The course culminates with our participants engaging in a mock review panel with international donor organizations and verbal feedback session with the donors.

A series of short follow up webinars is planned for the spring and summer of 2020 to further support participants move forward on the business side of the preservation of cultural heritage.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smithsonian Institution for the increase and diffusion of knowledge</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8570" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-08" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>52.3666969 4.8945398</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">54295</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-22">3000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-10-22">51295</value>
   <provider-org type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Smithsonian Institution for the increase and diffusion of knowledge</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8570/Leadership_Course_for_Cultural_Heritage_CharlotteHooij-1.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support provided</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In short, the PCF aims for more inclusive societies in which culture thrives through 3 outcome areas: Alternative Narratives that matter (AN)*, Networks for Exchange (NfE)** and Growth of People and Organisations (GPO)***, it does so through providing short term and long term grants, awards and supporting / (co-) organizing activities. (Also see our Theory of Change and M&amp;E Framework.)

*Alternative narratives (AN) &#x2013; stories that lead to greater understanding; stories that are seldom heard, that differ from a dominant narrative, that reveal a more complex reality

**Networks of exchange (NfE) &#x2013; interchange among organisations and individuals that broaden horizons and open new possibilities

***Growth of individuals and organisations (GPO) &#x2013; activities that strengthen the confidence and competence of cultural practitioners</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leadership course for 10 international heritage stewards</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">10 international Heritage stewards working in difficult circumstances have acquired skills that will help them further advance their work locally or regionally</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The PCF strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees reporting personal / organisational growth following a collaboration with the Fund</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rough estimation. A higher result would be considered positive.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
