<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-CER2.2019-11</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public and Private Libraries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Transfer the collections to a safer location

- 3 week training course in digitization for new staff members

- Identify parts of the collection affected by bombing, movement or poor storage and undertake measures for improve condition

- Digitization and cataloguing

- Identification of other endangered libraries, list them and work with owners

- Seminar for awareness raising and risk mitigation</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by The Imam Zaid Bin Ali Cultural Foundation</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yemen has been suffering from a multi-faceted war for five years. Just recently, the UN special envoy stated that the country &#x201C;faces an existential threat&#x201D;. The Gulf Cooperation Council has declared the entire Sa&#x2019;da region a war zone, and employed saturation bombing (&#x201C;carpet bombing&#x201D;) to de-populate and destroy the region. The private manuscript libraries of Yemen comprise one of the world&#x2019;s largest and most important collections of Arabic manuscripts. Collectively, these 6.000 private libraries possess some 50.000 codices, many of which are unique. These sources record a rich cultural legacy of Arabic and Islamic literature from the 8th century to the present. In recent years, Yemen&#x2019;s private libraries have suffered great losses, in part due to sectarian extremists who are ideologically opposed to the Zaydi Shiite school of Islam and have targeted Zaydi manuscripts for destruction. Over 10.000 manuscripts, including several entire libraries, have been destroyed in the past ten years (National Endowment for the Humanities, Enriching Digital Collections Grant (2010-2013). The present project, led by the The Imam Zaid Bin Ali Cultural Foundation (IZBACF) aims at digitizing manuscript collections from private libraries which are located in Sa&#x2019;da and Sana&#x2019;a.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerda Henkel Stifting</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8519" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="YE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.3694451 44.1910066</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.9509413 43.7477742999999</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-04"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-04">21040</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-04">21040</value>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerda Henkel Stifting</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8519/Project_8519_current_image_2020-01-20_11.31.34.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-CER2.2019" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
