<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13829</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">If We Vanish</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the World Health Organization, 45 decibels of sound is considered the ideal level for noise levels in cities. But in large cities of India, sound measurement levels are generally more than 90 decibel. Noise pollution can have serious effects on human health such as high stress levels, anxiety, sleeping disturbance and hearing loss &#x2013; and has even been identified as leading to a decrease in life expectancy. Increasing population, transportation vehicles, constructions, festivals and firecrackers are among the main reasons of the noise pollution in India. Delhi is considered as one of the loudest cities in the world and &#x2018;&#x2019;participants [of the WHO study] in Delhi recorded the highest average hearing loss &#x2013; equivalent to someone 19.34 years older than them.&#x2019;&#x2019; The Indian government is taking measures to prevent noise pollution by banning loud speakers after 10 pm, however enforcement of laws still remain weak.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outputs

&#xF09E;	3D sound recordings of 6 locations in India

&#xF09E;	1 darkroom for the immersive sound installations

&#xF09E;	1 information room installation

&#xF09E;	At least 4 installations/exhibitions of the work in Indian cities &#x2013; 800 people

&#xF09E;	Immersive yoga events &#x2013; 50 people

&#xF09E;	Social media output 

&#x200B;

Outcomes

&#xF09E;	creating awareness of noise pollution and its impact on society and environment

&#xF09E;	to point out the urgency of protecting natural soundscapes and environment

&#xF09E;	allow people to experience the positive influence of naturally quiet places on health and well-being

&#x200B;

Impact

The project intends to create understanding of how much noise pollution there is, and draw attention to this less well-known consequence of human interference. 

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to create a sound installation as a result of 3D sound recordings made in several locations of India. The recordings will be done in environments that are ecologically relatively untouched and diverse; the applicant states that the locations they have selected are the six quietest places in India. The project is a critique on the overwhelming levels of noise pollution that is threatening the health of humans in urban spheres as well as causing ecological imbalance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by Nikhil Nagaraj</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">people from all ages, school classes, eco conscious people, people affected by noise, music enthusiasts</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8437" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.7583142 73.3757026000001</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">14240</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">14240</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8437/update/28996/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-related delay</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8437/Project_8437_current_image_2020-01-22_09.20.06.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-01"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
