<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-CER.2019.13914</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Damage Assessment Mission National Museum of Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed Damage Assessment Mission (DAM) will identify and prioritise post-disaster conservation actions, specifically to:

&#x200B;

&#x2022; Attend local stakeholder meetings and site induction with key Museum staff and government officials including the Museum Director Prof. Kellner, Deputy Director National Museum of Brazil, Cristiane Serejo, Head of Conservation Ms Marcia Souza, and Rescue Coordinator, Claudia Rodrigues.

&#x2022; Document the recovery activities of artefacts and collections undertaken and in progress through site visits to the temporary Museum labs and storage containers on site.

&#x2022; Identify the level of material need, including storage requirements, conservation resources and expertise needed on the ground to prevent deterioration to salvaged materials and artefacts,

&#x2022; Clarify the role and involvement of other international bodies and NGOs as well as detailing the local protocols necessary for conservation work to be implemented.

&#x200B;

The result of the DAM will be presented in a joint meeting with representatives of the National Museum of Brazil, and will be published in a report/ roadmap. The report will be promoted via the IIC website and its network, including ICCROM, ICOM-CC, ICOM Brazil and IBRAM (The Brazilian Institute of Museums), supported by the British Council, Smithsonian Institution, ICOM LAC Regional Alliance and Blue Shield. Finally, the report will be presented in a Panel at the IIC Annual General Meeting in January 2020. The DAM also has the aim to raise awareness of the recovery needs as well as strengthening local professional and institutional capacity to unlock the funding needed to support the longer term ambition to restore the museum.

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by the International Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works (ICC)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988.CER.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8577" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-19" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-22.9068467 -43.1728965</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-09-19"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-01-09"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-19">2918</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-19">2918</value>
   <provider-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8577/Project_8577_current_image_2020-01-13_14.11.03.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988.CER.2019" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc.) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The PCF strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees reporting personal / organisational growth following a collaboration with the Fund</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1=Yes. 2=No</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
