<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13822</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Devouring Architecture</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Devouring Architecture is a project by Ishak Jalimam and his association Real Stage, which addresses the negative effects of invasive plant species on cultural heritage sites, and specifically modernist monuments, in Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina. The project consists of a series of workshops with scientists and artists, new media outputs and public events. The new media outputs will take the shape of photos, short films, and video art. By combining scientific study on the irreversible effects of invasive plant species with artistic translations of the outcomes the applicant hopes to raise awareness of this issue and the irreversible consequences it could have.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Invasive plant species have been imported to almost all places in the world, and can cause damage to both ecosystems and man-made structures. These species are often very aggressive and flourish in rocky areas. In Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina heritage sites are often unmanaged and vegetation is able to grow around and in the sites. Invasive plants can cause irreparable damage to these buildings, breaking up building materials and walls, which can even lead to the collapse of structures. In the ecosystems in the surrounding areas the invasive plants can wipe out other species who cannot compete against the proliferation of these species. With this project the applicant hopes to raise awareness on the need to systematically eradicate these plants, to be able to protect both built and natural heritage.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outputs 

&#xF09E;	Workshops between scientists and artists &#x2013; 20 people

&#xF09E;	Video art productions

&#xF09E;	Social media campaign &#x2013; 100.000 views 

&#xF09E;	Public events &#x2013; 2000 audience members 

&#xF09E;	Internet art (excerpts from the video productions made specifically to be consumed online)

&#xF09E;	Street projections of the works in Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina

&#x200B;

Outcomes

&#xF09E;	Generating knowledge on the life of invasive plant species and documentation of the effects these plants have on the cultural heritage of Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina

&#xF09E;	Raising awareness on this issue and the irreversible effects it could have on the cultural heritage of the country

&#xF09E;	Creating an opportunity for young artists to be involved in a collaborative and interdisciplinary project and giving them access to a platform

&#x200B;

Impact 

By generating knowledge and raising awareness on this issue the applicants hope to contribute to a change in people&#x2019;s mentalities and influence a more protective attitude towards the cultural heritage of Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina. 

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by Association Real Stage</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">local communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8452" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>43.8562586 18.4130763000001</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-10-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">14709</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">14709</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8452/Project_8452_current_image_2020-01-22_09.21.22.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-10-30"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-10-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
