<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-NGP.2018.13688</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aman Space</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Raising awareness among youth about art, gender and sexuality
- Longevity of an available safe physical space/s for artists, activists, students, is secured
- Improved alternative media practices when it comes to LGBT+ and gender related issues
- LGBT+ individuals&#x2019; stories and experiences are documented
- Higher inclusion for marginalized groups (within marginalized groups) is achieved (through focus groups, media, arts, support groups&#x2026; etc.)
- A space, physically and virtually to students, artists and writers is secured.
- A space for sharing stories, networking and youth engagement on topics of arts, gender, sexuality is created.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Next Generation Partnerships</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The activities proposed as part of the Next Generation partnership include a residency programme for young, predominantly local artists, allowing them to grow and to work collaboratively with older mentors in a safe environment, a podcast which will be developed out of a discussion group, and a travelling diary book, to be entitled Hdoud, which will be produced with activists, artists and writers working together and published at the end of its journey. There will also be workshops, held at the organisations new space, in storytelling, theatre and filmmaking. The filmmaking workshops will eventually produce a series of short films to be shared on their social media platforms. Since the current publishing activities of My Kali have such a strong regional reach, these will also be supported through the partnership.

Linking all activities together will be the inauguration of a semi-public space that participants and artists can use. This space in Amman will offer a safe place for members of the LGBT community and it will be the location for workshops, podcast recordings, artistic residencies and exhibitions. While each activity will be overseen by a project manager, in practise the structure of the organisation is highly networked. The close bond between the various team members was also observed by the researcher during the visit. This means that, despite the relatively large number of activities, there will be close ties between the various projects, with participants and leaders engaging in multiple projects and binding them together.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">While homosexuality is not technically illegal in Jordan, social attitudes are extremely conservative, with high levels of discrimination and prejudice. Homosexuality is often seen as a Western import and a sign of foreign meddling in society, a perception My Kali has worked hard to combat, for example by using Arabic instead of Western terminology. Their Arabic language ABC of terminology and Frequently Asked Questions are two of the highest read pages on their site, and they explained during the meeting with the researcher that they are gradually starting to have an effect on the terminology and language used in mainstream discourse about homosexuality. It is therefore important that PCF&#x2019;s involvement not be too widely publicized in My Kali&#x2019;s public communications to avoid misinterpretation. 

Each of the core team members and project managers, as well as the vast majority of the rest of the team, is under the age of thirty, and they have a proven track record of opening up space and providing opportunities for young, particularly LGBT, people in the arts. This impact would be expanded with the inauguration of their semi-public space through the Next Generation programme, which would allow both safe meeting spaces for their readership and a physical space for the creation and exhibition of artistic work. Especially with the artistic residency programme they will provide young artists with opportunity for creation, exposure and mentorship.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8404" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>ngproposals@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603, 1017 CE, Amsterdam, the Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.9539494 35.910635</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-06-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2018-11-01">226000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-01">226000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988.NGP.2018" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8404/Project_8404_current_image_2019-11-13_14.55.15.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Networks for Exchange</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantee Reports Valuable Connections Made</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to valuable connections made. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Sensitivity</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partner carries out assessment/investigation of the role gender plays in their work</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline year="2018"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
