<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-CER2.2019.13876</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Damage and Risk Assessment: Setting Salvage Priorities, Digitalization and Inventorying</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by National Museum Jamaica</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project, under the coordination of Director Jonathan Greenland, aims to enhance the emergency preparedness of the National Museum of Jamaica. Its collection holds over 17.000 artefacts representing the most important historical events and cultural production of Jamaican history. The current condition of the Museum building and storage space are not adequate to protect the collection from the natural disasters, like hurricanes, floods and earthquakes, to which it is likely to be exposed in the future. During the project, which focuses mostly on the main repository of the Museum, the existing disaster and emergency management policies are updated, and measures to prevent looting (alarm system; detailed inventorying) and fire damage (smoke detectors; fire extinguishers) are installed. Furthermore, the inventory system will be modernized and the collection will be digitized, as to better organize the collection and to increase its accessibility.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x2022; Updating the existing disaster and emergency management policies, and revising the salvage priority list.

&#x2022; Replacement of the windows with UV filtering and impact resistant glass

&#x2022; Replacement of the current emergency exit and the addition of an extra emergency exit door.

&#x2022; Installing a wireless alarm system, linking to the smoke detectors to facilitate distant alert.

&#x2022; Installation of a split air conditioning system to replace the current duct ventilation system.

&#x2022; Increasing fire safety: additional fire suppressing extinguisher spray foam and CO2 gas, removal of plywood drywall sections and replacement with fire resistant material.

&#x2022; Installation of an automatic 15 KVA diesel generator to run the cooling system, lights etc. should there be an extended grid power shutdown.

&#x2022; Implementation of a digital asset management strategy, and digitization of the collection, to enhance storage and inventory, and the accessibility of the collection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8511" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>18.0178743 -76.8099041</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-07-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">17661.2</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-22">17661.2</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8511/Project_8511_current_image_2020-01-20_11.37.27.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-CER2.2019" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
