<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13828</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Chorography of the Euphrates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outputs

&#xF09E; Exhibition - expected reach 2000 people

&#xF09E; Publication - expected reach 2000 people

&#x200B;

Outcomes

&#xF09E; Visual documentation of the environmental effects on the region

&#xF09E; Giving the effected communities the opportunity to tell their tale

&#xF09E; Raising awareness of the situation the region is facing, and helping environmental NGOs get attention for this issue

&#x200B;

Impact

The ultimate goal of this project is to encourage governments and communities to take action against the environmental degeneration of the area.

&#x200B;

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Marshlands of Iraq, a region that has been agriculturally productive for centuries, are situated in between the main rivers of Tigris and Euphrates. The farm lands are naturally fertilized by the floods that happen seasonally, however, nowadays the riverbanks are facing droughts which put the agricultural areas and the people that rely on them at risk. The general director of Nature Iraq Azzam Alwash explains the importance of floods with these words: &#x2018;_Quite literally, the soil of the sedimentary plane of southern Iraq came from the mountains and sedimented in the south forming the land that we inhabit. The waters of the Tigris and Euphrates flow to make southern Iraq/Mesopotamia the Garden of Eden in the middle of a barren desert. The annual floods create the marshlands and these floods heal the farm lands as the flood waters absorb the salts that accumulate from the evaporation of and deposit a new layer of silts and clays laden with minerals from the mountains and thus the Sumerian farmers never needed fertilization as nature took care of that_.&#x2019; Today the water shortage caused by the dams in Turkey and Iran cause severe damage on agriculture and on the natural cycle of the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With this project the photographers Tamara Abdul Hadi and Roi Saade aim to document the effect of drought on the Marshlands between the Euphrates and Tigris in Iraq. These agricultural lands, which have been tilled for centuries, are under threat from climate change, exacerbated by the building of dams in Turkey. This project, which will document and map the area and its people, aims to raise awareness and showcase how local communities are affected by the environmental change in the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by Tamara Abdul Hadi and Roi Saade</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">communities on the river banks of Tigris and Euphrates</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8440" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.5257657 47.7737970000001</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.315241 44.3660671</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-01">11580</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">11580</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8440/Project_8440_current_image_2020-01-22_09.20.27.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-05-01"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
