<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13837</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam Grey-Green Dictionary</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">**Outputs / Deliverables**

A series of residencies (expected 5) in the contested areas. Reach: 5 artists and the art communities who will be involved in the project

A series of workshops between artists and local indigenous communities to share knowledge of nature and to learn about bio- diversity in the areas. Reach: 4 or 5 International and local NGOs who work in the field of community development and environment. Hundreds of local indigenous people involved in the process (workshops, talks and collaborations)

A &#x2018;dictionary&#x2019; &#x2013; artist books, prints produced with local plants inks and dyes. 500 prints. Online version of the dictionary in form of e-book. Reach: Hundreds of local, national and regional artist communities, 1,000 people reach via printed publication, 10,000 readers reached via online publication.

A series of moving image works/ film processed with plant-based developers, traditional color processes and botanicals\_. \_The films will be made available online for free access Reach: 25,000 audience reached via film screenings and online version of the film series.

Mobile exhibitions, talks and workshops in Hanoi, and other contested provinces. Reach:

20,000 audience reached as audience of the exhibition, talks and workshops.

**Outcomes**

Participating artists become more socially and politically-engaged via intensive researches at site as well as during and after the creation of the project. Evidence: Two rounds of Interviews to be conducted during and after the project.

A more open and constructive dialogue between the participating artists, NGOs and the local communities. Evidence: Workshop results produced and/or documented. Interviews conducted after the workshops.

Local communities become more aware of the sustainable development and environmental/ecological issues. Evidence: Workshops, talks, and exhibitions at site

Interviews, questionnaire collected before and after the project

A growing number of art audiences (not only in big city but also in the project areas) Evidence: Social media engagements, attendance rate at events, Q&amp;A discussion and questionnaire</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DocLab Hanoi and Manzi Studios propose a series of five artist residencies in forests in which the artists will work in close contact with local communities. The concept of the residencies is based on 1960s-70s detention camps for artists and writers, who returned with traditional knowledge of nature. In the context of urbanisation and state-controlled media and education, the resulting exhibitions will be a dictionary of knowledge, intended to reconnect society with nature and art with activism, against unchecked development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The loss of forests due to economic development often goes hand in hand with the loss of ethnic minorities&#x2019; ecological knowledge. Due to increasing urbanisation and censorship the majority of the Vietnamese people have lost touch with their environment and cultural history, lacking awareness of sustainability and of the historical and continued government control against freedom of expression. Artists are generally positioned as outsiders and have little interest in social or environmental issues. After residencies with Indigenous forest communities, artists will produce a dictionary of ecological knowledge.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by Hanoi DocLab</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">young urban audience, general public, ethnic minorities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8424" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.0008143 105.8517814</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.0277644 105.8341598</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.4747064 105.5708865</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-11-15"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-04-01">16000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">20000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8424/Project_8424_current_image_2020-01-22_09.18.34.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-15"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-15"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
