<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-NG.2019.13713</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Desde Adentro</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-20 young women, ages 15-20, from Santa Margarita girl&#x2019;s prison</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by Asociaci&#xF3;n Cultural Mercado Central</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender discrimination, poverty and sexual violence against women is an undeniable crisis in Peruvian society. Limited access to education, to resources and inequalities in working condition mislead young women to an &#x2018;&#x2019;easy way out&#x2019;&#x2019; or namely to drug trafficking. According to reports by INPE (National Penitentiary Institute), between sixty to seventy percent of women in prison were arrested on charges of drug trafficking and 85 percent have children to support at home. There are single mothers who are living with their children in the prison, pregnant women, or women that have experienced sexual violence or harassment. We can understand that the participants of this project are in a vulnerable situation both as imprisoned individuals at an early age and as women within a socially unequal society.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Desde Adentro project will take place in the premises of Santa Margarita rehabilitation center at Lima and it is to create an audio-visual laboratory for and by underage women in the detention center. 15-20 young women will participate in filmmaking workshops and activities, where they will learn different formats of cinematographic language to create their own stories.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">_++Outputs:++_ 

Film making workshop and video library creation in Santa Margarita rehabilitation center 

&#xA7; with 15-20 young women, between ages 15-20

&#xA7; 4 stages of activities: exploration for creation, construction of narratives, video library, dissemination

&#xA7; 4 audio-visual stories as the product of workshops

&#xA7; The screening of short films inside and outside of the detention center

_++Outcomes:++_

&#xA7; to create a safe and open space for discussion and creativity 

&#xA7; to support self-exploration and self-expression of women in center

&#xA7; to provide the participants technical skills on film making and cinematographic language for creating alternative narratives 

_++Impact:++_ 

&#xA7; to acknowledge a broader public on the conditions and lack of resources in the detention center and on the vulnerabilities of imprisoned women 

&#xA7; to spark discussions on the sexual violence, poverty and gender inequality in the Peruvian society. 

&#xA7; to challenge male dominated mainstream media by telling the story of &#x2018;&#x2019;others&#x2019;&#x2019;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-NG.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8323" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>ngproposals@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603, 1017 CE Amsterdam</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-12.0463731 -77.042754</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-07-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-04-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-07-31">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-07">20000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-NG.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8323/update/29045/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-related delay</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8323/update/29044/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stage 1 successfully completed, writing scripts for the next stage</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8323/Project_8323_current_image_2019-10-21_11.55.18.JPG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-NG.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-06-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-06-12"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-06-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
