<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13858</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Environmental Education Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by EnvaTechs</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Energy and water supply, desertification, waste management and the loss of biodiversity are some of the most pressing environmental concerns facing Jordan today. In a region that already suffers from a severe scarcity of natural resources, climate change is also directly affecting the water and agricultural sectors. There are notable wrong practices by locals that harm the environment but also a lot of potential to enact change in the current poor environmental situation. Seeing environmental education as an untapped resource in combating environmental challenges in the region, EnvaTechs hopes to increase the awareness of the local population - in particular the younger generation - about such issues in order to foster the development of positive environmental conservation behaviour changes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EnvaTechs wants to make Jordanian youth more aware of environmental problems facing the region and their potential future impact through the use of innovative learning methods and immersive technologies. VR headsets will allow teachers, students and other stakeholders such as educators and specialists from NGOs, educational institutes and ministries in Amman to view high-quality visualizations that will encourage personal behaviour changes towards the environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">_++Outputs++_

The EnvaTechs team will host 10-18 workshops (one per school) that showcase an environmental VR experience for students in formal schools in Amman.

Reach: Each workshop will host 20 students.

20-36 number of teachers (two per school) will be provided with training in order to guide the VR experience.

A cloud platform will be created for schools to access all materials associated with the VR experience.

EnvaTechs will work with 20 students on a school competition initiative that aims to create a new positive change toward the environment.

EnvaTechs will also hold 25 VR sessions for other local stakeholders, including educators and specialists from NGOs, educational institutes and ministries.

_Outcomes_

The VR experience will improve behaviour towards the environment in the students who participate.

Within 3 months of the workshop implementation, at least 25% of the students will develop a deeper sense of social responsibility.

Teachers&apos; skills and abilities will be developed through using interactive pedagogy.

_Impact_

New patterns of behaviour towards the environment in individuals, groups, and society as a whole in Jordan, with a focus on protecting and preserving the environment through practices at school, home and in local neighbourhoods.

Active participation and increased emotional intelligence, cognitive skills, efficacy and responsibility of students towards the environment and society.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">students, teachers, NGOs and ministries</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8421" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.9539494 35.910635</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">13500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">13500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8421/Project_8421_current_image_2020-01-22_09.08.43.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-03-01"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
