<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13857</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Educational Games as a Radical Tool</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Project by Makouk</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Egypt, similarly to other parts of the Middle East, the idea of conservation and environmental activism is unknown and almost non-existent, despite pressing issues such as water shortages, extinction of species and environmental pollution, to name just a few. Not to mention the larger issues of marine degradation and the possibility of the entire Delta region being submerged under water due to rising sea levels as a direct result of global warming. The Middle East has a long history of living side-by-side and in cohesion with the environment. The Nile River gave ancient Egypt its life, creating a symbiotic relationship that was extremely fruitful. Modern Egypt is attempting to take control of that environment, but it is seeing devastating changes in both the environment and, more importantly, in people who believe they are the owners of the planet and animal life that surrounds them. In 2017, 40,000 Egyptians died because of pollution, the UN Environment Programme said. This progress, experts said, highlights the need to put the environment at the centre of the attention of the government and the general public.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The educational project proposed by the social enterprise Makouk, consists of two parts, the development of the card game and a workshop. By designing the card game Makouk aims to raise awareness on the activities that negatively impact our environment while re-imagining a different perspective on the relationship with the Earth. The workshop (in 3 governorates of Egypt) is intended to guide educators and community centres on how to use the game in the particular educational context.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">_++Outputs++_

3 day multi-purpose workshop with 6 experts from different disciplines including economics, environmental studies, political theory and anthropology

Reach: 6 experts 

Design and development of 500 card games in 20 days

2 game workshops in 2 international organizations

Reach: 10 participants

3 game workshops in 3 different community centers in 3 rural and urban governorates: Cairo, Alexandria, Giza

Reach: 30 facilitators in different community centers will be trained

_++Outcomes++_

Accessibility of an environmental awareness game in the market.

Environmental awareness of employees in the international organizations.

Game as a practical tool to raise environmental awareness for community centres.

Raising environmental awareness in the communities of 3 community centres in 3 different governorates of Egypt.

_++Impact++_

Create a chain of spreading awareness on environmental issues and concerns hopefully affecting the habits of individuals.

Encourage more educators to work in the field of environmental sustainability.

Give children (future generations) a tool that they can imagine and hopefully prepare for a better future scenario regarding planet earth.

Encourage entities to work and set goals for their carbon footprints.

Creating an understanding of the different environmental responsibilities as an individual, as a local system and global regulations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">educators, community centers, international organizations, 12+ age group</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8422" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.0444196 31.2357116000001</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-02-15"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-01">12041</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">12041</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8422/update/28960/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-related delay</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8422/update/28992/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-related delay</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8422/Project_8422_current_image_2020-01-22_09.18.14.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-15"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-02-15"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
