<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-N.2019.13805</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Studio 8</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outputs

&#xF09E; Maintain their space and team for three years

&#xF09E; Produce 2 dance theatre productions

&#xF09E; Produce 2 joint theatre productions

&#xF09E; Organise 3 iterations of the IDEA Festival

&#x200B;

Outcomes

&#xF09E; Consolidation of Studio 8 as an organisation.

&#xF09E; Facilities available for dancers and performing artists to participate in workshops and productions.

&#xF09E; Professional development of young dance artists in Jordan, which will contribute to their employment and livelihood opportunities.

&#xF09E; Increased support and appreciation for the performing arts in Jordan, and Amman in particular, by generating, and making accessible dance performances.

&#xF09E; More knowledge exchange and cross-disciplinary collaborations within the performing arts scene in Amman.

&#x200B;

Impact

In terms of long term impact the aim of Studio 8 is to provide a creative environment within which dancers, choreographers, musicians, and designers can collaborate in producing unique, challenging and diverse works that offer new perspectives and interpretations of society in Jordan. Simultaneously, they aim to bring their dance creations and activities to new audiences through performance, presentation and touring programs.

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund Network Partners</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Studio 8 purposefully brings dance closer to society through the development, implementation and creation of multidisciplinary, innovative and pioneering dance works. Through this they aim to promote social good, community spirit and participation, and to reflect on their histories and identities. Founded by two brothers who were raised in refugee camps in Jordan the work they produce and the way they engage with their environment is rooted in that experience. With their productions they build new and vibrant connections between traditional and contemporary forms of cultural expression, and interrogate the past and the future of dance in Jordan and the wider region. Their programmes explore and highlight social issues, provide agency for disadvantaged communities and imagine alternative futures for the city and communities of Amman. 

In Jordan access to dance as a creative discipline has been diminishing over the last years, and there is no institutional form of dance education. Through their work Studio 8 want to show communities the power of performing arts and create new audiences within these communities. For (young) dancers and performance artists they want to provide an infrastructure within which they can develop their practice and build viable careers within the discipline.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Studio 8, founded in 2014, is a dance and performing arts organisation based in Amman, Jordan. Studio 8 aims to tackle the lack of formal dance education in the country and to help build creative capacity amongst local dancers, chorographers, designers, and musicians. They focus primarily on two target groups: young professionals and local disadvantaged communities. Studio 8&#x2019;s vision is embedded in the local context and many of their productions examine the urban structure of Amman, which has absorbed many refugee communities from the region and as such has a fusion of different cultures. They explore concepts of traditional and modern culture and find hybrids through their performances.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8476" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.9539494 35.910635</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-01-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">50000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-N.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8476/Project_8476_current_image_2019-11-21_11.23.34.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Networks for Exchange</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantee Reports Valuable Connections Made</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to valuable connections made. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
