<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-SC1.2019.13856</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CLIMAVORE: How We Eat As Humans Change Climates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by SALT</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture is still the occupation of the majority of Turkish people, despite the fact that share of industry and services are raising constantly. Turkey is one of the few self-sufficient countries in the world in terms of food. Its fertile soil, adequate climate, and abundant rainfall permit growing almost any kinds of crops. With this in mind, SALT proposes the project that reflects on environmental transformations and climate change on Turkish food landscapes and society. It focuses on specific ingredients such as buffalo milk and the transformation of the wetland habitats surrounding Istanbul, the challenges of hazelnut production on the northern coasts of Turkey, or the Mediterraneanization of the fisheries in the Black Sea. The exhibition aims to trace the ways in which food practices and politics have shaped the Turkish landscape and how new modes of eating can build new landscapes, imaginaries and societies that respond to those transformations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The exhibition project &#x2018;CLIMAVORE: How We Eat As Humans Change Climates&#x2019; proposed by non-profit organisation SALT, aims to display the impacts of climate change through research on the agricultural production of Turkey and speculate how to envision new platforms for alternative action. Proposed exhibition and additional program will take place in Istanbul, Turkey. The program is a continuation of CLIMAVORE, a long-term project that sets out to envision seasons of food production and consumption that reacts to man-induced climatic events and landscape alterations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">_++Outputs++_

Exhibition at SALT Beyo&#x11F;lu. Five indoor installations.

Reach: average of 55.000 people visit exhibitions at SALT. Culture professionals and enthusiasts, academicians, researchers, and the general public

Off-site outdoors installation.

Reach: the agricultural community based on that location, the general public, students, academics, farmers, food producers and cultural workers

Collaboration with restaurants. Developing recipes for wider public.

A film and video screening programme.

A Reading Room and Visual Archive. (Ottoman documents, that can help construct a history of climate through financial transactions over time, such as agricultural loans or economic bailouts that occurred after significant drought)

E-publication.

Reach: exhibition visitors as well as anyone who could not physically visit

Public programs/Workshops

Reach: 100 people (participants: the general public, students and academics of design, ecology, urban planning, agriculture, economy, history, sociology, farmers, food producers, cultural workers)

Curated trips to selected countryside areas in Turkey following the the harvest times of hazelnuts, olives, figs, grapes and apples.

Reach: 30 people from all ages and socio-economic groups.

_++Outcomes++_

Food production landscapes will benefit from the exchange of knowledge and dialogue platform provided.

Five new artworks will be produced that reflect upon food seasonality and climate change in Turkey in conversation and collaboration with farmers and food activists. These artworks will be accompanied by the public program.

Verbal and written exchanges, a lasting dialogue with the community, participants and visitors will be established.

_++Impact++_

Support of the communities and local stakeholders to create platforms that can establish and enhance regenerative food production methods.

Bringing together farmers, food producers, cultural workers and the general public to have a series of open conversations, exchanges and actions to reimagine how we eat as climate changes and to inspire longer-term action across all possible scales.

Development of strategies with food producers and restaurants that advance a more equitable society that shares knowledge and better practices through what can be eaten in an era of increasingly evident man-induced climatic events.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">culture professionals and enthusiasts, academicians, researchers, general public</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8423" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>41.0082376 28.9783589</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-03-30"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-30">14000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">14000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8423/update/28958/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-related delay</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8423/Project_8423_current_image_2020-01-22_09.18.24.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-03-30"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
