<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-000.2019</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Open Call for Proposals: Promotion and Preservation of Haitian Arts &amp; Culture</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">**The Prince Claus Fund announces an Open Call for proposals specifically aimed at cultural initiatives that foster, preserve and promote Haitian culture, in its broadest sense, with, where possible, a specific focus on Vodou art and culture. We invite individual artists, collectives or cultural organisations living, registered and working in Haiti, to present their ideas that seek preservation, appreciation and production of cultural works in Haiti.**

In a world where media plays an important role of shaping public&#x2019;s perception of foreign countries, Haiti is often portrayed in association with poverty and disasters. This limited view of the country hides other diverse aspects of its society and communities. The everyday life of Haitians, their cultural practices and religious traditions often go unnoticed or untold. The Prince Claus Fund believes that culture and the arts of a country give a more nuanced picture of a place and its people. In Haiti, culture and arts have been a major player in showcasing the diversity of the country, its people and its cultural heritage.

Projects would be selected based on their quality, innovation, expected social impact and their relevance to the context. We especially encourage projects that give focus to the themes of Vodou practice, arts and culture.

**The Prince Claus Fund will support initiatives within the financial range of &#x20AC;15.000 &#x2013; &#x20AC;20.000.**

The support will be allocated through an open call for proposals by the Prince Claus Fund, which will accept applications on a rolling basis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In collaboration with Cultural Heritage and Art Protection in Haiti Fund - Fondation des Fondateurs</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#xB7; Offer different perspectives on Haitian culture and Vodou than those usually shown in the media

&#xB7; Encourage out of the box cultural projects by artists and cultural practitioners that re-interpret common (mis)conceptions within Haiti, and create space for multiple points of view;

&#xB7; Stimulate and inspire communities to actively engage with cultural heritage;

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cultural Heritage and Art Protection in Haiti Fund - Fondation des Fondateurs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8569" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>52.3666969 4.8945398</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-06-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-27">60000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-27">60000</value>
   <provider-org type="70">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cultural Heritage and Art Protection in Haiti Fund - Fondation des Fondateurs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8569/Project_8569_current_image_2020-01-09_11.21.29.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-PCF" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc.) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support provided</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In short, the PCF aims for more inclusive societies in which culture thrives through 3 outcome areas: Alternative Narratives that matter (AN)*, Networks for Exchange (NfE)** and Growth of People and Organisations (GPO)***, it does so through providing short term and long term grants, awards and supporting / (co-) organizing activities. (Also see our Theory of Change and M&amp;E Framework.)

*Alternative narratives (AN) &#x2013; stories that lead to greater understanding; stories that are seldom heard, that differ from a dominant narrative, that reveal a more complex reality

**Networks of exchange (NfE) &#x2013; interchange among organisations and individuals that broaden horizons and open new possibilities

***Growth of individuals and organisations (GPO) &#x2013; activities that strengthen the confidence and competence of cultural practitioners</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supported projects</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund organizes several activities (mostly in The Netherlands) throughout the year that are linked to its different programmes. Some of these activities are done in collaboration with other cultural organizations. These activities vary from the Annual Awards Ceremony in Amsterdam, to an annual international Cultural Speeddate in which Dutch as well as international cultural practitioners participate, activities for and with youth, exhibitions etc.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The PCF strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees reporting personal / organisational growth following a collaboration with the Fund</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rough estimation. A higher result would be considered positive.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender sensitivity</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strives to be a gender equal funder.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grantees identifying as female</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
