<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988.SC1.2019.13825</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Equal Terrains &#x2013; Equal Beings</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India has one of the richest biodiversity in the world, both in terms of species and ecosystems. The country is one of four most bio diverse hotspots in the world, where various endemic species exits only in these regions. &#x2018;One of seventeen mega-diverse countries, it is home to 7.6% of all mammalian, 12.6% of all avian, 6.2% of all reptilian, 4.4% of all amphibian, 11.7% of all fish, and 6.0% of all flowering plant species.&#x2019; The biodiversity of the country is under threat due to pollution, human interference, over population and deforestation for industrial and infrastructural purposes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outputs

&#xF09E;	The public hearing or jan sunwai - reach: 300 

&#xF09E;	Documentation and communication of the event - reach: 15.000

&#xF09E;	Screenings of the film in schools  across the country - reach: 50.000

&#x200B;

Outcomes

&#xF09E;	Raising awareness about the way people relate to the natural world, and create a sense of responsibility

&#xF09E;	Interest by media to cover the need for environmental protection 

&#xF09E;	Change in the political landscape and policy making, growing awareness of the necessity to address inter-species justice and the protection of the environment

&#x200B;

Impact

In the long run the project hopes to have changed people&#x2019;s perception towards the natural world (both fair and fauna) and to have influence policy makers to change the legislation on the protection of the natural world. 

&#x2003;

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project Equal Terrains / Equal Beings is a project by Ravi Agarwal that is based on a traditional system of public hearings or _jan sunwai. _Agarwal will stage a public hearing/panel where experts will present their concerns, findings and recommendations to the audience. Public hearings are a proven method in India as a form of justice in social and environmental movements, outside of the official judicial system. In this project Agarwal will research the relationship of human and non-humans, in an attempt to rethink the equal rights of different species in the environmental discourse. The project will be filmed and documented, with the aim of using the outcomes to be able to raise awareness in a broader community that the people directly involved in the hearing itself.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by Toxics Link</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">general public, cultural practitioners, activists, community members</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8442" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>28.6139391 77.2090212000001</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-02-01">12438</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">12438</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8442/update/28962/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">COVID-related delay</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8442/Project_8442_current_image_2020-01-22_09.20.46.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-end>
     <target>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&#x200B;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-04-30"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
