<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019.13835</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biblioteca Comunit&#xE1;ria Flutuante Mamori</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="6" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recently, the c.a. 2000 inhabitants of Mamori Lake in the Amazon have experienced more extreme weather due to climate change. Constructed mainly with imported urban materials, their homes are not fit to deal with the local climate, especially increased variations in the tide. Brajovic proposes to develop architecture with local sustainable knowledge and materials as well as recycled waste to invent a new aesthetics of the tropics. The resulting floating building will be used as a library to promote reading and collect books on environmental sustainability for the local communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the community of Mamori Lake, architect Marko Brajovic will construct a floating library. Experimenting with local knowledge, natural materials and recycled waste, they will develop a tropical architecture that is better suited to climate change (e.g. floods) and local culture than imported building materials. The project aims to make reading accessible, and the books the library will hold focus on inspiring sustainability. With the architecture the applicant aims to provide a global example of context specific and sustainable building.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">_++Outputs++_

A floating architecture that serves as a library and community meeting place
 Reach: 2000 inhabitants of Mamori Lake, 1500 inhabitants of neighboring Mira Lake, 20 architecture students annually

A library installed in the floating building with 200 books first year (2020) and 100 books each year by NGO Vaga Lume.
 Reach: 4000 local inhabitants (see above) directly

A video documentary with a making-of the floating architecture, implementation of the library, interview of the community leader and kids, drone view and photographs of result.

Reach: about 35000 people globally 

_++Outcomes++_

Local and Amazone-wide influence on future architecture, teaching the community sustainable construction, re-qualifying local architecture with the reuse of waste material. 
 Evidence: improvement in local construction projects using local bamboo, natural materials, floating architecture, renewable energy. Photo documentation and interviews.  

Globally inspire experimental architecture based on mutual learning and collaboration with local communities, to develop Climate Crises architecture for the next years.
 Evidence: measure (social) media attention and new projects around the region and globe inspired by these initiatives. 

Call attention to the Amazon rainforest to control deforestation and mining. 
 Evidence: measure (social) media attention and new projects around the region and globe inspired by these initiatives. 

Create a learning, reading and discussion centre, inform local community about their ecosystem, regenerative culture and value of vernacular architecture and waste material treatment.
 Evidence: local female leaders will organize spontaneous events, the knowledge about local ecosystem will grow in the region, reflected in better disposals and results of solid waste.

Inspire other organizations to invest in social and environmental projects in the Amazon region. To collaborate with local communities, inform them about alien waste materials, consider the importance of local culture and invest in green technology.
 Evidence: after this project new collaborations will help local and regional infrastructure to evolve.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by Atelier Marko Brajovic</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="3" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">local residents from Mamori Lake, Brazil, residents from surrounding lake communities, architecture students from around the world</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goethe-Institut e.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8433" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>grantsandcollaborations@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-3.8194444 -60.3612225</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">15000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-11-14">15000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8433/update/28995/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ahead of planning and adapted use of materials</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8433/Floating_library_6.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-SC1.2019-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-end>
     <target></target>
     <actual></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">People reached</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-01"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target not applicable in this instance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
