<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988.CER2.2019.05</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural History Museum, Bulawayo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by National Museums and Monuments of Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activities:

&#xF0B7; Facilitators Meetings &#x2013; creation of team for the development of the Disaster Emergency Plan for the Natural History Museum, consisting of 4 experts from the National Museums and Monuments of Zimbabwe. Mapping and identification of the stakeholders, and preparation of all project activities (workshops, drills and plans).

&#xF0B7; All-Stakeholder Meeting &#x2013; bringing together all who are interested or involved in the disaster planning and response of the Museum, including government agencies, local communities, local authorities, media, and tour operators among others. To build a network and a cohesive approach.

&#xF0B7; 5-day Workshop: Development of the Disaster Emergency Plan &#x2013; bringing together museum curators, local communities, local authority fire-fighting departments, police, media, and experts from local universities and government agencies. Risk identification of the Museum, development of a framework for the Disaster Emergency Plan, identification of existing

response facilities, division of tasks and roles in case of emergency to relevant stakeholders, and capacity building of the curators of other museums to develop similar plans.

&#xF0B7; Development of the Disaster Emergency Plan &#x2013; a small team of experts will develop a detailed plan, taking into account the outcomes of the workshop.

&#xF0B7; Capacity building workshops for the museum staff &#x2013; training of the museum staff on the implementation of the Disaster Emergency Plan. Involving the general staff, the tour guides, curators and assistants, security and maintenance personnel.

&#xF0B7; Disaster Response Drill &#x2013; to test the developed plan, and to build experience on response in an actual crisis situation.

&#xF0B7; Improvement of the Emergency Preparedness and Mitigation Measures &#x2013; improving the preparedness of the Museum for fire and theft, by the instalment of fire extinguishers, hose reels, and CCTV cameras.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Natural History Museum of Bulawayo, Zimbabwe has an enormous collection of thousands of natural- and cultural heritage objects covering the topics of arachnology, entomology, mammalogy, herpetology, ichthyology, geology and archaeology. The Museum is frequently visited by schools, other educational institutions, and tourists, and the collection is intensively researched by scholars from all over the world. The Museum is one of the few of this value and scope in sub-Saharan Africa. The Museum is currently faces a number of threats, for which it is not well prepared. There is a high risk of flooding during the seasonal rains, and due to a lack of security measures there is a risk of theft and vandalism. Also, there is a significant threat of fire, because of a faulty electrical wiring system and flammable material in the collection. To overcome this threat and prevent damage to the collection in the future, the museum will develop a comprehensive and practical disaster emergency plan for the museum. They the museum staff will be trained on the implementation of the disaster preparedness plan, and fire- and looting preventive measures, such as fire extinguishers and CCTV cameras, will be installed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerda Henkel Stifting</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8516" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-20.1325066 28.626479</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-05-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-05-15">24680</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-15">24680</value>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerda Henkel Stifting</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8516/Project_8516_current_image_2020-01-20_11.28.21.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-CER2.2019" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
