<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-CER2.2019.02</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marakwet Community Traditional Furrows System in Kerio Valley, Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Construct landslide susceptibility map for affected areas

2) Identify and map out factors responsible for landslides occurrence

3) Provide baseline information for local community

4) Via GPS locate areas that are prone to landslides in order to empower the local community and thus mitigate the impacts of the landslides

5) Conduct results dissemination, community engagement and public awareness on emergency preparedness to stakeholders and the local community.

&#x200B;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A project by Marakwet Community Heritage Group</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya is classified by the United Nations as a chronically water scarce country due to its low natural water replenishment rates. The people living in the Marakwet escarpment have developed a system of furrows which dates back to pre-colonial times. The irrigation systems runs for more than 40 kilometers and descends from 1,500 to 1,200 meters. The furrow irrigation system is owned by the clans living there and also take over water management. The Traditional Marakwet Community Furrow Irrigation System not only is a provider of water for the community, it is also a tangible heritage which makes it of outstanding universal value in the entire landscape. The irrigation system is a testimony to a civilization that has withstood the test of time despite the challenges it faces. As a fragile piece of heritage, urgent and precise interventions need to be undertaken to safeguard the traditional furrows for posterity. The system is threatened by landslides which have increased in the last seven years. The project aims at creating a landslide susceptibility map for the affected areas and to define the factors leading to landslides. This information is to be shared with the local community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerda Henkel Stifting</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8513" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.9988983 36.0621579</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-09-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-15">18517</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-15">18571</value>
   <provider-org type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gerda Henkel Stifting</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8513/Project_8513_current_image_2020-01-20_11.27.35.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988-CER2.2019" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
