<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-4115988-CER.2019.13809</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41159889" secondary-reporter="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Damage Assessment Mission in Ghazni and Ningarhar Province</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As natural and man-made disasters come together in Afghanistan, there is no shortage of cultural heritage under threat. Recent fighting in Ghazni province (Central Afghanistan) and Ningarhar Province (East Afghanistan) has not only affected the cultural heritage , but has also made the sites difficult to access. The Taliban (Ghazni and Ningarhar) and the ISKP/ISIS (Ningarhar) control several areas and fighting with the Afghan government, supported by international forces, continues. The situation has become quite urgent, as many cultural heritage sites in the affected areas are on the verge of collapsing, such as the ancient towers of Ghazni City. The sites are important to the local community and have great architectural and historic value. An assessment of the damage done to the heritage and the value of the heritage to the local communities is needed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Damage Assessment mission will undertake the following activities:

&#xB7; Assess the cultural heritage affected by conflict or natural heritage, insofar as they are in safe and secure areas 

o This includes Ghazni City and the city of Jalalabad, as well as the Behsood and Surkhrod Districts

&#xB7; The assessment will follow these criteria:

o The importance of the site to the community

o The level of damage and risk to the site

o Feasibility of reparation

o Community willingness and support for protection of local authorities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">a project by the Bureau for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-4115988.CER.2019" ref="NL-KVK-41159889" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prince Claus Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8575" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <email>cer@princeclausfund.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Herengracht 603 1017 CE Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="AF" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>33.4982289 67.7615983</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.1718313 70.6216794</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="16066" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-08-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-09-30"></period-end>
   <value akvo:label="Total" currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">4950</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-08-01">4950</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8575/update/29082/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DAM successfully completed and a positive spinoff</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8575/Project_8575_current_image_2020-01-13_11.47.44.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-4115988.CER.2019" type="1"></related-activity>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth of People and Organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Prince Claus Fund strongly believes that &apos;people develop themselves&apos;, as once stated by Prince Claus himself. The Fund facilitates such personal and organisational development by supporting activities that contribute to the professional development of individuals in the cultural sector, e.g. through increasing exposure and visibility towards new audiences, by facilitating exchanges for talent development and funding training courses (e.g. on first aid to cultural heritage after emergencies). The fund also supports the development of cultural organisations, in particular through the Network Partnership Programme that allows organisations from different contexts to learn from each other. Furthermore, the Fund aims to contribute to the overall knowledge base on Culture and Development, e.g. through M&amp;E and research.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Growth on a personal and / or organisational level according to project partner.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the end of the project the project partner is asked whether this project and this collaboration with the Prince Claus Fund has led to growth on a personal and / or organisational level. 1 = Yes 2 = No</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative narratives shared / created / safeguarded</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project creates and shares &apos;Alternative Narratives&apos;, which is one of the 3 overall outcome areas of the Prince Claus Fund, as also explained in the Theory of Change. Alternative narratives (AN) are stories, explanations, histories, spaces that provide an alternative to the dominant discourses and / or that are threatened by disappearance. Alternative narratives must be heard or seen to have significance. They take different forms, which include literature, oral history, visual arts, theatre, music, cultural heritage, i.e. artistic expressions in all disciplines. The safe spaces to make and experience AN are also included. Given its overall aim of more inclusive societies, the Fund supports AN that are relevant within context and foster inclusive societies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#Heritage (-sites, objects, collections etc) safeguarded</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2019"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
