<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>47135-XPCRZM074A</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="47135" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private Sector Support to Climate Resilience in Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed additional investment activities provide opportunities to support investments in improved climate resilient technologies through funding for technical cooperation activities, offering incentive payments and small grants to private businesses, farmers and households. Having a robust participatory process (CRAFTs) which could facilitate continued support/training for the private sector and the climate information services, provides the required enabling environment and a basis to bring about climate resilience at scale through private-sector and market based approaches. The overall concept is to build a national widespread presence and network in the country of public and private actors that will facilitate widespread diffusion of climate resilient technologies and farming practices to improve yields and sustain livelihoods. In addition, the project would contribute to the achievement of the World Bank Cascade Objective, with the aim to build climate resilience in the sub-basins by mobilizing/catalyzing private sector investments in economic sectors such as agriculture and natural capital and by providing technical support to relevant private sector players in Zambia</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="44001" role="4" type="40" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-16" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+1-202-458-1801</telephone>
   <email>cifadminunit@worldbank.org</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Bank, 1818 H Street, NW, Washington, DC 20433 USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100" xml:lang="EN">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ZAMBIA</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <collaboration-type code="2"></collaboration-type>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
