<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">ALTAEYUSH - Processi comunitari integrati e multidimensionali  di inclusione e coesione socio-economica per il rafforzamento  della resilienza dei gru</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Il progetto ALTAEYUSH (&#x627;&#x644;&#x62A;&#x639;&#x627;&#x64A;&#x634; ,(che in arabo significa convivenza tra culture e religioni diverse nel &#x201C;rispetto 
dell&#x2019;altro&#x201D;, nasce dalla volont&#xE0; di FOCSIV e dei partner di mettere in atto processi comunitari integrati e 
multidimensionali di inclusione e coesione socio-economica per il rafforzamento della resilienza dei gruppi 
etnico-religiosi vulnerabili in Iraq, nel Distretto di Hamdaniya (Governatorato di Ninive). 
Il progetto, della durata di 24 mesi, si pone come obiettivo generale di &#x201C;Contribuire a ridurre le disuguaglianze 
e le prassi discriminatorie legate alla religione, al sesso, all&#x2019;et&#xE0;, alla disabilit&#xE0; e alla condizione economica nei 
confronti delle persone maggiormente vulnerabili, in particolare delle minoranze cristiane, nel 
Governatorato di Ninive&#x201D;, in linea con l&#x2019;OSS 10 - Ridurre le disuguaglianze all&#x2019;interno dei e fra i Paesi &#x2013; che 
prevede che &#x201C;entro il 2030 tutti dovranno avere diritto all&#x2019;empowerment e l&#x2019;inclusione sociale, economica e 
politica dovr&#xE0; essere promossa&#x201D;. 
Il partenariato, dopo un attento needs assessment svolto con un confronto continuo con le comunit&#xE0; e le 
autorit&#xE0; religiose e politiche locali e in virt&#xF9; dell&#x2019;esperienza pluriennale del soggetto proponente in Iraq, ha 
rilevato una grande diversit&#xE0; etnica, religiosa e culturale tra le comunit&#xE0; stanziate nei territori di intervento. La 
caduta del regime di Saddam Hussein nel 2003 e la presa di controllo dell&#x2019;area da parte dello Stato Islamico nel 
2014 hanno provocato oltre che la distruzione completa di tutte le infrastrutture, anche un profondo senso di 
insicurezza e di irrisolta conflittualit&#xE0; a livello politico, economico, sociale e religioso e un flusso migratorio delle 
minoranze religiose, soprattutto quella cristiana, all&#x2019;estero e internamente verso il Kurdistan iracheno. Il 
processo di ricostruzione e il flusso migratorio di rientro sono tuttora lenti e difficili a causa di istituzioni 
pubbliche assenti. La mancanza di iniziative nell&#x2019;ambito della formazione, dell&#x2019;impiego lavorativo e dello 
scambio culturale, inteso come spazio di dialogo e coesione sociale, indebolisce le relazioni e le opportunit&#xE0; di 
reciproca conoscenza tra le diverse componenti etnico-religiose della comunit&#xE0; locale.
La percentuale di disoccupati cresce, il settore agricolo, che rappresentava il principale comparto produttivo, 
ha subito gravi danni in seguito all&#x2019;occupazione dei terreni, e si registra la necessit&#xE0; di promuovere attivit&#xE0; per 
il rafforzamento della resilienza e della convivenza pacifica.
I risultati del progetto, che riguardano i diversi gruppi etnico-religiosi del distretto di Hamdaniya sono relativi 
al rafforzamento della resilienza e del dialogo, all&#x2019;aumento delle capacit&#xE0; produttive nel settore agroalimentare e alla facilitazione di accesso al mercato del lavoro. 
Tutte le attivit&#xE0; della presente iniziativa sono orientate alla riduzione delle vulnerabilit&#xE0; e alla lotta contro le 
disuguaglianze, attraverso la diffusione di un messaggio di integrazione e interconnessione tra comunit&#xE0; 
diverse.
Sar&#xE0; realizzato un centro culturale comunitario a Qaraqosh che rappresenter&#xE0; un luogo di incontro e scambio 
in un&#x2019;ottica di rafforzamento della coesione sociale della popolazione locale e per la prevenzione di futuri 
conflitti. Nel centro saranno implementate attivit&#xE0; di partecipazione, di cittadinanza attiva e di rafforzamento 
dei servizi di assistenza e protezione sociale su base comunitaria (formazione di formatori e operatori locali,
laboratori artistici e workshop creativo-espressivi), rivolte a persone di ambo i sessi, dando priorit&#xE0; a donne, 
giovani, minori e persone con disabilit&#xE0; fisiche o psicologiche e che hanno subito stress post-traumatico. 
Saranno supportate le capacit&#xE0; produttive delle famiglie nel settore agro-alimentare, attraverso la costituzione 
di una cooperativa che contribuir&#xE0; alla creazione di posti di lavoro dignitosi, alla promozione di un&#x2019;agricoltura 
attenta all&#x2019;approvvigionamento energetico sostenibile</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Action ALTAEYUSH (&#x627;&#x644;&#x62A;&#x639;&#x627;&#x64A;&#x634; ,(the Arabic word for coexistence between different cultures and religions with 
&quot;respect for the other&quot;, stems from FOCSIV and its partners&#x2019; desire to implement integrated and 
multidimensional community processes of inclusion and socio-economic cohesion in order to strengthen the 
resilience of vulnerable ethnic-religious groups in Iraq, mainly in Hamdaniya District-Nineveh Governorate. 
The Initiative, with a duration of 24 months, has as its overall objective to &quot;Contribute to reducing inequalities 
and discriminatory practices related to religion, gender, age, disability and economic status against the most 
vulnerable people, particularly Christian minorities, in the Governorate of Nineveh&quot;, in line with SDG 10 -
Reducing inequalities within and between countries - which states that &quot;by 2030 everyone must have the right 
to be empowered and the social, economic and political inclusion of all must be promoted&quot;. 
The partnership, after an accurate needs assessment carried out through a continuous comparison with the 
communities and the local religious and political authorities and by virtue of the long experience of the 
proponent in Iraq, has observed a great ethnic, religious and cultural diversity among the communities settled 
in the area of intervention. The fall of Saddam Hussein&apos;s regime in 2003 and the occupation by the Islamic State 
in 2014 caused not only the complete destruction of all infrastructures, but also a deep sense of insecurity and 
unresolved conflicts at political, economic, social and religious level and a migration flow of religious minorities, 
especially Christians, abroad and internally to Iraqi Kurdistan. The process of reconstruction and communities 
return are still slow and difficult because of the absence of public institutions. The persistent lack of initiatives 
in the field of training, employment and cultural exchange, this one conceived as a space for dialogue and social 
cohesion, weakens the relations and the opportunities for mutual exchange between the different ethnic-religious components of the local community.
The percentage of unemployed people is growing, the agricultural sector, which represented the main 
productive sector, has suffered serious damages as a result of the occupation of lands, and there is a need to 
promote activities to strengthen the resilience and a peaceful coexistence.
The results of the Initiative, which focus on the different ethnic-religious groups of Hamdaniya district, are 
related to the strengthening of resilience and dialogue, the increase of productive capacity in the agro-food 
sector and the facilitation of access to the labor market. 
All the activities of the Initiative are directed towards reducing vulnerabilities and fighting against inequalities 
by spreading a message of integration and interconnection among different communities.
In Qaraqosh a community cultural center will be built, representing a place of meeting and exchange in order 
to reinforce the social cohesion of local population and to prevent future conflicts. Activities on the values of 
participation and active citizenship and related to the empowerment of community-based services of social 
assistance and protection (training of trainers, art workshops and creative-expressive workshops) will be 
implemented, addressing people irrespective of gender, giving priority to women, youth, children and people 
with physical or psychological disabilities and who have suffered post-traumatic stress. 
The productive capacities of families in the agro-food sector will be supported through the establishment of a 
cooperative, which will contribute to the creation of decent jobs, the promotion of an agricultural system 
centered around a sustainable energy supply and the establishment of interpersonal and collaborative 
relationships among members based on trust and co-responsibility., regardless of ethnicity and religion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOCSIV - FEDERAZIONE DEGLI ORGANISMI CRISTIANI SERVIZIO INTERNAZ</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/05/2" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="31194" percentage="30" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agricultural co-operatives</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="50" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human rights</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vocational training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2020, substantially reduce the proportion of youth not in employment, education or training</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, achieve full and productive employment and decent work for all women and men, including for young people and persons with disabilities, and equal pay for work of equal value</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, double the agricultural productivity and incomes of small-scale food producers, in particular women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers, including through secure and equal access to land, other productive resources and inputs, knowledge, financial services, markets and opportunities for value addition and non-farm employment</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="2" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure equal opportunity and reduce inequalities of outcome, including by eliminating discriminatory laws, policies and practices and promoting appropriate legislation, policies and action in this regard</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recognize and value unpaid care and domestic work through the provision of public services, infrastructure and social protection policies and the promotion of shared responsibility within the household and the family as nationally appropriate</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce inequality within and among countries</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-01-01">319960</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-10">799900</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOCSIV - FEDERAZIONE DEGLI ORGANISMI CRISTIANI SERVIZIO INTERNAZ</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">479940</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FOCSIV - FEDERAZIONE DEGLI ORGANISMI CRISTIANI SERVIZIO INTERNAZ</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
