<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ-18/3884/SA1/H/INGO/8532</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of essential comprehensive package of primary health care services for most vulnerable population (returnees and host community) residing in out-of-camp settings in Hamdaniya district.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is designed to deliver a comprehensive basic primary health care package to vulnerable returnees and host communities residing in out-of-camp settings in Ninewa governorate. Cordaid plans to continue its existing support to 3 of the 4 Primary Health centers (PHCs) currently under Iraq Humanitarian Fund (IHF) 2017 and Cordaid funded project in the region with a health staff capacity building program.
Additionally 2 other existing PHCs -  that are in need of support as indicated by the DoH of Hamdaniya, Ninewa - will be included in this current grant to be supported with a Comprehensive Health care package as well as capacity building of staff. Cordaid is already working in Ninewa plain since 2016.

The target number of families is approximately 6000 (direct and indirect beneficiaries) and all of them will benefit from access to comprehensive healthcare services. The household size is estimated at an average of 6 members per family. The # of direct beneficiaries is based on a projected increase of returnee population from 50% at start, to 60% of pre-crisis numbers at the end of the project period. 

Cordaid is currently providing essential health care package in 4 PHC centers: Hamdaniya, Baghdida, Bartella and Wardak PHCCs with IHF 2017 and Cordaid existing funding source. The 4 PHCs cover around 30 villages and Hamadaniya PHCC serves cases coming from Mosul city as well. In the current IHPF project Cordaid will increase the efforts of capacity building for all 4 PHCCs in consultation with DoH. Under the new grant request Cordaid will equip and revitalize 2 more PHCCs (Nemrud and Said Hamaad) in Hamdaniya governorate and will continue the capacity building efforts for HF staff in the 3 PHCCs of Hamdaniya, Baghdida, Bartella as well as for these 2 additional HFs to prepare them for a sustainable hand over to DoH Ninewa. The specifics of the capacity building will be agreed upon with DoH and health cluster.
Wardek PHCC will be strengthened with staff capacity training before handing over to the government by the end of the existing project while the other 3 still need additional support on running cost, medication and staff capacity towards addressing  quality health service provision, PHCC management, and pharmaceutical supplies management in order to enable them to provide complete PHCC services before hand them over to Department of Health (DoH) Ninewa sustainably. Cordaid is proposing to use its experience in the above mentioned PHCCs to continue and expand its support through the 1st Standard Allocation 2018 funding mechanism. In addition, two PHCCs, based on needs assessment (see below) and request of the DoH of Hamdania will be supported with medical equipment, devices and regular complete medicine packages. Cordaid aims to revitalize the proposed 2 PHCCs and make them fully operational before handing them over to DoH Ninewa. In addition, in Namrud PHCC staff housing will be renovated to allow the use of the delivery room and to serve the entire population. 
By sustainable phasing out and operationalizing these PHCCs in the target area the project contributes to a sustainable response that will meet the health needs of the population, and support the DoH and the Iraqi Health system beyond the project duration. Cordaid will procure medicines for the above mentioned PHCCs through WHO and DoH, and will coordinate their continuous and unbroken supply to the PHCCs.

Since the program is designed to build the capacity of the PHCCs and the DoH staff working there, Cordaid will use its Health sector experience to support and strengthen the system with the DoH Ninewa. To ensure a supporting environment of local government authorities, local leaders and religious leaders will be consulted and liaised with to get full trust and support of the community. Active sharing and coordination will take place with the Health Cluster partners.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Habib Rajeh</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 (0) 7502469750</telephone>
   <email>habib.rajeh@cordaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hala Sabah Jameel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Program Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+964 750 213 2174</telephone>
   <email>hala.sabah.jameel@cordaid.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="IQ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="G015">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nineveh</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>36.35940000 43.15280000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-08-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-16">150165.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="IRQ72-8532">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-16">150165.94</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303306023">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-30">90099.56</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303887385">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-25">60066.38</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2018" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="6305756415">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-14">10577.73</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STICHTING CORDAID</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraq BI 2018</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-IRQ72-2018" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
