<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.19/00035</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening agribusiness relations for sustainable profits of producer
        associations in the Cauca Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.19/00035</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The training will contribute to strengthening the capacities of CREPIC and its
        local partners to provide specialized knowledge and coaching to agricultural commodity
        chains with the aim of creating value for the market and long-term sustainability of the
        sector. The focus of the training is on strengthening producer associations and their
        business relationships, access to markets, marketing and the generation of added value in
        the products.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8050" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.4448143 -76.6147395</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-09-01">59297</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8050/Project_8050_current_image_2019-10-21_15.36.30.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inception w/shop: Understanding partners</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant
          government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual
          projects and the programme as a whole. For project partners, it is compulsory to use the
          prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project
          achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of
          the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project
          output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by
          the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and
          budget must be made clear in the annual report. Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and
          not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement
          of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the
          annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project
          and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s)
          and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as
          a whole. Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning,
          reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more
          elaboration is demanded. In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual
          reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are
          obligatory. The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific
          conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in
          achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the
          report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted. The final
          report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report) Reflect on how the
            training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting
            organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in
            reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations
            for the post-project period. + In your email submitting the final report, the partners
            will enclose: - an inventory of equipment purchased - a document signed by the (Lead
            partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting
            organisation on the transfer of ownership - a list with the names and email addresses of
            staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland
            Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="The TMT was embedded in the capacity building component of the CLED project (OKP-COL-10009) and focused on improving the requesting organisation&apos;s (CREPIC) and partners&apos; capacity to strengthen the business performance of farming associations in the selected value chains, many of which are made up by women, indigenous people and demobilised FARC members.

As indicated earlier, the initial TMT programme included field work to apply the acquired knowledge and skills in the field, coached by iCRA. Due to COVID 19, field work could not be conducted, and trainees did not have the opportunity to interact with the above mentioned actors in value chains as initially intended; and could therefore only exhibit improved analytical and functional skills in the case study used online. Therefore, we judge that we were only partially successful in reaching the desired objectives. 

Even if the COVID 19 pandemic forced us to extend the TMT and postpone training activities several times, the interest of staff from the different organizations in following the TMT remained high. We designed an online training programme that kept interaction between participants lively. 

We submitted a new TMT (20 January 2021), that include now three more co-requesting organisations who had sent staff to this TMT and if granted, our aim is to continue the engagement and learning started with this TMT."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the
            project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the
            activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="- Output 1.  CREPIC, SENA, ESAP, FUP staff have improved knowledge and skills in analysing agro-enterprise competitiveness and value chain improvement strategies. Achievement:  23 participants (including stakeholders beyond CREPIC, SENA, ESAP and FUP &#x2013; see list of participants) analysed the coffee value chain (own selected case study) and made suggestion on how to improve the chain.  

- Output 2. CREPIC, SENA, ESAP, FUP staff have improved knowledge and skills in facilitating multi-stakeholder processes. Achievement:  Already the first workshop, still residential (before COVID 19), was joined by participants from more organisations than initially envisaged and allowed practising multi-stakeholder engagement in-situ. Even the postponement of activities due to COVID 19 did not affect this, in fact, even more stakeholders joined the online sessions, and in breakout online rooms we could continue working with different stakeholder groups. 

- Output 3. CREPIC, SENA, ESAP, FUP staff have improved knowledge and skills in linking small-scale producers to agricultural markets. Achievement:  The initial field work embedded in the training was designed to engage with small-scale producers. This was not possible due to COVID 19 and we could only discuss options in the online sessions but not test in real-life context, thus we judge this output as only partially achieved. 

-Output 4. REPIC, SENA, ESAP, FUP staff have improved knowledge and skills in gender equity and empowering women within value chains.Achievement:  iCRA based its training on the CASE approach, whose key values or principles are ownership, empowerment and sustainability. Initially, as in output 3, we had planned to engage with female small-scale producers, unfortunately this component had to remain at a conceptual level, thus we also judge this output as only partially achieved.  

&#x200B;"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CREPIC, SENA, ESAP,FUP</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="11.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">09-03-2021: Non governmental organisations (Foundations, Associations,
                Committees) were counted under the private organisations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge
            and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">09-03-2021: The initial field work embedded in the training was designed to
                engage with small-scale producers (application of acquired knowledge and skills).
                This was not possible due to COVID 19 and we could only discuss options in the
                online sessions but not test in real-life context (working environment).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.2. % scholarship holder&apos;s /TMT participants / alumni
            satisfaction</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="100.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new
            knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="100.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="23.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="56% of the participants were women. Each participating institution was at least represented by one woman and interestingly enough, the representative of the Foundation Women&apos;s World was a man. More and more women in Colombia are very qualified and joining institutions. The Colombian requesting organisation (Regional Centre for Productivity and Innovation of Cauca) is led by a woman and the institution has more professional women than men."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Participants acknowledged:

- Participatory knowledge building

- Teamwork and articulation

- Jointly building knowledge and skills

- Development based on creativity

- Knowledge and strategies to share in the territory

- Unifying vision among actors

- Recognizing themselves as equals, as part of a constructive learning process.

&#x200B;"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.2. % scholarship holder&apos;s /TMT participants / alumni satisfaction</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
