<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMTPLUS.20/00012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regional Water planning opportunities and innovations to increase water availability and promote climate resilience for irrigated agricultre in the Beira Agricultural growth corridor (RWPOI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">**This training program addresses regional water planning challenges from the angle of the end users. Facilitating water users to take an active role in water management, provides a fruitful entry to improve sustainability and returns on investment.**

ARA-Centro has the ambition to develop a strategy in which the water management policies will be effective. Not only by implementation of ARA Centro herself, this is impossible due to the size of the control area, but through policies and guidelines aimed at the implementation in water related projects and programs that are taking place in the BAGC by development professionals. The developing organisations, who are implementing projects and programs for and with water users, are hands-on. They work directly together with the end-user and are in possession of detailed knowledge of water users. These professionals fill the gap of detailed geographic knowledge that is missing at ARA-Centro.

Besides, the requesting parties would like to get a better insight in sustainable use of water and irrigation, e.g: alternatives for water storage, efficient water use, infiltration strategies, watershed management and more.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT+.20/00012</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience B.V.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-09098104" role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stichting Wageningen University and Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wageningen University &amp; Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8678" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-19.8315949 34.8370183</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="14081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="11006038">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-19">259590.86</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="22003730">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-03-19">129795.43</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-11-26">129795.43</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8678/Project_8678_current_image_2020-06-22_15.11.29.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Credit: Regional Water Management in BAGC Mozambique</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="9">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report. Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities. Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded. In the Grant Obligations and Conditions, the obligatory dates for submission of the annual/additional reports are mentioned. The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bottlenecks, deviations and possible adjustments</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analysis of bottlenecks which (may) have an implication on the achievement of project outputs and outcomes. Give an explanation on deviations from planning, and mention factors which had an effect on the project performance. Please elaborate on the measures that were taken in order to address the causes for deviations, delays, etc. In case of deviations in the financial statement of more than 20% of the annual budget per output and project management budget lines and of more than 20% per cost category, please explain the effect on the achievement of the planned outputs and outcomes. On the basis of the information presented, you can argue the need for, and propose adjustments to the planning. If applicable you may attach an adjusted project budget for the remaining project period. N.B. Proposals to change planned outputs need formal approval from Nuffic in advance. It is therefore essential to request approval in writing timely, and not to wait until you submit the annual report.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final report</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">If this report is a final report, the report should also focus on the following: &#x2022; Description of the achievements in the total project period in relation to the planned project output(s) and outcome(s). Assess the relevance of the outputs (impact of the project achievements on the development of the counterpart organisation and on policy priorities at national level). &#x2022; Assessment of the project approach (strategy) on effectiveness and efficiency (the relationship between the resource allocation and activities and the achieved objectives). Comment also on the risk assumptions made at the start. &#x2022; Description of changes in the project context that have had an influence on the implementation of the project. &#x2022; Analysis of bottlenecks which have occurred in the implementation of the project and the measures which have been taken to remove the bottlenecks. &#x2022; Sustainability. Describe the measures that have been taken and measures still to be taken to ensure the sustainability of the project outputs. Describe how project output(s) and outcome(s) will be continued, institutionalised and financed. Describe the factors that will have influence on sustainability. &#x2022; Name, if applicable, the spin-offs/success stories (refer to the corresponding work sheet in the achievement annex). &#x2022; Formulation of lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.

In their email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose:

&#xB7; an inventory of equipment purchased

&#xB7; a document signed by the Lead partner Dutch consortium and Lead partner consortium country A on the transfer of ownership

&#xB7; a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Follow up on conditions and recommendations</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the case of AAC recommendations, grant conditions, conditions / recommendations in previous decision letters or monitoring visit matters, please comment upon them here.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contributing to achieving the project outcomes and impact of the OKP programme in country</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section you are requested to describe the contributions which the project has made in achieving project outcomes and impacts of the Orange Knowledge programme in your country as described in the Orange Knowledge Country Plan of Implementation (CPI). To what extent does the project collaborate with other stakeholders within the same (sub)sector? In addition, project parties have to report on the coherence of their project activities with interventions supported by other donors/organisations.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">External factors and risk</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section you are requested to: a) discuss how you have managed the risks and assumptions which were identified at the start phase of the project, and b) explain any risks and assumptions that were not foreseen during the project formulation (articulation) but you have identified as likely to have an impact on the achievements of the project objectives. c) assess the actual relevance of the outcomes of the project, and of the viability of achieving the original outcomes, as stipulated in the approved project proposal. d) address any developments in the local context that may affect the project directly or indirectly (new or adjusted policies, political and socio-economic developments etc.)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other relevant information</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section, you may cover additional issues related to the project.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Analysis of results</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Please comment on the progress that you have made regarding the outputs and outcomes as mentioned in the project proposal. To what extent have they been achieved? Please provide an explanation for each of the results and comment on the activities that have taken place (so far).</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Visibility and communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RSR allows the project partners to place &#x2018;updates&#x2019; on the project page. The better the pictures and narratives are, the easier it will be to take stakeholders along in the journey and story of change of each project and create visibility for the Orange Knowledge programme. Nuffic asks all projects to upload project-specific updates in RSR at the very minimum once a year. Nuffic sees theses update as an opportunity for the partners and the projects to learn from each other: from their successes and drawback.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability is an issue that requires full attention right from the start of the project. Please highlight measures taken and achievements made during the reporting period, which are likely to contribute to the sustainability of the project outputs in four criteria: organisational, financial, technical and educational.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Holistic approach towards capacity development</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">What progress is being made in strengthening the overall capacity of the requesting organisation to deliver the products and services which are demanded by the labour market and society in general. Please differentiate between institutional, organisational, individual and educational capacity needs. please highlight the progress in procurement of investments and explain how the hardware is integrated in teaching/education. What successes and or constraints can be reported in relation to integrated capacity development and the 5 Capabilities ?</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Labour market and entrepreneurship</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">What progress is being made to relate higher education and TVET to the demands of the labour market? What are the prospects of graduates to find employment or to become self-employed?</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Opportunities for marginalised and vulnerable groups and gender perspective</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">What progress is being made to the achievement of better opportunities for marginalised and vulnerable groups, and of gender equality in project implementation as well as in the contents and delivery of education and training activities?</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">II. Partnerships between persons and organisations are inclusive and sustainable</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of Dutch training education organisations that have improved their training methods</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-21"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of MoU&#x2019;s or other types of formal collaboration agreements, or contracts, exist 1, 3, 5 years after end of project</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of staff of Dutch training education organisations that have gained new insights and ways of working</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations in line with country / regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="23"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% alumni who are promoted to a more strategic position post-study</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of scholarship holders that have successfully completed course/training (level/male/female/minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training (private/public)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of alumni who have applied the acquired knowledge and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% alumni who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. hydrometry, multi-stakeholder analyses, problem solving,</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of scholarship holders/alumni employed post-study within region and same employer (men/women)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% scholarship holder&apos;s/alumni satisfaction</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">I. Water is used sustainably and equitably, ensuring the needs of all sectors and the environment; Promote agricultural growth; Promote Water efficiency in agriculture</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">area of basins with an operational plan for integrated water
resources management (directly)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of people benefitting from operational plans for
integrated water resources management of basins (directly):</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50 000"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of professionals trained in water management
(directly)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">number of river basin delta organisations supported on water
management (directly)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">III. Organisations key to (sectoral) inclusive development of partner countries are strengthened by inflow of enhanced workforce.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">testimonials from employers on organisational changes (implemented procedure/techniques, work ethic etc. due to trained staff (critical mass)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of alumni promoted to more strategic positions within their own organisation or other organisation</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">narratives from alumni on policy and procedural changes, inclusive development, and innovations as a result of interventions</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of alumni who have applied the acquired knowledge and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% employer satisfaction on suitability of the training for the organisation</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of alumni  who state that they have applied in their workplace the knowledge and skills gained from the interventions</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of alumni still employed by the organisation that nominated them</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
