<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.20/00062</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Restructuring The Governance &amp; Management of Water in Bhutan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.20/00062</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Works and Human Settlement</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Hague Academy for Local Governance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Hague Academy for Local Governance</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="9190" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>27.4712216 89.6339041</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-18">59978.4</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9190/update/30522/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alumni Story: Strengthening Water Governance in Water Abundant Bhutan</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9190/update/32107/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training activities and conlcusions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/9190/Project_9190_current_image_2020-11-09_16.46.02.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Below is the list of the learning objectives that were mentioned in the proposal and how the TMT helped in reaching them.

&#xB7; **Defining and describing the concepts of good water governance: **

Participants had access to self-paced interactive training modules, followed by online discussions with the training team and experts, on:

- The need for good water governance

- An overview of water governance frameworks

- The integrated and multi-sectoral approaches for water governance

- Lessons learned on good water governance

- Institutional frameworks of multilevel water governance

- (Inter)national water cooperation and diplomacy

- Climate change and what it means in terms of effective water management

&#xB7; **Analysing the current water governance system in the country and identifying the main issues that are hampering its good performance:**

Participants completed in groups the two following exercises, and received afterwards written and oral feedback from the training team:

- Analysis of the status of water governance in Bhutan based on the OECD&apos;s 12 Principles on Water Governance 

- Identification and analysis of the causes and root causes of water challenges facing Bhutan using the mind map and Ishikawa diagram tools.

After the identification of the lack of reliable data by participants as a main water governance challenge in Bhutan, a 4-day face to face workshop was organised. This training activity aimed at building the knowledge and skills of the MoWHS staff and a number of their partners on data collection and sampling methods, and to establish an accurate water data baseline. 

&#xB7; **Analysing the linkages between the management and governance of irrigation and drinking water:**

Participants had access to self-paced interactive training modules on:

- Water for Irrigation 

- Public private partnerships

- Drinking water supply 

- Water pricing

During the live online meetings, the participants discussed among each other and with the experts the advantages and disadvantages of combining irrigation and drinking water responsibilities under the mandates of the new water agency in Bhutan.

&#xB7; **Discussing the success factors of international good practices of water governance:**

Participants had access to two recorded Powerpoints by senior water expert Wouter Wolters on:

- Examples of irrigation modernisation processes from around the world

- Experiences of Australia, Mexico and Pakistan with water governance reform 

Furthermore, based on the demand of the group, Wouter Wolters prepared a report about the lessons learnt from water reforms in Israel and gave his advice on which of these lessons can be relevant to the Bhutanese context.

Finally, all the experts that were involved in the training where asked to share international case studies and best practices related to water governance in their modules and online presentations. Some discussed examples:

- The institutional frameworks of multilevel water governance in South Africa by expert Eiman Karar

- Water related climate adaptation in In the Hindu Kush Himalaya region by expert Christian Siderius

&#xB7; **Designing an action plan to restructure the institutional set up for drinking water and irrigation, and to create a separate water agency initially responsible for drinking water and irrigation.**

- Participants mapped the stakeholders that have interest in or influence on irrigation and drinking water services in Bhutan, and discussed their different roles and relationships

- Participants followed two training modules on water for irrigation and drinking water 

- Participants prepared a draft proposal of an action plan with recommendations to establish the new Bhutan water agency, received feedback from THA training team and experts, and submitted the improved draft to the Royal Government of Bhutan

&#xB7; **Assessing the possibility of including the management and governance of other water activities, such as sanitation, under the mandates of the new agency that will be created:**

-The advantages and disadvantages of combining different water mandates under one water authority were discussed by expert Wouter Wolters and the representative of MoWHS during their continuous communication through all the project.

-The topic was discussed with the rest of the participants and experts Eiman Karar and Wouter Wolters during the live online meeting that followed the module on the institutional frameworks of multilevel water governance. 

**Lessons learnt and recommendations for the future:**

An ambitious and impressive list of improving the governance and management of water has been suggested by the participants. This is an indicator of their awareness and willingness to make a change. Yet, all the actions need to be made more SMART (specific, measurable, achievable, realistic and time-related). This requires a serious recognition and investment of the Bhutan government to enable its staff to make the required efforts.

One important achievement from this training is that the participants acquired a clearer view of what it takes to establish &#x2018;a new water agency&#x2019;. A coordinated approach of planning and management when thinking about national water policy will also call for more than one Ministry involved.

There is a lack of reliable water &#x2018;data&#x2019; which is a crucial challenge towards achieving good governance. The final training activity in this TMT consisted of face to face workshop on data collection, sampling and creating a data baseline. This is a step in the good direction. However, this data need to be further developed and to remain up-to-date. This requires more fianncial investment by the government, especially to collect the missing data from rural areas.

Science-based decision making is an issue in Bhutan, mainly because there is a little &#x2018;knowledge infrastructure&#x2019; in terms of colleges or universities or other institutions. More capacity building and educational programmes need to be implemented. Therefore, THA and MoWHS highly recommend to bring back Bhutan to the list of eligible countries for OKP TMT projects and individual scholarships."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="++Output 1 in the proposal:++ Increase the knowledge of 8 staff of MoWHS in the field of water governance and management.

This output was completely achieved as 16 staff of MoWHS increased their knowledge in water governance and management through the following activities:

A. 16/16 attended the first online training

7/16 attended the second online training

6 additional staff of MoWHS attended only the 4-day face to face workshop to increase their knowledge on data collection and sampling. These participants were not considered as graduates from the training since they did not complete any of the online modules on water governance. Nevertheless, they got trained on a crucial aspect of water management that is relevant for their jobs and will have access to the online training material.

In total, 22 staff of MoWHS took part in the different training activities of this project.

Adding to that, it is worth mentioning again that 3 staff from The National Environment 

Commission Secretariat, completed the second online training and gained knowledge in water governance and management, while three staff of local governments and one of the Ministry of Health completed the face to face workshop on data collection and sampling. 

B. The 16 participants who attended the first online training drafted an action plan to establish the new Bhutan water agency. After receiving feedback from the training team and completing the first online training, they improved the draft and submitted it to the Royal Government of Bhutan. Six of these participants are currently involved in the follow up on the implementation of the action plan.

++Output 2 in the proposal:++ MoWHS is able to begin with working on the tasks assigned by the Royal Government of Bhutan

As mentioned in the proposal, The Royal Government of Bhutan has asked the MoWHS to accomplish the following tasks: 

&#x2022; Task1: Identifying and analysing the issues that are hampering good water governance

&#x2022; Task 2: Restructuring the various water mandates in the kingdom

&#x2022; Task 3: Creating a separate water agency responsible for drinking water and irrigation

Output 2 was completely achieved according to the following means of verification:

++For task 1++: 

At the end of the first online training on &#x2018;good water governance&#x2019;, a report was submitted by MoWHS to the Royal Government of Bhutan identifying and describing the main challenges in the water sector. This report was reviewed twice by the training team who provided MoWHS with feedback. 

These challenges are: lack of coordination among the different ministries and agencies managing water, mismanagement of the allocated budget for water services, inadequate infrastructure and lack of infrastructure maintenance, lack of competency among water professionals, lack of available and up-to-date water data, lack of protection of water sources and poor monitoring of service delivery.

++For task 2:++

During the second online training on &#x2018;restructuring water governance and management in Bhutan&#x2019;, participants were requested by THA to suggest in writing concrete actions that their departments should implement in the ongoing water policy reform process. The actions that were identified related to the topics of: climate change adaptation, public policy making processes, administrative reforms, managing drinking water and water for irrigation, and national/local cooperation between relevant water stakeholders.

During the online closing meeting for this TMT, participants and experts were asked by THA to share their lessons learnt and final recommendations to restructuring water governance in Bhutan. Senior officials from MoWHS attended this meeting and became aware of the participants recommendations.

Although no official document has been drafted yet to create an overview of the suggested actions and recommendations above, all the information (written answers and the recorded online meeting) is archived on the online platform of the TMT project, and will remain accessible for MoWHS in the future. 

++For task 3:++

As mentioned in the first part of this question, the participants who attended the first online training submitted to the Royal Government of Bhutan an action plan with recommendations to establish the new Bhutan water agency, and 6 of these participants have been following up with the government on the implementation of the action plan."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new
            knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.5. % of scholarships awarded to minorities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation,
            supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.5. % of scholarships awarded to minorities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation, supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8"></target>
     <actual value="19.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">29-03-2022: The TMT consisted of three main training activities:
&#x2022;	A first in depth online training on &#x2018;good water governance&#x2019; from 23 November until 9 December 2020.
&#x2022;	A second in depth online training on &#x2018;restructuring the governance and management of water in Bhutan&#x2019; from 27 September until 1 November 2021.
&#x2022;	A 4-day face to face workshop in Bhutan on &#x2018;Water data collection and sampling&#x2019; from 18 until 21 October 2021.

The 19 participants that are considered graduates and who received their certificates attended at least one of the two in depth online trainings. 

Overall:
&#x2022;	16/19 graduates attended the first online training 
&#x2022;	10/19 graduates attended the second online training 

10 additional participants (4 males and 6 females) attended only the 4-day face to face workshop. However, they are not considered graduates since they did not participate in any of the two in depth online trainings.

All together 19+10= 29 participants where trained within this TMT.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="44.83">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">29-03-2022: &#x2022;	7 out of the 19 graduates are female
&#x2022;	6 out of the 10 participants who attended the 4-day face to face workshop only (not considered graduates) are females</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation, supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">31-03-2022: 1. In the face to face workshop, the hotel was chosen to be spacious and have enough rooms so female participants could have their own room and did not need to share it with other male participants to ensure that they are comfortable and safe. The hotel in itself had different sitting areas so males and females could have their own space if they wanted.
2. In the selection of the participants in the three training activities, The Hague Academy for Local Governance and the local partner ensured the maximum possible representation of females
3. During the online discussions, female participants were encouraged to speak up and share their opinions about the different topics</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.5. % of scholarships awarded to minorities</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
     <actual value="10.53">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">31-03-2022: 2 out of the 19 participants who graduated from this course are females in their mid-20s who recently joined the Ministry of Works and Human Settlement (MoWHS). They can be considered as minorities since they fall in a category that usually do not get the opportunity to participate in international trainings (new young female staff member).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="7.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">31-03-2022: The seven organisations that were strengthened by the group training are:

&#x2022;	The Ministry of Works and Human Settlement which is the requesting organisation for this TMT and from which 22 staff members were trained.

&#x2022;	The Hague Academy for Local Governance: THA and its associated experts became more knowledgeable of the Bhutanese context and gained a wider understanding of the topics of good water governance and water policy reforms.

&#x2022;	The National Environment Commission (NEC) Secretariat: This organisation was not initially one of the requesting organisations in the proposal. However, after concluding the first online training, it became clear that there is a need for the MoWHS to work and consult different stakeholders to initiate the new water agency and plan for the water policy reform. 

Due to it is crucial role in decision making on all the matters relating to the protection, conservation and improvement of the natural environment in Bhutan, 5 participants from the NEC were invited to join the second online training, of which three successfully completed it. 

The three graduates expressed how important it was for them to learn about water governance, and to exchange with the staff of the MoWHS and the experts about the topic. From their side, the NEC brought the environmental perspective to the discussion and were a great addition especially to the modules on climate change and food security.

&#x2022;	Three participants from three local governments (Paro Dzongkhag, Paro Municipality and Thimphu Thromde) and one participant from the Ministry of Health were invited to attend the 4-day face to face workshop on water data collection and sampling. These organisations represent some of the main partners of MoWHS in managing water at the local level. Their input and local knowledge were crucial to the success of the workshop, and to effectively plan the future steps to keep the collected data up to date.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">31-03-2022: &#x2022;	7 out of the 7 participants who filled the evaluation form of the first online training stated that they gained knowledge that they can apply in their daily work
&#x2022;	10 out of the 10 participants in the second online training listed the concrete knowledge and skills that they acquired from each of the different modules of that training
&#x2022;	4 out of 4 participants who filled the evaluation form of the 4-day face to face workshop stated that they acquired new knowledge from that workshop</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="The Hague Academy measured in different ways (questionnaires, written exercises and plenary discussions) the change in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes that resulted from the TMT project. Below, we illustrate some aspects of this change.

After attending the first online training, participants expressed by answering a questionnaire how the different modules and online sessions on &#x2018;good water governance&#x2019; were beneficial to their personal and professional development. Some of their reactions are: 

&#xB7; &#x2018;We learnt about the importance of engaging stakeholders for good water governance&#x2019;. This point was mentioned by three participants.

&#xB7; &#x2018;The knowledge gained from this training will definitely help me make positive contribution to the water sector in Bhutan since I am closely involved in both policy and technical related work.&#x2019;

&#xB7; &#x2018;As our Ministry is mandated with water and wastewater responsibilities, the training was very much relevant to us. The knowledge gained from this training will be useful in developing our proposal in reforming the institutional setup for water sector in our country.&#x2019;

After attending the second online training on &#x2018;restructuring the governance and management of water in Bhutan&#x2019;, participants were asked to share in writing on the online platform of the course their main takeaway lessons on each of the discussed topics, and that are relevant to their context. From their input, the change in their attitudes is visible and the actions that they want to take to improve water governance and management are concrete.  Some of their answers are:

&#xB7; &#x2018;It was good to learn about the various phases of the public policy cycle. Take away for me was developing optimal solutions considering resources available, being realistic, having specific budget for water and importance of evidence based policy.&#x2019;

&#xB7; &#x2018;Climate change is real. Things will get worse. Mountainous countries and mountain people like us will be affected more. We need to prepare and adapt to severe weather patterns. Should engage local governments and local people for effective adaptation measures.&#x2019; 

&#xB7; &#x2018;The excellent synthesis of the eight policy actions from the Comprehensive Assessment was informative in understanding the way forward for the irrigation sector. I feel even after 14 years, the recommendations in our context are still relevant, and some steps in the right direction have been taken by the government.&#x2019;

&#xB7; &#x2018;There is a need to have strong Community Based Management Approach and water cost and pricing chain to manage the scarce water resources efficiently and effectively.&#x2019;

&#xB7; &#x2018;I understood the importance of division of responsibilities specifically on the policy, implementation and regulation mandates. Also the importance to segregate the mandate on implementation and regulation to avoid conflict of interest. The involvement of water users at various level of decision making process and implementation is also key.&#x2019;

After attending the face to face workshop, participants became aware of the importance of a reliable data baseline for managing water and sanitation, and how the absence of such data has negatively impacted the capacity of MoWHS  and its partners in planning and budgeting water services. They also gained knowledge in data collection and survey sampling methods. This was mentioned in the evaluation questionnaire of the face to face workshop and during the final closing online meeting of the TMT."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="The participants in the two in depth online trainings became aware of the importance of gender inclusive governance when it comes to all the phases of the public policy making cycle.  According to the representative of the requesting organisation, as a result of the training, there is now a commitment in MoWHS to improve the mainstreaming of gender in all its water programmes. 

Special attention will be paid to gender equality in the problem identification phase and during public decision making processes. The MoWHS stated that they gained a better understanding of how water problems faced by men and women are different, and that they should be dealt with accordingly."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
