<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.19/00227</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and nutrition security through improved potato production and better propagation of seed potatoes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.19/00227</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delphy BV</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delphy BV</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research Institute Agronomique De Guinee (Institut de Recherche Agronomique de Guinee)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="9433" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.509167 -13.712222</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="31110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-01">59317.01</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9433/update/31209/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Photos of the training</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/9433/Project_9433_current_image_2021-02-03_18.10.55.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DO NOT USE Labour market and entrepreneurship</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">**(if applicable)** Describe the progress that is made in strengthening the capacity of the requesting organisation to deliver the products and services which are demanded by the labour market and society in general? Has competitiveness / efficiency been improved?
 

In case the requesting organisation is an education institution, what are the prospects of graduates to find employment or to become self-employed? Has the training had an impact on sectoral development?</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DO NOT USE Labour market and entrepreneurship</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">**(if applicable)** Describe the progress that is made in strengthening the capacity of the requesting organisation to deliver the products and services which are demanded by the labour market and society in general? Has competitiveness / efficiency been improved?
 

In case the requesting organisation is an education institution, what are the prospects of graduates to find employment or to become self-employed? Has the training had an impact on sectoral development?</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="As it says, DO NOT USE, I won&apos;t fill this out."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="The main capacity need was to get knowledge and skills on modern (seed) potato production. In the training we&#x2019;ve addressed all aspects of the production of potato (from seed to storage), and implemented this under practical circumstances. The profitability of these fields were a convincing argument for the participants and nucleus farmers. Farmers have taken up the production methods as taught in this training, and are experimenting themselves also with some of the advices. 

Through the inclusion of nucleus farmers and the demonstration days, we&#x2019;ve supported IRAG staff with linking to the local farmers&#x2019; context. This is key to support farmers in the application of good agricultural practices and modern cultivation techniques. The training included youth and women, and their role was discussed with all participants. 

On the effectiveness of the training, we have one comment. Due to COVID-19, travel restrictions and the inability to get a visa for Guinea, we&#x2019;ve had a period of almost 12 months in which the participants did not receive real-life training (except for online support on the demo fields). This meant that the last three training weeks a part was spent on the recap of the first two training weeks.  This meant that these last weeks were a refresher course and a deep-dive into new topics in one. Although this worked well for now, we have less opportunity to check the understanding of the participants of the knowledge from the last three training weeks as they were spaced close to each other. Keeping the schedule of the trainings as per training proposal would have been preferred, but the current circumstances force us to be more flexible. In the end, we&#x2019;ve managed to reach our goals and to do this efficiently given the circumstances."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="**15 staff members of IRAG (of which at least 8 women) are trained in the proposed training subject**

This output has been reached successfully. In total, fifteen staff members of IRAG (of which 8 women) have been trained on modern production of (seed) potatoes. During the training events, more people joined sporadically in the field, listening to the trainers and participants. These training events had three components; theory training in the classroom, practical training in the field, and knowledge transfer sessions. This design helped the participants to improve their understanding and skill set on good production of potatoes. 

**A demonstration plot for potato and vegetable production are established**

Two demonstration fields have been provided during the first two training weeks, for two &#x2018;nucleus&#x2019; farmers. These have been successful. Modern growing of potatoes was compared with &#x2018;business-as-usual&#x2019; growing by Guinean farmers. The farmers were very positive about the outcomes. Every 100 Guinean Francs that have been invested for the potato production, resulted in 43 francs of profit. This training under practical circumstances was very useful for the participants, as they could put their new knowledge and skills into practice. Theoretical understanding is just one part of grasping the knowledge; putting it into action is a whole different thing. 

**At least 1 demonstration days is given**

During the second training week (in 2020), our trainer has given a demonstration day. Here the training participants disseminated their knowledge about potato growing to local farmers. This was done, amongst others, through field assessment followed by providing practical growing advice. 

**Training materials on the training subjects, which are produced for the TMT, are used by IRAG staff for own trainings. **

The training materials have been handed over by the trainers, and the first steps of providing their own trainings with these materials have started by the participants. This was done during the trainings. This ensures that the participants are already familiar with explaining the content, helping them as well with their understanding of the materials. 

**5 Nucleus farmers have implemented knowledge supplied during the TMT. **

In the first part of the training (while travel was still possible), we established two demonstration fields at two nucleus farmers. These outcomes were very positive, as you have read above. Based on these outcomes, four more farmers in Dalaba have implemented this knowledge, and were supported by IRAG and CPH Dalaba (with Delphy on the background). 

**Gender issues are commonly recognised and cared for**

During the training, gender in the Guinean agricultural sector has been discussed, but also the position of female employees in IRAG. It came to the fore that the position for female employees is good within IRAG. The inclusion of (young) women in the training was helpful in this discussion."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-06-2021: IRAG, CPH Dalaba</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.3. % of scholarship holders / TMT participants / alumni employed post-study
            within region and same employer</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-06-2021: Two female participants were at the time of the training doing
                their internship. They received a position within IRAG, partly because of following
                this training. The others were already working at IRAG, and still are.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.2. % scholarship holder&apos;s /TMT participants / alumni
            satisfaction</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new
            knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="15"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="53.33"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.2. % scholarship holder&apos;s /TMT participants / alumni satisfaction</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.3. % of scholarship holders / TMT participants / alumni employed post-study within region and same employer</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-06-2021: IRAG, CPH Dalaba</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.3. % of scholarship holders / TMT participants / alumni employed post-study within region and same employer</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-06-2021: Two female participants were at the time of the training doing their internship. They received a position within IRAG, partly because of following this training. The others were already working at IRAG, and still are.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.2. % scholarship holder&apos;s /TMT participants / alumni satisfaction</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="15.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="53.33"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="In the training 8 out of 15 participants were women, two of which were interns (meaning young women). These women have had an important role in the training; they were role models for young women which were exposed to the training activities. 

Women are important in the agricultural sector, but only for work and not for decision-making. Seeing these (young) women participate in the such a training on an equal base with men, inspires young women to have a more equal role in agriculture. 

Part of the training was spent on discussing the different gender roles within the Guinean agriculture, and attention was given that the participating females were taken seriously throughout the training."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="The participants have grown in three different ways. 

1. Content-wise. The participants have learned how to cultivate (seed) potatoes using more modern technologies. Many rather basic technologies were very innovative for them. Seed potato production is a problem in Guinea. Most of the seed potatoes are imported from Europe (mainly France), and this costs of course a lot. Local seed potato production does take place, but is done in a rather unsuitable way which results in high infestation of pests and diseases. This training gave them a knowledge on how to cultivate (seed) potatoes in a good manner. 

2. Participative exercises. During the trainings, participative exercises have been conducted. Trainees were responsible for making plans for a certain field, or to investigate and explain certain specific topics, and then present this to the others. They collaboratively made plans of improvements for real-world examples. These exercises helped them to grasp the theory well, as they have to think for themselves and explain it then to the other part of the group. The trainers then gave on-the-job coaching, on both their understanding of the material, but also on the explanation. 

Once practiced this way, the participants are better able to explain it again to other groups as well. 

3. Practical training. The participants were employees of IRAG. Most of them have been educated well, but the focus on mainly theory only is a bottleneck for their work of helping the agricultural sector. The way this training was set up was meant to take them out of the classroom, and into the field. The training was taking place at CPH in Dalaba, a region in which potatoes are grown a lot. Therefore all theory could be taken directly to the field and helped the participants in identifying challenges in the field, and helping farmers with coping strategies."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
