<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.20/00047</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity building of Rwanda Water Resources Board in state-of-the-art remote sensing data and modeling tools to enable Food Security through Integrated Water Management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.20/00047</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Water</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Future Water</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda Water Resources Board</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="9423" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.9440727 30.0618851</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="38" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="31140" percentage="37" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-17">55327.91</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9423/update/30588/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Successful 3-day training in Kigali for Rwandan water professionals</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9423/update/30589/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TMT training finished with an online presentation of participants&apos; case studies</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9423/update/30587/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Tailor Made Training for Rwandan water professionals has officially started!</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/9423/Project_9423_current_image_2021-01-13_16.25.59.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="As was stated in the proposal by the requesting organization, The training should enhance capacity of the RWB staff in accessing and using innovative public-domain data and tools to analyze water resources and support water management. This is especially relevant for technical staff of RWB which need to work with such tools on a daily basis. To meet our training needs, the training should be focused on: 1. Remote sensing products and access to freely available satellite imagery; and 2. Hydrological and water allocation modelling. 

This training has greatly contributed to their needs, because whoever is able to work with Google Earth Engine can do exactly what is requested under the first focus point and the same holds for WEAP under the second focus point. 

Google Earth Engine is the perfect place to work with remote sensing products and freely available datasets. The training provided access to the GEE, it introduced the participants to the GEE environment, let them work on exercises to get familiar with GEE and some examples that could be useful for RWB were shown to them. During the case study at the end of the training, half of the participants worked on topic for which they had to use GEE, so they became even more familiar with the capabilities that GEE has. 

WEAP is a very useful to in terms of hydrological and water allocation modelling and the great benefit of WEAP is that it is free for third world countries. WEAP is a very powerful tool, because you can run WEAP with a lot of input data but also with very little input data if there is not a lot of data available. This is often an issue in hydrological modelling, a lack of input data, especially in countries in Africa. During the training the participants were helped in getting the (free) license to WEAP, they were lectured in the basics of WEAP, modifying existing models and even building simple models themselves. During the case study the other half of the participants worked on a topic using WEAP for which they had to start from scratch. 

The TMT training was, despite the circumstances with COVID-19, quite effective we believe. This is mainly due to the fact that we have used the Moodle platform to host the training, because we were able to record all lectures and video sessions, to upload all training material, to request the participants to upload answer sheets and fill in surveys for us to keep track of the progress and to make sure everything is available for them even after the training was finished. Another part that contributed to the effectiveness of the training is the fact that we were still able to go to Kigali for a 3-day onsite training, where we were able to teach most of the participants for three full days in a class room. This was of great benefit and really appreciated by the participants, because they were away from the office and really were focused on the training instead of combining the training with their normal work. The threshold to ask something was also a bit lower, which allowed for more interaction. 

Of course there were also some points that created a challenge, for example the internet connection in Rwanda was sometimes poor (due to heavy rains in the rainy season). Giving online lectures was therefore not always easy, but luckily everything was recorded and all recordings were made available on our Moodle platform. Another challenge was, as mentioned before, the fact that RWB was quite understaffed, which made it a challenge for the participants to keep up with the training (although the pace of the training was adjusted to the progress of the participants). Again, since all material and recordings are available on the Moodle platform, it was possible for the participants to keep up with the training material in their own time. 

Some lessons we&apos;ve learned / refreshed and some recommendations:

1. Use a platform like Moodle to organize all training material and record your lectures.

2. Make lectures interactive using quizzes, questions, the chat functionality etc. 

3. Make sure (if possible) to include a on-site training as part of the entire training program and make sure this training takes place on a location not to close to the office of the participants, to make sure they are fully focused on the training."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="B.1.1 About 2/3 of the participants had successfully finished the training at the deadline. However, training material and exercises etc. are still available on the FutureWater Moodle School platform for the other participants, but also for the new to be hired staff. RWB was quite a bit understaffed when the training took place and therefore part of the participants had difficulties combining the training with their daily work. However, all of the participants indicated that the Moodle platform was very useful and that most of them were working on the exercises at a moment that suited them best. Participants also indicated that they will try to finish the training after the deadline, this was also mentioned by the Head of the Department at RWB. He also indicated that new staff will be asked to work on the exercises and training material that we have developed and made available on our Moodle platform. It is therefore expected that most of the current participants, but also new staff will finish the training in the coming year.

B.1.4. / B.1.11. From all participants that followed the training, 46% were women and 54% were man. From the participants that finished the training at the deadline, also 46% were women and 54% were man. This indicates that gender is not a big issue at the RWB and that&apos;s also something that we noticed ourselves during the training, since the women were most active and really had a chance to speak up. 

B.1.8/B.1.10 We&apos;ve shared the survey results under B.1.8 but generally speaking, all participants indicated that they learned something new. Sometimes it was completely new, sometimes it was something that a few participants already were familiar with. The new skills that were obtained by the participants can really help them in understanding and quantifying IWRM related issues in Rwanda in more detail. After the training, we will stay in contact with some RWB staff through a new project mentioned before and in this project, the staff can implement their new skills and they can ask us questions in case they are stuck with something. Part of this new project will also be capacity building, in which more advanced topics will be covered, but for which they basics are needed that they obtained in this TMT training. A great example of a sustainable way of working together. 

B.O.1. The number of organization strengthened in this training in Rwanda is at least RWB, since their staff were the ones that participated in the training. However, RWB staff works closely together with other governmental and non-governmental institutes in Rwanda, which could increase the number of organizations that benefit from this training. FutureWater is the second organization that was strengthened by this group training, because we had to adapt to the COVID-19 situation and had to provide an online training course instead of on-site. This challenged us as well and we had to adapt and learn along the way of the training."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2022: In the end 13 participants were granted a certificate of
                completion of the course. We started with 20 participants, but RWB was a bit
                understaffed during the training and unfortunately there were some participants that
                were unable to follow. We did several adjustments to the training to be as flexible
                as possible, including: using the FutureWater Moodle School Elearning platform were
                all training material is made available, were recordings are available to be watched
                by those that missed the videoconference, we adjusted the pace of the training,
                extended the training with a few weeks etc. Especially the FutureWater Moodle School
                platform turned out the be very useful, because participants were positive about the
                ability to watch the recordings and be able to work on the assignments on their own
                pace and time.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2022: RWB is a public institute and we received some very positive
                feedback on the training. The participants indicated that they&apos;ve learned a lot from
                the training. We can also say that we at FutureWater (private) learned a lot from
                the training too, since we were dealing with a completely new situation (COVID 19)
                and had to adapt all the time.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new
            knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2022: We held a small survey during a final video conference and 100%
                of the participants stated that they acquired new knowledge. We also asked more
                specific questions, for example if they learning something new about WEAP (100%), or
                if they know how to use GEE in relation to IWRM (82%), if they enjoyed the course
                (100%) etc. All participants were very positive and stated that they learned a
                lot.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="46.15"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="13.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2022: In the end 13 participants were granted a certificate of completion of the course. We started with 20 participants, but RWB was a bit understaffed during the training and unfortunately there were some participants that were unable to follow. We did several adjustments to the training to be as flexible as possible, including: using the FutureWater Moodle School Elearning platform were all training material is made available, were recordings are available to be watched by those that missed the videoconference, we adjusted the pace of the training, extended the training with a few weeks etc. Especially the FutureWater Moodle School platform turned out the be very useful, because participants were positive about the ability to watch the recordings and be able to work on the assignments on their own pace and time.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2022: RWB is a public institute and we received some very positive feedback on the training. The participants indicated that they&apos;ve learned a lot from the training. We can also say that we at FutureWater (private) learned a lot from the training too, since we were dealing with a completely new situation (COVID 19) and had to adapt all the time.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10-01-2022: We held a small survey during a final video conference and 100% of the participants stated that they acquired new knowledge. We also asked more specific questions, for example if they learning something new about WEAP (100%), or if they know how to use GEE in relation to IWRM (82%), if they enjoyed the course (100%) etc. All participants were very positive and stated that they learned a lot.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="46.15"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Gender equality is already something that is very well organised in Rwanda. Rwanda is one of the most gender equal countries in the world, ranked 9th in the Global Gender Gap Report (World Economic Forum 2020). This makes Rwanda the only African country in the top 10 and ranked higher than countries such as Germany, Denmark and France. The gender equality is also very well visible in the Parliament of Rwanda, with a women representation of 61.9% and equal number of women and men in the Cabinet. Looking at our participants that finished the training, almost half (6/13) of them were women."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="We have taught the participants two work with two different models: WEAP for water allocation and planning, and Google Earth Engine to be used as a tool for IWRM. This is something the almost all participants at RWB had never worked with, so this is a definite improvement in the attributes that are used by RWB staff. We also gave several lectures on IWRM."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
