<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.19/00158</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From water scarcity to sustainable water use by vulnerable communities in rural areas in Palestine</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A tailor made training will be able to design a specific training based on the needs described for the participants described in an evidence based manner with reliable solutions that can be used within the Palestinian context. The training should include the following subjects:  

1. Community based Interventions 

2. Local Governance based interventions</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.19/00158</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BE Link Consultancy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BE Link Consultancy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juzoor</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8083" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.89972 35.21016</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="11002016">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">74648.58</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="22001390">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">59718.86</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-30">59718.86</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8083/Project_8083_current_image_2020-12-08_10.04.59.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="First of all, I would like to take this opportunity to thank Nuffic-OKP for supporting our collaboration with Juzoor for Health and Social Development since 2016 and in this TMT project in particular. 

Our overall conclusion is that this project went very well. We have managed to tailor the trainings further to the needs of Juzoor and organise two out of three trainings face-t0-face in Istanbul, Turkey and Ramallah, Palestine. Additionally, we managed to train 50% (28 instad of 14) more staff members.One of the lessons we have learned from this project, is to be not too flexible with requesting organisations in postpone training dates. We learned to try to stick with original planning. Due to the postponement of the last training reagrding WASH, we faced the COVID-19 in the second quarter of 2020 which caused delay. However, by analysing the situation carefully and communicating with all stakeholders, we find a suitable solution. It was a new approach to us which caused some anxiety within the project team. Fortunately, by applying the Hybrid approach (a combination of online and offline) our Dutch and local trainer could faciliate an effective training which is reflected by the positive response of trainees.  

&#x200B;"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="_**Output 1:**__ the trained staff is enabled to conduct and implement in close cooperation with key-stakeholders interventions to create awareness among vulnerable communities on sustainable water us age in rural areas:_

_**Output 2:**__ the trained staff is enabled to review and adjust current curricula and approaches regarding WASH:_

To achieve output 1 &amp; 2, we have organised a 5 days training titled: _Efficient Water Usage by Vulnerable Communities_. Through this training 23 (instead of 15 participants as mentioned in the logframe) relevant staff members of Juzoor gained deeper insights into the water topics such as: _water management, water4food, water vs. health, water vs. climate change and WASH_. As we were not able to organise this training face-to-face due to COVID-19 travel restrictions, we have applied a Hybrid approach (a combination of online and offline). Whereby our Dutch and local trainer worked together to implement an interactive and impactful training. The trained staff were assigned with follow-up activities to apply the gained knowledge at Juzoor. We have evaluated the training outcomes both with the participants and trainers. The overall response was positive. The participants scored the training in terms of relevance and importance with a 8.5 out of 10. Therefore, we conclude that these outputs, despite some practical challenges such as internet connection, are achieved by 85%. 

_**Output 3: **__the trained staff is enabled to design and execute projects effectively:_

In order to deliver on output 3, we have implemented a 5 days training on Project Management in the Development Sector (PMD). This training was organised in Ramallah and 15 relevant staff members participated. As follow-up to the training, the participants were provided with the opportunity to become certified project managers based on international standards. We facilitated online exams at the PMD organisation to enbale the participants gain internationally recognised certificates. As for the content of the training, we have used a practical approach and facilitated a real-life project cycle managment. More specifically, the participants were introduced to the art and science of project management. Right after discussion of the theorie, the participants were assigned with tasks to perform different stages of project cycle based on cases. With the idea to later on transfer these cases  into real interventions benefitting the organisation and its beneficiaries. During the last day of the training, all participants are tasked with a follow-up action plan to improve the project management guidelines and systems at Juzoor. The training is highly valued by the particpants and scored 9 out of 10. We conclude that we have achived this output with 90%. 

**Additional output: **    
Based on the needs and request of Juzoor, we have also organised a 3 days training** Strategic planning &amp; management  **in Istanbul, Turkey.

The main purpose of the strategic planning and management programme was to enable Juzoor to devise a new strategy for the period 2020-2023. 

Initially, the programme was intended for the management staff of Juzoor, ie, 12-14 persons. However, Juzoor determined it more beneficial for all staff to attend as well as its board members. In total therefore 26 persons attended the programme. To manage the event efficiently, two groups were formed; one with Juzoor management and board members and the second with operations staff. A local/Palestinian trainer worked with the latter group. However, for purposes of coherent organisation strengthening and team building, the BeLink consultant worked with all 26 participants at the beginning and end of the programme.

++Since its previous strategy session in 2016, Juzoor has performed well. Three points are worth highlighting:++

1. Juzoor&#x2019;s overall program and service offering in Policy &amp; Advocacy, Community Development and Continuous Professional Development has proved to be resilient and beneficial to the Palestinian society.

2. Younger staff members have a very positive view of Juzoor, summarised as:

- Belief and passion in the mission of Juzoor

- Willingness to pursue excellence

- Feeling of working in a dynamic environment with opportunities for growth

3. Juzoor&#x2019;s financial performance (Annex 2), over the period 2017 &#x2013; 2019, has been healthy. Most remarkably, Juzoor rendered services now account for around 9 per cent of total annual revenues, compared to less than 1 per cent in previous years. Hence, Juzoor&#x2019;s reliance on donor agencies, whilst still very high, has decreased.

++The following seven areas were determined to be important and necessary for inclusion in the formulation of the 2020-2023 Juzoor Strategy1:++

1. Adopt a slight change in Juzoor&#x2019;s vision/mission to reflect a broader more inclusive organisation.

2. Maintain Juzoor&#x2019;s focus on its core activities, ie, Policy &amp; Advocacy, Community Development and Continuous Professional Development.

3. Formulate a new organisation chart that reflects its operations and staff roles and responsibilities accurately.

4. Create a reserve fund of US$100,000 to combat cashflow difficulties.

5. Plan to own Juzoor&#x2019;s own premises to avert rental costs and derive more flexibility in the utilisation of space.

6. Create a digital repository for access by staff to monitor project status, progress, reports, etc.

7. Increase staff engagement to further improve organisational performance by scheduling:

- Monthly staff meetings as well as project related, technical meetings

- Quarterly innovation workshops

- Annual retreat for all staff

The trained staff members were assigned with back-to-homework to internalise the gained knowledge and produce the Strategy Plan 2020-2023. 

**Deviation from the original plan:**
- Training on WASH is organised based on a Hybrid approach instead of face-to-face
- The training on Stakeholders Management is replaced by Project Management with emphasise on stakeholders management
- Additional training on Strategic Planning is provided

**Impression and participants list:**
Please see attached documents. 

&#x200B;"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="28.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2021: 28 staff members of Juzoor for Health and Social Development (Juzoor) has directly benefited from the trainings under the TMT-project</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Female"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Male"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Minorities"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="85"></target>
     <actual value="85.71">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2021: During the training evaluation, around 85% of the trained staff have stated that have acquired new knowledge skills in effective communication and project management.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">28-04-2021: This section is not applicabale since we didn&apos;t had any scholarship withing this TMT-project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Juzoor is strengthened via the TMT interventions to constructively develop an implement a strategic plan, to develop and implement effectively water interventions</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Type of organisation" value="Private"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Type of organisation" value="Public"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="1.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="&gt; Project team members have learned to communicate more openly and professionally to manage expectations, divide role and responsibilities to work more efficiently &amp; effectively

&gt; The leadership has more in-depth insights into their leadership style and improved/ adjust it to lead their departments more effectively"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Gender equality has been a very important aspect of Juzoor&apos;s policy trhoughout the past years. Therefore, gender equality is well balanced in the workplaces at Juzoor accros Palestinian Territories. This is also reflected in the number of female participants with leadership positions in the trainings."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
