<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.21/00036</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening agricultural education in Tunisia by teaching trainers on climate
        smart horticulture &amp; entrepreneurship</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.21/00036</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre Sectoriel de Formation Professionnelle Agricole</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cultures Mara&#xEE;ch&#xE8;res de Primeurs de Chott Mariem</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delphy BV</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delphy BV</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="9694" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>35.8245029 10.634584</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="75" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-05-01">59994.55</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9694/update/31593/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Module 2 Soil - The Foundation of Agriculture</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9694/update/31847/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Module 4 - The Principles of Greenhouse Cultivation</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9694/update/32062/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Module 5 - With greenhouse cultivation production is a measure of
          success!</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/9694/Project_9694_current_image_2021-04-12_15.59.16.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant
          government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual
          projects and the programme as a whole. For project partners, it is compulsory to use the
          prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project
          achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of
          the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project
          output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by
          the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and
          budget must be made clear in the annual report. Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and
          not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement
          of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the
          annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project
          and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s)
          and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as
          a whole. Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning,
          reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more
          elaboration is demanded. In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual
          reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are
          obligatory. The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific
          conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in
          achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the
          report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted. The final
          report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report) Reflect on how the
            training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting
            organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in
            reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations
            for the post-project period. + In your email submitting the final report, the partners
            will enclose: - an inventory of equipment purchased - a document signed by the (Lead
            partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting
            organisation on the transfer of ownership - a list with the names and email addresses of
            staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland
            Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="A gap exists within the transition from school to work. Chott Mariem&apos;s teachers do not have sufficient knowledge on climate smart agriculture, modern greenhouse management including irrigation, fertigation and climate control, on greenhouse establishment, and on entrepreneurship, which are priority themes in the agricultural sector. Consequently, the staff are not able to teach the students on these topics, which causes a gap between the competencies of TVET graduates and the needs within the agricultural sector. Moreover, the Tunisian education system lacks interactive teaching techniques, soft skills, and coaching, which enlarges the gap between graduated students and the job market. By training the staff on above mentioned topics, this programme contributed to bridging the knowledge gap of the staff.

The main lessons learned are:

1. Mixing theory, practice, online and on-site training creates a dynamic training;
2. Having a demonstration cultivation in the greenhouse fosters experimental learning;
3. Providing online cultivation advice in between on-site training weeks is very useful to keep production going and the participants motivated;
4. Combining trainers from multiple TVETs causes a bigger difference in backgrounds but is very good for creating connections.

It is recommended to implement a follow-up training programme to update and extend the gained theory and skills. The focus should be on:

1. Production of other crops (for instance tomato or pepper, which are the main crops in greenhouse vegetable production and also important on the Tunisian market);
2. Extending the knowledge gained on entrepreneurship, for instance by giving the participants their own demonstration greenhouse for one cultivation cycle. They will receive some money to start cultivation and are expected to return it after the cultivation cycle. They will have to buy inputs for cultivation (seeds, substrate etc), manage cultivation (crop work, coordinating labour), marketing and selling their produce, and lastly managing their inputs and outputs by making a business plan.

Moreover, it is recommended to continue stimulating collaboration and knowledge sharing between the TVETs, for instance by hosting demonstration days and visiting each other&#x2019;s demonstration greenhouses and open fields."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the
            project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the
            activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Eighteen participants were trained within the programme, from three different TVETs and one participant from AFVA. The programme has offered them both knowledge and skills in content as on knowledge transfer and blended learning. The staff were trained on all aspects of cultivation, starting from climate smart agriculture and the principles of greenhouse cultivation, going to post-harvest and business management. To foster experimental learning a demonstration greenhouse wasestablished, where cucumber was grown. The cultivation of cucumber was online supported in-between training weeks. Moreover, the participants visited a nursery for vegetable seedlings and multiple greenhouses, including the greenhouse established as part of the TMT+ with LSFPAAV Bouch&#xE9;rik and the one established as part of the TMT+ with CFPA El Alia."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation,
            supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="2.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-02-2022: 1) Gender equal atmosphere &amp; training material 2) Minimum
                of at least half participating female trainers</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-02-2022: Plus two representatives of agricultural institutions ( cellule
                territoriale de vulgarisation Akouda &amp; Union r&#xE9;gionale de l&apos;agriculture et
                de la p&#xEA;che</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new
            knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="18.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="72.22"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Actually already more than half of the trainers at CSFPA Chott Mariem are female. Also, 70% of the participants in the training were female. This had a direct and indirect effect. Direct as the capacity of the female teachers was strengthened. Indirect, as female students face successful role models, and with this gain self-esteem and a positive mind set on their possibilities in (Tunisian) society. Moreover, young female trainers from iCRA and Delphy were included to give the right example. Gender equality was discussed throughout the trainings, and it became apparent that the TVET already is very open minded and tolerant towards this."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="The participants were trained on knowledge transfer, blended learning and entrepreneurship. This gained knowledge and skills are implemented within their own teaching, slowly transforming the traditional education system within Tunisian TVETs. Moreover, the participants were trained on climate smart agriculture, greenhouse production and cultivation practices of cucumber. Also, this gained knowledge and skills are currently implemented by the trainers, using the established demonstration greenhouse to foster experimental learning within the TVET."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation, supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
