<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.19/00062</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creating livelihood opportunities for women, youngsters and small farmers through poultry farming in the Nanded district, India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) After the training 20 trainers have relevant knowledge on broiler production and are able to share this knowledge through blended learning techniques.

2)400 youngsters, women and drop-outs are trained per year.

3) In one year time the farmer&#x2019;s income will have risen from RS15 to RS25 per bird.

4) In five years&#x2019; time the total number of poultry farms in this district will have risen from 110 to 150. These new farms will be run by young people and women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.19/00062</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sanskriti Samvardhan Mandal is a village based voluntary organization with a view to educate and empower the deprived rural community. The focus of its activities has always been on the deprived rural communities, especially women and girls. 

Nanded District is one of the most backward districts of Maharashtra. The district comes under Marathwada region which is extremely water scarce and drought prone area. Due to the water scarcity, agricultural production and therefore the incomes are quite unpredictable. To tackle this, farmers need to be trained in alternative businesses like poultry farming that can assure livelihood in extreme climatic conditions such as drought. Although Krishi Vigyan Kendra provides courses on poultry production, they have discovered that we are lagging behind in knowledge and experience. By developing the (practical) knowledge of the trainers, they will be better prepared for training and advising people. These trainings will eventually lead to higher production numbers, which will make poultry production a very good alternative for (more) women and young people. And that will lead to more prosperity in this area. 

We have planned two trainings for teachers, trainers, extension workers and farmers. In turn they will share their knowledge with their own target group. Thus at least 400 people per year will be reached through this training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8059" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>19.1595 77.3109</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11430" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-24">59338.4</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11001994">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">74174.22</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="22001370">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">59339.37</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="11008253">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-06">-8969.22</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="22005425">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2021-01-06">5865.63</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8059/document/Participants_KHv6Kfz.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participants</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A03"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8059/IMG_20191104_142338.jpg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trainer with participants at broiler house, credit: Trainer with participants at broiler house</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="https://www.aerestrainingcentre.com/?_ga=2.209291867.870608107.1547031370-1316506360.1539671127">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">http://ssmandal.net/krishi-vigyan-kendra-kvk/</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="I have filled in this document at the end of the project and actually everything has been said already. To conclude this project I express the hope that the Covid-19 crisis will be over soon and that we can start working on the activities as described in the MOU. Besides that I hope that we will find sponsors for future activities with the training centre. This appears to be quite a challenge, but we are not without hope. 
The least we can do is start an online project between Aeres students and students from Sanskriti Samvardhan Mandal. That, of course is the advantage of being a member of the big Aeres family in which we have several institutes for lower, intermediate and higher vocational education.">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">08-02-2021: I have filled in this document at the end of the project and actually everything has been said already. To conclude this project I express the hope that the Covid-19 crisis will be over soon and that we can start working on the activities as described in the MOU. Besides that I hope that we will find sponsors for future activities with the training centre. This appears to be quite a challenge, but we are not without hope. 
The least we can do is start an online project between Aeres students and students from Sanskriti Samvardhan Mandal. That, of course is the advantage of being a member of the big Aeres family in which we have several institutes for lower, intermediate and higher vocational education.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Despite the difficult start of the project (the fact that so few women were present) we are very satisfied with the final results. A highlight for us was experiencing how the whole group transformed from docile and passive to enthusiastic and active in a fortnight. This way we achieved this was by offering a programme that alternated between theory and practice. But also the theory lessons were activating. It was uncomfortable for everyone in the beginning to take part in group activities that had the intention of &apos;loosening&apos; them and waking up their brains. However, the result was astonishing. There grew dynamic and self-confidence in the group, especially among the farmers and women who normally stay in the background. The icing on the cake was when the training was visited by a senior civil servant and the participants were given the opportunity to share the results of the training. The farmers (picture) stood there full of self-confidence and effortlessly complemented each other in their account of the training. Actually, it was already great to see how the participants grew as human beings. It was also special to hear during the second training a few months after the first one that the farmers had already achieved clear results with their new approach to farm management. The figures they put on the table (something they had learned during the first training - keeping track of results) spoke volumes. This was so striking that even one of our trainers, who has years of experience with this kind of training, was impressed. Other impacts of the training: An MOU has been signed with our educational partner Sanskriti Samvardhan Mandal to come to follow-up training. The challenge now is to find funding for this and we are still working on it. Part of the MOU is that people from this organisation will come to Barneveld for training at a reduced rate, but unfortunately the Corono crisis has thrown a spanner in the works. All participants are included in our alumni network. This means that they are included in our mailings and have access to our Alumni Facebook page. In addition, the participants have started a whatsapp group to share information with each other. All participants are still working in the positions they were in when the training started. This is particularly relevant for the trainers and extension workers who participated in the training. The requesting organisation (SSM) has been very positive about the results of the training and would like to train more teachers, especially when it comes to didactic skills. Besides people from the requesting organisation, four participants from other organisations joined the training. These organisations are mainly involved in training young people with disabilities: - Trinita Society for Social and Health Research (West Bengal) - Handicapped Development Foundation (Manipur) - Child Guidance Centre/CARDS (Guntur) We already had contact a Dutch foundation that is connected to these Indian parties, and for them this was a great opportunity. Especially the participant from Guntur had to make quite a journey for this. Partly thanks to this addition, we got well over the intended number of participants of 20 and we are quite sure that at least 400 youngster, women and drop-outs are reached with this new knowledge per year."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rise in employment and opportunities through poultry training.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Income rise per bird in one year (15 to 25)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="25.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-12-2020: Definitely the income has increased per bird due to --
1) Better feed conversion ratio, use of quality inputs.
2) Reduction in mortality due to bio security measures used by the farmers
3) Better management has also resulted in better gain in weight therefore the resulting effect of gain in income from Rupees 15 to rupees 25 it has been achieved by most of the participants.

Taken from evaluation form as supplied by SSM Sagroli.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">After the training 20 trainers have relevant knowledge on broiler production and are able to share this knowledge through blended learning techniques</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20"></target>
     <actual value="28.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-12-2020: During the training in which several teaching methods were adopted where the learning of the training had to be used by the participants in their field.
In the period between the two trainings they had to assess and evaluate a Poultry farm from their nearby area, so has to implement these learnings on that farm.
During the period emphasis was given to hands on training. Trainees were doing all management practices inside and outside of the shed.
Plenty of group discussions were conducted during the training which has also helped participants to apply the learning in to their real life situation. Such types of cross learnings helped trainees to clarify all complex issues.
Participants were asked to present the assignment in terms of training the farmers, in terms of evaluation of poultry farm. It has helped in better learning and understanding of the technical content by the participant.
During the training we visited few poultry farm. We could personally see and discuss the impact of the technology, we could discuss the shortcomings, and it&#x2019;s strong and weak points that were also a good learning.
Videos -- several videos were shown to the participants who give us advance knowledge in poultry industry.

Taken from the evaluation form as filled in SSM Sagroli.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">400 youngsters, women and drop-outs are trained per year</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
     <actual value="400.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-12-2020: The six organisations that has been strengthened during the training have a major mandate of training the farmers and women&#x2019;s on poultry as an enterprise and therefore through the extension activities of these six organisations we have reached targeted number of farmers to be trained further on regular basis.
Because of covid-19 the dissemination method has changed we are not able to visit the farm as such but still the technology shared digitally getting excellent response.

From evaluation SSM Sagroli

The picture shows participants with local women who were trained by them as part of this program.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="75"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">01-12-2020: It was amazing to see that after the first training women and farmers (drop-outs) were able to present themselves and express their ideas about certain topics, even before a high official who came to visit this project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">15-12-2020: The following organisations where strengthened&#x2014;
1. SSM,
2. Siddhivinayak poultry Satara,
3. Innocent smile foundation Chennai,
4. Innocent smile foundation kolkatta and
5. Innocent smile foundation Manipur,
6. District Livestock department government of Maharashtra.
Trainees from these institutes were trained therefore these institutes are strengthened, In addition 12 rural youths who were engaged in poultry farming participated in the training in which they gained knowledge and strengthened.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for a participation of 50% females.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="28.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">22-12-2020: Sadly, only six females participated in the course. This was contrary to what we had agreed on, but we we were happy that we could double the number after we started with three women on the first day. During the trainings that were given by our participants more local women and female students were involved.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="6.00">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Female"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="22.00">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Male"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Minorities"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="As reported already it was a challenge to get enough women involved, but we have succeeded also through the second training in which are participants played a role in teaching others."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Part of the training was a visit to local farms, a parent stock farm, a hatchery and a slaughterhouse. In this way, the context of poultry farming was visualised and it became clear to participants how the links lie within the entire chain. Considering the reactions of the participants, this was an eye-opener for them. Certainly as far as the teachers and extension workers are concerned, this will translate into the way in which they will share their poultry knowledge with students and farmers. (Picture of parentstock farm)"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
