<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.19/00013</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing capacity of &apos;Dalit&apos; towards sustainable SRHR services for dalit population</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As an organization, Dalit is lagging behind than other organizations in terms of capacity, experience and resources. There is lack of skills and knowledge in strategic thinking among the members of apex bodies (executive and general board).The TMT aims to strengthen the management capacity that will provide new knowledge, skills and helps to build confidence amongst the relatively young and inexperienced staff who could be the potential change makers. This will encourage them to stay within the organisation and thereby ensuring the sustainability of the organization.The training on leadership and peoples&#x2019; management

could help them to deal with management issues related to coordination and communications among staff and offices. This TMT will enable the capacity development in advocacy &amp; lobbying, networking, negotiation, and conducting high-level dialogues. This will guide Dalit to play a key role in &#x2018;sounding board&#x2019; to create visibility with the strong message. Besides, developing an effective monitoring framework will ensure efficient information flow, effective results-based management and documentation there by pave the way to develop a knowledge management system. This could be the base for organizational learning, transparency, visibility, legitimacy, knowledge sharing for advocacy, etc.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="4" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.19/00013</narrative>
  </description>
  <description akvo:type="8" type="2" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The TMT aims to help Dalit to implement its projects more effectively and become a sustainable institution that can provide SRHR services and effectively use gender and SRHR as a crosscutting theme in its efforts to improve the lives of the dalit communities. Since Dalit is one of the pioneers in developing change-makers among the dalit community, this model could be more effective if Dalit increase their capacity in terms of knowledge, skills and attitude and provide professional support to the change-makers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dalit</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MDF Training&amp;Consultancy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MDF Training&amp;Consultancy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8031" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>22.845641 89.5403279</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="13010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction ref="11001976">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">74925.51</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="22001353">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-05-27">59940.41</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-06-15">59940.4</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8031/Project_8031_current_image_2019-10-10_13.35.35.JPEG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dr. Mubina Tabassum, credit: In search of Knowledge!</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="As the pioneer SRHR organization for the caste discriminated society, the project has been highly relevant for Dalit as it could meet the capacity requirements of the targeted staff through different activities. Also, it could support the senior management to deal with the Covid-19 in a better way. As a result, despite the postponement of activities for few months the project has achieved all its objectives with the exception of result 2.1 where the advocacy and policy strategy is yet to be formulated. As mentioned by MDF in the proposal, this would be done through the coaching sessions after the project period considering the convenience of the related staff. For result 2.2, the monitoring system upgraded by developing the M&amp;E frameworks and results tracker; but the Knowledge Management system development is yet to happen as due to Covid-19, a lot of activities had to be done within last quarter of the extended project period. However, it is already in the action plan of the organization. On the other hand, the Covid-19 caused Dalit to focus strongly on (financial) sustainability. The staff became more confident because of the training and there have been visible changes within organization by the trained and capacitated staff. Two submitted proposals were already won in recent times. Contribution of the staff supported changes in the Gender and Safeguarding policies as well.

The change process is not always easy; it is an acculturation process which requires time and attention. To make the changes accepted and efficient, few areas could be focused by Dalit;

- Practice and apply the new knowledge and skills to enhance the capacity.
- The newly formed teams as the results of the TMT; such as Business Development team, Resource Mobilization team, need to be supported and followed-up and should maintain an effective coordination between them.
- The Business Development team need regular support and follow-up to ensure the progress and to establish a well-equipped business Plan.
- Restructure or review the areas of intervention to cope up with the new trends and the shifted funding modalities.
- Moreover, it is highly recommended that to have a plan for staff&#x2019;s coaching in regular and systematic basis to support and ensure the growth of the staff and the organization."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Since the project started in 2019, the status of the progress and achievements are shown below according to the outcomes and outputs:

**Outcome 1: Dalit functions as an &#x2018;incubator&#x2019; to create active &#x2018;change makers&#x2019; / &#x2018;ambassadors&#x2019; from the dalit community for the protection of their SRHR.**

A series of training on selected areas provided by MDF to Dalit under a comprehensive training package consisting of management development, business development, SRHR, resource mobilization and fund raising, advocacy and policy influencing. It is observed that the participants have well received the trainings and were open for new knowledge and showed the interest to apply the learning in their workplaces and day to day life as well. However, the trainings, increased the confidence of Dalit staffs and the know-how in preparing an advocacy message for Dalit community. The staff, especially the staff from the marginalized community (&#x2026;.) has gained better capacity to understand and practice different skills through these training as active &#x2018;change makers.

**Outcome 2: Dalit created a &#x2018;sounding board&#x2019; to advocate and lobby the SRHR issues to protect the women of dalit community.**

Dalit as the CSO lead, has been able to establish a Coalition for Dalit Right (CfDR) along with 10 CSO and CBOs at Khulna District in the aim of exploring dalit human rights. CfDR is dedicated to raising voice together for promoting and protecting human rights of dalit peoples. Earlier also, Dalit continued advocacy, mobilization, awareness, coordination and networking interventions.

**Result 1.1: Empowered strategic leadership available in all tiers of Dalit management.**

Training on Strategic Leadership and Change Management for the senior management and Leadership and People Management to the second and third (hierarchy) tiers were conducted. This was followed with series of coaching. The coaching sessions have taken place one to one where the participants developed their own action plan for personal management development. Moreover, the training introduced different approaches and techniques which are contributing to instill specific characteristics, thought to be strategically sound and skilled. As planned, 4 staff members has been identified as potential leaders from different level who could take leadership role in future.

**Result 1.2: Project staff and the organization staff are capacitated with sufficient / updated knowledge in SRHR related issues.**

Two trainings conducted for senior management and field managers on advanced and Basic SRHR knowledge and practice consecutively. It was observed that the training opened new window for the staff members especially, gender transformative approach. The causes and consequences of SRHR issues and reflecting of personal values and norms regarding SRHR issues being part ofthat. The training contributed to reflect and refine their understanding and helped to grasp the cultural attribution in the present context. It is expected that the new knowledge will be used in their next program design as well.

**Result 1.3: Dalit management and staff acquired the relevant knowledge and skills to transition into a self-reliant organization and providing sustainable services.**

A Sustainable Business Development Approach training helped them to develop an understanding in identifying alternative and creative sources of funds for their own sustainability. Moreover, At the end of the course a business development team is formed with some dedicated staff members worked on further development. MDF expert conducted series of coaching on different aspects of business development canvas based on their business development case. Dalit staffs are trained on different aspects of business development through follow-up training on Resource Mobilization and Fund raising, Financial Planning, Managing Client Feedback etc. Those coaching and follow-up training enhanced their capacity in business development. Following through the journey, Dalit team developed a draft business plan for the Dalit hospital and Dalit Aurvedic Center. However, Dalit might still need external support until they become less donor dependent gradually and the transition towards a self- reliant and sustainable organization. Following the Resource Mobilization and Fund raising training, Dalit formed a team for resource mobilization which is now working on searching for new funds and modalities for developing new projects. To strengthen the knowledge of increasing fund-raising capacity, MDF provided a three days training on &#x2018;Writing a Winning proposal&#x2019; to the key staff members. It helped participants to identify the gaps and area of improvement in identifying potential donors and to write quality proposals. Besides this will strengthen their fund mobilization activity in future.

**Result 2.1: Advocacy, lobbying and policy influencing strategy operationalized for SRHR issues.**

The training on Advocacy and Policy influencing was an eye-opener for the participants. It was a new learning for the Dalit staffs. In Bangladesh, the rights issues of the caste- discriminated communities are still not clearly addressed. So, the challenges are extensive comparing to other rights-based programmes. However, it was found that considering the current context, the Advocacy and Policy influencing training has contributed significantly to gain confidence to make strategic choices to deal with the challenges. Dalit has formulated an advocacy message during the training- _**&#x201C;No one remains deprived of his rights because of his/her birth identity&#x201D;.**_ In the recent covid pandemic situation the advocacy work is going comparatively slow. However, the team will resume work in full pace once situation becomes normal.

**Result 2.2: The Monitoring system upgraded with systematic documentation for knowledge management (KM) system**

After the training, the M&amp;E staff of Dalit has systematized their initiatives in quality assurance. They are intended to analyse and disseminate the information with other project focals and utilizing the learning from the training to develop effective monitoring tools for designing and tracking the programs/results systematically. To track the programs/results systematically, Dalit recently have developed a results tracker with the direct support of the M&amp;E staff. To achieve the results to the fullest, Dalit is yet to develop a full-fledged knowledge management system. At present, they are planning for a resource center to preserve and showcase the knowledge materials that has been produced so far.

&#x200B;"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.9. % alumni / TMT participants who are promoted to a more strategic position post-study</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_25% of alumni of which 10% women, are promoted to a more strategic position within 3 years after the TMT_</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.26">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: 1 female participant who were working as Community Development Organizer participated in both SRHR and Advanced SRHR training. She was promoted as Field Supervisor after receiving both of the training due to her activeness in the project activities.
Another female participant, who were working as unpaid &apos;Watch Group member&apos; has been promoted as a &apos;Paid Volunteer&apos; to another project after receiving the training.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: 100% of the participants stated that they have learnt at least some thing new from different training. Some training was totally new for them such as Writing Winning Proposal, Advanced SRHR and Resource Mobilization. It is observed that the participants&#x2019; renewed knowledge helped significantly in improving quality of service and management decision making process. However, it is expected, it will take time to have an effect on &#x2018;mind-shift&#x2019; to have an improved and open management system and organizational culture. It is an acculturation process which has been starting in different tiers that were also observed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.2. % scholarship holder&apos;s /TMT participants / alumni satisfaction</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="95"></target>
     <actual value="95.74">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: 95% staff expressed their satisfaction on different training topics. Apart from training delivery, other logistical arrangements were also part of this satisfaction. Most of the participants rated the training as &quot;good&quot; or &quot;very good&quot; in the training evaluations. 
A comment on the Advanced SRHR training is:
&quot; If a person and an organization wants to keep pace with the reality of life, they should participate in the training courses facilitated by MDF&quot; 
Another comment on Advanced SRHR:
&quot; I consider this as a great opportunity that I could participate in this training of MDF and i could learn a lot about the reality from this course. This type of training is very much necessary as it opens our eyes and helps us to support the targeted participants of the projects&quot; 
A comment on M&amp;E training:
&quot; Overall, this training was so essential for our organization in future to implement the field activities&quot;
Comments on Strategic Leadership and Change Management:
&quot;This training is very good. It will make our work sustainable, Thanks MDF.&quot; 
&quot; This training was beyond my expectation. It helps me to know myself scientifically, emotionally and practically. I can say its a mirror training for me. Thanks again, again and again.&quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: According to the staff of Dalit, 100 % of the trained staff were able to apply the acquired training knowledge somehow in their work. The application also depended on their nature of work and chance to apply. Few staff, especially who are working currently as managers and also as monitoring officers, as reported, could use the training in multiple directions; while others could use to some extent.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation, supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_3 facilities will be created by MAIL and it will develop and implement a gender policy to increase the number of female staff and to create a more women friendly environment within the Ministry._</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: Multiple initiatives were taken to provide extra facilities to the female participants such as females were encouraged generally to participate in the training programs, they were given secured residential facilities which included female friendly venue and toilet. Besides, the non residential training were scheduled to be finished on time and female staff were supported by males while returning home after the training when it was necessary. Females were also given preferences regarding distribution of computer/ laptops for official use.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_1 organisation (MAIL) is  strengthened directly by the TMT. As follow-upt to the TMT, the trained staff will transfer the gained knowledge to fellow collegaues in 5 district offices within 1 year after the project. _</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: The organization &apos;Dalit&apos; is strengthened by this TMT.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Type of organisation" value="Private"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Type of organisation" value="Public"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.4. Number of organisations developed and implemented a gender strategy</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_1 organisation (MAIL)developed and implemented a gender strategy. This central policy will be also applied to all district offices in the country_</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: The organization has updated the Gender and Safeguarding Policy. The updated gender policy included 4 months maternity leave with pay which was earlier only 2 months. In addition, 7 days paternity leave which was earlier 3 days. One female staff also has been assigned as the &apos;Gender Focal&apos; person of the organization. 

The Safeguarding Policy included &apos;0 tolerance&apos; for sexual harassment at all level of organization and target beneficiaries.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.3. Number of organisations with institutional mechanism for quality assurance</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">_1 organisation (MAIL) has developed performance indicators for quality assurance_</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: The quality control is strengthened by the newly developed M&amp;E framework and results tracker of the project. These 2 things have been developed as an direct output of the M&amp;E training. The trained staff also have started developing M&amp;E framework of other projects.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="47.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">02-08-2021: Total target participants of this TMT was 50. However, 47 participated, among them 25 participants were from minority community (caste discriminated community).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Female"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Male"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Minorities"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="N/A"></target>
     <actual value="N/A"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Several changes in attitudes and attributes has been noted among the staff members after receiving the training:

Personal:

Staff are showing increased level of confidence as they received training on different topics related to their professional activities. They seem to understand and perform better in their current role and can meaningfully contribute in project and organizational activities. the staff working as the team lead started to inspire the team members by practicing different leadership and management skills.

Professional:

They exchange dialogues more confidently among colleagues and other in different forums. The proactively communicates with the stakeholders who are the rights holders and enthusiastically participate in organizational activities as &apos;Change makers&apos;."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Some initiatives were taken to improve gender equality and gender awareness:

- All the wooden Sexual harassment complain box has been replaced by transparent boxes.
- Gender complaint and suggestion box has been installed in all branch offices and also in head office.
- 2 breast feeding corner have been established.
- a checklist has been developed to identify the gender gaps and to take necessary initiatives accordingly.
- Mid level staff has been trained on Gender topics.
- Recruitment process has been redesigned considering the gender lens in team formulation, question making and reference checking, etc

&#x200B;"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
