<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.19/00295</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green roads for climate resilience and water management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.19/00295</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Local Infrastructure (DoLI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MetaMeta</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MetaMeta</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8367" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>27.6587525 85.3247183</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11110" percentage="75" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="14010" percentage="25" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">59364</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8367/Group_photo_Session.JPG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant
          government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual
          projects and the programme as a whole. For project partners, it is compulsory to use the
          prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project
          achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of
          the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project
          output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by
          the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and
          budget must be made clear in the annual report. Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and
          not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement
          of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the
          annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project
          and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s)
          and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as
          a whole. Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning,
          reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more
          elaboration is demanded. In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual
          reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are
          obligatory. The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific
          conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in
          achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the
          report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted. The final
          report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report) Reflect on how the
            training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting
            organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in
            reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations
            for the post-project period. + In your email submitting the final report, the partners
            will enclose: - an inventory of equipment purchased - a document signed by the (Lead
            partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting
            organisation on the transfer of ownership - a list with the names and email addresses of
            staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland
            Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="We have uploaded the final report that we have submitted to tmtreports@nuffic.nl on 30/01/2021"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the
            project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the
            activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="We proposed to give a 2-weeks training in our proposal.  Later, we decided, together with DoLI, to undertake multiple activities (preparatory meetings between MM and DoLI in December 2020, 2-days introductory workshop and road assessments with DoLI and municipalities in February 2020 and the main training in November 2020). The introductory workshop helped us to better tailor the 6-days main training to the local challenges. The initial plan was to provide the main training in between March and August but due to COVID-19, we had to push the schedule couple of time. In November 2020, we successfully organized the 6-days training. Meanwhile, regarding the development of guidelines on &#x2018;springs protection and management&#x2019; we helped DoLI to form a Technical Working Committee (TWC) that will work together with MM drafting the guidelines. 

Therefore, we state that we were able to adapt to the COVID-19 problematic situation and achieve the objectives of this project by the end of November 2020."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">DoLI has been strengthened by the TMT</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">11-10-2021: The objective of this training project was to increase the
                capacity of the Department of Local Infrastructure (DoLI) and local units (i.e.
                municipalities) in order to mainstream integrated, gender inclusive and
                participatory road water management. Organizations strengthened by this training
                project: 1. Department of Local Infrastructure, DoLI (requesting organization) 2.
                Godawari Municipality 3. Kirtipur Municipality 4. Panchapuri Municipality 5.
                Bheriganga Municiaplity 6. Gurbhakot Municipality 7. Bheri Municipality 8. Lekbeshi
                Municipality</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation,
            supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Create coregroup of female engineers as role models to stimulate others
                through trainings and events</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">11-10-2021: We gave special attention to gender with focus on women and
                marginalized groups participation in road planning, construction and maintenance but
                also on empowering women engineers in DoLI and municipalities. Apart from the
                presentations on women inclusion in road development we, further, discussed the
                gender context and the challenges of women in Nepal. We discussed the Gender and
                Social Inclusion (GESI) Policy for infrastructure projects in Nepal (e.g., if they
                participants are aware of this policy, if they use it in their organization, how it
                is implemented and how to improve it and make it more effective). We also had a
                discussion with the participants on the Internship program &#x2018;Empowering women
                engineers&#x2019; offered by DRSP since 2007. We asked the participants if this
                program is still carried out and how it could be better promoted. Finally,
                participants developed action plans for the inclusion of women in their
                organizations and field.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new
            knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="90.48">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">11-10-2021: We undertook both direct evaluation by asking the participants
                to fill in an evaluation form and indirect evaluation through observation. The
                general opinion of the participants was very positive. Through the direct
                evaluation, we show that the majority of the participants (90%) strongly agreed that
                the objectives of the training were met, the presenters were engaging, the content
                of the training was easy to follow, the discussions and groupwork sessions were
                relevant and helpful, the training was useful and it should be continued for the
                benefit of DoLI and the municipalities. Through the indirect evaluation, we saw that
                all participants were very active and happy to share their thoughts and explore the
                application of the topics discussed in their work.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="38">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 out of 24 participants are women</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="32.50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">12-10-2021: As mentioned in B.I.1., we had 21 participants (7 female) in
                the first introductory workshop in February and another 21 participants (7 female)
                in the main training in November. However one female doubles up, ie. followed both
                trainings, hence the change in reported numbers.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="24"></target>
     <actual value="40.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">12-10-2021: Response: a total of 40 unique participants were trained
                combined in an introductory and main training. The first training comprised 14 men
                and 7 women, which was also the case for the second. However two participants from
                the first also attended the second, hence a total of 40 unique participants were
                trained (13 female / 27 male). Our apologies for the miscount.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge
            and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="100.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.3. % of scholarship holders / TMT participants / alumni employed post-study
            within region and same employer</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90"></target>
     <actual value="100.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="The initial plan was to have at least 9 women attending the final main training (November 2020). Unfortunately, 2 women didn&#x2019;t attend due to illness of their kids. Yet 7 women attended (33%).

Special attention was given on women participation in planning, implementation, and maintenance of roads both through presentation and group work and discussion. The participants come up with the plan on how to include women in the road development and to create employment opportunities for women by suggesting their engagement of them in road construction groups (RCBs) and road maintenance groups (RMGs). They also suggested the participation of women from the planning phase and in bioengineering. Therefore, the group work/discussion session and the answers of the participants to the questionnaire for module 4 helped us to understand the knowledge and skills gained by the participants."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="We undertook an assessment of the experience of participants with the topics on each module at the end of each module. We set assessments for 4 modules namely i. Road Water Management and environmental practices for Nepal; ii. Technical know-how and skills on low-cost, high impact solution-how to do it?; iii. Capacity Building and Knowledge management-how to support local units?; &amp; iv. Inclusion through governance. At the start of each module, we shared questions with the participants. At the end of each module, we discussed the participants&#x2019; answers to those questions. This helped us to make sure that the topics discussed under each module were well-understood by **all participants**. 

&#x200B;"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.3. % of scholarship holders / TMT participants / alumni employed post-study within region and same employer</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.6. Number of stimulating measures/extra facilities aimed at preparation, supervision and aftercare of female candidates</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
