<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.20/00156</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IDP-based sustainable economic reconstruction in the South Sudan- Ugandan cross-border area</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OKP-TMT.20/00156</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Technology Empowerment Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecopolis Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecopolis Europe</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="9420" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>2.9693988 31.3970415</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="EMPL" percentage="100" vocabulary="99"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-06-18">59984</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9420/update/31861/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Joint interviews by Ecopolis Europa and CTEN with potential permanent TVET providers</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9420/update/31879/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Testimonial 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/9420/update/31880/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Testimonial 2</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/9420/Project_9420_current_image_2020-12-03_17.02.44.png">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="CTEN described its main capacity need as the knowledge and expertise to approach and convince South Sudanese and Ugandan TVET institutions, and translate the perceived economic opportunities of IDPs into sustainable TVET courses that these institutions can implement in the future. In order to achieve this, EE accompanied CTEN to 6 different potential TVET providers, and interviewed them several times about their experience, reflections and ideas for business TVET courses for South Sudanese IDP entrepreneurs. The joint interviews and following analyses of the provider&#x2019;s capabilities were essential in addressing the capacity needs of CTEN. CTEN staff confirms that this TMT has been successful in connecting them to potential TVET providers, and enabling them to have in depth discussions with them, assess their suitability, and make well-founded decisions and partnerships based on this. 

**Lessons learned and recommendations for post-project period**

One of the first lessons learned for both CTEN and EE was that one should dare to question the ways that things are &#x2018;usually done&#x2019;. When working with any target group, it is important to start without too many assumptions, but to actually ask questions and especially listen to people. 

Through continuously asking and listening, CTEN and EE found out that IDP entrepreneurs don&#x2019;t have the time to attend week-long general trainings. Furthermore, these trainings have limited impact due to the gap in level, topic, etc, and the absence of any follow-up to see if the participants actually understand to content of the course. 

One recommendation for the post-project period (which EE will still be involved in) is that future business trainings should follow a dual approach: classroom education only part-time, on those cross-cutting topics that are a challenge for (almost) everyone. This should be supplemented with individual mentoring and coaching programmes, preferable partly organised from within the community. This makes IDPs less dependent on external aid, which is one of the reasons that many of these entrepreneurs started their business in the first place: to become self-reliant. 

Finally, target group feedback included that they were happy that CTEN and EE made so many visits to the field, and kept asking the target group about their experiences and wishes, forcing them to also think about that critically and building a strong and sustainable relationship. This way, empowering an organisation like CTEN can (and should) go hand-in-hand with empowering their target group/beneficiaries."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="**CTEN staff capable to:** 

**- Identify, together with economic development support providers in the cross- border area, successful and sustainable private economic activities of South Sudanese IDPs;** 

In order to identify successful private economic activities of South Sudanese IPDs, EE (Ecopolis Europa) and CTEN started the project by moving into the settlements together and speaking to many different businesspeople. After several visits and conversations, a group of 15 businesspeople was formed in both Rhino Camp and Bidibidi. Both groups contain people from various trades and consist of both men and women. Through these groups, CTEN and EE built relationships with these people, which was very helpful in getting to know them, the systemic function they provide in their communities, and the challenges they face. These relationships can form a sustainable basis for CTEN to continue their work on. 

**- Assess required key competences of actors in successful sustainable private economic reconstruction activities;** 

In order to find the key competences of the identified successful businesspeople, it was important to first understand who these people are, and where they came from. CTEN and EE found that many of the people who had started up their own business in the settlements, had already been businesspeople back in South Sudan. In individual interviews, most of them mentioned a motivation to not keep waiting for support or aid, but to improve their conditions themselves. CTEN and EE found that this private sector mentality was an important asset for most of the businesspeople. The majority used the skills that they already had from their previous businesses, but the limited nature of their skills often impeded further growth of their businesses. 

**- Translate, together with South Sudanese and Ugandan TVET providers, these key competences into knowledge, skills and professional attitudes to be generated in TVET course curricula;** 

After assessing the key competences and main challenges of successful entrepreneurs in the refugee settlements, CTEN started by making a list of the knowledge, skills and attitudes that made a good businessman or -women. After several rounds of discussions and feedback between CTEN and EE, CTEN produced a &#x2018;Curriculum Development Plan&#x2019;, in which these key competences were divided into three categories with multiple sub-categories: Business skills, supply chain management, and start-up capital. The categories contain quite elaborate topics. For instance, the category &#x2018;business skills&#x2019; deals with technical things like financial literacy, but also with _attitudes_ like entrepreneurial thinking and salesmanship. These topics were later discussed with the potential TVET providers.

**- Identify suitable permanent South Sudanese and Ugandan TVET providers in the cross- border area interested and capable to adapt existing or develop new TVET curricula for selected economic reconstruction activities;** 

In order to enable CTEN staff to identify and start a collaboration with suitable permanent TVET providers, EE accompanied CTEN to several meetings. On the Ugandan side, five local universities were selected for introductory meetings, to assess their experience and possibilities on providing business training to South Sudanese refugees. Afterwards, the interviews were evaluated by CTEN staff, facilitated by EE. Based on this assessment, three universities were selected for a more in-depth assessment: Muni University, Makerere University and Business School (MUBS), and Uganda Christian University (UCU). On the South-Sudanese side (in the Western Equatoria State), there are fewer institutions of higher learning. One potential TVET provider was identified and interviewed: Yei Teacher Training College (YTTC). This college is an affiliate of Kyambogo University and Juba University. 

Together with CTEN, EE discussed with the TVET providers topics such as needs assessments, follow-up after trainings, and capability of adapting existing curricula to specific target groups. The aim of this TMT was not to make a definitive choice with CTEN, but to jointly develop the skills and experience within CTEN to make an informed decision when identifying a suitable TVET provider, based on their specific needs.

_**- Elaborate a draft pilot curriculum for South Sudanese IDPs, implemented by permanent TVET providers in South Sudan and Uganda, on sustainable private economic enterprise for reconstruction in the cross-border region.**_ 

After the first round of interviews with the South Sudanese IDP businesspeople, CTEN and EE identified multiple knowledge and skills gaps hampering the entrepreneurs. Based on this, CTEN developed a draft pilot curriculum for a TVET business course. However, when discussing this and prior TVET experiences with other stakeholders such as UNHCR field officers, TVET providers, and key informants within the refugee settlements, CTEN and EE discovered several problems. One UNHCR field officer was very dissatisfied with the trainings generally given in the IDP settlements. This officer stated that these trainings always came with grand promises, but that these often turned out to be empty. This response was sadly validated in many further interviews. TVET course providers gave examples of not being involved at all in the target group selection, needs assessments and setting of the ToRs of a project, resulting &#x201C;absolutely unnecessary&#x201D; trainings, or with very limited follow-up. Another UNHCR officer confirmed that there was hardly ever any continuous monitoring of participants, and that this would be an important improvement to existing programmes. 

To break with this cycle of &#x2018;failing forward&#x2019;, CTEN and EE jointly decided that the developed draft pilot curriculum designed would not be put in practice as such, since these type of qualification courses do not seem to yield the desired results. Instead, a dual approach with on the one hand a customised programme with short courses on cross-cutting themes that are challenging for all businesspeople, and on the other hand an individualised coaching and mentoring programme, would be a better focus. To enhance CTEN&#x2019;s capacity to set up such a programme, this concept was not only discussed with the selected TVET providers, but also with several NGOs providing business skills trainings and coaching programmes to IDPs: DCA, CEFORD and GIZ. The fieldwork that was conducted in this part of the TMT enables CTEN to develop a sustainable support programme for entrepreneurs, by identifying the needs of participants and transforming these into a strong curriculum that considers individual challenges and opportunities."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-02-2022: Organizations are: CTEN (applicant organization) and also the
                target group organizations BIDO Zone1 (BidiBidi) and BIDO Ofua (Rhino
                Camp)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge
            and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-02-2022: The training was of a &quot;hands-on&quot; character, so the learned
                skills were immediately brought into practice by the participants</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new
            knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-02-2022: Unanimously participants stated to have acquired valuable
                skills and insights</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="28"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="3.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-02-2022: Organizations are: CTEN (applicant organization) and also the target group organizations BIDO Zone1 (BidiBidi) and BIDO Ofua (Rhino Camp)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.O.2. % of alumni / TMT participants who have applied the acquired knowledge and skills within their working environment</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="100"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-02-2022: The training was of a &quot;hands-on&quot; character, so the learned skills were immediately brought into practice by the participants</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.8. % alumni / TMT participants who state that they have acquired new knowledge and skills; e.g. problem solving, effective communication</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="100.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17-02-2022: Unanimously participants stated to have acquired valuable skills and insights</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="28.00"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Especially personal attitudes have changed towards South Sudanese IDP business(wo)men; They are not anymore seen as &quot;exploitative middlemen&quot;, but rather  as a support needing target group that perform important economic functions ins IDP settlement areas"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Gender awareness has improved, especially concerning gender aspects at the target group of IDP entrepreneurs and how these cope with these differences. This includes for example the different challenges and opportunities that businesswomen and -men face. CTEN staff is now more capable to recognise and respond to these difference."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
