<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="FR" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT.19/00187</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" secondary-reporter="0" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Nuffic</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Pr&#xE9;vention des grossesses non d&#xE9;sir&#xE9;es et des comportements sexuels &#xE0; risque en milieu scolaire et universitaire au Nord du B&#xE9;nin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description akvo:type="5" type="1" xmlns:akvo="http://akvo.org/iati-activities">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">OKP-TMT.19/00187</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">CINOP Global</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">CINOP Global</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">L&apos;Universit&#xE9; de Parakou</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-41150085" role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Nuffic</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="8596" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="NL-KVK-27327087">
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Akvo Foundation</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Nuffic</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>okp@nuffic.nl</email>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">P.O. Box 29777, 2502 LT The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BJ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.3466822 2.6090043</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="13010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">58241.6</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8596/update/30337/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Rapport global</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="FR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8596/update/30671/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Tableau: Mise en oeuvre des interventions jeunes-leaders OKP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="FR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8596/update/30672/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Tableau: Mise en oeuvre des interventions jeunes-leaders OKP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="FR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://rsr.akvo.org/project/8596/update/30673/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Tableau: Mise en oeuvre des interventions jeunes-leaders OKP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="FR"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="IMAGE/JPEG" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/akvo-rsr-production-media-files/db/project/8596/Project_8596_current_image_2020-08-31_12.18.37.PNG">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Project photo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41150085-OKP-TMT" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">DO NOT USE Labour market and entrepreneurship</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">**(if applicable)** Describe the progress that is made in strengthening the capacity of the requesting organisation to deliver the products and services which are demanded by the labour market and society in general? Has competitiveness / efficiency been improved?
 

In case the requesting organisation is an education institution, what are the prospects of graduates to find employment or to become self-employed? Has the training had an impact on sectoral development?</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Narrative report</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">Reporting is an important management tool which is used to inform relevant government officials and other stakeholders about the results being achieved by individual projects and the programme as a whole. 
For project partners, it is compulsory to use the prescribed Orange Knowledge annual report format in order to report on project achievements. The annual report also provides valuable data on the financial situation of the project. Based on an analysis of the project performance in relation to the project output(s) and expected outcome(s), a revision of the project work plan may be suggested by the project partners. The consequences of a possible revision on the project work plan and budget must be made clear in the annual report.
Nuffic monitors outputs and outcomes and not activities . Therefore, the main focus of the annual report must be on the achievement of the project&#x2019;s output(s) and planned outcome(s). The information provided in the annual reports of the projects is used by Nuffic to monitor the progress of the project and to inform the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other stakeholders about the output(s) and outcome(s) being achieved by individual projects and the Orange Knowledge programme as a whole. 
Please note that if project progress is in accordance with the original planning, reporting requirements are minimal. Only in case of deviations from the planning, more elaboration is demanded.
In the grant award letter, the dates for submission of the annual reports are mentioned. In case of a three-year project, between 5-7 reports are obligatory.
The first report (0) is a very short report which focuses on specific conditions and/or recommendations in the grant. There is no need to report on progress in achieving outputs and outcomes, which is done in the first annual report. As annex to the report 0, the consortium agreements between the partners should be submitted.
The final report must reflect on the entire project period.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">DO NOT USE Labour market and entrepreneurship</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">**(if applicable)** Describe the progress that is made in strengthening the capacity of the requesting organisation to deliver the products and services which are demanded by the labour market and society in general? Has competitiveness / efficiency been improved?
 

In case the requesting organisation is an education institution, what are the prospects of graduates to find employment or to become self-employed? Has the training had an impact on sectoral development?</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">14. Final report TMT+/TMT</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">Final conclusions TMT+/TMT (in case of final report)
Reflect on how the training has contributed to addressing the capacity needs as described by the requesting organisation in the proposal form. How effective and efficient has the TMT+ been in reaching the desired objectives? Please formulate lessons learned and recommendations for the post-project period.
 

+
 

In your email submitting the final report, the partners will enclose: 
 - an inventory of equipment purchased 
 - a document signed by the (Lead partner) Dutch consortium/provider and Lead partner consortium country A or requesting organisation on the transfer of ownership
 - a list with the names and email addresses of staff members who participated in staff training for their registration in the Holland Alumni Network database</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Overall, the project performed beyond expectations! It met all its goals and above.
ACHIEVEMENTS
Considering the attained outputs, one can summarize it as follows:
1. From a quantitative point of view:
- 01 manual has been produced and shared with the participants
- 22 trainers trained (ToT) 
- 210 young leaders trained and currently active within the university and schools
- About 3005 beneficiaries from the target groups reached 
- Leader sheets, supervision and passive data collection tools are made available and shared with supervisors.
2. Qualitative
With regard to the emotions observed in the trainers during the experience sharing session with the trainers, and the substance of the 02 sketches made by the beneficiaries during the closing ceremony, we can confirm the very extent wide impact of the project at the college level. These effects are the result of a good quality of technical support and the interest shown in the project by young leaders and trainers.
The support of the national, regional and local authorities was also important in boosting the project performance and impact.

IMPLEMENTATION
The strengths noted during the implementation of this project were:
- Good programming and planning of activities (work plan, methodological and administrative details)
- The relevance of the content of the interventions
- Flexibility and fluidity in exchanges between experts and the University team through rapid consensus and concrete actions
- The dynamism of actors observed on site
- The quality of the technical support documents  produced and the expertise support provided of the CINOP experts
- Little administrative burden (despite the rigor at the university level which had little influence on the organizational aspect)
- Good coordination (both dynamic coordinators at CINOP and UP)
- The concerns of college principals at the start dissipated thanks to the quality of the animations with relevant content which have proven their potential to deconstruct standards and to structure relevant and effective interventions
- The dynamism of CINOP and its flexibility
- The quality of interpersonal relationships (University - colleges - CINOP)
These positive elements altogether made it possible that attained results finally exceeded expectations.  And although the project has come to its end, the developped capacities are already in place and will continue to serve as a framework for future interventions trhoughout the Borgou department and beyond.

NEEDED IMPROVMENTS
The project achievement could have been much more tremendous if the following was not noted: 
- The coordination work at UP relied exclusively one individual (Prof Sambi&#xE9;ni). Although he remained professional and dynamic in the collaboration, support from other university staff members would have eased things a lot.  
- Lack of enthusiasm among university participants. And this situation is very contrasting if compared to the strong mobilisation at the 9 invited schools in Parakou.
- The framework for TMT projects is a bit constraining. Nevertheless, significant results were achieved thanks to the opening of CINOP which made it possible to carry out activities that were not specified in the basic project (initially planned).

LESSONS LEARNED
An organizing and monitoring committee made it possible to carry out and ensure the anchoring of the actions of the project, the orientations of which made it possible to widen the geographical coverage of the structures from 6 at the start to 10.
Thanks to the interventions planned and carried out on the TMP project, evidence is being made on the immensity and diversity of the needs of adolescents and on the determinants of risky sexual behavior observed in adolescents and young people. The risky sexual behaviors of pupils and students reflect a lack of institutional communication related to comprehensive sexuality education at the academic level and the unavailability of proven skills on Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights and open approaches. To influence these determinants, it has been proven thanks to this initiative that a mobilization and unfailing adhesion of the stakeholders and the federation of the efforts would have more impact. Through these interventions of the `` OKP-TMT BEN_SDSR UP &apos;&apos; project, funded by the Government of the Netherlands, the availability of trained and competent staff in SHSR within the teaching and administrative staff of the targeted establishments remains an effective response to better address SRHR issues. and guide adolescents and even teachers on these issues. In addition, the teams at the college level are stronger, dynamic and motivated than that of the University. It is observed that at the college level, the dichotomy between values &#x200B;&#x200B;and the quality of messages is well clarified.
RECOMMANDATIONS AND SUGGESTIONS
The following can be considered:
- It would have been desirable to have sufficient funding (more than the approved &#x20AC; 72.000 as total budget) so as to enable more interventions towards the target groups. We lacked funds to reach out to more people in the target groups. 
-  The beneficiary organisations should organize a permanent monitoring system to ensure the planning, implementation and monitoring of project activities
- It is effective to organize next year the  a refresher and upgrading of trainers / supervisors. If possible, they should be assisted to developp their annual action plan at the level of their respective schools.
- Keep the WhatsApp group of the trainers alive so as to enable continuous exchanges of ideas and practices, experiences, etc. among members of the group created for this purpose
- Set up a system for capitalizing on achievements and mobilizing resources
- Consider scaling up the initiative at the level of the Borgou department.

CONCLUSION
The OKP-TMT BEN_SDSR UP project, although disrupted by a health crisis, showed good relevance in the present context very favorable to the SSRAJ in Benin with very important substantive, political and institutional exchanges which are taking place. place thanks to the commendable and visible commitment of CINOP.
The main achievement of the interventions remains the surge of institutions at all levels to strengthen these achievements of the project not only through their administrative support but also financial and technical for the generalization of the approach.
The various obstacles and suggestions noted should be given careful consideration if the project intends to make way for a larger project / program.
Adolescent girls deserve to express their full potential in a context of dominant and compressive masculinity. They expect a lot from this innovative project for their empowerment and respect for their sexual and reproductive rights. Only a good coherence of approaches, the synergy of action between actors, good governance and the mobilization of community forces could make the difference.
All stakeholders are therefore called upon to take on this challenge!

APPENDIX
 The list of trained staff is appended below."></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">2. Project progress and achievement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">In this section (maximum 1000 words), please provide a global overview of the project progress **per output**. To what extent have they been achieved? Comment on the activities that have taken place and the most important milestones.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="Output 1.   22 trainers trained (6 initially planned)  
 22 trainers followed successfully the ToT traject. Initially, only 6 trainers were foreseen. But the project managed to train above the initial 6 university staff members, also 14 teachers at the 9 involved secondary schools of the town of Parakou. 
Output 2.  210 young leaders SDSR (none foreseen initially) 
210 young leaders SDSR trained and already operational in their respective school environments
Output 3.   3505 in the target groups reached (1500 persons initially planned) 
3005 (2505 pupils and students sensitized ; the whole student population (400 young girls) of the Lyc&#xE9;e des Jeunes Filles ; 100 parents)"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner
          countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp;
          aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully
            completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <dimension name="Category of graduates Category of graduates" value="Male Female"></dimension>
    </baseline>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="232">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates Category of graduates" value="Male Female"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="232">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates Category of graduates" value="Male Female"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">19-03-2021: 22 trainers 210 young-leaders SDSR</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group
            training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">l&#x2019;Universit&#xE9; de Parakou et 6 &#xE9;tablissements secondaires
                pilotes</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">08-03-2021: 10 beneficiary organisations: Universit&#xE9; de Parakou (UP)
                is lead; Lyc&#xE9;e Mathieu Bouk&#xE9; ; Colll&#xE8;ge Hubert Maga ; Coll&#xE8;ge
                Gu&#xE9;ma ; Coll&#xE8;ge Albarika ; Coll&#xE8;ge Titirou ; Coll&#xE8;ge Banikani;
                CEG Zongo ; EFMS et Lyc&#xE9;e jeunes filles.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="55.16">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">22-03-2021: The project achievements are beyond expectation.22 trainers
                followed successfully the ToT traject. Initially, only 6 trainers were foreseen. But
                the project managed to train above the initial 6 university staff members, also 14
                teachers at the 9 involved secondary schools of the town of Parakou.210 young
                leaders SDSR trained and already operational in their respective school
                environments</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes
            through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the
            workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="FR">B. Enhanced knowledge and skills of individuals and organisations (in partner countries and in the NL) in line with country/regional specific labour market needs &amp; aiming at inclusiveness</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.O.1. Number of organisations strengthened by individual and/or group training</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">l&#x2019;Universit&#xE9; de Parakou et 6 &#xE9;tablissements secondaires pilotes</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">08-03-2021: 10 beneficiary organisations: Universit&#xE9; de Parakou (UP) is lead; Lyc&#xE9;e Mathieu Bouk&#xE9; ; Colll&#xE8;ge Hubert Maga ; Coll&#xE8;ge Gu&#xE9;ma ; Coll&#xE8;ge Albarika ; Coll&#xE8;ge Titirou ; Coll&#xE8;ge Banikani; CEG Zongo ; EFMS et Lyc&#xE9;e jeunes filles.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.1. Number of scholarship holders / TMT participants that have successfully completed course/training (male / female / minorities)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="232"></target>
     <actual value="232.00">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">19-03-2021: 22 trainers
210 young-leaders SDSR</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
     <actual value="139.00">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Female"></dimension>
     </actual>
     <actual value="93.00">
      <dimension name="Category of graduates" value="Male"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.4. % of scholarships awarded to women</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="55.16">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="FR">22-03-2021: The project achievements are beyond expectation.22 trainers followed successfully the ToT traject. 
Initially, only 6 trainers were foreseen. But the project managed to train above the initial 6 university staff members, also 14 teachers at the 9 involved secondary schools of the town of Parakou.210 young leaders SDSR trained and already operational in their respective school environments</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.10. Changes in personal, academic and professional attitudes and attributes through training and education programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="FR">B.I.11. Improved gender equality and gender awareness in the workplace</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2022-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
