<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5514000101-KOS-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program support to the Kosovar Stability Initiative 2015-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Program support to the Kosovar Stability Initiative 2015-2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support to the Kosovar Stability Initiative Program</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Core support to the Kosovar Stability Initiative Program</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective of this intervention is to enhance democratic governance and human rights through increasing the availability of empirical research, inspiring well-informed and evidence based public policies; raising awareness and engaging in cooperation across borders, advocacy and networking and supporting an effective social dialogue process and promotion of cultural heritage in Kosovo.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iniciativa Kosovare per Stabilitet</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University, college or other teaching institution, research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="8.8" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.8 - Protect labour rights and promote safe and secure working environments for all workers, including migrant workers, in particular women migrants, and those in precarious employment.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.8 - Skydda arbetstagarnas r&#xE4;ttigheter och fr&#xE4;mja en trygg och s&#xE4;ker arbetsmilj&#xF6; f&#xF6;r alla arbetstagare, inklusive arbetskraftsinvandrare, i synnerhet kvinnliga migranter, och m&#xE4;nniskor i otrygga anst&#xE4;llningar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">59316.906504692</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">116870.2156255478</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">187200.1872001872</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">184111.2031667127</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">59316.906504692</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">116870.2156255478</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">187200.1872001872</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">184111.2031667127</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-01">557578.921144</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-09-28">59316.906504692</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-28">116870.2156255478</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-02-28">117000.117000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-09-28">70200.0702000702</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-28">184111.2031667127</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During the period of Sida support, IKS has produced 20 papers, analyses and reports, guidebooks, manuals and several documentary films thus contributing to important social and political processes. In addition, the organization has promoted its vision and values through a large number of conferences, round tables and thematic workshops. Direct capacity building for public institutions&#x2019; officials at national and local levels were part of&#xA0; IKS program.
The activity of IKS is organized in these pillars:
SOCIAL JUSTICE &amp;amp; INCLUSION (2015 &#x2013; 2018)
SO 1: Improve the quality and intensity of social dialogue through improving the pre-conditions for meaningful discussion between social partners.
Results:
Policy contribution and influencing work undertaken in informal and formal meetings with different stakeholders in the sector including regular contacts and exchanges with the Minister, deputy Minister of Labour and Social Welfare and other relevant Ministries. Strengthening the administrative and management capacities of Trade Unions and Employer Organizations in their capacity as social partners in organization, management, fundraising and advocacy, providing support to the organizational reform of Trade Union Organizations, supporting the functioning of the Socio-Economic Council through secretarial and technical support, information provision and process facilitation.
SOCIAL JUSTICE RELATED LEGISLATION (2015 &#x2013; 2018)
SO 2: Labour and social dialogue related legislation is improved and updated in line with the EU Acquis and international standards, while simultaneously better reflecting the socio-economic reality of the country:
Results:
IKS promoted an overarching approach to advancing social justice policies and practice, while ensuring that they are based on evidence to ensure equal treatment and inclusion of all peoples of Kosovo, including women, ethnic and sexual minorities, people with disabilities etc. Activities&#xA0; were implemented with the financial support of Sida, the EU funded Project &#x201C;Support to Social Partners&#x201D; (SSP) and the British Embassy funded &#x201C;Supporting Ministry of Labour and Social Welfare in Reviewing&#xA0;and Amending Labour and Social Dialogue Related Legislation&#x201D;.&#xA0;
Activities: Consultative roundtables with TUs and CSOs on the legislation package in support the Ministry to integrate the TU and CSO input into the laws, delivery of two workshops and one seminar to ministries&#x2019; officials that will compose the working groups in charge of drafting the concept document(s), support given to the ministries in the analysis phase of the provisions of the law(s) that will require amendment , support the formulation of the concept document(s) and in organizing and conducting the working group sessions for drafting the concept document(s), participation in the entire cycle of amendment procedure until submitted for the legislative review.
CULTURAL HERITAGE
SO 3: Capturing the elements of intangible cultural heritage, recording and promoting them with the wider public with the purpose of reviving the ancient elements of tradition, culture and collective memory.
IKS has undertaken the role of the Heritage and Diversity Program Coordinator for Pristina Region to oversee the development and implementation of the Heritage Plans prepared by the local stakeholders for the local communities. Each region has an HDP coordinator which ensures linkages and encourages constant dialogue among entities and communities in order to promote the protection, maintenance and effective management of heritage assets and practices. .&#xA0;
During the beginning of the project, IKS has organized:
8 site visits, with 312 primary school students, parents and teachers. 4 site visits with General Public, with 185 persons of different social categories.
IKS has been a partner in the implementation of the USA cultural heritage Funded project led by IRD titled the &#x201C;Preservation and Restoration of three Cultural Heritage sites in the Prizren Region. The overall goal of the project was to preserve and restore the Oldest Music School in Kosovo located in Prizren and St. Jovan Church and Parish House of St. Stephen Church in Ho&#xE7;&#xEB; e Madhe, using a community-based approach and promotion of the site as a significant cultural and architectural value.
Under this pillar IKS implemented the following activities:
Researched, designed and distributed around 200 brochures on the three sites, produced a 10 minutes documentary film on the restoration of the three sites, designed and preparation of information on the three sites to be posted in the Kosovo Guide - a tourist guide that promotes all the three cultural heritage sites, the project&#x2019;s promotion efforts were combined with educational and promotional activities that included promotion of the site as a tourist attraction in major local websites, organized the inauguration event in Lorenc Antoni musical school.
ANTI-CORRUPTION (2015 &#x2013; 2018)
SO 4: EU revisits its Anti-Corruption policies.
As part of the Framework 7 / Horizon 2020 ANTICORRP project, under the leadership of the University of Gothenburg, IKS/KSI has engaged in three areas: Ethnography of Corruption, EU funding, Development and Corruption and Organised Crime.
IKS/KSI has undertaken extensive fieldwork research in Kosovo, conducting interviews, observing and mapping patterns of interaction between local politicians, institutions and citizens, public participation in local politics, practices of gift exchange, informal economy, bribes, favours, as well as forms of social protest against corruption. Other countries in which ethnographic research was also conducted are: Italy, Hungary, Bosnia, Turkey, Russia, Tanzania, and Mexico. The final objective of this work was to produce, through fine-grained case studies, a number of qualitative socio-cultural indicators which can be used to complement and contrast quantitative, national and sub-national indicators for the analysis and prediction of patterns of corruption in different regional settings. Research reports can be found in the following links:
http://anticorrp.eu/publications/the-making-of-citizenship-against-corruption-in-kosovo-protest-lies-and-the-public-good/ http://anticorrp.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/WP-4.2-Deliverable-combined-data-set.pdf</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55140001" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
