<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10841A0102-XKX-16062</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EU delegation, Statistics Kosovo, 2019-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EU-delegering Statistik Kosovo 2019-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen omfattar ett fyra&#xE5;rigt program f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka Kosovos statistiksystem. Insatsen &#xE4;r fokuserad p&#xE5; att st&#xE4;rka Kosovos Statistikbyr&#xE5; (KAS) och dess roll i det nationella statistiksystemet. 

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen &#xE4;r 3 530 000 EUR. Av dessa finansierar EU, genom EU-kontoret i Pristina, 2 000 000 EUR vilka kommer att utbetalas till Sida i enlighet med det delegeringsavtal som partnerna ingick i december 2018. Sidas bidrag till insatsen &#xE4;r 1 530 000 EUR fr&#xE5;n den bilaterala budgeten f&#xF6;r reformsamarbete med Kosovo. Detta beslut omfattar d&#xE4;rmed 16 millioner SEK, vilket skall motsvara  1 530 000 EUR 

Delegeringsavtalet mellan EU och Sida , och dess bilagor, beskriver det &#xF6;vergripande syftet med samarbetet. Sida ansvarar f&#xF6;r implementeringen och rapporteringen av insatsen gentemot EU (representerat av EU-kontoret i Pristina). 
Sida avser att ing&#xE5; &#xF6;verenskommelse med Statistiska Centralbyr&#xE5;n (SCB) f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra resultatkomponenter 1, nationalr&#xE4;kenskaper, och 2, social statistik, baserat p&#xE5; deras unika sakexpertis. Detta tillvaratar de goda relationer och den kontextspecifika kunskap som SCB har byggt upp i sitt l&#xE5;ngvariga samarbete med Kosovo och &#xE4;r samtidigt i linje med Sidas prioriteringar vad g&#xE4;ller myndighetssamverkan. 
SCB har dock inte m&#xF6;jlighet att bidra med sakexpertis och/eller resurser f&#xF6;r projektets tre &#xF6;vriga resultatkomponenter vilka omfattar IT-system, koordinering inom statistiksystemet samt ledarskaps- och organisationsutveckling. Sidas implementerande partner f&#xF6;r dessa resultatkomponenter kommer d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r - d&#xE5; ingen m&#xF6;jlig partner med kompetens och m&#xF6;jlighet att genomf&#xF6;ra dessa delar har identifierats - att handlas upp i enlighet med LOU.  
Sida kommer d&#xE4;rtill att ing&#xE5; avtal med KAS -  vilket &#xE4;r centralt f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla KAS engagemang och &#xE4;garskap i projektet.  

Centrala dialogfr&#xE5;gor under implementering utg&#xF6;rs av:
* Vikten av att framh&#xE5;lla och st&#xE4;rka KAS nationella &#xE4;garskap och aktiva roll i projektet.
* S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;llandet av tillg&#xE4;ngliga resurser f&#xF6;r KAS i relation till implementeringen (detta g&#xE4;ller specifikt IT-resurser).
* Uppf&#xF6;ljning av KAS utveckling p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;dena ledarskap och organisationsutveckling. 
* Behovet av att st&#xE4;rka integrering av Sidas tematiska perspektiv, med fokus p&#xE5; konflikt-, r&#xE4;ttighets - och fattigdomsperspektivet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This intervention is a four year comprehensive programme with the aim to strengthen the National Statistics System of Kosovo (NSS), with the Kosovo Agency of Statistics (KAS) at the core: Strengthening of the Statistical System of Kosovo, 2019-2022. This programme will be supported by the EU, represented by the EU Office in Kosovo and the Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency (Sida), represented by the Swedish Embassy in Pristina. The EU contribution of 2 million euro will be delegated to Sida. Sida will contribute an additional 16 million SEK to the project. Sida, through the Embassy of Sweden in Kosovo, will oversee the contribution in full.

Sida&apos;s national partner will be KAS. Sida will furthermore enter into a service purchase agreement with Statistics Sweden (SCB) to implement component 1 and 2  of the programme, in national and social statistics. Sida will furthermore though open procurement in accordance with LOU procure a second implementing partner to implement components in IT, coordination and organizational development (3,4,5)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the contribution is to contribute to the strengthening of the statistical system of Kosovo by enabling the development of reliable statistical information and facilitating improved decision making. Specifically, this action aims at increasing the capacities of KAS to carry out its core activities in a standardised and independent manner &#x2013; in line with EU standards &#x2013; as well as strengthen KAS&#x2019;s management and coordination capacities.
To attain this overarching objective, the contribution aims to:&#xA0;
* Improve the timeliness and shortening the timing of the release of all statistics in order to improve the Kosovo Government&#x2019;s decision-making process;
* Improve inter-institutional coordination and information sharing among the main stakeholders in the statistical sector;
* Improve data dissemination by enhancing data availability and visibility for public users;
* Support KAS in carrying out its core activities and mandate in a standardised and independent manner.
The above objectives are foreseen to be achieved trough the achievement of the following five results:
1: Further improvement of sector statistics and National Accounts statistics
2:&#xA0;Further improvement of sector statistics and National Accounts statistics
3: Further improvement of metadata systems, documentation and dissemination and modernisation of data collection methods
4: Strengthening of planning and coordination of the statistical system to improve the delivery of objectives and outputs in line with the 5-year programme for official statistics, and the communication and collaboration with key stakeholders
5. Building the overall capacity and resilience of KAS to maximize results and achieve sustainability by means of a series of linked
The results above correspond to the five components of the programme and are all, in the logical framework of the programme, measurable through verifiable indicators.
The programme document further clarifies the programme structure and proposed sets of activities under each results/components. Though at a fairly detailed level already, these will be further elaborated on in the three month inception phase of the programme where a more detailed time-line for the programme will also be agreed upon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCB/Statistiska centralbyr&#xE5;n</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SCB/Statistiska centralbyr&#xE5;n</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16062" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Statistical capacity building</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="17.19" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.19 - By 2030, build on existing initiatives to develop measurements of progress on sustainable development that complement gross domestic product, and support statistical capacity-building in developing countries</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.19 - By 2030, build on existing initiatives to develop measurements of progress on sustainable development that complement gross domestic product, and support statistical capacity-building in developing countries.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">333453.8119833506</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">333453.8119833506</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-03">302456.667265</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/10841_amendment-to-agrement_between-sida-and-scb-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to agreement between Sida and SCB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/delegation-agreement-eu-sida.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delegation Agreement between EU to Sida</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/delegation-agreement-eu-sida-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delegation Agreement between Sida and EUOK</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/grant-arrangement-between-sida-and-scb_june-2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Arrangement between Sida and SCB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/grant-arrangement-between-sida-and-scb_june-2019-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Arrangement between Sida and Statistics of Sweden (SCB)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/amendment-to-agrement_between-sida-and-scb.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant arragment_Amendment to agreement Sida and SCB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/mou_sida_and_kas-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memorandum of understanding between Sida and Kosovo Agency for Statistics</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/mou_sida_and_kas.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memorandum of understanding between Sida and Kosovo Agency for Statistics</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/decision-.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Strengthening Statistical System in Kosovo 2019 - 2023</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During this second year of implementation of the programme the political climate in
Kosovo has been unstable, which has led to instability in the work of the government.
Consequently, this has impacted the efficiency and effectiveness of work in all
institutions. Apart from this, COVID19 has affected the work at the institutions.
The implementation of the programme is on track and the vast majority of planned
activities are being implemented. Some interventions are experiencing delays in
implementation and have a slightly lower utilization rate of funds. Although progress has
been made in improving statistical system, further improvements are needed.
Highlights from the report:
R1 There has been some improvements when it comes to national accounts and business
statistics. Emphasis on: Transition of table 0303 to Eurostat, and NOE calculations on
restaurants KAS is self-sustainable, which demonstrates that the institutional capacities
has been raised at KAS. Apart from this, questionnaires were prepared for STS and SBS,
which will improve the quality of statistics.

R2 Some progress has been made. Nevertheless, in the upcoming two years the project
will focus more on this result area. When it comes to triangulation of data discussions
have been initiated between KAS and Civil Registry Agency (CRA) to share data
between the two government institutions, however further work is needed in the coming
years. KAS has, for the first time, published SILC and Eurostat has published in their
website. Given that statistics is defined as information about the economic and social
conditions in a society, it can provide many of the facts needed when socio-political
reforms are discussed, planned and implemented. SILC will contribute to the knowledge
needed for reforms in this area of social-economic. Gender Equality Index has
improvement and Kosovo has more data on this area now. LCS questionnaire is
prepared, further work will be done on this.

R3 Metadata process is extensive, therefore until the end of the project support will be
provided. The activities are going in the right direction. Staff has attended several
trainings online (Udemy), which has contributed to the cultural learning change in the
institution. IT equipment has contributed to digitalization of KAS. Staff Satisfaction
Survey has improved, and staff was trained. The team at KAS is self-sustainable for the
next one, minor help for project will be provided. Whereas, IT capacities are still low,
further support will be needed in capacity building and also resources (new employees). A
cyber security assessment was conducted which detected several risks. These will be
assessed together with KAS in the upcoming period.

R4 Progress was made towards this result. Innovative electronic training courses (on
questionnaire design and testing), methodology descriptive on interviewing techniques
were held. The highlight of this was that junior staff found these trainings more
appealing than senior ones did. Gender Statistics webinar was held, this includes
provision of gender-disaggregated statistics, as well as the production of gender specific
outputs and studies wherever possible. It is crucial that all KAS personnel have in their
mind set of work the gender-sensitivity.

R5 Progress was made towards this result. Out of 8 inters 6 were recruited. Sida will
push to hire the IT inters in upcoming reporting period. Sida pushed the recruitment to
be gender balanced. Documents were produced for internal use. However, a close
monitoring will be needed on how these documents will be implemented in KAS.

Communication: During the year, folders, notebooks and stickers with the EU and
Swedish logo were shared with all partners for them to use in line with the
communication Plan. Partners also displayed the EU and Swedish logo in several events
and printed products during the year. However, the communication plan is lacking
behind. Therefore, focus in upcoming two years should be put in implementing the
communication plan that was presented.

Donors: Since the start of the EU-Sida support in the area of economic statistics,
IPAMB2017 has also begun support to KAS in the area of NA. Initially there was
concern that these two projects would compete for the same (scarce) staff resources and
have similar activities, which will lead to duplication. However, this has been avoided as
both Statistics Sweden and IPAMB2017 team through working together and ensure
complementary activities. Consequently, a joint work plan has been agreed upon and
followed.

Risk management is an integral and continuous part of Sidas routines when working
with project management. The foreseen risks for the programme are listed below at risk
register.

As the programme is moving into its third and last year of implementation Sida plans to
provide assistance to partners as they elaborate their programme proposals for the
coming phase regarding integration of gender equality, anti-corruption and capacity
development. Follow-up the implementation speed in 2021 to monitor the delayed
activities.

PIU: During the reporting period some changes where done within implementation of
project. SCB had internal reorganization. Therefore, LTE for Kosovo was changed. The
new TL will join the project fully from the August 2021 (next reporting period). The
position of administrative assistance was redundant. However, after close monitoring it
was decided this position to be reinforced. Next reporting period new administrative
assistant will be employed.

Financial: during the reported period 563,563 EURO were spend. This is amount is
slightly lower than predicted, which was expected keeping into consideration COVID
19. SCB&apos;s total expenditure for this period was 3,015,789 SEK, whereas the total amount
forecasted was 3,524,002 SEK. Which means 85.5% of the planned budget was utilized.
Whereas, FCG&apos;s total expenditure was 2,503,745 SEK, while the forecasted budget was
3,545,054 SEK. Which means 70% of the budget was utlized.

During the reported period also the Embassy has done the reallocation of the budget
(from general implementation budget line to FCG contract) where an amount of 114,700
SEK for audit was added to the contract to FCG, in order to execute the payment to

FCG. PO requested from FCG to send a more detailed budget and forecast for the
upcoming years where audit is included as well. In the budget of 15,309,000 SEK was
added 114,700 SEK for the audit payment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10841" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
