<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5303006603-KOS-41010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Environmental Program 2016-2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kosovos Milj&#xF6;program 2016-2020</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to Environment and Climate in Kosovo-Idicative for 2014</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Support to Environment and Climate in Kosovo-Idicative for 2014</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="61009" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry of Environment</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="61009" role="4" type="71">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other non-financial corporations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Environmental policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="410" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">General Environment Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="15.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">15.1 - By 2020, ensure the conservation, restoration and sustainable use of terrestrial and inland freshwater ecosystems and their services, in particular forests, wetlands, mountains and drylands, in line with obligations under international agreements.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">15.1 - Till 2020 bevara, &#xE5;terst&#xE4;lla och h&#xE5;llbart anv&#xE4;nda ekosystem p&#xE5; land och i s&#xF6;tvatten och deras ekosystemtj&#xE4;nster, s&#xE4;rskilt skogar, v&#xE5;tmarker, berg och torra omr&#xE5;den, i enlighet med de skyldigheter som anges i internationella &#xF6;verenskommelser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="6.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">6.4 - By 2030, substantially increase water-use efficiency across all sectors and ensure sustainable withdrawals and supply of freshwater to address water scarcity and substantially reduce the number of people suffering from water scarcity.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">6.4 - Till 2030 v&#xE4;sentligt effektivisera vattenanv&#xE4;ndningen inom alla sektorer samt s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla h&#xE5;llbara uttag och en h&#xE5;llbar f&#xF6;rs&#xF6;rjning med s&#xF6;tvatten f&#xF6;r att angripa vattenbristen och v&#xE4;sentligt minska det antal m&#xE4;nniskor som lider av vattenbrist.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">78952.8231051513</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">190389.4806562646</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">78952.8231051513</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">190389.4806562646</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">296584.532523</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-02-28">34317.1987859432</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">17026.618301801</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">27609.0060174071</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kosovo/kep-agreement-sweden-mesp-20151028.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specifik agreement MESP Sida</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.upload.openaid.se/kosovo/decision-kep.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Beslut om insats KEP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Below are presented the results acheived over the reported period 04.01.2019 to 03.01.2020. The measurements of the achievements has been calculated on the base of the relation between the activities implemented and activities planned as well as on the base of the other monitoring indicators. Component 1: Strengthening KEPA&#x2019;s capacity for environmental monitoring, assessment and reporting, the results achieved during the reporting period: Result 1: Gender sensitive web reporting and environmental information system established fully achieved. The Environmental Information System (EIS) equipment (software and hardware) has been supplied and successfully tested. This result has been fully achieved through fully achieved. Result 2: Kosovo Environmental Protection Agency (KEPA) staff trained to monitor, assess and report disaggregated by sex and ethnicity, partially achieved. On-the-job training about the Environmental Information System (EIS) was conducted on the field through the implementation of 1 specific workshop and meeting with the working groups. Component 2: Conservation of bio-diversity through Red Book of animal species in Kosovo, has been fully achieved through the implementation of the activities: Key Institutions provided with measurable and assessable tools on biodiversity protection and conservation Population of the following species: (1) Lynx lynx; (2) Ursus arctos; (3) Aquila chrysaetos; (4) Tetrastes bonasia Fully achieved (100.0%). A background document for Red Book of Animal Species was finalised. Procurement documents for the field inventory and for the equipment that is necessary for the data collection for the finalisation of the Red Book of Animal Species were prepared. The related tender was opened, the equipment was supplied. Baseline Report and Database of Animal Species finalised. Methodology for the classification of Animal Species finalised. Three Workshops regarding the preparation of the Redbook of Animal Species were implemented. The field inventory was completed. The field inventory reports were delivered. Woman and man, staff from nature monitoring Institutions trained on monitoring and conservation techniques for animal groups. Finalisation and implementation of the on-the job training programme on monitoring of freshwater ecosystemsand preparation of standard methodologies and guidelines. Organisation of the first meeting of the working group for the facilitation of participatory planning and analysis activities for data generation and statistics on biodiversity and monitoring conservation. Finalisation and implementation of a training programme on legal perspectives on monitoring, preservation and conservation of animal species. Awareness of NGO&#x2019;s, communities and key institutions on importance/methods of biodiversity protection increased through the finalisation of public awareness promotional material and the implementation of 9 preparatory workshops and meetings with working groups Component 3: Strengthening of the management of trans-boundary areas: the following results have been achieved during the reporting period: Capacities of NP Directorates to manage the natural resources are strengthened; including participation-gender mainstreaming has been partially achieved. The following activities have taken place: Implementation of on-the-job training through 5 workshops and meetings with selected target groups. Assistance to Ministry of environment and Spatial Planning (MESP) KEPA in developing a strategy to establish operational national parks (NP) information centres; design of touristic sites, etc. Assistance to MESP in preparing and implementing a preliminary plan to organise fairs and promotion of traditional product brands. Transboundary gender responsive cooperation and coordination for nature conservation are enhanced fully achieved. Completion of the assessment of pressures and impacts of human activities on landscape, biodiversity and cultural heritage included in the updated Assessment Report of the KEP. Finalisation of the plan and programme of measures to protect and/or restore natural ecosystems, habitats and species. Component 4: Establishment of groundwater monitoring network in Kosovo, partially achieved through the implementation of the activities described below Indicators of achievement: Groundwater monitoring points (wells) refurbished partially achieved. Implementation of visits on the fields and of preliminary surveys. Identification of groundwater monitoring points (wells) to be refurbished. Preparation of a design for the refurbishment of designated wells for monitoring purposes. Drafting the procurement documents for the refurbishment works of wells and for the groundwater monitoring equipment supply. Remote monitoring stations are linked with central server in Kosovo Hidro-Meteorological Institute (KHMI) and real-time data on groundwater status to KHMI HQ transmitted, partially achieved. Preliminary proposal of the system linking the monitoring stations with central server in KHMI and for the transmission of real-time data. Implementation of 3 workshops and working group meetings with central and local administrations. Component 5: Strengthening capacity for implementation of environmental legislation at central-local level, results are fully achieved through the implementation of the activities: Institutional capacity of Municipalities and MESP to implement environmental legislation/regulations enhanced. Number and quality of gender impact assessment of environmental legislation/regulations Fully achieved. Completion of the Assessment Analysis and updating of Assessment Report. Completion of the draft laws on Chemicals and Inspectorates. Finalisation of the fifth Pilot LEAP. Finalisation of LEAP Strategy. Delivering of Draft Plan for mainstreaming environmental/climate change resilience. Implementation of 10 Workshops / Working Groups meetings on IPPC (4), on EIA (4), on Hazardous Waste (1) and on Environmental Risk (1). Communication-cooperation between the central and local levels to implement environmental laws improved. Capacity of MESP and municipalities for participation and mainstreaming gender issues strengthened has been fully achieved. Implementation of High Level&#x2019; meeting on Coordination Mechanisms. Drafting the Environmental Glossary and the Environmental Code. Drafting the Institutional and Legal Reform Programme. 6: Groundwater investigation in Drini River Basin results has been fully achieved through the implementation of the activities: Groundwater monitoring programme (to observe qualitative and quantitative status) designed ? 25 wells constructed and pumping tests and analysis of results performed Fully achieved (100.0%). Finalisation of ToR, BoQ, drawings and TD for Geophysical Investigations and well drilling. Finalisation of Report for the location of wells. Selection of the contractor and implementation of the works for the well drilling. Completion of the Geophysical Investigations. Coordination with MESP and respective Municipalities for solving the access rights for drilling of the wells. Supervision and control activities of well completion, including final well completion report and commissioning. Carrying out of the hydraulic-hydrogeological analysis of well drilling and pumping test data, conduct well and aquifer yield tests. Characterization of quantitative status of Groundwater Bodies (GWB) in Drin River Basin ? Percentage of households without water on premises, by sex of main person responsible for collecting drinking water, size and type of household Fully achieved. Updating of existing programme for monitoring of groundwater quality in coordination with component 4 of the Programme. Identification of the transboundary GWB in the Drin River Basin by making use of the results of the &quot;Drin River Basin Characteristics-Hydrology Report&quot;. Identification of the flow system of the GWB in the Drin River Basin (recharge and discharge) ? Characterization of qualitative status of groundwater bodies in the Drini River Basin ? Aquifer capacities and groundwater potential analysed. Groundwater quality status within Drini RB determined. Finalisation the templates for the finalisation of the first Quality Test Report. Definition of the Methodologies and approaches on quality status and trend status. Implementation of the water quality tests. Capacities of WD/KEPA/KHMI strengthened and sampling and monitoring mechanism improved by 2018. Conduction of on-the-job training to strengthen capacities of MESP personnel and implementation of 6 key meetings of selected working groups Review and proposing changes to existing MESP and reporting set-up. Component 7: River Basin Management Plan for Drini River Basin has also achieved the following results: Water bodies (surface water and groundwater) within Drini River Basin (RB) characterized has been partially achieved. Implementation of the activities for mapping of surface water resources and for the identification of the groundwater resources and protected areas of Drini RB has been drafted. Assessment of impacts from physical/artificial alteration of water bodies has been drafted. Development of a database for keeping records on water resources: topographic, hydrologic, meteorological and water quality data. Water balance and sector-wise water resources allocation model for Drini RB analysed using gender-sensitive data has been partially achieved. Organisation of the activities and start of the analysis of the water balance and sector wise water resources&#x2019; allocation model for Drini RB. Assessment of existing water extraction infrastructure and water use (actual and future). Programme of measures based on the gender cost-efficiency analysis developed and prioritized partially achieved. Assessment of the pressure originating from anthropogenic activities. Analysis of water extraction control and water demand management. Stakeholders are involved, engaged and informed on the development of the River Basin Management Plan (RBMP). Facilitation of participation of MESP staff in the regional cooperation in Drini River Basin has been partially achieved (55.6%). Organisation of Public Awareness (PA) campaign (through spoken and written public media and leaflets). Organisation and implementation of on-the-job training through 13 workshops and meetings with working groups and technical committees. Gap Assessment Report prepared in gender sensitive way Fully achieved (100.0%). Implementation of the Gap Analysis and Review of Data Availability to be included in the updated Assessment Report of KEP. Finalisation of the Report on the methodologies for SWMIS. Water bodies (surface water and groundwater) within Drini River Basin characterized. Implementation of the activities for mapping of surface water resources and for the identification of the groundwater resources and protected areas of Drini RB. Assessment of impacts from physical/artificial alteration of water bodies. Development of a database for keeping records on water resources: topographic, hydrologic, meteorological and water quality data. Water balance and sector-wise water resources allocation model for Drini RB analysed using gender-sensitive data. Organisation of the activities and start of the analysis of the water balance and sector wise water resources&#x2019; allocation model for Drini RB. Assessment of existing water extraction infrastructure and water use (actual and future). Programme of measures based on the gender cost-efficiency analysis developed and prioritized. Assessment of the pressure originating from anthropogenic activities, under impact of climate change and climate variability and water adaptation strategy. Analysis of water extraction control and water demand management. Stakeholders are involved, engaged and informed on the development of the River Basin Management Plan (RBMP). Facilitation of participation of MESP staff in the regional cooperation in Drini River Basin. Identification of relevant transborder initiatives to be implemented. Organisation and implementation of on-the-job training through 17 workshops, conferences and meetings with working groups and technical committees Result from the component 8: Support to Inter-Ministerial Water Council has been fully achieved through the implementation of the activities described below: New Water related Laws drafted and approved. Updating of the Water Meter System (WMS) to be approved by the GoK. Review of all water services&#x2019; legislation consistency/ compliance with EU directives and inclusion of all related data in the updated Assessment Report. Finalisation of a report on Terminology and Methodology for Water Glossary. Assistance to the MESP EPWD and Minister in drafting the new Water Law. Potential for private sector participation (PSP) in the water services industry of Kosovo assessed. Reconnaissance visit to concerned Ministries and other stakeholders. Assessment of Private Sector Participation (PSP) in the water services industry of Kosovo. Pan-Albanian (English-Albanian) water sector glossary developed in coordination with other donors ? Relevant other amended new secondary laws enacted and sector framework is made public. Reconnaissance visits to academic institutions and water stakeholders to discuss the initiative. Linking up with other similar projects, in particular the GIZ project in Albania. Identification and analysis of best procedure and address to push the initiative through. Suggesting and initiating a working group. Finalisation and delivering of the first Pan-Albanian Water Glossary for the final consultation with key stakeholders. RWCs providing efficient, safe affordable and sustainable water services to all municipalities and existing rural systems. Wastewater treated / drinking water provided at EU standards. Financial analysis of water sector and of the rate of cost recovery (included in the WS). Assessment of the performance trends of the existing RWCs. Proposal of concrete legal -financial implications in reducing the f RWC number from 7 to less. Kosovo water footprint assessment completed. Presentation of a comprehensive set of methods for water footprint assessment. Showing how water footprints can be calculated for individual processes and products, as well as for consumers, businesses and nation. Description how to assess the sustainability of the water footprint aggregation within a river basin or of a specific product. Development of standards for water footprint accounting, water footprint assessment and reduction of negative impacts. Development of practical tools to support people / interested organisations in water footprint accounting, impact assessment, reduction ? Sector policies in minority municipalities replicated. Assessment of current institutional set-up and capacities in the minority areas. Development of a list of prioritized sector reforms that need to be replicated. Laying of a roadmap of integrating the minority municipalities in the water sector reforms Implementation of Gender and Equality Policies: Number and quality of gender impact assessment of environmental legislation/regulations and gender and equality policies implemented. Updating and implementation of the Gender and Equality Action Plan. Finalisation and updating of the &#x201C;View on my glasses&#x201D; report on Institutional Gender and Equality Analysis. Organisation and implementation of on-the-job training through 5 dedicated workshops, working group meetings and conferences for municipal and ministerial staff. Regarding the institution capacity building, the approach applied by KEP has been to build capacity through technical assistance experts that support and work together with the staff members of the beneficiary departments and institutions to achieve the results specified in the program document. It is assessed that the capacity building of the ministry it is concluded that this has been realized to a considerable extent. The fact that the ministry and its agencies have been able to achieve the planned results in this complex program and deliver expected results on time, gives indication that the internal capacities of the ministry are strengthened. The engagement and participation of ministry has been strong and effective and there is general satisfaction among staff at all levels with the performance of the technical assistance, who has managed in most cases to keep the role of assisting the beneficiary institutions, without taking over too much of implementation. However, to assess the level of the increased capacity of the ministry of environment, more in depth review/evaluation will take place by the completion of the project. The capacities of the ministry should be seen in the light of the fulfilling requirements from the EU Acquis-chapter 27, as part of the Stabilization and Association Agreement that Kosovo signed with EC in 2015. According to the EC progress report for 2019, limited progress has been observed. Despite considerable results&#xA0; achieved by this program, many of the deliverables (revised and newly drafted laws, sub-legislation and other administrative and management manuals) are not approved by the political level of the ministry. This hinders implementation which indicate low priority in the government agenda that is given for improving environment &#xA0;and managing environmental challenges in the country. &#xA0;&#xA0;&#xA0; It is Sida assessment that the majority of the results are expected achievement at the end of the project.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <contribution contributionid="53030066" xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></contribution>
  <strategies xmlns="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.0" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</title>
    <titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</titleSV>
   </strategy>
  </strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
