<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12605A0101-KOS-31210</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFAO Climate change mitigation within forestry sector</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNFAO lindring av klimat f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar- inom skogsbrukssektorn</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FAO har ans&#xF6;kt om st&#xF6;d p&#xE5; 24 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &#x201D;Support on strengthening sustainable and multipurpose forest management for improved rural livelihoods in Kosovo&#x201D; under perioden 2019&#x2013;2023. 

Insatsen syftar till att st&#xE4;rka skogssektorns bidrag till Kosovos ekonomi och bidra till att minska fattigdomen p&#xE5; landsbygden genom ett resurseffektivt skogsbruk med ett integrerat j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsperspektiv.  

FAO kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med Kosovos jordbruksministerium (Kosovo Ministry of Agriculture Forestry and Rural Development), Kosovos skogsv&#xE5;rdsverk (Kosovo Forest Agency), samt Milj&#xF6;ministeiet (Ministry of Environment and Spatial Planning).

Projektets sammanlagda budget uppg&#xE5;r till cirka 50 miljoner SEK (5,3 miljoner USD), varav Sverige bidrar med 24 miljoner SEK (2.2 miljoner EURO/2.54 miljoner USD), EU-kommission, genom IPA 2019, bidrar med 15 miljoner SEK (1.6 miljoner EURO/1.7 miljoner USD) och Kosovan Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Rural Development (and its Kosovo Forest Agency) bidrar med resterande 8 miljoner SEK (0.7 miljoner EURO/0.8 miljoner USD).
Samfinansieringen av projektet bidrar till &#xF6;kat nationellt &#xE4;garskap och ansvarstagande.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The FAO has as applied to Sida for funding of 24 million SEK to carry out the &quot;Support on strengthening sustainable and multipurpose forest management for improved rural livelihoods in Kosovo&quot; during the period 2019-2023. 

The intervention aim is to increase forest sector&#x2019;s contribution to the Kosovo economy and reduce poverty in rural areas through efficient and gender-responsive forest management. 

The FAO will implement the intervention in close cooperation with the Kosovo Ministry of Agriculture Forestry and Rural Development and Kosovo Forest Agency and will closly cooperate with the Ministry of Environment and Spatial Planning.

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is approx. 50 million SEK (5,3 million USD), out of which Sweden will contribute with 24 million SEK (2.2 million EURO/ 2,54 million USD) and the European Commission thorough IPA 2019 will provide 15 million SEK (1.6 million EURO/1.7 million UDS) and the remaining 8 million SEK (0,7 million EURO/0.8 million USD) is contributed by the Kosovan Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Rural Development (and its Kosovo Forest Agency).
The co-financing of the project contributes to increased national ownership and responsibility.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The forest sector is considered to have a high potential in increasing its contribution to the national economy and the economic development. One of the Government&#x2019;s roles in this process is to support and facilitate the development of the sector.
The main objectives of the proposed intervention is to increase forest sector&#x2019;s contribution to the Kosovo economy and reduce poverty in rural areas through efficient and gender-responsive forest management.
The Programme outputs and activities are aligned with the existing and proposed new Kosovo Forest Law, the EU Forest Strategy, the IPA (Instrument for Pre-Accession) with the EU, the 2010-2020 Policy and Strategy Paper (PSP) on Forestry Sector Development, as well as the evolving Forest Policy of Kosovo.
In a overall context of sustainable development goals, Programme&#x2019;s strategy will enable Kosovo to improve forest legality, accountable governance, and rural people&#x2019;s interest, skills and competencies for a spirit of self-empowerment. This will lead to more productive participatory forestry, which will generate multiple benefits for the rural low-income women and men.
Developmental Goal is to increase forest sector&#x2019;s contribution to Kosovo economy and reduce poverty in rural areas through efficient and gender-responsive forest management.
The Programme Outcome is that Kosovar forests in Target Regions are managed more efficiently with multi-purpose, participatory approach, strengthened in accordance with the approved Law on Forests and supported with gender-responsive value-chains for poverty alleviation.
The Programme is implemented through three Components, each further operationalized into specific Outputs and achieved through Activities.
First Component is dedicated to improving timber legality, trade and law enforcement in forest sector.
Second Component enhances transparency and strengthens the institutional capacity in good governance and implementation of forest policies, strategies and programmes.
Third Component introduces and implements multi-purpose forest management, strengthens inclusive forest value chains for poverty alleviation of rural women and men, and establishes new skills and capacities in forest fire management.
The implementing partner is United Nation Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO). The Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) is one of the largest specialized agencies in the United Nations system and the lead agency for agriculture, forestry, fisheries and rural development. The Organization is comprised of 194 Member States, two associate members and one member organization the European Union. Serving both for developing countries and transition economies, FAO since its founding in 1945, acts as a neutral forum where all nations meet as equals to negotiate agreements and debate policy issues, global and regional. FAO is also a source of knowledge and information, helping developing countries and transition economies to modernize and improve agriculture, forestry and fisheries practices and ensure safe and healthy nutrition for all. The FAO is a custodian UN agency for 21 of the 230 SDG indicators identified by the UN Statistical Commission, across SDGs 2, 5, 6, 12, 14 and 15, and a contributing agency for six more. As a custodian agency, FAO will help to ensure that national data are comparable and aggregated at sub-regional, regional and global levels.
The FAO has been collecting and analysing data on forest resources since 1946. Feeding into the monitoring of several SDG 15 targets, the Global Forest Resources Assessment contains information for 234 countries and territories on more than 100 variables related to the extent of forests, their conditions, uses and values.FAO during the period 2011-2017, has considerably supported Kosovo to setup institutional environment for sustainable forest management thanks to a project funded by Finland. The project&#x2019;s primarily focus was to support the institutions who are mandated for the implementation of the PSP adopted by Government of Kosovo in 2010. Consequently, Kosovo Government capacities have been enhanced: inter-ministerial arrangements for supervising and monitoring PSP implementation were created; the Action Plan for PSP implementation was formulated and used for operational activities; the system for Monitoring and Evaluation of PSP implementation was designed and used for annual forest sector progress reports. Joint Annual Reviews were introduced, and they became a regular institutional practice for discussing the annual progress of the sector.
The Forest Management Board (FMB) for supervising the implementation of PSP became functional and Kosovo forest authorities became part of regional and international forest related initiatives. Information and communication strategy on the importance of the forestry sector was designed followed by a mass media campaign. Sustainable forest management was addressed through development of National Afforestation and Reforestation Program (NARP), Kosovo Forest Health Program (KFHP), as well as Kosovo Forest Information System (KFIS).
Climate change was addressed through modelling of Wood Biomass Supply and Demand in Kosovo. Finally, public forestry work and trainings in the northern Kosovo municipalities were carried out and a forest laboratory for applied research was established and equipped at the Kosovo Forest Institute.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41301" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAO/Food and Agriculture Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41301" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food and Agricultural Organisation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="312" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.b - Fr&#xE4;mja mekanismer f&#xF6;r att h&#xF6;ja f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till effektiv klimatrelaterad planering och f&#xF6;rvaltning i de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, med s&#xE4;rskilt fokus p&#xE5; kvinnor, ungdomar samt lokala och marginaliserade samh&#xE4;llen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.b - Promote mechanisms for raising capacity for effective climate change-related planning and management in least developed countries and small island developing States, including focusing on women, youth and local and marginalized communities.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">15.3 - By 2030, combat desertification, restore degraded land and soil, including land affected by desertification, drought and floods, and strive to achieve a land degradation-neutral world.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">15.3 - Till 2030 bek&#xE4;mpa &#xF6;kenspridning, &#xE5;terst&#xE4;lla f&#xF6;rst&#xF6;rd mark och jord, inklusive mark som drabbats av &#xF6;kenspridning, torka och &#xF6;versv&#xE4;mningar, samt str&#xE4;va efter att uppn&#xE5; en v&#xE4;rld utan nettof&#xF6;rst&#xF6;ring av mark.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453072</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">740278.5562453072</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">542905.8492676202</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">542905.84926762</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-01">2326589.748199</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-10-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">211508.1589272306</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-06-28">542905.84926762</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This conclusion on performance of the contribution &quot;UNFAO Climate change mitigation within forestry sector&quot; covers the period from 5 September 2019 (when the agreement is signed by both parties) until 30 September 2020. The UNFAO started implementation on 16 October 2019, upon recipient of the first disbursement-according to the internal rules. An FAO internal Programme Task Force was established in October 2019 in line with FAO &quot;Project Cycle&quot; comprised of technical and programme staff from Regional Office in Budapest and FAO Headquarters responsible for the technical, operational and administrative aspects of the programme. During the first year of the implementation the programme has been delayed severely, with very limited programme activities being conducted. The programme core team in the field has not been set up (field staff recruited) by UNFAO programme management office in Budapest-Hungary. FAO have not provided explanations regarding reasons for delays in recruitment of the field core staff. A situation of COVID 19 was mentioned as a reason. However, the implementation started almost 6 months before the pandemic, and the total lock-down in the country lasted less than two months. &#xA0; Due to the delayed recruitment&apos;s of the programme field staff (consisted of 4 key positions), the COVID-19 pandemic had more impact in the implementation of the planned programme activities in the field. The selection process for the Local Team Leader and the Local Forestry Specialist, as well as administrative staff has not been finalised during this reporting period. This issue increases risks related to achieving results. In addition, out of 11 short-term program specialists, planned to be contracted, only two were recruited and have started their work from distance. The work plan and budget has been revised twice, in March and June 2020 and approved by the programme steering committee that was established in March 2020. Both meeting of the steering committee took place virtually due to the situation over COVID 19 pandemic.Partial office equipment&#x2019;s have been purchased, and there are several planned procurements still pending. Few programme planned activities during this period have taken place in the field, mainly managed distantly by the FAO programme team in Budapest: Regarding component 1: Improve timber legality, trade and law enforcement in forest sectorThe objective of this component is to support the preparation of the necessary forestry by-laws, improving public service capacities to support law enforcement with new skills and equipment, and generate public support to combat illegal activities in the forest sector. Following activities were conducted during this period:- A Local Legal Specialist and a Local Forest Economist Specialist were selected competitively and hired, and the vacancy announcement for an International Legal Specialist published and applications received;- The Local Legal and Forest Economist Specialists developed the plan for establishing the baseline on timber legality and conducting a fiscal assessment of the forest sector. Activities within component 2 related to enhancement of the e transparency and strengthen the institutional capacity in good governance and implementation of forest policies, strategies and programmes, minor activities have taken place. Requirements for the specialists from these fields of expertise are still pending. Regarding component 3 that aims to introduce and implement the multi-purpose forest management, strengthens inclusive forest value chains for poverty alleviation of rural women and men, and develop new skills and capacities in forest fire management-Target areas for developing and implementing the Multipurpose Forest Management Planning have been identified and selected for further analyses following the proposals from the Kosovo Forest Agency. In addition, it is reported that a baseline assessment and new methodology with the modules for multipurpose forest management planning in Kosovo have been proposed to Kosovo Forest Agency and methodology for value chain mapping and action plan for their development was drafted. Also, related to implementation of the activities of this component there is a pending recruitment of the specialist for Local Forest Value Chain Specialist. Other planned activities of the work plan are pending, delayed or in early phases of the development. When it comes to the Kosovo Forest Information System (KFIS) platform financed under the previous program support by Finland, is still not completed by FAO. The KFIS was expected to be functional and handed over to Kosovo Forest Agency in 2019. The KFIS system is fundamental for this program. This outcome is still pending and there is no deadline reported by FAO when the software will be completed and operational. The KFIS software is essential for the implementation of the present programme. In addition, there has been no reported dialogue between FAO as implementer and the Kosovo&#x2019;s Ministry of Agriculture Forestry and Rural Development when it comes to approval of the new Forestry Law that is still in the Kosovan Parliament pending approval. The new Forestry Law is crucial for the program implementation, since this program implementation is based almost entirely on the application of the new Forestry Law. The FAO have not reported neither a communication with all programme stakeholders (line ministries and other government institutions and non-government organizations, including related Sida financed projects in environment and management of natural resources in the country), that will be collaborating during implementation of this programme. Due to this, planned Task Force groups have not been established. In addition, no dialogue has been reported by FAO in relation to EU Office in Kosovo regarding the pledged funding from EU Office in Kosovo for this programme. The lack of the continues communication with EU Office in Kosovo, could potentially have budget implications to the programme and possibly jeopardize the projected results. Sida&apos;s overall assessment of the first year is that the start-up of the program has been slow and that the implementing organisation has lacked in demonstrating innovative approach and flexibility to manage these challanges. A lessons learned is that the lack of an existing local office with sufficient number of staff has affected the results and aggravated the fundamentals in the first phase of the program. This has also worsened due to the un-expected situation with caused by the pandemic.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12605" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
