<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5514000002-XKX-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Program Support to KCSF 2015-2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Program Support to KCSF 2015-2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo Civil Society Foundation program/core support 2015-2018</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kosovo Civil Society Foundation program/core support 2015-2018</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sida support covers all KCSF core activities as laid out in the KCSF Programmatic Strategy. The overall goal of KCSF Programmatic Strategy is to enable civil society for the democratic development of Kosovo. The intended overall goal is the ultimate result of KCSF&#x2019;s theory of change, which is the overarching logic of its strategy.
On achieving the indented goal, KCSF works in three areas:
1) Competent civil society to empower citizens&apos; potential for Kosovo&apos;s democratic development;
2) Civil society initiatives and partners mobilized and supported to enhance civil society role on Kosovo&apos;s democratic development; and,
3) Evidence-based arguments produced and utilized in the policy debate on civil society development and the European integration process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FCG Swedish Development AB</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="90000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Misc</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="17.17" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">45738.4278598547</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">13340.7168528834</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1e-10</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">45738.4278598547</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">13340.7168528834</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-07-01">65884.71166</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-28">45738.3908459269</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">13340.7168528834</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The three areas of work should not be considered as isolated from one another, on the contrary they are interrelated and complement each other. However, to have a structured idea of what they entail they can be thought of as:
1) Capacity building of civil society.
2) Forwarding of funds to civil society organisations (CSOs).
3) Advocacy work through a constructive dialogue with ministries and governmental agencies.
The first area of work is highly relevant for the other two, since improved capacity among CSOs make them a more suitable recipient of forwarded funds and also a more informed and constructive partner doing advocacy work. Throughout the activity period, KCSF continued and upgraded their&#xA0;capacity building programs&#xA0;that serve more than 150 CSOs annually, both from Kosovo and the Western Balkans. KCSF also launched a scheme supporting hundreds of Kosovan CSOs&apos; participation in regional, European and international fora and networks, and a similar scheme supporting partner organizations to&#xA0;contribute to the implementation of key reforms under the Stabilisation and Association Agreement (SAA) in Kosovo.
The second area of work&#xA0;&quot;contributed significantly to building stronger civil society organisations in Kosovo since 2015, both through its fair, independent and efficient grant making schemes, which includes both institutional grants and project grants, as well as through its training and advise especially to weaker and smaller civil society organisations&quot; according to the mid-term review. However,&#xA0;the main achievement came at the end of the activity period with the launch of the pool funding mechansim EJA (Engagement for Joint Action).&#xA0;EJA is expected to improve effectiveness through better coordination on several levels. KCSF&apos;s funding is provided by donors who traditionally have specified their own targets and reporting requirements, leading to sub-optimal efficiency. Through EJA, several donors agree on objectives and implementation modalities and pool their funding. For KCSF this will lower administrative costs and give the possibility to work more long term and retain staff more easily since the set up will be less project based. For donors, it gives an opportunity to coordinate better and use funds more efficiently. For CSOs, it provides long term clarity on possibilities for funding. Developing EJA is quite a feat and one of the strategic long term achievements, which would have been impossible to accomplish without core support from the Swedish Embassy. The mid-term review stated that &quot;KCSF is recognised as an efficient organisation and, with the introduction of&#xA0;a pooled funding mechanism and the promise of donors to join this, is expected to become even more efficient.&quot; &#xA0;
In the third area of work, KCSF normally mobilizes and works alongside other CSOs when conducting dialogue with different ministries, especially the ministries of public administration, local governance and EU integration. This&#xA0; dialogue was relatively slow for a long time due to the absence of a functioning government. However, important achievements were made: KCSF pioneered work on the&#xA0;minimum standards for public consultation. Public consultation is a key element in a sound democracy, and ensures that the public can contribute to the policies they are influenced by. Additionally it enables governmental bodies to draft laws of higher quality, since input from the affected parties are taken into account. The regulation&#xA0;which obliges all central level institutions to conduct public consultations in policy-making processes entered into force in 2017.
The previous law on preventing money laundering and financing of terrorism contained highly restrictive provisions for CSOs. E.g. it required formal approval from state authorities for any payment from CSOs above EUR 1,000. Failure to adhere to such requirements were punished by imprisonment and fines. The law was drafted without public consultation, and KCSF&#xA0;submitted numerous written comments to the Financial Intelligence Unit (FIU) of Kosovo and&#xA0; the Ministry of Finance as well as mobilizing Kosovan CSOs and establishing partnerships with European and global CSOs active in the area. This work convinced the FIU and KCSF formed part of a working group to amend the law. In May 2016, the new Law on preventing the money laundry and fighting the financing of terrorism was adopted, with the majority of restrictive provisions on CSOs removed.&#xA0;
Further restrictions for civil society were prevented in April 2019, when parliament restored the positive version of the NGO Law following an advocacy campaign led by KCSF.&#xA0;The most recent amendment of the NGO Law took place during 2016-2017 through a process characterized by inclusive policy-making and in December 2017 the government approved the law. However, the parliamentary committee proposed 38 amendments, some being very restrictive, which were then passed in parliament. Around 300 civil society organizations led by KCSF sent a formal request to the President of Kosovo, asking him not to sign the law and as a result from the advocacy campaign the 38 amendments were not accepted into the final law. Had it remained unchanged, it would have legalized the possibility for NGO capital to be transferred to private institutions - increasing the risk for corruption - and it would also have given authorities the possibility to terminate NGOs based on arbitrary interpretations of the organisation&apos;s activities.
According to the mid-term review&#xA0;&quot;KCSF is considered a leader in facilitating civil society participation in public decision making, both by facilitating the possibilities for participation and by funding think tanks and other CSOs in doing research and advocacy on important issues, especially at national level but also to some extent at local level.&quot;</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55140000" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
