<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5502017202-KOS-31220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">CNVP Privat Skog Kosovo fas 2</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CNVP Private Forestry Kosovo Phase 2</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektets huvudsakliga m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att st&#xF6;tta privat och decentraliserad  skogsutveckling i Kosovo och, f&#xF6;r relevanta punkter, ocks&#xE5; p&#xE5;         regional niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project&apos;s main aim is to support private and decentralised        forestry development in Kosovo and, for relevant issues, also at      regional level</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CNVP Foundation/Connecting Natural Values and People Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry development</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="312" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.1 - Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters in all countries.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.1 - St&#xE4;rka motst&#xE5;ndskraften mot och f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till anpassning till klimatrelaterade faror och naturkatastrofer i alla l&#xE4;nder.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">15.2 - By 2020, promote the implementation of sustainable management of all types of forests, halt deforestation, restore degraded forests and substantially increase afforestation and reforestation globally.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">15.2 - Till 2020 fr&#xE4;mja genomf&#xF6;randet av h&#xE5;llbart brukande av alla typer av skogar, stoppa avskogningen, &#xE5;terst&#xE4;lla utarmade skogar och kraftigt &#xF6;ka nybeskogningen och &#xE5;terbeskogningen i hela v&#xE4;rlden.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">15.3 - By 2030, combat desertification, restore degraded land and soil, including land affected by desertification, drought and floods, and strive to achieve a land degradation-neutral world.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">15.3 - Till 2030 bek&#xE4;mpa &#xF6;kenspridning, &#xE5;terst&#xE4;lla f&#xF6;rst&#xF6;rd mark och jord, inklusive mark som drabbats av &#xF6;kenspridning, torka och &#xF6;versv&#xE4;mningar, samt str&#xE4;va efter att uppn&#xE5; en v&#xE4;rld utan nettof&#xF6;rst&#xF6;ring av mark.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="9.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">9.1 - Bygga ut tillf&#xF6;rlitlig, h&#xE5;llbar och motst&#xE5;ndskraftig infrastruktur av h&#xF6;g kvalitet, inklusive regional och gr&#xE4;ns&#xF6;verskridande infrastruktur, f&#xF6;r att st&#xF6;dja ekonomisk utveckling och m&#xE4;nniskors v&#xE4;lbefinnande, med fokus p&#xE5; ekonomiskt &#xF6;verkomlig och r&#xE4;ttvis tillg&#xE5;ng f&#xF6;r alla.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">9.1 - Develop quality, reliable, sustainable and resilient infrastructure, including regional and transborder infrastructure, to support economic development and human well-being, with a focus on affordable and equitable access for all.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">317262.2383908459</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-08-01">437324.159244</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">317262.2383908459</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/55020172_AddendumSWEDEN-CNVP-2018.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment agreement with CNVP</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/cnvp-pfk-p2-agreement-amendment-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to the agreement CNVP Sida 2014</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/cnvp-pfk-p2-agreement-amendment-2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to the agreement CNVP Sida 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/cnvp-pfk-p2-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement SSPDF 2, 2014</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/cnvp-pfk-p2-decision-amendment-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om avtals&#xE4;ndring 1 SSPDF phase 2, 2014</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/cnvp-pfk-p2-decision-amendment-2.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om avtals&#xE4;ndring 2 SSPDF phase 2, 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/cnvp-pfk-p2-decision-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats SSPDF phase 2, 2014</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">During 2018, based on the conclusions and recommendations of the mid-term review (MTR) of SSPDF that took place during February and March 2017, CNVP has improved the quality of the results&#x2019; monitoring framework, having produced a new Results Based Management (RBM) and Monitoring Plan (MP) (see Annex 1).In 2018, beneficiaries/users of JFM, the Municipalities and KFA have signed contracts to complete the process of JFM in two municipalities (Novo Berde and Ka&#xE7;canik). This is the second process of JFM that the state management of forests has delegated to a FFO, creating a partnership between KFA, the municipality and the FFO for sustainable forest management.The National Private Forest Owner Association (NAPFO) is the umbrella of 23 Associations of Private Forest Owner Associations (APFOs). It has continued to increase the capacities of its members on strategic planning, increasing membership, delivering services, promoting Women and Youth Producers Groups (WYPG) within APFOs, and increasing the level of participation of women in the steering bodies of APFOs.Linked to advocacy, the SSPDF project has continued to increase further the capacities of NAPFO and the APFOs. As a result, NAPFO has finalized an official document &#x201C;Agenda 2018&#x201D; (see Annex 5) where all important issues related to improvement of the legal framework conditions, policies and support to private forestry owners (PFO) have been ranked.NAPFO has continued to extend and strengthen its influence on decision-making bodies (policy decisions) realizing many meetings, drafting documents, and requesting improved management of the forestry sector in Kosovo.The SSPDF project during 2018 continued to organize events and round tables. It proposed amendments for a new draft law for forestry, as well as simplified procedures for logging wood for private forest owners. The advocacy process of NAPFO that relates to the new draft law on forestry has continued and resulted in including proposed amendments for JFM.The promotion of biomass production and its use for renewable energy in Kosovo has continued. The SSPDF project has promoted innovative approaches for increasing biomass production and using it to generate energy as a way of mitigating climate change.In this regard project, the project finalized five case study for municipalities that have potential for investment in decentralized district heating systems based on biomass. At the same time, this concept and case studies were discussed with main stakeholders in Kosovo, including the Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Rural Development (MAFRD), the Ministry of Economic Development (MED), the Ministry of Local Government Administration (MLGA), the Ministry of Environment and Spatial Planning (MESP), municipalities, NAPFO and the APFOs.The project has been working to bring Sustainable Forest Management (SFM) in public forest ownership through the introduction of joint forest management (JFM) practices where local communities or associations take responsibility for the sustainable management of these forests.In private forests, the project has been supporting: the structure of private forest owners&#x2019; associations (NAFPO and APFO); further service delivery efforts to enhance sustainable management practices; the design and implementation of the legal and policy framework; and ways of adding value to forestry products through value chain development.The detailed actions taken by the SSPDF project in 2018 based on the annual work plan are described in Annex 2 (Activity database).As part of the capacity development measure related to private forestry management and JFM, the SSPDF project has increased the number of municipalities included under the JFM process (10 municipalities) as well as the number of management plans (MPs) prepared (74).The main accomplishment during 2018 is that stakeholders received the concept of JFM. This helps to ensure SFM which contributes to forestry protection, decreases the level of management informality, and brings more benefit for both the local community and the environment. This process enables the direct involvement of the community in managing public forest land, which did not exist before. Areas given for JFM are mainly degraded coppice forest which has been heavily impacted by uncontrolled logging, mainly for firewood. Forest protection can now be more easily managed through close coordination and cooperation with the local community.Local associations are continuously working with their members to increase membership, strengthen representation at regional and national level, involve women in forestry activities, and improve service delivery to members.During the year 4 field visits have been conducted by the Program manager and the Country manager. A visit form Sida HQ also took place in April 2018 to learn about the CNVP work in the field and meeting were organized with the representatives of the Associations of the Family Forest Owners in few municipalities and were CNVP presented work and the resulats of the woman producers groups within these assoatiations.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55020172" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
