<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13589A0101-XKX-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support KCSF 2020-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Core support KCSF 2020-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In a time when Kosovo&apos;s politically elected leaders show limited success in forming stable governments, fighting corruption and coming to constructive solutions to the conflict with Serbia, an active and professional civil society has an important role to play.
Civil society in Kosovo has a strong tradition especially from the 1990s and building post-war and independent Kosovo. It is currently seen as the main channel to fight corruption and building inter-ethnic relations in the country as well as serving marginalized groups.&#xA0;At the same time&#xA0;as&#xA0;being vibrant and dynamic, civil society in Kosovo is heterogeneous and the number of registered CSOs amount to approximately 10 000. However, only about 10% of these are estimated to be active and often their legitimacy to represent specific groups is hard to verify,&#xA0;due to unclear&#xA0;membership base and non-systematic communication of constituency demand (Kosovar Civil Society Index, 2018, KCSF). Moreover, CSOs are highly dependent on funding from donors, which has often led to activities being donor driven rather than membership/constituency driven. In spite of this, civil society&#xA0;enjoys relatively high trust among citizens and there has been an increase in membership and volunteering&#xA0;for CSOs in the last couple of years (Public Pulse XV, 2019, UNDP &amp; USAID).
In Sida&apos;s strive to reach the targets of the result strategy, support to the civil society is an important component.&#xA0;The strategy&#xA0;states that &quot;civil society&apos;s role as a force for change in the countries of the Western Balkans is a catalyst for democratic development. Swedish support should include initiatvies&#xA0;to increase the capacity and sustainability of civil society/.../working&#xA0;for democratic values and&#xA0;human rights.&quot;
Through its role in strenghtening civil society&#xA0;via analyses,&#xA0;trainings and fund forwarding, KCSF is deemed highly relevant as a partner to Sida. Fund forwarding has been at the&#xA0;core of KCSF&apos;s work since the beginning over 20 years ago. The PFM, which will&#xA0;be officially launched&#xA0;in March 2020,&#xA0;provides a clearer long term framework for&#xA0;how this will be conducted. The instruments&#xA0;proposed for fund forwarding within the PFM are:&#xA0;
Institutional grants (IG)
Institutional grants aim to support the implementation of the strategies of the organizations and in parallel with strengthening the internal organizational capacities become the voice of citizens in the thematic areas that they cover. Financial support for the work of the organization is intended to sustain organizations that are change agents and to act and contribute to main societal developments in their area of expertise. Organizations will be eligible to receive funding for a duration of 24-36 months. The maximum budget for the institutional grants will be 40,000 EUR/annually.
Organizational development grants (ODG)
Organizational development grants are characterized by the focus on supporting the capacity building of the organization (staff, development of internal tools and systems of the organization, internal documents, etc.). Depending on the request from the organization, a single activity or a series of activities can be funded. The maximum duration for these grants is 24 months and the maximum budget allowed is 15,000 EUR per grant.
Small project grants 
Different from past calls for project grants, under this call, citizen initiatives and individuals would be eligible, while the scope of projects is expected to be narrower and more focused. Hence the application procedure for submitting a concept note will be simplified to ensure that organizations of various levels of capacity are reached. Civil society initiatives are required to operate in their respective localities and in addition, organizations that have an annual budget over 25,000 EUR annually are excluded from this call. This is to enable that CSOs compete among equals and are not put in the same basket with well-established CSOs that have established a capacity for proposal writing and application. Maximum budget per grant is 10,000 EUR and maximum duration should not exceed 12 months.
Medium project grants 
Medium project grants aim to support medium and larger interventions. Targeted CSOs are those with sufficient capacities to implement projects expected to have an impact on a national level or on more systematic processes, with a duration of up to 24 months, and with a budget up to 50,000 EUR per project. Medium project grants will be ready for utilization as an instrument subject to additional donors joining the PFM.
Urgent grants 
This instrument is intended for rare instances in which a quick response from civil society initiatives is needed and there may not be time to react through standard application procedures. Main characteristics for this instrument are: urgency of the matter and necessity of reaction, easy application and quick decision-making, short term and focused results. Similar to the project grants, this instrument will be open also for citizen initiatives and individuals. The maximum budget for this type of instrument is 3,000 EUR.
Awards
Awards honor successful initiatives, the work and activities of organizations or individuals who have contributed in the development of a democratic society in Kosovo. The maximum amount of the award will be 5,000 EUR with the purpose of elevating the profile of the recipients and commend such qualities as: innovation, courage/bravery, and impact/achievement in civil society&#x2019;s pursuit of Kosovo&#x2019;s democratization.
The fact that PFM will provide more opportunities for grassroot organizations and even individuals to apply for grants will probably&#xA0;contribute directly to two of the four shifts identified through the MDPA;&#xA0;a stronger focus on Sida&apos;s target group and a geographical shift from central to local level.&#xA0;Sida believes that the increased flexibility for&#xA0;who can apply for grants can&#xA0;have relatively big impact&#xA0;with limited funding.&#xA0;Evaluation of applications will be carried out by an independent group of evaluators from a roster set up by KCSF. No employees of KCSF or any donors will participate in the evaluation process. The mechanism has been established to minimize risks of nepotism and to strenghten work on anti-corruption.&#xA0;An efficiency audit carried out by Ernst &amp; Young at the end of 2019&#xA0;assesses&#xA0;current granting procedures to be robust.
Apart from compulsory trainings for grantees on internal management and control and other topics, the resource center provides a training program called &quot;European integration school&quot; which consists of a one day crash course on EU and civil society which&#xA0;is held&#xA0;once or twice per month. Additionally, there are four thematic workshops and four open lectures each year. Information is provided on the European reform agenda priorities, what different programs are offered by the EU and how civil society can benefit from the programs to build a more democratic Kosovo.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Kosovar Civil Society Foundation (KCSF) har bett om k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d fr&#xE5;n Sida under fyra &#xE5;r (mars 2020-december 2023). Detta &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning p&#xE5; k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d som givits till KCSF sedan 2015. Sida kommer att bidra med SEK 24 000 000 under perioden. F&#xF6;r tillf&#xE4;llet har KCSF tre andra stora givare; schweiziska bist&#xE5;ndsmyndigheten SDC, Norge och Luxemburg. Ingen av dessa ger k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d. F&#xF6;r budget&#xE5;ret 2020 kommer Sidas andel vara 38%, SDC:s 36%, Luxemburgs 20% och Norges 6%. KCSF:s vision &#xE4;r att Kosovo omvandlas till ett demokratiskt och socioekonomiskt utvecklat samh&#xE4;lle med goda f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r EU-integrering . KCSF utf&#xF6;r sitt arbete genom tre olika enheter:

1) Enheten f&#xF6;r vidaref&#xF6;rmedling, som hanterar f&#xF6;rmedling av medel till andra civilsamh&#xE4;llesorganisationer med fokus p&#xE5; utveckling av demokratiska processer och EU-integrering. Enheten hanterar hela f&#xF6;rmedlingskedjan: fr&#xE5;n inbjudan till civilsamh&#xE4;llet att presentera projektf&#xF6;rslag, via granskning och beviljande av ans&#xF6;kningar, till utv&#xE4;rdering av finansierade projekt.
2) Resurscentret, som tillhandah&#xE5;ller utbildningar inom intern kontroll, ekonomisk styrning och hantering av projektcykler samt skr&#xE4;ddarsydda utbildningar enligt specifika &#xF6;nskem&#xE5;l.
3) Enheten f&#xF6;r forskning och p&#xE5;verkansarbete, som utf&#xF6;r analyser av situationen f&#xF6;r det civila samh&#xE4;llet i Kosovo genom studier och forskningsinitiativ, samt kommunicerar betydelsen av ett engagerat civilsamh&#xE4;lle f&#xF6;r en demokratisk utveckling till politiker och beslutsfattare.

KCSFs f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringsteori bygger p&#xE5; tv&#xE5; likv&#xE4;rdiga v&#xE4;gar: den f&#xF6;rsta syftar till ett meningsfullt engagemang hos det civila samh&#xE4;llet i politiska processer genom att bygga organisationers institutionella och kunskapsm&#xE4;ssiga kapacitet, den andra syftar till att skapa inkluderande politiska processer genom direkt och indirekt p&#xE5;verkansarbete gentemot politiker och tj&#xE4;nstem&#xE4;n. KCSF f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntar sig att bidra till &#xE5; ena sidan ett civilsamh&#xE4;lle med befogenhet och kompetens att identifiera sina egna behov och aktivt engagera sig i politiska processer och &#xE5; andra sidan ministerier och myndigheter som bedriver policyutveckling som &#xE4;r &#xF6;ppen f&#xF6;r engagemang fr&#xE5;n olika intressegrupper, s&#xE5;som civilsamh&#xE4;llet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovar Civil Society Foundation (KCSF) has asked Sida for core support during four years (March 2020-December 2023). This is a continuation of the core support given to KCSF since 2015. Sida will contribute with SEK 24 000 000 during the period. Currently KCSF has three other major donors; Swiss Development Cooperation (SDC), Norway and Luxemburg. None of these provides core support. For the fiscal year 2020, Sida&apos;s share of the budget amounts to 38%, SDC&apos;s to 36%, Luxemburg&apos;s to 20% and Norway&apos;s to 6%. KCSF&apos;s vision is to see Kosovo transformed into a democratic society with the prospect of EU integration and an advanced socio-economic situation. KCSF carries out its work through three different units:

1) The fund forwarding unit, which handles forwarding of funds to other CSOs, within the fields of supporting democratic processes and contributing to EU integration. The unit handles the whole chain of fund forwarding: from establishing calls for proposal, via granting applications, to monitoring and evaluation of funded projects.
2) The resource centre, which provides trainings on internal control, financial management and project cycle management as well as tailor made trainings on specific requests.
3) The resarch and advocacy unit, which conducts analyses of the situation for civil society in Kosovo through surveys and research initiatives and advocates the importance of civil society to decision makers.

KCSF&apos;s theory of change builds on two pathways of change: the first aims for the meaningful engagement of civil society in policy processes through building capacity, the second aims at realization of inclusive policy processes through direct and indirect interaction with politicians and civil servants. As an end result, KCSF expects to have contributed to on the one hand CSOs that are empowered and competent to identify their needs and actively engage in policy processes and on the other hand ministries and agencies that conduct a participatory policy making process open to substantive involvement of interest groups, such as CSOs.

KCSF has in collaboration with Sida and SDC developed a tool to simplify the pooling of funds from different donors. This mechanism will be launched during the agreeement period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KCSF/Kosovar Civil Society Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KCSF/Kosovar Civil Society Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="17.17" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.17 - Encourage and promote effective public, public-private and civil society partnerships, building on the experience and resourcing strategies of partnerships.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.0191211441</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">816145.6936655435</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">651487.019121144</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">816145.6936655433</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-01">1411555.208095</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-03-28">651487.0191211441</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-04-28">816145.6936655435</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/200302_grant-agreement_sida_kcsf.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/13589_200302_GrantAgreement_Sida_Kcsf.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/13589_200228Decisiononcontribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/200228-decision-on-contribution-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/200228-decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution, KCSF</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13589" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1150102" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="10550000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2014-01-01">
    <sida:title>Reform cooperation with Eastern Europe, the Western Balkans and Turkey 2014-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Reformsamarbete med &#xD6;steuropa, V&#xE4;stra Balkan och Turkiet 2014-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
