<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12605A0103-XKX-31210</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNFAO Climate change mitigation within forestry sector</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">UNFAO lindring av klimat f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ndringar- inom skogsbrukssektorn</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FAO har ans&#xF6;kt om st&#xF6;d p&#xE5; 24 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &#x201D;Support on strengthening sustainable and multipurpose forest management for improved rural livelihoods in Kosovo&#x201D; under perioden 2019&#x2013;2023. 

Insatsen syftar till att st&#xE4;rka skogssektorns bidrag till Kosovos ekonomi och bidra till att minska fattigdomen p&#xE5; landsbygden genom ett resurseffektivt skogsbruk med ett integrerat j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhetsperspektiv.  

FAO kommer att genomf&#xF6;ra insatsen i n&#xE4;ra samarbete med Kosovos jordbruksministerium (Kosovo Ministry of Agriculture Forestry and Rural Development), Kosovos skogsv&#xE5;rdsverk (Kosovo Forest Agency), samt Milj&#xF6;ministeiet (Ministry of Environment and Spatial Planning).

Projektets sammanlagda budget uppg&#xE5;r till cirka 50 miljoner SEK (5,3 miljoner USD), varav Sverige bidrar med 24 miljoner SEK (2.2 miljoner EURO/2.54 miljoner USD), EU-kommission, genom IPA 2019, bidrar med 15 miljoner SEK (1.6 miljoner EURO/1.7 miljoner USD) och Kosovan Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Rural Development (and its Kosovo Forest Agency) bidrar med resterande 8 miljoner SEK (0.7 miljoner EURO/0.8 miljoner USD).
Samfinansieringen av projektet bidrar till &#xF6;kat nationellt &#xE4;garskap och ansvarstagande.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The FAO has as applied to Sida for funding of 24 million SEK to carry out the &quot;Support on strengthening sustainable and multipurpose forest management for improved rural livelihoods in Kosovo&quot; during the period 2019-2023. 

The intervention aim is to increase forest sector&#x2019;s contribution to the Kosovo economy and reduce poverty in rural areas through efficient and gender-responsive forest management. 

The FAO will implement the intervention in close cooperation with the Kosovo Ministry of Agriculture Forestry and Rural Development and Kosovo Forest Agency and will closly cooperate with the Ministry of Environment and Spatial Planning.

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is approx. 50 million SEK (5,3 million USD), out of which Sweden will contribute with 24 million SEK (2.2 million EURO/ 2,54 million USD) and the European Commission thorough IPA 2019 will provide 15 million SEK (1.6 million EURO/1.7 million UDS) and the remaining 8 million SEK (0,7 million EURO/0.8 million USD) is contributed by the Kosovan Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Rural Development (and its Kosovo Forest Agency).
The co-financing of the project contributes to increased national ownership and responsibility.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives of the proposed intervention is to increase forest sectors contribution to the Kosovo economy and reduce poverty in rural areas through efficient and gender-responsive forest management. 

The Programme Outcome is that Kosovar forests in Target Regions are managed more efficiently with multi-purpose, participatory approach, strengthened in accordance with the approved Law on Forests and supported with gender-responsive value-chains for poverty alleviation. 

The Programme is implemented through three Components:

First Component is dedicated to improving timber legality, trade and law enforcement in forest sector. 

Second Component enhances transparency and strengthens the institutional capacity in good governance and implementation of forest policies, strategies and programmes. 

Third Component introduces and implements multi-purpose forest management, strengthens inclusive forest value chains for poverty alleviation of rural women and men, and establishes new skills and capacities in forest fire management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="41301" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAO/Food and Agriculture Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41301" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAO/Food and Agriculture Organization</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="31210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="312" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="13.B" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">13.b - Fr&#xE4;mja mekanismer f&#xF6;r att h&#xF6;ja f&#xF6;rm&#xE5;gan till effektiv klimatrelaterad planering och f&#xF6;rvaltning i de minst utvecklade l&#xE4;nderna, med s&#xE4;rskilt fokus p&#xE5; kvinnor, ungdomar samt lokala och marginaliserade samh&#xE4;llen.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">13.b - Promote mechanisms for raising capacity for effective climate change-related planning and management in least developed countries and small island developing States, including focusing on women, youth and local and marginalized communities.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="15.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">15.9 - By 2020, integrate ecosystem and biodiversity values into national and local planning, development processes, poverty reduction strategies and accounts.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">15.9 - Senast 2020 integrera ekosystemens och den biologiska m&#xE5;ngfaldens v&#xE4;rden i nationella och lokala planerings- och utvecklingsprocesser, i strategier f&#xF6;r fattigdomsminskning samt i r&#xE4;kenskaper.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">582961.2097611025</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">582961.2097611026</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-09-01">528770.397318</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/12605_ContributionAgreementFAO-SWE.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement between Sida and UNFAO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/vbtla/12605_ContributionAgreementFAO-SWE.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement between Sida and UNFAO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/vbtla/12605_Decision12605FAOForetsry.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision Support to UNFAO</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/12605_Decision12605FAOForetsry.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision UNFAO Climate change mitigation within forestry sector</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Component 1: Improve timber legality, trade and law enforcement in forest sector The key by-laws for timber legality are identified and drafted, these by-laws focuses to regulate Forest Utilisation, Transport and Trade, Forest Management Planning and use of Non-Timber Forest Products. The Working Group is preparing the draft law for its proceedings for the approval by the government. The project team reviewed the draft law and provided its comments on the draft law for consideration. A Monitoring and Evaluation tool entitled Baseline and indicators on timber legality in Kosovo and Fiscal Assessment of the forestry sector have been designed and conducted. These two tools are enabling monitoring the implementation of forest related legislation and contribution of the forestry sector to national economy. The training programme on legal aspects and capacity building for law enforcement in forestry is designed and delivered (the first module) to the law implementers. The national Task Force on Timber Legality and Forest Protection is established with a decision taken by government on July 2021. The Strategy for communication and information in the forestry sector 2021  2025, along with its Action Plan is finalized are ready for the implementation. 

Component 2. Enhance transparency and strengthen the institutional capacity in good governance and implementation of forest policies, strategies and programmes Kosovo Forest Information System  KFIS under final review and fixing the bugs, errors and defects and developing the missing functionalities. The evaluation of the PSP 2010  2020 conducted and results presented to the working group for developing new PSP 2021  2030. The Working Group initiated formulation of the PSP 2021  2030. The action plan for starting with implementation of the national afforestation and reforestation program (NARP) is ready. The forestry personnel and labour force are trained for afforestation and reforestation, according to the NARP objectives. Appropriate training programs on Forest health capacity building are identified and under development. 

Component 3. Introduce multi-purpose forest management and inclusive forest value chains for poverty alleviation of rural women and men The methodology for preparing the long-term multipurpose forest management plans designed, presented, discussed and ready for piloting. The methodology for identification and development of forest products value chains designed presented and discussed with all stakeholders in pilot areas.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="1" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12605" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
