<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-10841A0302-KOS-16062</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EU delegation, Statistics Kosovo, 2019-2023</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">EU-delegering Statistik Kosovo 2019-2023</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the contribution is to contribute to the strengthening of the statistical system of Kosovo by enabling the development of reliable statistical information and facilitating improved decision making. Specifically, this action aims at increasing the capacities of KAS to carry out its core activities in a standardised and independent manner &#x2013; in line with EU standards &#x2013; as well as strengthen KAS&#x2019;s management and coordination capacities.
To attain this overarching objective, the contribution aims to:&#xA0;
* Improve the timeliness and shortening the timing of the release of all statistics in order to improve the Kosovo Government&#x2019;s decision-making process;
* Improve inter-institutional coordination and information sharing among the main stakeholders in the statistical sector;
* Improve data dissemination by enhancing data availability and visibility for public users;
* Support KAS in carrying out its core activities and mandate in a standardised and independent manner.
The above objectives are foreseen to be achieved trough the achievement of the following five results:
1: Further improvement of sector statistics and National Accounts statistics
2:&#xA0;Further improvement of sector statistics and National Accounts statistics
3: Further improvement of metadata systems, documentation and dissemination and modernisation of data collection methods
4: Strengthening of planning and coordination of the statistical system to improve the delivery of objectives and outputs in line with the 5-year programme for official statistics, and the communication and collaboration with key stakeholders
5. Building the overall capacity and resilience of KAS to maximize results and achieve sustainability by means of a series of linked
The results above correspond to the five components of the programme and are all, in the logical framework of the programme, measurable through verifiable indicators.
The programme document further clarifies the programme structure and proposed sets of activities under each results/components. Though at a fairly detailed level already, these will be further elaborated on in the three month inception phase of the programme where a more detailed time-line for the programme will also be agreed upon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen omfattar ett fyra&#xE5;rigt program f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka Kosovos statistiksystem. Insatsen &#xE4;r fokuserad p&#xE5; att st&#xE4;rka Kosovos Statistikbyr&#xE5; (KAS) och dess roll i det nationella statistiksystemet. 

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r den f&#xF6;reslagna insatsen &#xE4;r 3 530 000 EUR. Av dessa finansierar EU, genom EU-kontoret i Pristina, 2 000 000 EUR vilka kommer att utbetalas till Sida i enlighet med det delegeringsavtal som partnerna ingick i december 2018. Sidas bidrag till insatsen &#xE4;r 1 530 000 EUR fr&#xE5;n den bilaterala budgeten f&#xF6;r reformsamarbete med Kosovo. Detta beslut omfattar d&#xE4;rmed 16 millioner SEK, vilket skall motsvara  1 530 000 EUR 

Delegeringsavtalet mellan EU och Sida , och dess bilagor, beskriver det &#xF6;vergripande syftet med samarbetet. Sida ansvarar f&#xF6;r implementeringen och rapporteringen av insatsen gentemot EU (representerat av EU-kontoret i Pristina). 
Sida avser att ing&#xE5; &#xF6;verenskommelse med Statistiska Centralbyr&#xE5;n (SCB) f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra resultatkomponenter 1, nationalr&#xE4;kenskaper, och 2, social statistik, baserat p&#xE5; deras unika sakexpertis. Detta tillvaratar de goda relationer och den kontextspecifika kunskap som SCB har byggt upp i sitt l&#xE5;ngvariga samarbete med Kosovo och &#xE4;r samtidigt i linje med Sidas prioriteringar vad g&#xE4;ller myndighetssamverkan. 
SCB har dock inte m&#xF6;jlighet att bidra med sakexpertis och/eller resurser f&#xF6;r projektets tre &#xF6;vriga resultatkomponenter vilka omfattar IT-system, koordinering inom statistiksystemet samt ledarskaps- och organisationsutveckling. Sidas implementerande partner f&#xF6;r dessa resultatkomponenter kommer d&#xE4;rf&#xF6;r - d&#xE5; ingen m&#xF6;jlig partner med kompetens och m&#xF6;jlighet att genomf&#xF6;ra dessa delar har identifierats - att handlas upp i enlighet med LOU.  
Sida kommer d&#xE4;rtill att ing&#xE5; avtal med KAS -  vilket &#xE4;r centralt f&#xF6;r att s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla KAS engagemang och &#xE4;garskap i projektet.  

Centrala dialogfr&#xE5;gor under implementering utg&#xF6;rs av:
* Vikten av att framh&#xE5;lla och st&#xE4;rka KAS nationella &#xE4;garskap och aktiva roll i projektet.
* S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;llandet av tillg&#xE4;ngliga resurser f&#xF6;r KAS i relation till implementeringen (detta g&#xE4;ller specifikt IT-resurser).
* Uppf&#xF6;ljning av KAS utveckling p&#xE5; omr&#xE5;dena ledarskap och organisationsutveckling. 
* Behovet av att st&#xE4;rka integrering av Sidas tematiska perspektiv, med fokus p&#xE5; konflikt-, r&#xE4;ttighets - och fattigdomsperspektivet.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This intervention is a four year comprehensive programme with the aim to strengthen the National Statistics System of Kosovo (NSS), with the Kosovo Agency of Statistics (KAS) at the core: Strengthening of the Statistical System of Kosovo, 2019-2022. This programme will be supported by the EU, represented by the EU Office in Kosovo and the Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency (Sida), represented by the Swedish Embassy in Pristina. The EU contribution of 2 million euro will be delegated to Sida. Sida will contribute an additional 16 million SEK to the project. Sida, through the Embassy of Sweden in Kosovo, will oversee the contribution in full.

Sida&apos;s national partner will be KAS. Sida will furthermore enter into a service purchase agreement with Statistics Sweden (SCB) to implement component 1 and 2  of the programme, in national and social statistics. Sida will furthermore though open procurement in accordance with LOU procure a second implementing partner to implement components in IT, coordination and organizational development (3,4,5)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Government in donor country</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="11001" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-07" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16062" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Statistical capacity building</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="17.19" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">17.19 - By 2030, build on existing initiatives to develop measurements of progress on sustainable development that complement gross domestic product, and support statistical capacity-building in developing countries</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">17.19 - By 2030, build on existing initiatives to develop measurements of progress on sustainable development that complement gross domestic product, and support statistical capacity-building in developing countries.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">49594.4493305971</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">33062.9662203981</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2024-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">16531.483110199</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2023-01-01">33062.9662203981</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-07">87596.658381</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/10841_amendment-to-agrement_between-sida-and-scb-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to agreement between Sida and SCB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/delegation-agreement-eu-sida.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delegation Agreement between EU to Sida</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/delegation-agreement-eu-sida-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Delegation Agreement between Sida and EUOK</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/grant-arrangement-between-sida-and-scb_june-2019.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Arrangement between Sida and SCB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/grant-arrangement-between-sida-and-scb_june-2019-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Arrangement between Sida and Statistics of Sweden (SCB)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/amendment-to-agrement_between-sida-and-scb.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant arragment_Amendment to agreement Sida and SCB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/mou_sida_and_kas-1.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memorandum of understanding between Sida and Kosovo Agency for Statistics</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/mou_sida_and_kas.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memorandum of understanding between Sida and Kosovo Agency for Statistics</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/decision-.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Strengthening Statistical System in Kosovo 2019 - 2023</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The institutional cooperation between the Kosovo Agency for Statistics (KAS) and Statistics Sweden started in 2001. In 2016 the EU Office in Pristina (EUOK) approached Sida with a suggestion to combine upcoming support for KAS through a delegation of funds from the EU to Sida, planned for the IPA II 2017 phase to Sida. The dialogue resulted in an Action Document (AD) included in the IPA II 2017 support. The AD was consulted with Sida as well as KAS and was completed in the spring of 2017. In order to clarify the programme structure, set up of the activities the Document of Action (DoA) was drafted.
Afterwards, EUOK and the Embassy of Sweden in Pristina, accorded by agreement to implement the &#x2018;Strengthening Statistical System in Kosovo 2019- 2023&#x2019; programme initially for the period from 1st May 2019 to 30th April 2023 with an initial budget of 3,530,000 EURO from which 2,000,000 Euro were contribution from EU and 1,530,000 from Sida. The implementing partners are Statistics of Sweden (SCB) and consulting company FCG. Whereas, the main beneficary is KAS and&#xA0;all Kosovo institutions, data providers and users.
The whole project implementation is under the supervision of the Project Implementation Unit (PIU) headed by FCG Sweden and its Team Leader. Components 1 and 2 are managed by Statistics Sweden, while components 3, 4 and 5 are managed by FCG Sweden. However, it must be noted that there are two exceptions to this division of tasks as within Component 1, sub-activity 1.1.3 is managed by FCG Sweden, while under Component 4, activity 4.1 is managed by Statistics Sweden.
The programme has begun 1 May-2019 as stipulted within the agreement between EUOK. The current reporting period reflects progress made during a period of one year 1 May 2019 - 30 April 2020. The first assigment, was the inception phase which was conducted during June &#x2013; August 2019, with a purpose to further assessed and elaborated the components and activities.
During the first year of implementation the following activities of the five expected results were performed:
1: Further improvement of sector statistics and National Accounts statistics: In relation to the project objective, the inclusion of the non-observed economy (NOE) in the national accounts contributes to the strengthening of the statistical system. The NOE make a sufficient part of the gross domestic product (GDP) in Kosovo. To ensure good quality national accounts and exhaustive estimates of GDP, it is vital to have a complete coverage of economic production.
The project has supported KAS to calculate the indicators for NOE urban and sub-urban bus, taxi, other land transport, accommodation and construction. The indicators have been calculated on yearly bases back to 2008 and on quarterly base back to 2010, in current and fixed prices. The project has supported KAS with documentation of the calculations in excel working sheet and a narrative description of the method for estimation. This documentation contributes to KAS&#xB4;s capacities to carry out its core activities in a standardised and independent manner.
In relation to the project objective, updated short-term business statistics (STS) questionnaires is crucial to shortening the release of the statistics in order to improve the Kosovo decision-making processes. The questionnaires should fulfil the Eurostat regulation, but at the same time being reduced of information that is not necessary. This way KAS can free recourses to focus on achieving quality in the remaining important variables and reduce the response burden for businesses in Kosovo.
The project has supported KAS in creating improved STS survey questionnaires in accordance with Eurostat standards for manufacturing, transport, retail and wholesale trade. Newly designed STS survey questionnaires in accordance with Eurostat standards for construction, services and building permits. The project has also supported KAS by improving the yearly PRODCOM survey questionnaire in accordance with Eurostat standards and reducing some over information.
2: Further development of Social statistics indicators and preparation for a population register and implementation of the 2021 population census: In relation to the project objective, the production of statistics on income and living conditions (SILC) and gender equality index (GEI) are important for Kosovo&#x2019;s understanding of the living conditions for its citizens. SILC has been an important missing piece in the statistical system. The production of SILC contributes to strengthen the system, facilitating improved decision-making regarding the social sector. The GEI facilitates decision-makers to benchmark Kosovo with other European countries regarding the gender situation.
The project has supported KAS in producing SILC output indicators, prepare the national publication and quality report. KAS has transmitted SILC data to Eurostat in two attempts. Eurostat has returned with feedback on the data quality. The project is supporting KAS to transmit data in a third attempt during April/May. The project has supported KAS in producing a partial GEI and at the same time strengthened the subject knowledge by devoting time to explain the index calculation and the definitions of the indicators. KAS has transmitted a primarily index to European Institute for Gender Equality (EIGE), via Kosovo&#x2019;s Agency for Gender Equality. The quality of the transmission is currently under discussion with EIGE. The transmitted index is lacking indicators based on SILC. These indicators have been prepared in code, but KAS needs to re-run the code when Eurostat&#x2019;s has approved the SILC data transmission.
3: Further improvement of metadata systems, documentation and dissemination practices and modernisation of data collection methods: During the first six-month period, Key Expert 3 has conducted an in-depth analysis of the present situation in the IT field. It was noticed an evident lack of documentation for various IT systems and databases that were managed by the previous projects and IT staff, who left KAS on a short notice without leaving any IT documentation or manuals behind. This was not anticipated at the period when the ToR/DoA was written, which makes the situation much more difficult and required urgent reaction and support from the project. The project has supported KAS in metadata system, documentation and dissemination practices, methods and mentoring. Manuals were drafted for the following: User Satisfaction Survey (USS),PGP Encryption of sensitive data, LCS staff for comparison of tables, Survey Solution, SQL Queries/ Joins (for the scenario of Tax Administration Database), Server Documentation Book (which was required by EUROSTAT). Manuals on how to develop questionnaires: User Satisfaction Survey (USS) and Staff Satisfaction Survey (SSS). Subsequently, USS Report (with charts and tables) was developed which will be used for upcoming reports. IT application and database works achieved are the following: functionalisation and bug fixing Import Index Prices, Production Import Prices, Tax Administration, Business Register, SSL CertificationThe project also provided support on Gross Domestic Product to be published on time. Furthermore, a new database was designed that holds encrypted data to decentralise Business Register and enable other KAS employees to have access. Summary of tangible interventions are under component 3. Continuous mentoring on SQL Server to IT staff.
4: Planning and coordination of the statistical system are strengthened to improve the delivery of objectives and outputs in line with the 5-year programme for official statistics, and the communication and collaboration with key stakeholders:
- drafting two Administrative Instructions on Data Confidentiality &amp;amp; Access into micro-data, and Sale of Statistical Data which are now ready for the Government of Kosovo to approve them as bylaws.
- organising a study visit in Latvia in order for KAS to exchange with its Latvian counterpart (CSB) and learn about the Latvian NSS which could be an inspiration for the Kosovo NSS.
In relation to the project overall objective to strengthen KAS, the project recognizes the importance for KAS as NSI, to produce high quality statistics even during crises. All nations suffer the consequences of the COVID-19 outbreak, affecting for example business, regulations on physical contacts and in some cases free movement. The project has prepared electronic training materials regarding methodologies on the challenges of producing price statistics under the pandemic (webinar), and an electronic training course material (filmed presentations) in methods in questionnaire design.
5: Building the overall capacity and resilience of KAS to maximize results and achieve sustainability by strengthening management and organisational development: The Organisational Culture, Leadership and Knowledge and Skill Needs Questionnaire survey was carried out under Result Area 5 to collect information providing input for the development of management models to be implemented in the activities belonging to the Result Area. Although four activities were eliminated from Result 5 at the request of the beneficiary, an important part of the collected data and information could be used in the preparation of the remaining activities, especially in relation to the Internal training function and Knowledge management. The achievements of the first project year were as follows: Six interns were recruited and started their internship in March 2020. The process and its results were presented in the Report on the Recruitment and Selection of Trainees Further two interns for IT positions will be recruited as soon as the situation will permit it. The model of the Internal Training Function has been developed describing the role, tasks, responsibilities, as well as its relationships with KAS Departments and staff at different levels. The model&#x2019;s implementation plan was elaborated. Information has been collected for the development of the Internal Training Function Manual. The existing knowledge management practices and needs for further development were analyzed and suggestions for improvement and development presented in the Report on knowledge management at KAS with recommendations for action.
Changes and challenges&#xA0;
During the programme&#x2019;s first months, certain problems were identified in the budget, mainly concerning overhead SCB budget line. The initial budget between Sida and SCB, has been reallocated. The reason for this was that the reimbursables for the long-term expert (LTE) were not sufficient. This is due to the fact that the consultants drawing up the DoA budget did not consider the possibility of a long-term consultant coming with family. SCB is as a Swedish authority obliged to follow the financial remuneration guidelines in the URA- contract (for seconding staff abroad). SCBs draft budget has designed a budget within given limits. This situation has affected the number of short term missions SCB can perform in the programme period. Nevertheless, this situation was solved with commitment of the Embassy given the situation alterations in benefit of all parties (Sida, SCB and Kosovo Agency for Statistics). The decision that was taken is the following: the LTE will stay in Kosovo for two years, afterwards work will be carried out from distance.&#xA0;
Another challenge that ocuured is that the initial budget between Sida and FCG, has been reallocated. Reallocation happened due to the fact that during the 1st Steering Committee Meeting (SCM) which took place in Pristina on October 14th, 2019, KAS requested certain changes to the project plan. Overall, the message was that a number of activities in Result Area 5 &#x2018;Organisational Development&#x2019; should be removed (half of them) to the benefit of IT and statistical production areas. Furthemore, under result 1 activity related to census was removed since meanwhile KAS has finished this task.The reason for the request was that KAS, the Beneficiary, considered that the DoA, which was finalised during the Autumn 2018 and served as the main basis for the project design, did not reflect its current priorities which had meanwhile changed or had already been implemented.
It was then decided that a budgetary reallocation should take place. The PIU, and a number of KAS Directors and staff met on November 19th, 2019, to discuss the proposal for reallocation of resources between the Result Areas and the insertion of one new Activity. The subsequent budget reallocation request was submitted to Sida on December 19th, 2019, and eventually approved and effective from January 15th, 2020. Also, EUOK in Kosovo agreed for this reallocations.&#xA0;
Furthermore, on 9th January 2020 Team Leader resigned for personal reasons, which required to find a replacement solution. After long discussion and alternative it was decided that KE3 to be promoted as TL. KE3 acted as Acting Team Leader from January, 30th, 2020 and was eventually approved by Sida as the new Project Team Leader on March, 23rd, 2020. KE3/TL combines the responsibility of Key Expert 3 (IT component) and TL. This led to another budget reallocation request which was approved by Sida on March 23rd, 2020. By recruiting Key Expert 3 as LTE, which was a local expert KE3 has allowed reallocation of days for short-term experts. Decision, on hiring local staff, proved the positive effect especially during the COVID-19 situation. LTE was going at KAS to provide support.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="10841" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
