<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5514000303-XKX-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cultural Heritage without Borders Kosovo 2016-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Cultural Heritage without Borders Kosovo 2016-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">CHwB Kosovo har ans&#xF6;kt om k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d till implementeringen av organisationens strategiska plan f&#xF6;r 2016-2019. St&#xF6;det uppg&#xE5;r till totalt 17 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r perioden 2016-2019.

Insatsens &#xF6;vergripande m&#xE5;l &#xE4;r att skapa f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar och m&#xF6;jligheter f&#xF6;r &#xE5;tnjutandet av kulturell frihet och m&#xE5;ngfald. Syftet &#xE4;r ocks&#xE5; att &#xF6;ka kulturarvets betydelse i arbetet mot att fr&#xE4;mja m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, fredsbyggande processer, f&#xF6;rsoning och demokratisk utveckling.

M&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning 1: St&#xE4;rka samh&#xE4;llets vitalitet samt ansvarsskyldigheten hos duty-bearers.
CHwB arbetar med att st&#xE4;rka duty-bearers incitament till att fullf&#xF6;lja deras uppgifter, ansvar och &#xE5;taganden. Organisationen st&#xF6;ttar samtidigt civilsamh&#xE4;llet genom att st&#xE4;rka deras roll i att p&#xE5;verka och kr&#xE4;va ansvarsskyldighet hos nationella institutioner, synnerligen vad g&#xE4;ller m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter och kulturarv.

M&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning 2: Fr&#xE4;mja samarbetet mellan regioner samt synergier vilka fr&#xE4;mjar ekonomisk utveckling. 
Kulturarv ska i st&#xF6;rre utstr&#xE4;ckning anv&#xE4;ndas som ett verktyg f&#xF6;r att fr&#xE4;mja social och ekonomisk utveckling, fr&#xE4;mst genom att skapa arbetstillf&#xE4;llen, anv&#xE4;nda lokala resurser och kunskaper samt st&#xF6;tta ett milj&#xF6;m&#xE4;ssigt h&#xE5;llbart arbetss&#xE4;tt.

M&#xE5;ls&#xE4;ttning 3: CHwB Kosovo som f&#xF6;respr&#xE5;kare av bevarandet av Kosovos kulturarv.
CHwB Kosovo &#xE4;r en lokal organisation som har vuxit fram fr&#xE5;n den svenska organisationen Kulturarv utan Gr&#xE4;nser (KuG).  Som s&#xE5;dan syftar organisationen till att bevara sin status som en trov&#xE4;rdig r&#xF6;st i arbetet mot att skydda och fr&#xE4;mja kulturarv i Kosovo, d&#xE5; detta &#xE4;r en v&#xE4;rdefull tillg&#xE5;ng f&#xF6;r samh&#xE4;llet i stort.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Core support to Kosovo Foundation for Cultural Heritage without Borders. The overall goal is to create conditions and opportunities for enjoyment of cultural freedom and diversity and for cultural heritage to be increasingly used as a tool to promote human rights.            peace-building and democratic development.

CHwB Kosovo has applied to Sida for core support for the implementation of their Strategic Plan for 2016-2019.The total amount for support for the period of 2016-2019 is 17 million SEK.

The overall goal is to create conditions and opportunities for the enjoyment of cultural freedom and cultural diversity and for cultural heritage to be increasingly used as a tool to promote human rights, peace-building and democratic development.

Key objective 1: The vibrancy of community and accountability of duty bearers is strengthened
CHwB works to strengthen duty-bearers in fulfilling their obligations and supporting civil society organizations in holding the national institutions accountable to relevant human rights and cultural heritage conventions.

Key objective 2: Fostering territorial cooperation &amp; synergies for economic development
Cultural heritage is used as a tool for social and economic development, primarily by creating employment opportunities, utilizing local resources and techniques and supporting environmental sustainability.

Key objective 3: CHwB Kosovo - voice of cultural heritage in Kosovo
CHwB Kosovo is the legacy of Swedish Foundation of CHwB. As such it aims to remain as significant and credible voice of protection and promotion of cultural heritage in Kosovo, as a public common good belonging to all communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This intervention is in the form of core support to the CHwB Kosovo for implementation of the Strategic Plan 2018-2022 of CHwB Kosovo.
CHwB&apos;s overall goal is to create conditions and opportunities for the enjoyment of cultural freedom and cultural diversity and for cultural heritage to be increasingly used as a tool to promote human rights, peace-building and democratic development.
Impact 1: Culture for Growth
To create an environment where the community will become the main administrator of change and foster a sustainable economic growth through culture and cultural heritage in Kosovo and in the region.
Impact 2: Culture for Creativity
Culture for Creativity known as Heritage Space (HS) supports the creation and development of clusters for various niches in the Creative Industries in relation to cultural heritage. HS is designed to facilitate the creation of support platforms that will provide targeted fields to accelerate sector growth and help creative individuals/groups to improve their product and take their creative ideas to market.
Impact 3: Adaptive Reuse
The Adaptive Reuse is a series of measures and actions to be undertaken for documentation, restoration and reuse of the monuments. It ensures that building is preserved using the traditional techniques and materials, applied by local community. ARB aims to use restoration as a tool to achieve another goal- reutilization of cultural heritage sites.
Impact 4: CHwB Kosovo - voice of cultural heritage in Kosovo
CHwB Kosovo is the legacy of Swedish Foundation of CHwB. As such, it aims to remain as significant and credible voice of protection and promotion of cultural heritage in Kosovo, as a public common good belonging to all communities.
Impact 5: Heritage as Human Right
The right of access to and enjoyment of cultural heritage is a human right guaranteed by international law, and it must be taken seriously.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHWB/Cultural Heritage without Borders</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CHWB/Cultural Heritage without Borders</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="XK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kosovo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="11.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">11.4 - Strengthen efforts to protect and safeguard the world&#x2019;s cultural and natural heritage.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">11.4 - St&#xE4;rka insatserna f&#xF6;r att skydda och trygga v&#xE4;rldens kultur- och naturarv.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="8.9" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">8.9 - By 2030, devise and implement policies to promote sustainable tourism that creates jobs and promotes local culture and products.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">8.9 - Senast 2030 utarbeta och genomf&#xF6;ra politik f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar turism som skapar arbetstillf&#xE4;llen och fr&#xE4;mjar lokal kultur och lokala produkter.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/agreement-chwb-kosovo-2016.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement on core support to CHwB Kosovo 2016-2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/chwbk-2016-2019-amendment-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amendment to the Agreement on core support to CHwB</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/beslut-insats-chwb-2016.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om insats Cultural Heritage without Borders</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/kosovo/chwb-beslut-andring-insats.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Beslut om &#xE4;ndring av insats Cultural Heritage without Borders</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/vbtla/55140003_55140003_SignedDecisionCHwBKosovo.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision CHwB Kosovo</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key results and impact noted during 2020 are:
-  A Memorandum of Understanding for implementation of the project Development of the Economic Region West through Cultural Heritage was signed between CHwB Kosovo and the 6 Municipalities of the west economic region. The Regional Council of Cultural Heritage  West (RCCHW) has been established aiming to monitor the implementation of the Action Plan for the Development of the Economic Region West through Cultural Heritage 2020-2023. The Council is responsible for proposing annual priorities in the field of cultural heritage, that have a regional impact towards regional economic development. The RCCHW is represented by the local governance from the six municipalities of the west economic region (De&#xE7;an, Gjakova, Istog, Junik, Klina, Peja), representatives from Civil Society Organisations from each municipality and members of the Central Government from the Regional Centres for Cultural Heritage in Peja and Gjakova. 
- The project of Cross Border Cooperation between Kosovo and North Macedonia was implemented successfully by creation of priority lists of projects for Cultural Heritage for the three border municipalities in Kosovo and three in North Macedonia and restoration of six CH sites. All the work is done in inclusive, transparent and participatory process.
- Heritage Space Platform 2020 resulted on development of 9 small projects out of total 86 eligible applications (40 women and 46 men). The selected projects of the HS are about using oral history, film/video, animation, illustration, digital arts, archiving, digitization, documentation, photography, research, writing, interpretation, digital cultural heritage, web development, translation, graphic design, publishing, sculpture, workshops.
- As a result of the partnership between CHwB Kosovo and ILUCIDARE, during 2020 it was established a G&#xEB;rr-G&#xEB;rr Co-Creation Platform, that will offer space of co-creation, education, production and generate new possibilities of interaction with existing heritage sites and discourses in Kosovo.
- Through 2020, CHwB Kosovo continued with restoration of two kulla houses and three stone watermills in the western part of Kosovo. In general, the restorations were focused on primary structure consolidations, the stonewalls and the reconstruction of the roof as the most deteriorated parts.  All interventions were done based on the local craftsmanship and traditional techniques.
- The research project &quot;Creative and rural Kosovo&quot; was developed during 2020 and was expected to be completed by beginning of 2021. The aim of this project is to conduct a thorough research in 50 villages of Kosovo that were selected due to their importance based on cultural and natural heritage attributes, proximity to national and regional roads, main cities and natural attractions. The product will give recommendations on the future development of the villages, based on their main attribution. This document will serve as the basis for the development of detailed projects in selected fields that would contribute in the whole regeneration of these villages and beyond. The plan is to present this to the Government for possible funding or co-funding with donors.
- The Cultural Heritage as a Human Right component is mainstreamed to improve the access to cultural heritage sites regardless of age, gender, religion, physical or intellectual abilities. The designing and implementation of the accessibility for disabled people in the Museum of Vitia and Prizren has ensured the inclusiveness to heritage sites.
- Documentation about new cultural heritage sites of the RAE communities are delivered to the Ministry of Culture and will be added in the list of cultural heritage of Kosovo. The selection process was done in close cooperation with community representatives and local and central authorities.
- CHwB Kosovo published series of four books so called &apos;Lost cities&apos; which describe the cities of Ulpiana, Novoberda, Janjeva and Trepca. These books reveal the social life, influence, culture, craftsmanship and heritage of these cites, the existence of which survives today largely in the form of ruins and memory of the few remaining inhabitants. 
As a result of discussions with Sida during previous years, CHwB Kosovo has started to include reporting about cross cutting issues such as:
- Work with communities to recover their sense of dignity and inspire them to be active promoters of their rights on cultural heritage
- Increase transparency and accountability of cultural institutions and engagement of local communities
- Inclusive access to cultural heritage sites regardless of age, gender, ethnicity, religion, physical or intellectual abilities
- Enhancing gender equality with womens empowerment
- Environmental and conflicts perspectives.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="55140003" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
