<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-TUN16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunisia Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TUNISIA&#xB4;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND In 2011 the &#x2018;Jasmine Revolution&#x2019; took place which ended years of dictatorship in Tunisia and started the country on the path to democracy. This path has not been easy. There were two political murders which led to a stalemate in parliament for a while, and the process of drawing up and agreeing a new constitution took much longer than expected. Nevertheless, the new constitution was finally agreed and has been widely praised as one of the most progressive in the Arab world. In 2014, Tunisia held free and fair elections that resulted in a coalition government consisting of a party which had associations with the previous regime, working together with a party that had previously been declared illegal. So a democratic system is developing but there are still many challenges. For example, the political parties tend to be based on the personality of the leader rather than on a programme of policies, levels of trust between the politicians are quite low and the people working in politics tend to lack the skills and knowledge that they need to work effectively in a multiparty democracy. THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN TUNISIA NIMD started working in Tunisia in 2012 and the core aim of NIMD&#x2019;s programme has been building the capacity of the parties and politicians to work effectively in this new democracy and as part of that to encourage interparty dialogue. To achieve this, NIMD set up a School of Politics together with its local partner, Centre des &#xC9;tudes M&#xE9;diterran&#xE9;ennes Internationales. Here politicians work together in a multiparty setting to learn the skills and knowledge that they need to work together in a multiparty democracy. By learning together, they also get to know each other and get used to talking together which can help to increase trust and encourage interparty dialogue. By the end of 2014, 6 cohorts of politicians, approximately 180 people, had completed a programme. TSoP graduation NIMD has also set up an informal multiparty dialogue platform called &#x2018;Couscous Politique&#x2019;, where politicians informally discuss political issues while eating traditional Tunisian couscous. Mentoring programme Together with Demo Finland, NIMD is running a mentoring programme which pairs up regional and national politicians. This aims to help national politicians to learn more about issues at a regional level and vice versa. It also aims to improve multiparty dialogue at the regional level. Women&#x2019;s Political Rights Programme Tunisia is also one of three counties where NIMD is running the Women&#x2019;s Political Rights Programme. This programme is aimed at increasing the political participation of women in Tunisia, Colombia and Kenya.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre des Etudes Mediterraneennes et Internationales (CEMI)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Demo Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International IDEA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">332045</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-09">73396</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Tunisia February 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-27">80100</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Tunisia July 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">5291</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">30880</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the key objectives of the programme is to promote collaboration and consultation between political actors and between political and civic actors. The figures clearly show that such collaboration is present to a limited degree in current participants of the Tunisian School of Politics. Around half of them indicated that they regularly collaborate with other political or civic actors. Since this is a major focus of the programme, we hope and expect for this percentage to rise in future measurements. This expectation is confirmed by research among alumni of the Tunisian School of Politics. In order to determine the quality of such collaboration, additional research would be needed to assess what kinds of collaboration exist, e.g. political initiatives, joint projects, dialogue etc.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors (participants) who indicate that they collaborate with other political actors (including government actors) at least once monthly</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="48" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: Current participants: 48% Breakdown: &lt; 1 times monthly: 52% 2-3 times monthly: 18% 4-5 times monthly: 13% &gt;5 times monthly: 17% Qualitative description: The survey was carried out among both current participants and alumni of the TSoP programme. The question was how often they collaborated with other political actors outside of TSoP activities. 48% of current participants indicate that they frequently collaborate with other political actors. For the sake of comparison, the same survey was also conducted among alumni of the TSoP. Among this population, a much higher percentage (88%) indicated that they frequently work together with other political actors. During their training within the TSoP, they are sensitized to the importance of collaborating with other political actors and gained experience learning and working in a multi-party setting. As a result, we would expect this percentage to rise for the current group of participants when measured again in 2018 or 2020. Results of the same survey carried out among alumni: &lt; 1 times monthly: 12% 2-3 times monthly: 44% 4-5 times monthly: 14% &gt;5 times monthly: 30%</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Existing safe spaces hosting a functional dialogue and/or cooperation platforms.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The leaders of the political parties believe that the country has progressed from the strong political instability which characterized the early years after the Jasmin Revolution. Political tensions do not threaten the stability of the country or democratic progress as much as they used to. They agree that it is now necessary to invest in safe spaces for dialogue between all relevant political and civic actors, to create an enabling environment for political actors to engage in inclusive policy making. The dialogue platform which was established in 2016 is one way to address this. Another is investing in capacity strengthening of political parties and individual politicians.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of dialogue platforms in place and level of influence on policy formulation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 1 (on a scale of 1-4) 1 &#x2013; No influence 2 &#x2013; Some of the discussions in the dialogue platform lead to policy initiatives, but whether these are successful depends on factors outside the sphere of influence of the platform 3 &#x2013; The dialogue platform is in a position to address key political issues with policy initiatives and some of these are successful 4 &#x2013; The dialogue platform is able to propose and implement policy initiatives autonomous of external factors Qualitative description: The participants in the focus group discussion were members of the dialogue platform established by CEMI. This included representatives of eight political parties represented in the Tunisian Parliament. The consensus was that the dialogue platform does not currently have influence on policy formulation. It was only established in 2016 and has not yet engaged in policy initiatives. Its role in the political spectrum has not yet been defined. However, the participants are full of ambition and are working on an agenda for the coming years. One of the key objectives of the programme will be to strengthen this platform and equip it with the skills needed to exercise influence on public policy.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concrete proposals for an accepted and equitable political system proposed and accepted.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Extent to which political actors at the national level experience an enabling environment that includes them in policy-making</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 2 (on a scale of 1-4) 1 - no voice and no influence on policy making 2 &#x2013; able to take part in debates over policy making but do not necessarily feel their voice is being heard or that they exercise influence on the government 3 &#x2013; able to take part in debates over policy making and sometimes feel or establish that their views are taken into account by the government 4 &#x2013; fully able to participate in the political debate and exercise influence over the government Qualitative description: The participants of the focus group discussion were the leaders of seven political parties represented in parliament. They agreed that political actors, both those that are part of the ruling coalition and those that are part of the opposition, enjoy an acceptable margin of maneuver to influence public policy. However, this margin depends strongly on their individual position in the political scene, rather than on their status as elected representatives. As a result, the score was established as at the higher end of 2: &#x2018;able to take part in debates over policy making but do not necessarily feel their voice is being heard or that they exercise influence on the government.&#x2019; All of the leaders present during the focus group discussion acknowledged that alumni of the Tunisian School of Politics have played an important role in drafting and influencing new public policies, thereby contributing to improved policy-making and increased influence on the government.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Higher recognition and approval ratings of political actors by citizens.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of Afrobarometer respondents expressing trust in political parties</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="40" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The most recently available 2013-14 Afrobarometer measured public trust of respondents in the ruling party and in opposition parties separately. Combining these responses and collapsing the categories of &#x201C;somewhat&#x201D; and &#x201D;a lot&#x201D;, we see that there is considerable trust in political parties in Tunisia. This trust is considerably lower in opposition parties (30%) than in the governing party (49%).</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of political actors in fragile settings to effective ad legitimately participate in political (dialogue) processes.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents (manifestos, election programmes, position papers, policy proposals) by political parties that indicate being based on inputs from their defined support base (potential voters)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
