<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-ETH17</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia Programme 2017</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2016, under the flexible fund facility that NIMD and AWEPA created to respond swiftly to emerging political trends, openings and developments in new countries or regions, the possibilities for a possible programme in Ethiopia were explored. A first scoping mission took place in April 2016, after a number of exploratory discussions between the Dutch MFA, the Dutch Embassy in Addis Ababa and NIMD-AWEPA. The outcome of the assessment was that there is interest in and room for a joint NIMD-AWEPA programme, although it should be developed and implemented gradually, through a &#x2018;phased approach&#x2019;. The conclusions of the assessment where shared and discussed with the NL MFA in July and a summary report was presented to Ethiopian stakeholders in August 2016. The assumptions and conclusions were positively confirmed and have laid the foundations the development of a country programme in Ethiopia in 2017. Given the political context in Ethiopia, the programme will start with capacity building for political actors as a first entry point. Through this capacity building, the building of trust among the political actors can be facilitated; this trust could then lay the basis for interparty dialogue in the future. Given the country&apos;s federal arrangement, a two-tiered intervention approach is proposed- at both the Federal and Regional levels. At a regional level the strategy is to start with Oromia, being by far the largest region, and then move to engage, as necessary, other regions depending on demand. The presence of political leaders willing to explore more democratic avenues of engagement, can only help to facilitate this process. The first phase programming is foreseen for two years (2017-2018), after which an assessment will be made on the actual political space to continue with the programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties participating in interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties participating in interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="17"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
