<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-HON18</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Honduras Programme 2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Political Update 2018
After four years of difficult and harsh political dialogue, the main Honduran political parties did not produce an integral electoral reform demanded by broad citizenship and recommended by Electoral Observation Missions after 2013 general elections. However, the involvement of illicit networks in national and local politics financing (linked to drug-trafficking activities), and the abuse in the use of public funds during the prior electoral cycle (2010-2014), led to the enactment of a law for the regulation of politics financing, which had technical assistance of the electoral division of MACCIH (the mission against corruption in the country, headed by the OAS) and relevant diplomatic support from important cooperation donors as the US. Approved with the support of all political parties in Parliament, it came into force in the end of May 2017, when its technical unit composed of three commissioners was easily appointed (it is a relevant detail that each of these commissioners was proposed by the three main political forces of the country, which means that political negotiations occurred). Although the unit has little time to do its work (general elections will be in November 2017), the mere existence of the law has had an impact on the reduction of propaganda in public spaces and media, compared to previous processes, especially the primary elections of March 2017.
The elections of November will be disputed mainly between three parties: Nacional (ruling party), Liberal and Libre. PAC (the surprise party of 2013 elections) has weakened due to internal struggles, however, its founder -the sports chronicler and political outsider Nasralla- will be the candidate of a party alliance led by Libre (party created by Manuel Zelaya, the president deposed in a coup of state in 2009) and PINU-SD, whose one of its main proposals is the convocation to a constituent national assembly. The current President Juan Hernandez (Nacional) has good possibilities to be re-elected, amidst doubts and complaints of the other parties on the legal constitutionality of their participation. The presence of electoral observation to verify the quality of the elections will provide recommendations that will be inputs for an eventual dialogue for electoral reforms, which could be complex based on the (polarized) position assumed by the political parties after the result in the elections. Precisely, the parliament&apos;s integration and capacity for political dialogue after the November elections will determine, not only the margin of governance within the National Congress and the balance of power with the executive branch, but also the possibilities of political reform in the country. No significant increase in female political representation is expected due to the inappropriate regulation of &#x201C;zippered lists&#x201D; to implement the 50% quota.
Another aspect -not less important- is that Honduran drug lords who have surrendered to US authorities or been extradited during 2015 and 2016 have revealed in their federal court judgments economic collaboration and close influence with important politicians of the country. Major US government pressures are expected due to these revelations (and others linked to acts of corruption), which could be investigated by MACCIH, with unpredictable impact on the traditional impunity of the national political class and the political-parties&#x2019; scenario for the coming years.



2. Problem Analysis &amp; Theory of Change Update (max 2 pages)

Provide a narrative update on the problem analysis and the Theory of Change in light of the political update. Explain if the ToC as described in the MAP is still valid, or whether there is a need to adapt the Theory of Change, and if so, in what way.

The ToC continues to be valid. NIMD has been accompanying Electoral and Political Party reform for the past years as this is crucial for a more democratic functioning of the political party system. This continues to be a difficult process because the parties have a vested interest in keeping things the way they are. Recommendations of the EU Electoral Mission and other missions are hardly followed up and -until now- there is no political pressure from civil society to advance on those issues. The enactment of the political party financing law and the appointment of the technical unit in charge of its implementation provide a good opportunity for parties&#x2019; transparency and accountability strengthening; this, together with the outcome of general elections in November 2017, could boost political dialogue chance in 2018.  However, the narrow MACCIH electoral mandate (reduced to the technical assistance in the enactment of political party financing regulations) would diminish its recent positive influence. Some lobby among G-16 development cooperation representatives (specially OAS) should be tried to strengthen MACCIH role in the follow-up of electoral missions&#x2019; recommendations, as well with civil society representatives, to promote accompaniment and political pressure for their adoption. NIMD will stimulate and assist technically these lobbying efforts to advance on relevant electoral reform issues. 

Political culture in Honduras still faces challenges to shift a male oriented party culture. NIMD keeps working on improving this political culture through democracy schools for young people and political and candidate education for political women. NIMD opts to move forward in those subjects where we can effectively make a difference, while following the political developments to assess when we can play an effective role in the other objectives of the Multi Annual Plan i.e. fiscal reform, transparency, water management and regional integration.


3. Programme outlook (max 4 pages)

During 2018, the NIMD Program in Honduras will focus on monitoring and follow-up of processes initiated in previous years under SP, adapting them - when appropriate - to the new political and social context. The opportunity provided by the creation and start-up of the Technical Unit responsible for implementing the Political Parties Financing Act (UTPL) will be used to provide technical assistance to the unit and, in coordination with it, with the political parties to strengthen their transparency and accountability. Capacities will be strengthened in political and social actors to follow-up on the recommendations of electoral observation missions (EU, OAS) and put pressure on the start of political and multisector dialogue leading to their adoption by political parties. As a result of the election decision on November 2017, NIMD ties with the parliament (National Congress) will be updated to strengthen the legislative process, accompanying Legislative Management and prioritized parliamentary commissions (electoral, budget and finance, gender equity, climate change and water, among others) to encourage dialogue and consultation with civil society actors. In particular, the knowledge, skills and abilities of women parliamentarians will be strengthened to give continuity to the Interparliamentary Gender Agenda built between 2014-2018 and to add more female MPs into different commissions (Parliamentary Academy). All this in synergy with the strengthening of women&apos;s and gender secretariats of political parties and coordinated with the caucus of Honduran MPs of PARLACEN to advance in the achievement of affirmative actions for the equitable political participation of women in the country.

Technical support will continue to the Fiscal Dialogue Promoter Group (GPDF) for the promotion of multi-sectoral dialogue spaces for the achievement of a taxation for development. Likewise, NIMD will facilitate dialogue initiatives between different political and social actors about water and its sustainable management. Specific training programs and the Democracy School (EFD) will focus on strengthening capacities for democratic values and the inclusion of underrepresented groups in politics (particularly women, youth and the LGBTI population). A national meeting of EFD alumni will be held during 1st trimester of 2018 and a regional meeting of EFD alumni will be organized in conjunction with other NIMD programs in the region (northern triangle C.A.). No less important is the capacity building of NIMD Honduras staff.

In the planning of 2018 and for the different levels of intervention (system, actors and culture) the following results, indicators and interventions have been foreseen:

Political system

Four (4) result areas, each with their own intervention and intermediate indicator:

1.1 Political and electoral reform further strengthen the representation of democratic system and institutions

&#x2022; Intervention: Technical assistance and capacity building of civic and political actors in political and electoral reforms

&#x2022; Intervention: Facilitation of dialogue spaces/platforms between political actors and between political actors and civil society actors

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: % participation by key stakeholder representatives (civic and political actors) in the dialogue initiative

1.2 Political framework lowers the barriers for political participation for currently underrepresented groups

&#x2022; Intervention: Technical assistance and capacity building to political parties&#xB4; women leadership in defining an agenda on how to ensure equal rights for men and women within their parties.

&#x2022; Intervention: Technical assistance on how to make changes in electoral law and other regulations related to effective women participation in politics and to reduce violence against political women

&#x2022; Intervention: Capacity building of women MPs

&#x2022; Intervention: Strategic planning processes and capacity building with Gender Equity Commission in Parliament

&#x2022; Intervention: Cooperate with the women&#x2019;s caucus of Parlacen and other regional initiatives to create synergies and learn from best practices

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: # of L&amp;A initiatives for making the political system more inclusive (in relation to women)

1.3 Better channels for coordination between democratic and civil society actors as supra national, national and local level.

&#x2022; Intervention: Facilitate thematic dialogue between supranational, national and local politicians

&#x2022; Intervention: Capacity building of candidates and elected politicians on prioritized thematic issues (fiscal reform, climatic change and water management)

&#x2022; Intervention: Support dialogue between political actors and civil society to reduce corruption and improve state incomes for development financing

&#x2022; Intervention: Provide technical assistance for MP&apos;s and CSO&apos;s

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: # of ongoing NIMD supported dialogue initiatives

1.4 The political system offers channels for effective lobby and advocacy

&#x2022; Intervention: Creation and facilitation of spaces for interaction/ lobby, planning, between MP&apos;s and CSO&apos;s

&#x2022; Intervention: Provide technical assistance for MP&apos;s and CSO&apos;s

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: # of agreements reached (reform agendas / policies / legal amendments)

Political actors

Three (3) result areas, each with their own intervention and intermediate indicator:

2.1 Developed capacity of politicians to reach consensus on issues of national concern

&#x2022; Intervention: Capacity building of political parties on dialogue and consensus building

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: # of representatives (male/female) of political actors have participated in democratic values oriented training activities (e.g.: democracy schools)

2.2 Increased number of political parties and other political actors that develop proposals regarding Political and Electoral Reform (including women&#xB4;s political participation), Fiscal Reform and Reform of environmental and water legislation, including citizens&#x2019; proposals and concerns.

&#x2022; Intervention: Technical assistance and training of members of Parlacen, MPs, party members and CS actors on the importance of CS dialogue and citizen&#xB4;s consultation on Political reform and electoral system, the fiscal system, transparency and environmental policies and legislation

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: Level of cooperation with other actors (political and civic)

2.3 Organizational core capabilities of NIMD Honduras strengthened

&#x2022; Intervention: Systematization of best practices and learned lessons within NIMD Honduras Program

&#x2022; Intervention: Sharing of best practices with other NIMD offices in the region

&#x2022; Intervention: Capacity building of NIMD human resources on relevant capabilities needed to be improved

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator:  % execution of capacity development plans

Political culture

Two (2) result areas, each with their own intervention and intermediate indicator:

3.1 Internalization of democratic norms and values by political actors

&#x2022; Intervention: Democracy Schools

&#x2022; Intervention: Thematic follow-up meetings and forae for Democracy School alumni.

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: # of representatives (male/female) of political actors have participated in democratic values oriented training activities (e.g.: democracy schools)

3.2 Increased awareness of the importance of coordination between political and civic actors

&#x2022; Intervention: Facilitation of thematic meetings, debates and formal/informal encounters between political and civic actors, involving MPs of thematic Parliament Commissions, NGOs and other relevant stakeholders.

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: % participation by key stakeholder representatives (civic and political actors) in the dialogue initiative

Gender and inclusion will be approached as a cross cutting theme at the system, actor and culture level. 

&#x2022; Intermediate indicator: # of L&amp;A initiatives for making the political system more inclusive (in relation to women)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-07-19">1000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advanced payment by HQ for GPMD fee 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-04-26">30863</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Honduras April 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-08-06">21540</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Honduras August 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-15">11700</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Honduras January 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-29">28690</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Honduras June 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-03-08">22246</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Honduras March 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-10-18">32200</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Honduras October 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-06">5160</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Honduras September 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">117000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Honduras budget 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties trained</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of proposals submitted to the parliament</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of proposals submitted to the parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">An enabling environment for policitical and civic actors to play their policy roles</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">An enabling environment for policitical and civic actors to play their policy roles</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of agreements reached as a result of dialogue / platform meetings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of agreements reached as a result of dialogue / platform meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="109"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates of democracy schools</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates of democracy schools</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="16"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="17"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs included in NIMD supported activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs included in NIMD supported activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported dialogue initiatives</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported dialogue initiatives</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported interparty dialogue meetings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported interparty dialogue meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported multi-stakeholder dialogue meetings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported multi-stakeholder dialogue meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="290"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="44"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOTAL # of people included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOTAL # of people included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="652"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% participation by key stakeholder representatives (civic and political actors) in the dialogue initiative</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% participation by key stakeholder representatives (civic and political actors) in the dialogue initiative</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="67"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of L&amp;A initiatives for making the political system more inclusive (in relation to women / youth / minority groups)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of L&amp;A initiatives for making the political system more inclusive (in relation to women / youth / minority groups)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="7"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties participating in dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties participating in dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="7"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of institutionalized mechanisms for greater engagement by political and civic actors (structural change)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of institutionalized mechanisms for greater engagement by political and civic actors (structural change)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="13" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">scores on NIMD&apos;s 5-C organizational scan</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">scores on NIMD&apos;s 5-C organizational scan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.34" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="4.17">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that collaborate with civic actors at least x times per year</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that collaborate with civic actors at least x times per year</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="35.8" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="63">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that reference the following topics in their manifesto/public statements, other publications - democratic values and/or rule of law and/or gender sensitive &amp; inclusive politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that reference the following topics in their manifesto/public statements, other publications - democratic values and/or rule of law and/or gender sensitive &amp; inclusive politics</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="42" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="50">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of inclusive law making processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of inclusive law making processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="5" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents by political actors, based on inputs from a defined support base (women, youth and/or minority groups)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents by political actors, based on inputs from a defined support base (women, youth and/or minority groups)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="5" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of active alliances between political actors and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of active alliances between political actors and civic actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="5" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
