<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-MOZ16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MOZAMBIQUE&#x2019;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND Mozambique became independent in 1975. After a long and bloody civil war between rebel movement Renamo and the Frelimo government, a Peace Agreement was signed in 1992. With the Peace Agreement, Mozambique adopted the system of multiparty democracy. For a long time, Frelimo and Renamo dominated the political arena in Mozambique, with Frelimo being overwhelmingly dominant and holding an absolute majority in parliament. In 2009, the Mozambique Democratic Movement (MDM) entered the political scene and presented itself as a new political force. Despite more than 20 years of peace and relative stability, the civil war between Renamo and Frelimo still shapes the political reality of today. The ruling and main opposition parties still tend to see each other as enemies. This can be seen in the political discourse and makes it difficult for them to reach consensus. Since 2012, the political tensions between ruling party Frelimo and former rebel movement Renamo have been rising, resulting in low-intensity confrontations between the government and the opposition. Mozambique&#x2019;s rapid economic expansion over the past 20 years, which is mainly a result of the booming natural resources industry, has had only a moderate impact on poverty reduction and the distribution of wealth. This has led to increased social discontent and political confrontations. THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN MOZAMBIQUE NIMD&#x2019;s work in Mozambique started in 2000. The programme activities mainly focus on trying to reduce the tensions between the parliamentary parties and tries to create space for dialogue and constructive collaboration. The programme facilitates training on dialogue skills for the members of the parties and stimulates the involvement of a broad range of stakeholders (civil society organizations, church leaders and the international community). Capacity strengthening The programme furthermore aims to contribute to a safe environment for elections by facilitating dialogue sessions between the political parties and the electoral management body (CNE), In order to enable the political parties in Mozambique to contribute in an effective way to electoral activities, NIMD supports the parliamentary political parties to strengthen their organizational and programmatic capacities. The basis for these activities are the multi-annual strategic plans of the parties that were developed with support of NIMD. Democracy Schools In the current tense political climate and economic situation, the voice of the citizens in Mozambique often remains unheard. Citizens, local authorities, and political leaders often have insufficient capacity and incentives to initiate and maintain constructive and inclusive dialogue and interaction. To foster democratic behaviour and facilitate the creation of space for dialogue and cooperation between citizens and local authorities, NIMD facilitates democracy education programmes at provincial level. The democracy schools in Mozambique promote active citizenship and strengthen citizen engagement in local governance through practical leadership training programmes. By doing so, NIMD aims to contribute to the creation of a new generation of young politicians with democratic values and with the skills to act as agents of change.  Programme deviations/ToC update: In 2016 Mozambique the critical situation the country has been experiencing in the recent years continued. This had to do with political events, which were made worse by the public debt situation which has lead the country to a historical financial crunch.  These events have influenced the implementation of several of the activities in the programme. The political parties, particularly those not involved directly in the military political conflict, were proactive in the discussions during the programme events and brought proposals to the table as solutions to the political situation.
Despite  a great deal of momentum in regards to political dialogue, in practical terms, no tangible and concrete results leading to the creation of a climate of closer rapprochement or political stability between the parties has been produced. The evidence of this is the fact that during one of the negotiation breaks (8 October) one of the members of the negotiating team from Renamo party was shot dead. The atmosphere of political tension abated following telephone conversations between the President of the Republic and the President of the Renamo at the end of December when they decided to give truce in the armed conflict during the festive season and later extended it for further 60 days (to the end of February 2017).

The issue of public debt dominated the public debate and had a strong impact on the activities, as the government institutions marked as key partners in the activities were showing some fear of interacting with political parties. Nevertheless, it was possible to include them in some activities as demonstrated in the matrix. Some thematic activities did not take place as planned due to the tense political environment the country is going through. Instead the theme of the activities was changed to other relevant, less contentious issues. 

In this period, we can conclude that the relationship between the political parties and civil society has improved significantly due to a consensual national agenda that consists of re-establishing political and democratic stability. Here it is important to highlight that in the previous government, there was strong interference from political parties in the midst of civil society. This situation created great mistrust on both sides. However, because of the political crisis, there has been a convergence of opinion, with both political parties and civil society calling for a sustainable peace solution.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Demo Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD Mozambique</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">319878</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-06-16">79769</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Mozambique June 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-24">53315</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Mozambique March 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-08">153494</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Mozambique September 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-28">319878</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique budget 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">8891</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">37500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capability to attract and relate of political actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of types of collaborations between MPs and political actors or CS stakeholders that are perceived as being active</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of active alliances between political actors and/or between political actors and CS stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Figure 1.2: Types of collaboration between different actors according to the qualitative information collected in the interview Different actors Not active Partially active Active Ruling party/opposition parties &#x25CF; Opposition parties themselves &#x25CF; Opposition parties/ Civil society &#x25CF; Ruling party/Civil society &#x25CF; MPs /Civil society &#x25CF; Qualitative description: The political actors that were interviewed identified three mechanisms of collaboration between them, namely: (i) Sharing of information, (ii) Consulted meetings and (iii) joint activities. The civil society organizations that were interviewed identified five mechanisms of collaboration among them and with political actors, namely: (i) Development of laws; (ii) Participation in debates, (iii) Participation in consultation sessions, (iv) Provision of capacity to some parties and through (v) Providing inputs to the electoral manifest for some politic parties. All of the respondents (politics actors, MPs and civil society stakeholders) stated that they collaborate with each other. These actors have a similar perception about the level of collaboration between with each other, for instance 70% of political actors view their collaboration with civic actors as being active and 30% of them as being partially active. Likewise, 71% of civil stakeholder&#x2019;s have an active collaboration with political actors, while 29% think that their collaboration is partially active. Although evidences from the field indicate there is active collaboration between civic and political actors, this collaboration does vary between actors. In the current legislative term, most MP&#x2019;s from RENAMO and MDM indicate that they consult civic actors mainly on imminent legislative debates, meaning that frequency of this collaboration varies from occasion to occasion. While there are peak periods such as during the electoral season, when laws proposals are under discussion, both political and civic actors tend to collaborate more intensively. However, there are times when collaboration is required but challenges arise which prohibit effective collaboration. Most representatives from the opposition political parties and civil society pointed out several challenges that limit their collaboration with the government. These challenges were traced back to 1994. The main challenge identified includes the claim that the process of peace building, democratization and decentralization was imperfect which mainly benefited the ruling party and excluded other key political actors such as RENAMO. The representatives interviewed believe that this is the reason for of the current socio-political and economic inequalities as well as military conflicts in Mozambique. Furthermore, despite the progress made in some areas no political space for government, political and civil actors to work together has been established in the country. The Mozambican state and government has not yet consolidated an adequate system of checks and balances in governance processes; within the decentralization process of power and institutions this has also not been completed yet. Participants also regard the judiciary system as not being totally independent from government interests. Furthermore, the lack of a culture of sharing information and the lack of skills of most political and civil actors was considered to be a key barrier to greater engagement between various stakeholders. Although Political actors stated that they have a close collaboration with civic actors, civic actors claim that such collaboration is conditional on the interest coming from the political parties. Whereas collaboration tends to be more difficult when it is requested by civil actors. Civil society organizations indicated that they faced challenges of having their plans or request for information accepted by politic parties which shows certain levels of mistrust, even though their request may be accepted at a later state. They also stated that they often used informal channels to access information from political actors. Thus one conclusion that can be made is that civil society organizations may be serving the interests of specific political parties. Despite the above mentioned challenges civil society organizations have collaborated with political actors in the development of many laws such as the law against domestic violence (2009); Family law (2004); revision of the criminal code (2014) as well as participating in debates, consultation sessions, collaboration through capacity building of party members and have also given inputs to the electoral manifesto of some politic parties. On the basis of the information that was collected, it is concluded that the collaboration between the political parties, as well as that between civil society and political parties, still needs improvement. Further, more space for formal dialogue and for the increased inclusion of civil society stakeholders needs to be established or used effectively in order to allow for better collaboration in the process of policy development and implementation.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors that voice and monitor citizen interests</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents (manifestos, election programmes, position papers, policy proposal) by political actors based on inputs from a defined support base (on improving gender equality and/or on inclusion)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 0 Qualitative description: The collected information reveals that there is no political document, such as a manifesto, election program, position paper or policy proposal approved or adopted by political parties based specifically on the inputs from a defined support base (such as women and youth league party representatives). The key finding is that the three political parties (FRELIMO, MDM and RENAMO) despite the fact that both their youth and women members are of the opinion that they are significantly included in political party activities through formal mechanisms, such as through youth and women leagues. However, they believe that their inclusion is still not sufficient to ensure that their particular interests and demands are met. Political activity is still regarded as man&#x2019;s activity and age is a key determinant for assuming political leadership. Furthermore, women and youth believe that their participation in critical decisions processes of their political parties is still weak. These groups did not indicate whether their parties had policies in place aimed at enhancing effective political participation of women and youth. In addition to the lack of policy, it was also revealed that the process of inception and implementation of women and youth political inclusiveness takes a linear form which is developed at a central level and cascades to their leagues, with their role being to follow up and implement orders coming from the central level. The women interviewed also revealed that their parties&#x2019; strategies and documents inceptions and implementation was not reflective of what had been discussed with them and their inputs.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Extent to which civic actors experience an enabling environment in which they can influence/are involved in inclusive policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 0% Not Enabling Partially Enabling Enabling All SC actors (n=7) 71% (5) 29% (2) 0% (0) n=5 n=2 n=0 Academics 100% (3) 0% (0) 0% (0) NGOs 50% (2) 50% (2) 0% (0) Final result of the indicator 0% (0) Qualitative description: The collected information reveals that the government of Mozambique recognizes civic actors as key partners in the process of building inclusive and sustainable political and socio-economic development and this is reflected in the national constitution. Furthermore, they recognize that civic actors&#x2019; have the right to participate in democratic policy dialogue with government. However, in spite of an existing national comprehensives legal-framework and formal mechanisms to promote civic actors&#x2019; participation in the policy making and implementation process, the level of trust and collaboration has deteriorated significantly in the past years. The civic actor understanding is that the political environment for their participation is very limited and that there is an increasing level of political intolerance and intimidation of different actors who think differently to government or the ruling party. Civic actors and academics feel that they are consulted in order to legitimize the process. However the government does not necessary take their input into a consideration within the policy making process. Additionally, the civic actors believe that the government is not interested in communicating and promoting a dialogue about key aspects of the national development policy. Some of the individuals who were interviewed revealed that the reason for this deteriorating relationship is mainly because of the current economic and political governance challenges that are ongoing in the country, specifically the prolonged political-military conflict (involving RENAMO armed-men and the government military-forces). The recent economic financial public scandals, such as the public debit, EMATUM and unclear military material deals have been some of the main reasons for the conflict. Other aspects on which civic actors and academics believe that government has become more intolerant in the last few years include the contention regarding the possible decentralization of government, the attempt of prohibiting civic protests related to social discontent such as socio-economic grievances, corruption and the exclusion of citizens within a democratic process, and the increasing cases of kidnappings and unexplained assassinations (Professor Gilles Cistac, Persecutor Marcelo Vilankulo and the recent shooting of the scholar and TV political commentator, Prof. Jaime Macuane). This data reveals that despite the achievements of the recognition of civic actors in the political process within the national constitution, the level of political engagement and collaboration between government and civil actors, is still low. Furthermore the political environment is characterized by fear and insecurity, which creates a context of distrust between the actors, further fuelling a tradition of non-collaboration between various stakeholders in the political process.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that experience an enabling environment in which they are involved in inclusive policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="40" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 40% Not Enabling Partially Enabling Enabling All Political actors (n=10) 50% ( 5) 10% (1) 40% (4) n=8 n=1 n=1 FRELIMO 0% (0) 0% (0) 100% (4) RENAMO 75% (3) 25% (1) 0% (0) MDM 100% (2) 0% (0) 0% (0) Final result of the indicator 40% (4) Qualitative description: Both FRELIMO and RENAMO acknowledge that the working environment between them has deteriorated over the years, more so since the last presidential and legislative elections. In order to restore the positive working relationship between RENAMO and FRELIMO there are many important aspects that would need to be addressed first at a high political level by the two parties and government. These aspects include the causes of political and military conflicts (such as decentralization/provincial autonomy) and reaching a security and peace agreement on the Joaquim Chissano Conference Center conversations. The MDM also indicated that its relationship with both RENAMO and FRELIMO has not been healthy. Further the relation with the ruling party has often been complicated, especially at local, provincial, district and municipality levels. The collected information reveals that there is also a lack of trust among the opposition parties (MDM and RENAMO), for instance only on a few occasions have they been able to reach consensus in parliament. An example of this is the case of 2012 where the two parties were able to join forces and vote against a government/ruling party law proposal regarding the Public Probity Law.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of civic actors that that consider members of the governing party as constructive partner in policy development and implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors (mainly MPs) and civic actors see each other as important partners in the process of policy making and implementation, with 100% of both actors seeing each other as partners in process of policy making and implementation to enhancing a national inclusive and sustainable socio-political and economic growth and development. There has been some successful policy collaboration and partnership between civic political actors. The civic actors were able to strongly influence the processes. Some laws that have been passed in the parliament and enacted by the executive which were proposed by civil society, for Instance, the Law against Domestic Violence (2009) and the new Family Law (2004) were both suggested by the civil society. Although the civil society views political actors as partners they are aware that challenges still exist and improvements are required, especially when it deals with issues of trust and partnership with the MPs from the ruling party and the government. The civic actors revealed and criticized the ruling party&#x2019;s MPs and government because of some cases in which laws and policy formulation were approved and adopted by the government based on top-down approach, ignoring all possible inputs from the civil society. The interviewed civic actors also revealed that their participation in policy making and implementation has deteriorated since the period the opposition parties stated (the second terms of the President Guebuza and continue to President Nyusi government). Since then they perceive that the government and national parliament often does not respect the existing mechanisms of policy dialogue among government and civil society. The room given to civil society for contributing in policy making and implementation is getting limited; the time usually allocated to them is not enough to provide sound inputs. For instance, the scholars interviewed in this baseline study feel that in significant cases they were consulted for a practically policy making process but most of their inputs were not integrated into the final product in the form of implemented policy. The civic actors revealed that they relationship with government becomes challenging after the civil society national agenda had shifted from simple humanitarian developmental services delivery organization but also to extend their interests in economic and governance agendas. This was mainly significant in increasing social inequalities and poverty while the wealth of the country is continually concentrated in the minority (political elite of FRELIMO). With the discovery of natural resources, the civil society have significantly increased their demand for good governance, inclusive and sustainable resources development and management policy which would allow the government and state to be transparent and accountable to its citizens.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of opposition parties that consider members of the governing party as constructive partner in policy development and implementation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 0% for opposition parties and 100% for civic actors Do not see as partners See as partners All Political actors Who consider governing party as partner All opposition parties (n=6) 100% (2) 0% (0) RENAMO (n=4) 100% (4) 0% (0) MDM (n=2) 100% (2) 0% (0) Final result of the indicator for opposition parties 0 All CS stakeholders (n=7) 0% (0) 100% (7) Final result of the indicator for CS stakeholders 7 Qualitative description: The political actors have a problem of trusting each other. This is particularly complicated when it comes to establishment of working partnership between RENAMO and FRELIMO. The two parties recognize that their political history has had a major effect on developing an effective working relationship. RENAMO members interviewed stated that FRELIMO was not open and interested in promoting democratic policy dialogue within the country, and was not prepared to accept outside FRELIMO policy inputs, especially when it came from the opposition party such as RENAMO which they consider to be a long term enemy. The information collected reveals that despite the mistrust between the two parties, during the time of President Joaquim Chissano administration the political environment was significantly conducive for the opposition parties&#x2019; collaboration with the ruling party/government in many important policy processes. They understand that during that time the two parties were always able to find common ground and interests in order to work together for the benefit of socio-political and economic development of the country. They consider that this good political working environment deteriorated since President Guebuza and continued with the new elected President Mr. Nyusi. Additionally to the current political and economic and governance problems which Mozambique is experiencing, this started during the second term of President Guebuza. The political environment for the opposition parties to operate freely and collaborate on common developmental policy have become structurally and systematically limited. An example was the arrest of a senior member of RENAMO, Mr. Antonio Muchanga, just after the meeting of members of the State Council at the presidential office. At the time of his arrest, Mr. Muchanga was both an MP and a member of the state Council, which in fact gave him political immunity, but this was immediately removed in that meeting. The political actors interviewed from RENAMO believe that been the two major political actors in the country an eventual collaboration in policy making and implementation is critical. But eventually collaboration would be possible after the two parties have reached an agreement on the political and military national conflicts causes, such as the decentralization/provincial autonomy process, and the Joaquim Chissano Conference Center conversations (which was stopped after the outbreak of the military attacks by government forces and opposition parties). Contrary to the perception of RENAMO, the political actors from the FRELIMO perception is that the political environment is conducive for the political actors to collaborate in policy making and implementation process and, Mozambique have all legal-framework to allow the opposition parties to operate freely since they political actions are based on the national constitution. The FRELIMO Political actors also said that they always open to receive new policy ideas and inputs from all national political and developmental stakeholders. However, they highlighted that the problem is the opposition parties who are not prepared and also do not have the capacity to actively participate in national politics using democratic means. The MDM on the other hand indicated that their relationship with FRELIMO is not healthy. Further their relations with FRELIMO are often complicated, especially at local, provincial, district and municipality levels were the MDM is in power as such as Nampula, Quelimane and Beira. In terms of working relationship between MDM and RENAMO, the MDM members interviewed revealed that their relationship with RENAMO is at lower level but does not necessary have a great impact on political activities of the both parties. Although political parties recognize the gains of collaboration in Mozambique, not all political actors see each other&#x2019;s as partners in the process on development and implementation of legislation. Data reveled political actors from the opposition do not perceive the ruling political party and MPs as their partners (67% RENAMO, 33% MDM). Only FRELIMO (100%) consider other parties and MPs as partners.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partners (based on adapted 5 Core Capabilities of NIMD&apos;s scan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partners increased their scores on NIMD&apos;s organizational scan (BART), which is based on the 5 C model</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.7" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 3.7 (5C average) Commit and act 3.7 Deliver results 3.3 Adapt and self-renew 3.6 Attract and relate to external stakeholders 3.9 Balance coherence and diversity 3.9 Qualitative description: The results of the organisational assessment scan demonstrate that the IMD Mozambique is perceived to be relatively strong organisation with a broad range of capabilities thanks to the transference of experienced staff and fundamental resources from NIMD country office. The organisation scores particularly high on the i) ability to relate to external stakeholders, with 3.9; ii) balance coherence and diversity, 3.9 and iii) Capable to commit and act with 3.7. The relatively lower scores, although not bad, corresponds to the i) capability of adapting and self-renewing with 3.6 and capability of delivering results with 3.3. In general, the strengths of the organization reflected on the high score of the many dimensions were inherited from the NIMD-CO performance. More specifically, the participants indicated that the IMD Office is considered to be a strategically effective organization with consistent programs, has good leadership composed by national board members, develop and implement relevant programs and integrity political situations and challenges. Based on the previous NIMD office, the staff have proven to be able to deliver results according to the plans. These qualities also became clear in a recent appraisal done by the Finnish Embassy for another programme which classified IMD has having strong HR capacities for the program implementation, although some improvements has to be done on HR policy. Besides these strengths, a # of points for improvement were also mentioned. E.g. the approval of an adequate HR policy, the organisation has to put in place sufficient risk policies, more encouragement of learning, the source of funds has to be diversified; simple and participatory M&amp;E system; more flexibility on the decisions of the NIMD-HQ related to the resource mobilization. With regard to external communication it was pointed out the need to give more visibility of IMD as an autonomous Mozambican organization although always important to advertise the natural partnership with NIMD. It was also given the suggestion to move forward with the previous idea of creation of a communication plan and media strategy. In that regard in the coming months IMD will have to create its website to profile its activities and intensify relations with media.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies and proposed amendments jointly formulated for submission to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties taking part in the dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies and proposed amendments jointly formulated for submission to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties taking part in the dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women involved in politics that feel they are able to take part in decision-making processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women involved in politics that feel they are able to take part in decision-making processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of diversity and inclusivity of actors participating in the policy platform</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of diversity and inclusivity of actors participating in the policy platform</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of amendments proposed by MPs</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of amendments proposed by MPs</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
