<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-SAL16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">El Salvador Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EL SALVADOR&#x2019;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND El Salvador is located in the northern part of Central America, and is part of the so called Northern Triangle together with Honduras and Guatemala. The three countries face a lot of similar challenges especially in the area of security. Socio economic situation Although the economy has steadily increased over the last decade in El Salvador, a large proportion of the population continues to live in poverty and the level of unemployment remains high. Young people and women are even more vulnerable to the socio economic situation. Furthermore, the country experiences some of the highest crime levels of the world. On top of that, climate change poses a serious challenge for El Salvador, because it is particularly vulnerable to extreme climatic events such as hurricanes, floods and droughts. As a result, tensions around sufficient clean water supply have built up. The country is dependent on Guatemala and Honduras for its water supply. Democratic system Over the last decades, the democratic system of El Salvador has been dominated by two parties : the conservative right-wing party &#x2018;Nationalist Republican Alliance (ARENA)&#x2019; and the &#x2018;Farabundo Mart&#xED; National Liberation Front (FMLN)&#x2019;, which transitioned from a guerrilla movement to a leftist political party. After an initial domination of the political landscape by the ARENA party from 1989 until 2009, in 2009 the FMLN managed to win the elections for the first time and subsequently installed the first left-wing government in El Salvador. In February 2014, the FMLN won the elections again with a very narrow margin. In March 2015, elections took place for the Legislative Assembly, the Central American Parliament and the municipal governments. For the first time in history Salvadorans chose plural or multi-party municipal councils (before that the &#x2018;winner takes all&#x2019; system was applied). These elections also had another new feature: for the first time a quota regulation of 30% for women was applied for the electoral lists. Despite a high perception of corruption and friction between the judiciary on the one hand and the presidency and legislative assembly on the other, the democratic institutions are perceived to be functioning reasonably well. THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN EL SALVADOR NIMD&#x2019;s work in El Salvador started at the end of 2012. As a result, the programme was focused on preparing the political parties for the changes in the electoral system for the 2015 elections. In light of the changes in the electoral law for the municipal elections, NIMD developed a &#x2018;train the trainers programme&#x2019; for all political parties on dialogue skills and consensus building: important skills to have to ensure governability at local level. NIMD did this in coordination with other organizations. Inclusion of underrepresented groups In its work, NIMD pays special attention to the inclusion of underrepresented groups in politics. The establishment of the quota regulations was an important step forward in Guatemala and resulted in over 30% of women elected in the Legislative Assembly. NIMD supports capacity building of women politicians through an intensive training course for women politicians from all political parties and from national and local level. Furthermore, NIMD seeks to contribute to a democratic culture where the rights of women and men are respected. We do this by investigating the barriers that hamper political participation of women and by exchanging best practices on gender sensitive policy and legislation. Capacity building of youth Young people tend to shy away from a career in politics, not seeing the possibilities that the political arena offers to positively influence important decisions about the future of the country. NIMD is in the process of establishing a Democracy School for young people from political and civil society to prepare them for their careers. At this school they will be able to practice democratic skills and behaviours and learn how to speak, listen and debate with mutual respect and focus on programmatic content. Environmental Dialogue NIMD also facilitates dialogue between civil society and political actors on issues related to environmental governance and security, such as water management. This approach is part of our Democratic Dialogue for Environmental Security programme. The programme is implemented together with Cordaid and is being carried out in El Salvador, Colombia and Guatemala.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD El Salvador</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SV" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">143000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-20">15200</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement El Salvador Dec 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-19">19949</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement El Salvador February 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-22">25378</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement El Salvador July 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-27">3128</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement El Salvador July-2 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-19">34338</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement El Salvador May 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-06">48471</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement El Salvador October 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-28">143000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">El Salvador Budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">2115</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partners (based on adapted 5-Capabilities scan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In El Salvador NIMD operates a small country office since 2013. The office is currently represented by a staff of three people, composed of the country director, a programme manager and an administrative official. This team is supported by a political analyst with elaborate experience and a broad network of contacts in El Salvador&#xB4;s political society. The country office works closely together with a # of other organizations and institutions, both national and international. During 2014 and 2015 NIMD has worked to build relationships with all political parties, especially those represented in the Parliamentary Assembly. It has also fostered relationships with other key stakeholders related to the areas of work of the Institute. Among them may be mentioned: 1. State institutions: Legislative Assembly, especially the Commissions of Environment and Natural Resources and of Women and Children, Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources, Institute for the Development of Women (ISDEMU), Instituto Nacional de la Juventud (INJUVE), Association of Municipalities of the Republic of El Salvador (COMURES), National Institute of Municipal Development (ISDEM), the Supreme Electoral Tribunal and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. 2. Non-Governmental Organisations: ASRPODE, Water Forum, El Salvador Environmental Alliance, GAIA, CEICOM, CEPRODE, ISD, FUNDE, FUSADES FEPADE and FUNDEMUCA. 3. Academic institutions: UCA, Universidad de El Salvador (UES) and Evangelical University of El Salvador. 4. Development cooperation entities: EU, AECID, USAID, GIZ, Canadian Embassy, Embassy of Chile, Embassy of Mexico, UNDP and UN Women. 5. Regional Entities: SICA y PARLACEN. Due to the diminishing attention for Central America, it is hard for the NIMD office to obtain additional funding. NIMD has established relations with the main donors and will continue to pursue additional funding opportunities. The SP budget is small, and that means that the activities are quite limited in scale as an important part of the budget is spent on operational costs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capability of local partners (based on adapted 5 Core Capabilities of NIMD&#xB4;s scan)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="4.1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative Data: 4.1 (5C average) Capabilities Results Max C1 Commit and Act 4,3 5 C2 Deliver Results 3,9 5 C3 Adapt and Self Renew 4,1 5 C4 Attract and Relate 4,2 5 C5 Balance Coherence and Diversity 4,2 5 Qualitative Description: The office is well established and managed in a short period of time to estaliblish a good reputation with the political parties and national and international organizations. Currently the office is in the process of getting its national registration. This registration will broaden fund raising possibilities. The office is small. That means that it can easily adapt to changed circumstances and it is flexible in its way of working and responding to emerging needs. At the same time the size of the office is also vulnerability. Much depends on the ED and with the limited amount of staff it is hard to attend a surge in activities which for example happened after the office got additional financing from the Canadian Embassy. One of the measures that have been taken is to establish a network of experts and consultants that can be called upon. However, this means depending on external factors, the office itself has only limited possibilities to reorganize its work. The budget does not allow for elaborated human resources policies. Security of staff, information and the office is important. It was not easy to find an appropriate office in San Salvador. There has been an attempt of theft and as a result additional safety measures have been taken.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capability to attract and relate of political actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of active alliances between political actors and/or between political actors and CS stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative Data: 1 active alliance has been identified during the measurement period Qualitative Data: From the research undertaken 1 active alliance has been identified: 1. Alliance between political actors has been established regarding the electoral and political reform, specifically for the effective implementation of Multiparty Municipal Councils in 10 municipalities included in the &#x201C;El Salvador Safety Plan&#x201D; elaborated by El Salvador&#xB4;s Government. The members of this alliance are: the Under Secretary of Governance, ISDEM, COMURES and 10 municipalities prioritized in that referred Plan. This alliance is being supported by UNDP, AECID-FUNDEMUCA and NIMD. Their main goal is to provide technical assistance and training to municipalities for the proper functioning of the local government working together with the opposition parties within the councils with emphasis on policy dialogue and consensus negotiation skills.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe (and institutionalized) space for dialogue between all relevant political (and civic) actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of structural changes and new mechanisms for greater engagement by political and civic actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="4" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: There are 4 new mechanisms for greater engagement by political and civic actors. Qualitative description: From the research undertaken, the 4 new mechanisms identified are: 1. A Multiparty and civil society youth dialogue platform functioning in El Salvador as result from the youth training course developed by the NIMD in 2015. Youth from four out of five political parties represented in the National Parliament are represented in this platform: ARENA, GANA, PDC and PCN, and there are two civil society youth platforms represented: National Youth Assembly (ANJ) and the Intersectoral Coordinator Pro Youth of El Salvador (CIPJES). The platform&#x2019;s main goal is to coordinate, plan and execute actions and/or joint strategies to promote the strengthening of youth structures within the political parties and youth civic platforms and to provide training and support the political decision making process towards youth. It is currently defining its mode of operation and its work program. 2. A National Committee for the Implementation of Resolution 1325 from United Nations Security Council on Women, Peace and Security. This mechanism was created in 2014 by Executive Decree No.74. It is an interministerial and multi-actor working group to make policies and rule proposals entitled to ensure compliance with R1325 and its subsequent resolutions. The National Committee is composed by three main structures: a Board of Directors, a Technical Monitoring Committee and the Standing Advisory Group. The Board of Directors is made up of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Ministry of Justice and Public Security, Ministry of National Defense; Attorney General&apos;s Office (FGR), Public Prosecutor&#x2019;s Office (PGR), National Institute for Women Development (ISDEMU) and 3 non-governmental organizations, including Prudencia Ayala Feminist Coalition. Currently the National Action Plan is being developed with NIMD and UN Women support. 3. Management Group for the Multiparty City Councils (CMP by its Spanish name). It is currently composed of the Under Secretary of Governance, the National Development Foundation (FUNDE), the Central American University Jose Simeon Ca&#xF1;as (UCA), Social Initiative for Democracy (ISD), the Foundation for Local Development and Municipal Strengthening of Central American and Caribbean (FUNDEMUCA) and the NIMD. Its goal is to coordinate actions for the effective implementation of multiparty city councils that exist since 2015 as a result of a change in legislation. Currently an assessment of the CMP&#x2019;s first year of implementation is being developed. 4. Electoral Evaluation Workshop. First held in 2015 by the Electoral Supreme Court, with the participation of political parties&#x2019; representatives, civil society organizations, government agencies and universities. It was supported by NIMD and other organizations such as the OAS, A-WEB and International IDEA. They were organized in 11 working groups for two days. The objective is to organize an evaluation seminar after each electoral event.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors that voice and monitor citizen interests</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents (manifestos, election programmes, position papers, policy proposal) by political actors based on inputs from a defined support base.</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="4" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: There are 4 published political documents. Qualitative data: From the research undertaken, the 4 published political documents identified are: 1. A draft treaty on transboundary waters between Guatemala, Honduras and El Salvador (policy proposal). ACTOR: Ministry of Foreign Affairs. This policy proposal has been prepared by Salvadoran environmental organizations led by CEICOM, who are working with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and other political actors such as the Environment and Climate Change Commission, Salvadoran Deputies from the Central America Parliament, and other political and civil actors from Guatemala and Honduras. 2. A General Water Law proposal is under review at the Environment and Climate Change Legislative Commission. There are 3 proposals as input for the study: One has been made by the Water Forum (environmental NGO&#x2019;s network), one submitted by the Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources (MARN) and one by the Association of Irrigators from Atiocoyo (representing the private enterprise interests). 3. Women Parliamentary Group has agreed a Consensus Agenda for the 2015-2018 Legislature, and it has been built including inputs received from different actors, such as: ISDEMU, women&apos;s organizations, Attorney General&apos;s Office (FGR), UN Women and UNDP. The Agendas&#x2019; validation process was supported by NIMD. 4. Memory built for the 2015 Electoral Evaluation Workshop, which includes the main findings and recommendations proposed during that process. All of these published political documents have been supported by NIMD.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of LatinoBarometer respondents expressing trust in political parties</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="14" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The most recently available 2015 LatinoBarometer measured public trust of respondents in political parties overall. Collapsing the categories of &#x201C;somewhat&#x201D; and &#x201D;a lot&#x201D;, we see that there is very low trust in political parties in El Salvador.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional multi-stakeholder platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional multi-stakeholder platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Transborder Basin Treaty Working Group, consisting of 3 CSO&apos;s and NIMD, 3 male and 1 female 2) Municipal Councils Support Committee, consisting of 3 political actors, 2 development cooperations and NIMD, 3 male and 5 female, focussing on the implementation of the multiparty municipal councils in the municipalities prioritised by the Plan Safe Salvador 3) Multiparty and civil society youth table, consisting of 4 political parties, 1 CSO and 1 CSO Youth Platform, 13 male and 4 female.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates from democracy and political education schools (disaggregate sex, age, social group etc)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates from democracy and political education schools (disaggregate sex, age, social group etc)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="36">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">11 women. 24 men, 1 LGBTI</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political actors who have been trained on the importance of the CS dialogue</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political actors who have been trained on the importance of the CS dialogue</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="262">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">126 women and 136 men</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of civic actors that indicate that they experience an increased willingness-to-interact from political actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of civic actors that indicate that they experience an increased willingness-to-interact from political actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="75">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the 8 civil actors that we work with within the SP, 6 of them qualify the willingness to interact of political actors on a 10-point scale with a 6 or higher. The average score is 6.37</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies formulated based on consultation with interest groups, local experts, CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies formulated based on consultation with interest groups, local experts, CS</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Transborder Basin Treaty Proposal</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The interparty youth table, representing the 4 political parties with parliamentary representation at a national level, 4 male and 1 female. Foucs on youth topics. In 2016 3 interparty meetings were organised: 1 interparty youth table meeting to prepare a communication campaign to promote youth participation in politics, 1 interparty meeting to create a network of political women, 1 with the Comision de Medio Ambiente y Cambio Clim&#xE1;tico de la Asamblea Legislativa to compare Latin America&apos;s Water Laws as a support to create and approve a Water law in El Salvador</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that they regularly work together with other political actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that they regularly work together with other political actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="78">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The survey covered representatives from the 4 parties that NIMD regularly works with. Of the 9 political actors consulted, 78% indicate that they work regularly with others</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="565">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This includes 334 female, 230 male, 1 LGBTI, 498 political actors and 67 CSO representatives. The capacity building activities consisted of: 1) democracy schools (36 graduates) 2) legal warranties for women political participation workshop (39 women), 3) training of trainers workshop (22 women) 4) compared experiences on water management workshop (28 men and 14 women) 5) workshop on political communication without gender stereotypes (9 men and 16 women) 6) workshop on political communication with MP&apos;s, Gender Unit of the Congress and Congress Advisors (1 men, 31 women) 7) Workshop on political communication for young political actors (33 men, 5 women), 8) Workshop on political communication with women politicians (67 women) 9) dialogue training in the municipals councils framework (39 women, 56 men) 10) dialogue training to 10 municipal councils (50 women, 79 men), 11) dialogue and negotiation moduel within the women politicians training (40 women)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># women participants in programme activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># women participants in programme activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="334"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political parties that experience that their contribution to policy processes are more effective</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political parties that experience that their contribution to policy processes are more effective</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="75"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who have increased their interaction with CS since the training</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who have increased their interaction with CS since the training</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="78"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
