<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-GHA16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GHANA&#x2019;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND Ghana is generally seen as a development aid success story. In 2000 the first democratic transition of power took place after successful elections and in 2012 power changed hands again. In 2000 the NDC &#x2013; the party of former dictator Jerry Rawlings &#x2013; peacefully handed over power to another established party: the NPP. The NPP subsequently won but in 2012 lost again to the NDC. There are four parties in parliament. The NDC and the NPP are the largest. The parties, in comparison to other African countries, are quite established and ideological. Despite major improvements in education, food security and the economy, Ghana is currently facing serious economic challenges due to overpromising and underwhelming oil revenue and subsequent overspending as well as an energy crisis. At the same time, it is facing governance challenges related to the new activity of large scale commercial production of oil. THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN GHANA NIMD&#x2019;s programme in Ghana started in 2002 and the main focus has been on facilitating interparty dialogue. Political parties were extremely acrimonious towards each other. The attitude was: the winner takes all, if you lose power you lose everything. This blocked any serious political progress. Under the programme&#x2019;s guidance political leaders met and debated publicly for the first time. This led to an interparty dialogue platform that includes the party leadership of all parliamentary parties. The platform is facilitated by NIMD and local implementing partner organization, the Institute of Economic Affairs. Currently, the platform mainly focuses on three areas: constitutional reform, electoral reform, and addressing excessive executive powers. The platform aims to move Ghana away from what they call &#x2018;Winner takes all politics&#x2019; where whoever wins the election has all the power without enough checks and balances. Under the platform&#x2019;s guidance a transition of power act was drafted and passed into law. This makes for a much better democratic transition. NIMD also supports the parliamentary parties to develop their policies. In Ghana we do this partly by funding a policy analyst post for each of the four parliamentary parties.      Programme deviations/ToC update: Political developments took place as expected, as elections were held and the political opposition won the presidency. The new majority party (NPP) has traditionally been more open to interparty engagement, and the new dynamic suggests the new opposition (NDC) is more likely to be interested in working together. At the same time the two smaller parties in parliament have lost their seats, now all 275 seats are divided by the two largest parties. This may influence how the dialogue platform is constituted as previously it was for parliamentary parties of which there have nearly always been four.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Economic Affairs (IEA)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">137460</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-25">137.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Budget</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-17">68730</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Ghana June 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">7422</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">30000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that experience an enabling environment in which they are involved in inclusive policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level = 1 Quantitative data Number of youth leaders who have contributed to policy process The questionnaires provided the following quantitative data. 52% of the youth interviewed had contributed to a policy process before. Capacity in which youth leaders contributed to policy process 82% of those who had contributed to a policy process indicated that they had done so as part of a youth network or organization. 48% of this number said they had been invited to take part in the policy process by policy makers. Reflection of youth input in final policy For those who had contributed to a policy process, 8% thought their contributions to the policy process was well received. The remaining either had no idea whether their contributions had been received well, or thought the response had been discouraging. 18% of the number who had contributed to a policy process believed that their contribution had reflected in the final policy position. 82% thought it did not. 32% of the number that had contributed to a policy process before thought their contributions to the policy process had been effective. The remaining number thought their contribution had not been effective. Qualitative description The focus group discussion with youth leaders deepened the quantitative information gathered. The focus group discussion seemed to provide a higher degree of candidness than participants&#x2019; responses to the questionnaires provided. The following information emerged from the discussion: Characteristics of Youth Contribution to Policy Processes 1. High contribution of individual youth to policy processes In the estimation of youth leaders, individual youth had contributed to national development and policy making at the highest levels over the past three decades. Ghana&#x2019;s military uprising in 1979 and eventual return to democratic governance was led by persons within the category of youth. The country&#x2019;s second republic has seen several Ministers and Deputy Ministers of State within the youth bracket. There are many youth in the district assemblies. Parliament is seeing increasingly youthful membership. In the opinion of participants, &#x201C;it is the youth who have taken us to the place and the state in which we are today&#x201D;. The contribution of the youth in Ghana&#x2019;s national development and in policy processes however remained at an individual level. As individuals, members of the youth were participating at the highest levels of national governance and policy development. However, they were perceived by the wider body of Ghanaian youth as playing those roles in their personal capacities, and not as representatives of a youth constituency to which they hold themselves accountable. The youth therefore perceive them as distanced from their reality. &#x201C;The youth in government are too high and mighty&#x2026;&#x201D;.The youth in positions of government are further viewed by the youth as subservient to the policy positions and interests of the establishment. The contribution of the youth to national development and policy making is therefore characterized by individuals, who through personal effort and resources, have risen to positions in government. They are not viewed by the youth as representatives of the youth or accountable to them. 2. Insignificant contribution of formally educated youth to policy processes The contribution of formally educated youth (youth with secondary and tertiary education) in policy processes is considered largely insignificant. Youth of this category are active on social media, where vibrant discussions on policy issues are carried out. In the opinion of participants, their discussions have almost no effect on policy. They have minimal direct engagement with policy makers at national, district and local levels. Occasionally, some Ministers of State will respond to their discussions on social media, with posts and tweets buy direct engagement of this nature seems not to translate into policy action. Their need is for support to turn their contributions into collective influence with policy makers. 3. Ad hoc contribution of youth in local communities to policy processes Contribution of youth based in local communities to policy processes appears to be characterized by ad hoc spurts of vibrant mobilization and presentation of demands, which are taken seriously by their Assembly men/women and Members of Parliament, particularly as election periods draw close. Their contribution however remains at a very basic level of demands for physical infrastructure and facilities, and not analysis and input on policies that could address the fundamental challenges underlying their basic needs. The influence of the youth at this level derives from their voting power during election years. Assembly men and women, and Members of Parliament tend to take their demands seriously in order to secure their votes. There is a need is to educate them on the policy constraints underlying their needs and support them to demand policy changes/implementation to address those needs. 4. Constrained contribution of youth to political party policy-making processes Political parties indicate that they have mechanisms for youth input into party policy making processes. One party provides for the youth to make written statements where they wish to input into policy processes. Another party has provided its youth wing with the space to hold a Youth Congresses. The contribution of youth wings and their membership, to political party policy making processes, is however perceived by the youth as constrained and restrained. Youth wings perceive themselves as being restrained and held in check by political party leadership. They do not consider themselves free to express and act upon their opinions. A recent episode where the youth leader of a political party was reprimanded and disciplined for an enquiry he initiated into a party policy issue was cited as a reflection of the wider approach of political parties towards youth contribution to policy making processes. Number of Public Collective Statements by the Youth Key policy issues that directly affect their present and future wellbeing have been discussed without their collective input or reaction; as for example the protracted policy discussion on the number of years that high school should entail. &#x201C;We have not been able to influence any policy in Ghana to reflect youth interest&#x201D;. Effectiveness of Youth Contributions to Policy Processes Based upon the above characteristics of the youth&#x2019;s participation in policy processes, the youth consider their contributions to policy processes in Ghana as ineffective. They identify the following causes for their ineffectiveness. Causes of Ineffective Youth Contributions to Policy Processes The youth identify the following root causes of their ineffective contributions to policy processes. These are listed in order of importance surfacing from the focus group discussion. i. Underlying fear of the youth: The youth hold the opinion that members of government and political party leadership alike have an underlying fear of the youth, based on a perception of them as radical and lacking in restraint. Government and political party leadership have a fear of recognizing the youth as equal partners in policy making. In their opinion, this has resulted in government and political party leadership employing subtle mechanisms to constrain the youth from reaching beyond certain limits in mobilizing and presenting a youth position. They perceive an underlying fear that youth wings could break away from their mother party if allowed the space for policy discourse and influence. The youth therefore consider themselves to be held in check and stifled from expressing and pushing their opinions forward. They are however of the opinion that radical behaviors are in themselves a symptom of suppression and marginalization. It is important, in their view, that the youth are recognized as a marginalized group. The way to dissipate radical, unrestrained behaviors on their part is to offer avenues for their opinions to be expressed and addressed. ii. Antagonism between the Youth and Political leadership: The result of the above phenomenon is an underlying sense of antagonism between the youth and the leadership in government and political parties. This also affects the ability for constructive policy dialogue to transpire between them. It is inferred from the above that political party leadership may not, at present, experience the input of the youth as constructive, underlain as it is by antagonism on the part of the youth and fear and suspicion on their part as leaders. iii. Political polarization and divisions in the youth front: A factor of equal importance as the one above is the absence of a united youth front. The youth consider their front to be divided along political party lines and loyalties. They are therefore unable to present a united front. The youth have been affected by what they perceive as a developing political culture where self-interest, rather than national interest, drives the motivation of political actors. The youth are therefore unable to form a united front at community levels, within tertiary youth organizations/networks and as youth wings of political parties. iv. Apathy in the youth: The majority of the youth are in school and unaware or disinterested in policy issues affecting them. Their focus is narrowly focused on their grades. The social and educational culture within which they are located also does not encourage the challenging of authority or interjections into &#x201C;adult conversations&#x201D;. v. Absence of spaces for youth participation in policy dialogue: The youth hold the opinion that the space for their participation in policy dialogue does not exist. While platforms exist in principle, in practice, they are inaccessible to the majority of the youth. vi. Low capacity for policy analysis: Low capacity for policy analysis also affects their effectiveness in policy processes, confining their input to very basic levels of infrastructure provision.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased trust in the political process by different groups and citizens, including % of Latino and Afro barometer responds</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="41" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data 41% Qualitative description The most recently available 2013-14 Afrobarometer measured public trust of respondents in the ruling party and in opposition parties separately. Combining these responses and collapsing the categories of &#x201C;somewhat&#x201D; and &#x201D;a lot&#x201D;, we see that there is considerable trust in political parties in Ghana. This trust is somewhat higher in opposition parties (45%) than in the governing party (36%).</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of collective policy statements made publicly by political and civil society leaders</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data (0) No collective policy statements have been made together by political and civil society leaders (political leadership and youth leaders) Qualitative description As indicated earlier, the youth consider their front to be divided along political party lines and loyalties. They are therefore unable to present a united front. The youth have been affected by what they perceive as a developing political culture where self-interest, rather than national interest, drives the motivation of political actors. The youth are therefore unable to form a united front at community levels, within tertiary youth organizations/networks and as youth wings of political parties. 64% of the respondents said they had made some form of public statement representing the position of the youth, as against 36% who have not done so. The table below represents number of public statements they had made that represented the position of the youth. 36% said they had made up to 5 such public statements, 8% said they had made 6 to 10 public statements and 20% said they had made over 10 statements. Six respondents (24%) said they had made these statements as leaders/members of a youth organization; 2 respondents (8%) said they had made those statements as leaders of a youth network; 14 respondents (56%) did not respond to the question; and 3 respondents (12%) responded as other. In the focus group discussion, the youth indicated that they have not made any public policy statements that represent the collective position of identifiable sections of the youth as far as they can recall nor have they made any public statements together with other political actors. Public statements made by the youth have been limited to threats by irate youth at the community level, regarding issues such as political appointments and infrastructure in their communities.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that collaborate with other civic actors at least x times per year</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that they collaborate with civic actors at least 1 time per month</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="8" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data 8% of respondents indicated that there was interaction between political actors and youth leaders at least once a month. 60% of respondents indicated that there was interaction but on an ad hoc and infrequent basis. Qualitative description Frequency of Interaction with Policy makers There seems to be minimal to non-existent formal interaction between policy makers and civil society currently. Engagements of policy makers with the public are broad and not youth-centered. Policy makers therefore do not necessarily hear youth voices through these interactions. Although the youth are free to approach parliament with their input, they do not consider parliament accessible to them. Informal interaction between some Ministers of State and youth representatives transpires on social media. Much more regular interaction occurs at the community level between assembly men/women and youth. Youth in local communities participate actively in radio phone-in programs, where local authorities are called in to answer questions of importance to local people. The local authorities directly engage with the youth on these platforms. Youth in the northern parts of the country have a practice of gathering together in the evenings in what they refer to as the &#x201C;ghetoses&#x201D; and &#x201C;base&#x201D; to fraternize with each other. In these spaces, they regularly discuss community development issues, which will sometimes result in them calling on duty bearers and politicians to act on their concerns. These platforms have proven very effective in getting local authorities to act regarding the provision of services. These interactions are however ad hoc and unstructured. Action by political actors in response to youth demands is dependent on the influence of the said duty bearer or politician at the national level.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partners (based on adapted 5 Core Capabilities of NIMD&apos;s scan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partners increased their scores on NIMD&apos;s organizational scan (BART), which is based on the 5 C model</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="4.3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data Results Max C1 Commit and Act 4,1 5 C2 Deliver Results 4,3 5 C3 Adapt and Self-Renew 4,3 5 C4 Attract and Relate 4,6 5 C5 Balance coherence and diversity 4,5 5 Results Max C1 Strategic planning 3,5 5 Leadership 4,4 5 Healthy financial position 4,3 5 C2 Human resources 4,0 5 Infrastructure 4,1 5 Efficiency 4,4 5 Effectiveness 4,2 5 Relevance 4,8 5 C3 Understanding Contexts 4,1 5 Flexibility 4,3 5 Adequate PM&amp;E 4,4 5 Encourage learning 4,1 5 Up-to-date communication 4,7 5 C4 Alliances 4,6 5 Legitimacy 4,9 5 Integrity 4,8 5 Accountability 4,2 5 C5 Strategically coherent 4,3 5 Consistency 4,7 5 Balanced Stability 4,9 5 Inclusiveness 4,0 5 Qualitative description The BART scan indicates that the implementing partner in Ghana has the following strengths: Balanced stability: The organisation has a well-established network among political leaders. They have the convening power to organise regular inter-party dialogue meetings that are attended by party chairmen and sec gens. Overall the organisation manages to find common ground between the parties, by successfully navigating the interests of both ruling and opposition political parties. Integrity: Board, leadership and staff of the organisation are accepted by all relevant stakeholders and are generally considered sufficiently impartial. Leadership and staff of the organisation are also considered to be sufficiently knowledgeable and skilled by all relevant stakeholders. The organisation promotes high standards of integrity for political parties. Legitimacy: The organisation is capable of attracting the appropriate level of party representatives to ensure meaningful participation in its inter-party dialogue programme. The organisation is recognised as a knowledgeable partner for building bridges between political parties and other relevant stakeholders like government agencies, democratic institutions and civil society. The organisation is registered under the proper government regulation, applies its statutes and obeys national legislation. Relevance: The organisation is recognised by key democratic institutions and civil society actors as capable to contribute to strengthening democratic culture and systems through its work. The results delivered by the organisation meet the needs of the political parties and other external target groups that are collected through regular needs assessments. It is difficult to identify weaknesses in such a high scoring scan, if anything the following two elements could be indicated: Encourage learning: Overall staff consider the allocation of time for careful review and learning on the basis of PME or exchanges with peer organisations on common challenges and lessons learned no more than adequate. Strategic planning: Key democratic institutions and civic organisations are aware of the strategic plan of the organisation. Even when removing the outliers this element scores on the level of &#x2018;developing implementation&#x2019; this suggest room for improvement. Further, according to the staff the political parties as represented on the board are not well aware of the strategic plan and do not monitor its implementation as well as they could. Accountability: This sections seems to be among the lower scoring, however after further review there is a zero score placed as one staff member had no opinion on this issue, causing the overall score to drop. If this zero score is removed accountability is placed among the higher scores.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
