<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-BUR18</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burundi programme 2018</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Political update 2018 More than two years after the political crisis erupted in the run-up to the 2015 elections, there is no comprehensive and sustainable solution to the conflict in sight. The EAC-led dialogue on Burundi, facilitated by former Tanzanian President Mkapa has not yet succeeded in bringing the key protagonists around one table to negotiate on the key issues. Parallel to this process, the Government of Burundi and in particular the Ombudsman have started new initiatives for political dialogue with opposition in Burundi, offering opportunities for a breakthrough. Nonetheless, the government of Burundi is simultaneously exploring the possibility of constitutional reform enabling President Nkurunziza to run for a fourth term. 

The political landscape continues to be characterized by decreasing political space, polarization, exclusion of political opponents and marginalized groups from politics and decision-making and low-intensity political violence. Most political actors have moved from contestation around the 2015 elections to preparation for the next elections, scheduled for 2020. Anticipating these elections, major areas of concern are the regulatory environment for (opposition) political parties and the legitimacy and capacities of political parties. Additionally, in this context of limited political space, promising openings for working on democratic culture are to be found at the local level.

&#x2022; Outlook for 2018
The challenges Burundi is facing are huge and many fall outside NIMD&#x2019;s sphere of influence. Still, experiences in the past two years have shown that NIMD is in a position to contribute to some of these issues. A key systemic obstacle for peaceful politics is the closed regulatory environment for (opposition) political parties. Investing in a revision of political party legislation and its application is one of the preconditions for a fruitful dialogue process and for the end of the political crisis. The different ongoing dialogue processes need to address this in order to yield sustainable results. NIMD contributes to this by stimulating a bottom-up agenda on this issue from the parties through discussion and dialogue, fed by analyses. Together with an investment in the capacities of political parties as legitimate and capable conversation partners for both the Burundian government and for the international community, we aim to get this topic on the agenda of ongoing dialogue processes. 

Credible and legitimate political actors remain invaluable for long-term democratic development in Burundi. The focus in 2018 will be on supporting the organizational development and vision formulation of political parties through strategic planning. Exploiting political space on the local level, activities that link former and current students of democracy schools with local branches of political parties strengthen the space for democratic diversity and democratic behaviour. Lastly, actions plans for improved participation of women formulated by female representatives in 2017 will be followed up with activities that engage political party leaderships on the need for and benefits of increased participation of women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">238572</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burundi budget 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-03-16">101628</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Burundi March 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-13">52893</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Burundi September 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-09-13">56176</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Burundi September 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS18" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved organisational capacity of political actors in fragile settings to effectively and legitimately participate in political (dialogue) processes.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In general, the difference between different parties&#x2019; organizational capacity is quite large. There is a stark difference between the governing party, which has a functional structure, and the opposition parties, that attempt to operate while facing persecution and sometimes exist only because of infighting in the parties they originated from. A characterization of the parties grouped by allegiance to either the government or the opposition is provided below, indicating the difference that the current landscape means: The ruling party (CNDD-FDD), is focused on consolidating its bases for the continuous mobilization of members around activities for security building and local development (local infrastructure, building party headquarters, etc.); Two parties which have been integrated into the institutions of the Republic (UPRONA, FNL Bigirimana) face a very uncertain future because despite their legal status and seats in parliament their political identity is questioned. These parties exist in their current form after a split has occurred and leaders of their parties still lead independent political groups (Agathon Rwasa for the FNL and Charles Niditije for UPRONA). It remains questionable to what extent these parties will be able to to reorganize and reconstruct their bases in anticipation of uncertain future elections. Nditije&#x2019;s and Rwasa&#x2019;s political group formed a joint list of independents and despite them formally boycotting the elections they won seats in the national assembly. Rwasa and its members decided to take their seats, despite their boycott. Rwasa became the 1st Vice President of the national assembly and several members of Rwasa&#x2019;s group have been appointed as ministers in Cabinet. Despite Rwasa&#x2019;s shown effective leadership control over much of the old FNL structures and popularity his group formally is not a political party and this therefore poses significant challenges for consolidation and sustaining his political organization. Still the choice of UPRONA, FNL and Group Rwasa to enter institutions opens up some space of freedom and action they are all trying to take advantage of to find, in their own way, their respective bases to revive them and even lay the foundation for expansion; For the opposition parties united against the third term of President Nkurunziza, which have boycotted the elections and did not win seats in the assembly the focus is on survival. They exist despite the risks and the security constraints exercised by the Government. The functioning of the bodies of these parties is affected by this constraint. The meetings still held have no agenda turned to reconstruction and redevelopment objectives. In light of this report, the actors of these parties residing in the country operate in semi-clandestine fashion. Their leaders are largely abroad in exile. A key group of leaders have formed an opposition alliance called CNARED. This alliance includes a group of former CNDD-FDD politicians who initially protested against Nkurunziza&#x2019;s third term (les frondeurs) and have since established their own political party (PPD). For obvious reasons this group has no legal status in the country. Another opposition party that initially participated in CNARED but since has decided to take an independent stance is UPD. This party&#x2019;s leadership also consist of a group of former CNDD-FDD politicians that were expelled from the party in an internal conflict in 2008.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of key political parties that are recognized to have a distinctive party profile within the party landscape</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the context of Burundi, this indicator is operationalized as political parties with a political programme written and publicly available before the elections. In part because of NIMD&#x2019;s effort to support political parties in the development of a political programme, a large # of political parties developed a political programme in the course of NIMD&#x2019;s trainings: out of 13 parties, 11 developed a programme. Only 11 of these 13 belonged to the key political parties at the time. Out of these 11, only 2 (CNDD and UPRONA) did not have a programme publicly available before the 2015 elections. However, most political parties did not use the programmes actively in the campaign running up to the 2015 elections. This is an important qualification, that needs to be monitored for the mid and end term measurements.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="82" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs included in NIMD supported activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of CSOs included in NIMD supported activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of agreements reached as a result of dialogue / platform meetings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of agreements reached as a result of dialogue / platform meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of proposals submitted to the parliament</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of proposals submitted to the parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and legitimate political processes in fragile settings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inclusive and legitimate political processes in fragile settings</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported dialogue initiatives</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported dialogue initiatives</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported interparty dialogue meetings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported interparty dialogue meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties participating in dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties participating in dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties trained</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political parties trained</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="10"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOTAL # of people included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOTAL # of people included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1154"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported multi-stakeholder dialogue meetings</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of ongoing NIMD supported multi-stakeholder dialogue meetings</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="13"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates of democracy schools</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates of democracy schools</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="210"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women and youth who participate in NIMD supported training activities for political participation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women and youth who participate in NIMD supported training activities for political participation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="243"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of multi-actor meetings held regarding the need for a more open and inclusive political system</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of multi-actor meetings held regarding the need for a more open and inclusive political system</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="29"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># multi-party encounters organised by NIMD</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># multi-party encounters organised by NIMD</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of participants (men / women / youth) from political parties in capacity-building activities for participation in political dialogue processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of participants (men / women / youth) from political parties in capacity-building activities for participation in political dialogue processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="307"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="36"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of women included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="420"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% Progress on the implementation of capacity development plans</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% Progress on the implementation of capacity development plans</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="75"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of workshops and events organized or supported by NIMD to promote the inclusion of youth and minority groups within political parties</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of workshops and events organized or supported by NIMD to promote the inclusion of youth and minority groups within political parties</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="8"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% participation by key stakeholder representatives in NIMD supported dialogue initiatives</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% participation by key stakeholder representatives in NIMD supported dialogue initiatives</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="87"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Political parties (actors) that are actively engaged in Strategic Planning activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of Political parties (actors) that are actively engaged in Strategic Planning activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="9"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="na"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of youth (&lt; 25 years) included in NIMD (supported) activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="na"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">score 5C organisational capacity scan</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">score 5C organisational capacity scan</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2.01" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2.53">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Score of trust in the political leadership of rival parties by different political parties</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Score of trust in the political leadership of rival parties by different political parties</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.49" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2.95">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mid-term result</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
