<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-GEO16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia Programme Since 2010, all of NIMD&#x2019;s instruments are used equally in the Georgia programme: facilitating dialogue, strengthening the capacity of the parties and stimulating democratic behaviour. NIMD has supported politicians from different parties to work together by helping them to set up issues oriented multiparty dialogue platforms in Parliament, such as on gender or national minorities. NIMD helps the parties to build their capacity to function effectively by helping them to develop strategic plans and giving them training. NIMD also works on democracy education with democracy schools in 4 different regions, focusing particularly on developing the abilities of political parties, people working for civil society organizations, and local governments to lobby about issues that need addressing.    Programme deviations/ToC update: &#x2022; It is notable that external factors, namely the political developments in the country also influenced cooperation with political parties. Firstly, the ruling coalition - Georgian Dream fall apart, secondly, United National Movement (UNM) started to boycott the parliamentary sessions after the incident in Kortskheli (May 22, 2016), when supporters of government party physically assaulted the opposition leaders and lastly, after elections UNM party split into groups. It is also worth mentioning that only three parties (GD, UNM, AoP) were able to overcome the five percent threshold, leaving both liberal parties (FDs and Republicans) out of the parliament.

&#x2022; Explain if the ToC is still valid, or whether there is a need to adapt the ToC and/or the strategy for capacity building based on unforeseen developments
There are only three parties left in parliament, in part because of the threshold. The current ruling party has a supermayority and the ability the change the constitution by itself. The pro-western liberal parties, which always had a strong relationship both with NIMD as well as directly with Dutch political parties (VVD, D66), have failed to overcome the threshold. This does not seem to be a healthy democratic situation, as there is virtually only 1 opposition party left. Therefore, NIMD will focus more on a more pluralistic political arena and the capacity building of opposition parties in 2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD Eastern European Neighbourhood</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Embassy in Tbilisi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OSCE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">214430</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-30">75000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Georgia March 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-19">48133</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Georgia May 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-06">445</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Georgia October 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-23">61938</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Georgia September 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-28">214430</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Georgia budget 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">3299</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">45000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors that voice and monitor citizens&#x2019; interests</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Given the upcoming Parliamentary Elections on the 8th of October 2016, political actors have put some effort into addressing the concerns of the citizens. At the same time, their responses have largely remained too general and their political campaign was still focused on personalities rather than political programs; most of them have not yet presented electoral platforms, and so far, quite a few of them concentrated on issues that are at the very bottom of the public agenda. At the same time, it seems that the citizens have been paying closer attention to political manifestos than during the previous electoral campaigns. Still, according to the recent polls, the citizens remain very skeptical about political actors in general.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published documents (manifestos, election programs, position papers, policy proposals, etc.) developed on an inclusive basis</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="15" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In August 2016, more than half of the 10 political parties that had won seats in previous local and/or parliamentary elections did not yet present electoral programs with elections less than two months away. However, they did produce a total of 30 political documents and video missives. From the total of these 30 available documents, 15 demonstrated inclusiveness regarding the youth issues and gender equality. Practically none of them addressed meaningfully ethnic minority issues.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The nature of relations between political actors and civic actors remains problematic in Georgia. The civic actors are deemed to be fairly important by all political actors. At the same time, the proclivity of the incumbent to influence the agenda of the civic actors remains unchanged. The political actors that are in opposition are in general supportive of the civil society representatives. Still it seems that these attitudes may change if the political actor now in opposition takes power. At the very least, that is demonstrated by the contrasting attitudes that the former incumbent demonstrated towards the civic actors while in government and now in opposition. Some political actors, however, do view most important civic actors with suspicion and distrust. Still the civic actors are considered very important by all political forces.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political actors who indicate that they collaborate with other civic actors at least 5 times a year</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="8" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative description: in the first half of 2016 8 political parties participated in at least 3 events that involved engagement with the civic actors. The records of these meetings were provided by NIMD office in Tbilisi.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A more conductive environment for inclusive participation of women( and political processes and policymaking includes the voice of women and minority groups, and gender equality agenda receives wider support in and out of parliament)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies proposed by political parties that reflect national minority needs and interests</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="8" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2016, 8 major political parties including the ruling party have agreed to foster ethnic minority participation in political life by creating action plans with the support of NIMD (1 for each party).</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field for all political actors and civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of structural changes opening up space for greater engagement by political and civic actors, including # of structural changes and new mechanisms for greater engagement by political and civic actors + # of laws and mechanisms ensuring safe engagement between political and civic actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the first half of the 2016, 3 new mechanisms of engagement between political and civic actors were implemented with the support of NIMD. The first mechanism engaged 8 political parties to formulate ethnic minority inclusion action plans. The second mechanism instituted an internship program for ethnic minority representatives within 5 political parties. The third mechanism instituted a dialogue between political parties and local civic actors using NIMD Schools of Democracy as a platform. In the framework of these initiatives a total of 27 events were organized by NIMD where 8 political parties met with various civic actors and discussed wide variety of key issues. The thematic content of the discussions ranged from ethnic minority inclusion to economic growth, unemployment, democratic development, poverty reduction, healthcare, and environmental issues among others.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased trust in the political process by different groups and citizens, including % of Latino and Afro barometer responds</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="41.4" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 41,4 % To determine the level of trust in the political process we have chosen to examine public trust in Government, Political Parties, and Media as expressed by approval ratings in %. Additionally, we considered citizen trust in democratic development and in democracy as a form of government expressed in % of population positively assessing each indicator. In order to measure change, we have chosen to take the average (percentage) of the 5 indicators listed below. In 2016, the average score is 41,4%. Government &#x2013; 32% Political Parties &#x2013; 16% Media &#x2013; 76% Democratic Development &#x2013; 36% Democracy &#x2013; 47% Qualitative description: We have used the results of the surveys and polls conducted by the well-established national and international organizations as well as the data provided by the Central Electoral Commission of Georgia. The National Democratic Institute (NDI), the International Republican Institute (IRI), and the Caucasus Research Resource Center (CRRC) were chosen because of their long established credentials in the area and the high probability that they will be conducting the same or similar surveys in the coming years that will make the future assessment of developments possible. We arrived at Trust in Government score by averaging the combined score of public trust in executive, legislative, judicial and local branches of government. The scores for Media and political parties were readily available. As for the score for Democratic Development we averaged the citizen perception of improvement regarding the freedom of speech, human rights, rule of law, democratic governance and willingness to vote in the next election. The democracy score was based upon the public attitude towards democracy as the best form of government that was readily available from the survey we used.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partner</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partners increased their scores on NIMD&apos;s organizational scan (BART), which is based on the 5 C model</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="4.5" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">This score is an average of the scores on the 5 capabilities that are listed in the table below. In July and August 2016, an organizational scan based on the 5C model was conducted to assess NIMD EEN&#x2019;s capacity. In an anonymous survey with 11 staff members, the implementing partner scored an average of 4,5 out of 5. With all capabilities being well above average, NIMD EEN is a capable partner to implement the programme effectively.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates from democracy and political education schools (disaggregate sex, age, social group etc)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates from democracy and political education schools (disaggregate sex, age, social group etc)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="34">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">13 male and 21 female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="138"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
