<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-UGA16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UGANDA&#x2019;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND In 1986, Yoweri Museveni became president. Under his reign, an end was put to a violent period of political instability and the economy slowly improved. Museveni also introduced a new political system, whereby political parties were not allowed and politicians were elected on personal merit, not party affiliation. In 2005, the majority of Ugandans voted in a referendum for re-introducing multiparty politics. This was followed in 2006 by the first multiparty elections in twenty years. Despite this, Uganda is de facto a one-party state and still has a polarized political system. Opposition parties only have a limited ability to influence the political reform agenda. So the country&#x2019;s political system remains very fragile and political parties themselves face several challenges. For example, the parties largely rely on the appeal of their leaders rather than policies, face internal divisions, lack accountability and internal democracy and are not strongly organized. As Uganda nears the run-up to the 2016 general elections, concerns heighten over shrinking space for legitimate political activities. For example, the Public Order Management Act, which was introduced at the end of 2013, places restrictions on public meetings. One consequence is that opposition parties find it increasingly challenging to organize rallies. The much needed constitutional and electoral reforms are also not coming off the ground, despite a large public outcry and concerted efforts by a plethora of stakeholders including political parties for reforms. THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN UGANDA NIMD&#x2019;s overall objective in Uganda is to help foster a well-functioning, strong and vibrant multiparty democracy. We do this by focusing both on facilitating an inclusive political dialogue between the parties and helping the parties to develop into mature organizations with a sound organizational structure and a distinctive programmatic identity. In 2010, the six parliamentary parties, with NIMD&#x2019;s support, established an informal interparty dialogue process (IPOD). Establishing this marked a turning point in multiparty politics in Uganda as both the ruling party and opposition committed to regularly engaging with each other in a dialogue process aimed at addressing challenges facing Uganda. This process is facilitated on behalf of the six parties by NIMD-Uganda, a registered organization in the capital Kampala. Party Capacity Strengthening In 2014, NIMD also established the Political Party Capacity Strengthening Facility (PPCSF) in Uganda for member parties of IPOD. In NIMD&#x2019;s experience, ruling parties are more willing to engage with opposition political parties who act programmatically and have a clear constituency. This also allows them to play &#x2018;more on the ball and less on the adversary&#x2019;. Through strengthening the capacity and internal democracy of Ugandan political parties, the PPCSF facilitates Ugandan political parties to become more effective players in Uganda&#x2019;s multiparty system. For example, Project Implementation Committees have been set up by some political parties to define the strategic priorities for the party. It is run by a Project Management Unit located at NIMD&#x2019;s Uganda office. Outlook As tensions rise ahead of 2016 elections, the NIMD programme in Uganda focuses its efforts at three levels: Keep the interparty dialogue process going and to secure agreement on electoral reforms and build alliances and support for these in the wider stakeholder community; Prepare the parties for the 2016 elections and beyond by strengthening their organizational and programmatic capacities; Contribute to the peaceful conduct of the 2016 elections by investing in de-escalating mechanisms that enable looming political tensions to be spotted early on and provide an informal platform in which political parties can let off steam.   Programme deviations/ToC update: The 2016 elections ended with two developments that have implications on the operations of IPOD and implementation of the SP. First the composition of parliament changed from six political parties initially to four. This implies that IPOD membership reduced from six to four parties. In terms of programmatic delivery however, there are no implications foreseen to emerge from the changes in parliamentary composition.

Secondly, contestations over the conduct and outcome of the elections continue to exist among the ruling and opposition parties. On the one hand this has perforated embryonic trust and relationships among political actors. On the other hand, the state has tightened restrictions on political activity in the public sphere given a high proclivity of politically motivated violence. These conditions have undesirably affected commitment to interparty dialogue whilst impacting negatively on the enabling environment.

Third, existing fractures within the main opposition party&#x2014;the FDC&#x2014;affects the ability of its leaders to seamlessly engage in IPOD processes. In 2016, the party withdrew from the platform for a two months period. These differences also extend to relations between the FDC and other opposition parties

The ToC nevertheless remains valid given that it was developed on analysis of related conditions. Implementation of the SP is, however, starting with rebuilding bridges among political actors who have come to be increasingly sceptical of each other.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic Governance Facility</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD Uganda</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">419567</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-03-09">60000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Uganda March 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">7480</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-28">419567</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda budget 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">45000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partners (based on adapted 5 Core Capabilities of NIMD&apos;s scan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partners increased their scores on NIMD&apos;s organizational scan (BART), which is based on the 5 C model</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Baseline description: An organizational scan of IPOD was conducted in June 2015. The assessment was done based on the five capabilities. These were Capacity to: commit and act; deliver results; adapt and self-renew; attract and relate; and balance coherence and diversity. NIMD Uganda showed a relative balance in scores for each of the 5 capabilities. It was noted that the organisation was stronger in the capabilities on external relations. The assessment further revealed the need for clarity on the identity of the organisation and to develop a mechanism for internal learning.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Formulation of, proposing to, and approval of jointly formulated policies in parliament securing civil and political rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of (inclusive) policies jointly formulated and submitted to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties (taking part in the dialogue platforms)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="43" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative data: IPOD presented to the legal and parliamentary affairs committee joint positions on electoral and constitutional amendment bills. It included 43 proposals for political and electoral reforms. There were also some unsuccessful efforts to present joint position to the committee of defense and internal affairs on the NGO bill. Qualitative description: Outside the informal arrangements of political parties, there was yet another attempt in 9th Parliament by a coalition of MPs and CSOs to sponsor Private Member&#x2019;s Bills. The coalition of MPs was composed of NRM, Opposition and independent MPs. Efforts of this coalition were unsuccessful because NRM MPs silently withdrew from the activity due to pressure from the party. The failure by IPOD to present joint positions to Parliament led the passage of clauses in the bills, especially the NGO bill that are unfavorable to operations of CSOs and unleveled the playing field for political parties. Quantitative description: The composition of committees in Parliament follows strict gender sensitive criteria of including a mandatory 1/3 (one third) of women committee members. In 9th Parliament the minimum # of women MPs on every committee was 6/20 (six out of twenty) MPs. 1/3 (One third) of the entire committee leadership of session committees was women. The Speaker rejected any proposals for composition of committees that violated this criterion.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased trust in the political process by different groups and citizens, including % of Latino and Afro barometer responds</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="50" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative Data: 50% Qualitative description: There are generally low trust levels in the political processes in Uganda. The most recently available 2013-14 Afrobarometer measured public trust of respondents in the ruling party and in opposition parties separately. Combining these responses and collapsing the categories of &#x201C;somewhat&#x201D; and &#x201D;a lot&#x201D;, we see that there is trust in political parties in Uganda. This trust is considerably lower in opposition parties (30%) than in the governing party (71%). According to other Afrobarometer data only 39 percent of Ugandans are &#x201C;fairly satisfied&#x201D; with the way democracy works in the country. In the interviews, political actors expressed that the ruling party and its leader have the ability to and often have exercised undue influence on political processes. The president, who is leader of the ruling party, appoints members the Election Management Body (EMB). Thus, several actors especially those on the opposition side consider the EMB as partisan. The leading opposition party has also repeatedly expressed mistrust in other organs of political arbitration including the courts. This was advanced as a key reason why they did not seek to challenge the results of the 2016 presidential election in the Supreme Court, as provided by the Constitution. Mistrust is also reflected in the very modest hopes for impactful political dialogue. A previous unsuccessful quest for political reforms which had been agreed upon between the ruling party and the opposition (with the support of civil society) breeds scepticism over the commitment to dialogue positions by the ruling party.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that experience an enabling environment in which they are involved in inclusive policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 100 percent of opposition political actors interviewed indicated the political environment does not enable them to influence policy making. This figure is contrasted by political actors from the ruling party who find the environment enabling. Therefore baseline = 0 Qualitative description: Parliament remains a key institution for influencing policy given its legislative power. The possibility to table private members&#x2019; bills is a policy window through which political parties can present law and policy proposals. Civil society actors can also cooperate with members of parliament to sponsor policy proposals under this window. There are, however, limitations: First, with less than 15 percent of the seats in parliament, opposition parties require the buy-in of the ruling party to pass laws. Second, official procedure requires sponsors of parliamentary bills to first obtain a certificate of financial implications. The required certificate is given by the ministry of finance thereby providing the executive with a strong leverage over what makes it to the parliamentary agenda. During interviews and focus group discussions, political party representatives indicated that the possibility to influence law and policy making is limited to topics that are &#x201C;not politically contentious&#x201D; or where (sic) &#x201C;the ruling party has no embedded interest.&#x201D; Outside parliament, the political parties especially those in opposition do not enjoy a conducive space to engage in policy debates due to challenges with access to vital information and capacity of the political parties to conduct research.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are more aware of and have internalised democratic values, rule of law and gender sensitive &amp; inclusive politics.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that reference the following topics in their manifesto/public statements, other publications - democratic values and/or rule of law and/or gender sensitive &amp; inclusive politics</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 100 percent of political party manifestos include proposals for promoting democracy, rule of law and gender equality. Qualitative description: Political actors compete to demonstrate their commitment to democracy, rule of law and gender equality as reflected in their manifestos and policy documents. However, translating these policy pronouncements into action remains a challenge and raises questions on commitment.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors that voice and monitor citizen interests</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents (manifestos, election programmes, position papers, policy proposal) by political actors based on inputs from a defined support base (on improving gender equality and/or on inclusion</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="11" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: During the time of the 2016 elections a total four political parties (CP, FDC, NRM and UPC) under the IPOD framework each developed a manifesto document. The two parties (DP &amp; JEEMA) did not publish individual election manifestos as they had joined election alliances and therefore subscribed to group manifestos. Nevertheless they were able to develop specific position papers on topics such as agriculture, education, and employment. DP developed three papers while JEEMA had eight. Qualitative description: In the last legislative period, there is evidence that political parties involved women and youth as well as workers and PWD groups to feed into their policy and election manifesto development processes. NRM and FDC, for example, had extracts of the voice of the women in their respective manifestos.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe (and institutionalized) space for dialogue between all relevant political (and civic) actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Level of representation at the dialogue platform</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: There is one interparty dialogue platform&#x2014;the Interparty Organisation for Dialogue (IPOD). Its membership includes the four political parties represented in the current (10th) parliament namely: Democratic Party (DP), Forum for Democratic Change (FDC), National Resistance Movement (NRM) and Uganda People&#x2019;s Congress (UPC). Business in IPOD is steered by a Council of Secretary Generals (SGs), where each of the member parties has three representatives including the SGs. In the previous legislature period, the IPOD Council held meetings once every month. Representation in IPOD processes can be ranked on a scale of 1 &#x2013; 4, where: 4 = representation by party presidents and chairpersons 3 &#x2013; representation by secretary generals 2 &#x2013; representation by party official with mandate of SGs 1 &#x2013; representation by party officials In view of the above scale, the current level of representation lies between 2 and 3. All parties have representatives mandated by the SGs while some of the parties have their SGs participating regularly in IPOD council discussions. Qualitative description: IPOD is growing as a preferred space for dialogue among the political parties. However, it faces commitment issues and low trust levels among political actors. The IPOD Council of SGs is functional but the Summit of Party Presidents has not met. There are concerns about the effectiveness of party representatives on the IPOD council: some do not have the necessary mandate to commit their political parties during IPOD negotiations. Furthermore, the inclusion of civil society and special groups in IPOD business is still weak, although sub committees have been set-up to engender this.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of dialogue platforms in place</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is an operational Interparty Dialogue Platform (IPOD), which was founded in 2010. All the four parliamentary political parties subscribe to IPOD. In the past legislature period, IPOD had an agreed agenda aligned to the critical concerns such as the pursuit of a level playing field through proposing electoral reforms and negotiating modalities for political party financing. Whenever need arose, key relevant civic actors provided expert input to IPOD work. During the period, the IPOD membership also commenced discussions regarding institutionalisation of the platform, which are still ongoing.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is one interparty dialogue platform&#x2014;the Interparty Organisation for Dialogue (IPOD). Its membership includes the four political parties represented in the current (10th) parliament namely: Democratic Party (DP), Forum for Democratic Change (FDC), National Resistance Movement (NRM) and Uganda People&#x2019;s Congress (UPC). Business in IPOD is steered by a Council of Secretary Generals (SGs), where each of the member parties has three representatives including the SGs. In the previous legislature period, the IPOD Council held meetings once every month. Representation in IPOD processes can be ranked on a scale of 1 &#x2013; 4, where: 4 = representation by party presidents and chairpersons 3 &#x2013; representation by secretary generals 2 &#x2013; representation by party official with mandate of SGs 1 &#x2013; representation by party officials In view of the above scale, the current level of representation lies between 2 and 3. All parties have representatives mandated by the SGs while some of the parties have their SGs participating regularly in IPOD council discussions. Qualitative description: IPOD is growing as a preferred space for dialogue among the political parties. However, it faces commitment issues and low trust levels among political actors. The IPOD Council of SGs is functional but the Summit of Party Presidents has not met. There are concerns about the effectiveness of party representatives on the IPOD council: some do not have the necessary mandate to commit their political parties during IPOD negotiations. Furthermore, the inclusion of civil society and special groups in IPOD business is still weak, although sub committees have been set-up to engender this.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional multi-stakeholder platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional multi-stakeholder platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Platform for women and youth groups: 27 participants who included representatives of political party youth and women leagues as well as women and youth civic actors, focussing on the involvement of marginalised groups (particularly women and youth) in policy making processes and particularly internal party processes) 2) IPOD Caf&#xE9;: 4 political parties and citizens</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPOD is the interparty organization for dialogue in Uganda. In 2016 it represented 4 political parties at a national level. 4 out of the 11 IPOD council members are women. The interparty dialogue in 2016 mainly focused on political and electoral reforms and the functioning of political parties.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of consultation meetings/ # of events organized to consult civil and political actors on democratic practice</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of consultation meetings/ # of events organized to consult civil and political actors on democratic practice</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies and proposed amendments jointly formulated for submission to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties taking part in the dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies and proposed amendments jointly formulated for submission to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties taking part in the dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of events to consult citizens on their concerns</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of events to consult citizens on their concerns</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of civic actors consulted on policy issues</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of civic actors consulted on policy issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="5"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
