<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-KEN16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KENYA&#x2019;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND Kenya has a multi-party system in place since 1992, and has seen a steady economic development into a regional power. However, the existing patchwork of ethnic groups has become over the years a significant political issue, hindering democratic progress and creating domestic tensions. The low point of this setting showed in 2008, when after years of stability and economic growth, the world was shocked to witness the unexpected and severe intercommunal violence in the aftermath of the general elections. Over 1,100 people were killed and more than 500,000 were displaced, severely staining Kenya&#x2019;s democratic and peaceful reputation. This traumatic period highlighted that Kenya&#x2019;s ethnic politics from the past was still very much alive, but it also influenced the then-ongoing debate on the need for constitutional reform and overhaul of the governance system. Eventually, in 2010 a new constitution was written and promulgated through a national referendum. It was hailed as a progressive and democratic benchmark that also serves as guarantor of a broad set of human rights. Moreover, it entailed a completely new governance system by establishing 47 new county governments under a system of devolved government, with a two-tier structure in the legislature (adding a Senate) and division of functions and services between national and county level. The 2013 general elections were a first test of this new system and resulted in a win for the Jubilee alliance and their presidential candidate Uhuru Kenyatta from the Kikuyu dominated TNA party, with William Ruto from the Kalenjin led URP party as Deputy President. The opposition block CORD alliance mainly represents Luo, Luhya and Kamba communities, causing the current political landscape to be very polarized and &#x2018;ethnicized&#x2019; THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN KENYA NIMD has been active in Kenya since 2003, when we assisted the setting-up of the Centre for Multiparty Democracy (CMD) as dialogue platform for all parliamentary parties. Since then, the NIMD programme has supported CMD-Kenya to host the interparty dialogue and to implement activities geared at supporting political parties and to strengthen their interrelation with broader society. By bringing parties together to find a common position, a joint solution can be advocated and lobbied for to ensure policy is changed. The recently set-up Leadership Institute contributes to changing perspectives and mind sets of the political class. Another important programme focus is strengthening the role of women and underrepresented groups in political life. Better functioning parties Although the new constitution guarantees certain human and political rights, a lot of changes still needed to be reflected in national legislation. The programme has worked with parties to comply with the new requirements in the Political Parties Act and the provisions in the constitution, and has collaborated with the Office of the Registrar for Political Parties to strengthen the party landscape by facilitating the development of party strategic plans. Leadership Training The NIMD programme has supported the establishment of the CMD Institute of Leadership and Governance that targets politicians and party cadre to build their knowledge and skills. There is no academic requirement to become a politician, but leadership and democratic values are essential for good functioning politics and governance. By training batches of (aspiring) politicians since January 2015, the Leadership Institute has ambitions to become a regional centre for learning as well. Read more&#x2026; Women and youth The programme in Kenya has a long history of supporting the political rights of women, and especially in the run-up to elections where women candidates were supported and their agents trained. Since 2014 the Respect for Women&#x2019;s Political Rights programme is implemented in Kenya, with the specific aim of changing perceptions and negative gender stereotyping around the issue of women political leadership. One of the key approaches in this is actually to find supportive men that act as theme ambassadors who can convince their fellow party members of the importance of removing gender barriers in Kenyan politics. AFFIRMATIVE ACTION IN PRACTICE IN KENYA In 2003, NIMD set up the Centre for Multiparty Democracy in Kenya (CMD Kenya) to implement its programme. CMD Kenya is a political party dialogue platform. Its activities range from advocacy to facilitating dialogue and offering direct support to the political parties who are a member. One of the key themes within the platform is the role of women in Kenyan politics. The CMD platform has initiated several proposals to reduce formal barriers for women. The most notable process was the development of the new Constitution in 2010, where the NIMD programme lobbied for the inclusion of an affirmative action provision for women. The lobby was successful: Kenya&#x2019;s new Constitution includes a strong Bill of Rights, ensures the participation of ethnic minorities, and stipulates that not more than two-thirds of the members of elective or appointive bodies can be of the same gender. The new Constitution was a major victory for the women of Kenya, especially for those aspiring to take up a political role.  Programme deviations/ToC update: The party landscape in Kenya always turns volatile before the elections. New parties are founded and coalitions are formed. This manifested in 2016 in the merger of government coalition Jubilee into one party. The merger was planned by the leadership and it is yet to be seen how the merger will play out in the lower ranks of the parties. Reconciling some of the different interests and the always lingering ethnic tensions between the parties seems to be the biggest challenge ahead for the new party. 

For CMD this meant that because of the merger, there are less member parties. The seats taken up in the Oversight Board and committees by the different parties in the ruling coalition are now reduced to one seat for the newly merged party. This is problematic for the relevance of CMD since it diminishes the power of the ruling party in CMD and leaves room for parties that are less relevant in national politics to influence CMD.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-34106722" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AWEPA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CMD Kenya</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">389516</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-09">46557</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Kenya February 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-21">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Kenya January 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-22">54074</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Kenya July 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-26">56278</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Kenya May 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-06">75616</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Kenya October 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-28">389516</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya budget 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">11244</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">37500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that they collaborate with other political actors at least x times per year</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although interaction and trust among political and between political and civil actors takes place, it is not regular or institutionalized. Actors seek interaction dependent on the issues at hand and that are in their own immediate interest. The relations between the actors are not characterized by trust or a sense of mutual understanding but are opportunistic in seeking coalitions to further their personal gains.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="50" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that they collaborate with other political actors (including government actors) at least weekly = 50% Frequency of MP collaboration with other political actors Incidence as reported by MPs (n=10) Weekly 50% Bi-Weekly - Monthly 25% Quarterly 25% Every 6 months - Once a year - Other - The average frequency of inter-party collaboration over the past one year: 21 times a year, i.e. 0.4 times a week. Quantitative description: It emerged from the study that the level or frequency of interaction between political actors and government/other political parties was determined largely by the burning issue of the day. In light of the prevailing electoral reforms discussions, this topic has dominated the types and topic of interaction/collaboration between political parties and government. Feedback from the political parties indicated that there is a high level of interaction with the frequency of interaction dependent on the thematic issue. This would range from a frequency of daily with the current debate and controversy around electoral reforms to about quarterly for other issues such as internal dispute resolution. It however was noted that the level of interest and interaction for the political actors was largely determined by political economics i.e. will the party gain materially from the interaction and less by the interests of the citizenry.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that collaborate with other civic actors at least x times per year</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although interaction and trust among political and between political and civil actors takes place, it is not regular or institutionalized. Actors seek interaction dependent on the issues at hand and that are in their own immediate interest. The relations between the actors are not characterized by trust or a sense of mutual understanding but are opportunistic in seeking coalitions to further their personal gains.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="25" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 25% Frequency party collaboration with other political actors Incidence as reported by MPs (n=10) Weekly 25% Bi-Weekly 12.5% Monthly 12.5% Quarterly 12.5% Every 6 months - Once a year 25% Other 12.5% The average frequency of party collaboration with civic actors over the past one year: 19 times a year i.e. 0.36 times a week. Qualitative description: Through the inter-party consultative forums organized by CMD as well as other civil society actors, most political parties reported to having regular interactions. Most of the interaction between political parties and CSs was skewed towards interaction with CSs that were in the democratic capacity enhancement space e.g. The National Democratic Institute (NDI), Institute for Education in Democracy (IED), Electoral Institute for Sustainable Democracy in Africa (EISA) among others where as CSs that were focused on governance oversight appeared not to feature in the list of collaborators mentioned.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of law making processes with active CS consultation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="21" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessment of literature from parliament and Kenya Law Reports indicates that there is a fair level of involvement from CSs in various legislative processes. Total # of bills with active CS consultation in 2015 and 2016: 21 out of 65. 6 of these 21 bills with CS consultation have been assented to by the President.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased trust in the political process by different groups and citizens, including % of Latino and Afro barometer responds</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="54" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The most recently available 2013-14 Afrobarometer measured public trust of respondents in the ruling party and in opposition parties separately. Combining these responses and collapsing the categories of &#x201C;somewhat&#x201D; and &#x201D;a lot&#x201D;, we see that there is considerable trust in political parties in Kenya. This trust is considerably lower in opposition parties (46%) than in the governing party (61%).</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors that voice and monitor citizen interests</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents (manifestos, election programmes, position papers, policy proposal) by political actors based on inputs from a defined support base (on improving gender equality and/or on inclusion)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="15" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Discussions with political party leaders revealed that all of them have published documents in one way or the other to guide their operations. Of the 27 CMD member parties surveyed, each had at least 2 policy documents. However, it could with strong probability be established that only 15 of such documents had been arrived at through input from a defined support base. Interviews among select political parties indicated that most political parties have at a minimum one of the following documents with larger political parties have multiple while the smaller parties would have 1 or none.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Formulation of, proposing to, and approval of jointly formulated policies in parliament securing civil and political rights</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of (inclusive) policies jointly formulated and submitted to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties (taking part in the dialogue platforms)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the past one year the political debate has been dominated with reforms around the electoral process and the body in charge of the electoral process. In the last one year, Three bills have been tabled in Parliament that touch on civil and political rights. These are; (i) The Elections Laws (Amendments) (No. 3) Bill 2015 No. 3; (ii) The Constitution of Kenya (Amendment) Bill 2016; (iii) The Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (Amendment) Bill 2016. The three bills were introduced by the Chair of the Justice and Legal Affairs Committee (JLAC) of the National Assembly Hon. Samuel Chepkonga, meaning that they are bills from the JLAC and hence bipartisan. JLAC has members from the following ruling Jubilee coalition parties: the National Alliance (TNA), United Republican Party (URP), and New FORD- Kenya (NFK). JLAC also has representation from the Kenya National Congress (KNC), and Federal Party of Kenya (FPK) which are opposition parties. The principal object of the first Bill was to amend the Elections Act, 2011 and the Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission Act, 2011, in order to address the concerns that resulted following the general election held on 4th March 2013, which was the first under the new constitutional dispensation. Central to the conduct of the elections are the constitutional role and responsibility of the Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission (IEBC), and the Judiciary. However the delivery of the 2013 elections, like many aspects of public administration and management involved interplay of several agencies, both State and non-state actors. It is these aspects that this Bill sought to redress. The principal object of the second amendment bill is to amend various provisions of the Constitution dealing with electoral disputes. It is based on experiential lessons obtained from the challenges previously experienced (particularly the presidential election petition of 2013) in the determination of electoral disputes. This amendment seeks to provide for mechanisms that will facilitate seamless determination of election petitions. Principally the bill seeks to extend the period of hearing a presidential election petition from 14 to 30 days. The principal object of the third bill is to amend the Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission Act (No. 9 of 2011), in order to reorganize the procedure for appointment of chairperson and members of the Commission. The bill seeks to establish a Selection Panel that shall be drawn from parliamentary parties on account of their relative strength in the National Assembly. The bill aims to have the commissioners serve on part-time basis. It provides for the formation of a seven-member selection panel approved by Parliament to recruit commissioners. That would mark a departure from the current arrangement that gives the President leeway in appointing the commissioners.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partners (based on adapted 5 Core Capabilities of NIMD&apos;s scan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partners increased their scores on NIMD&apos;s organizational scan (BART), which is based on the 5 C model</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.5" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitive description: CMD-K scores an average of 3.5 across all five measured capabilities. The specific scores are shown in the following table and figures. Results Max C1 Commit and Act 3,4 5 C2 Deliver Results 3,2 5 C3 Adapt and Self-Renew 3,3 5 C4 Attract and Relate 3,8 5 C5 Balance coherence and diversity 3,8 5 Qualitative description: In general, the organization&#x2019;s higher scores on strategic coherence, accountability, consistency, and relevance demonstrate a strong base for positively impacting Kenya&#x2019;s democratic consolidation over the long-term, even with frequent and rapid shifts in the political environment. Moreover, healthy alliances with international organizations, domestic legal structures, civil society organizations, and political parties offer opportunities for information sharing and coordination on programming, fundraising, and communication. These are the strong points of the organization and although they need to be maintained, they do not need to be built up any further. The focus of the capacity building programme for the coming years will be on the weaker capacities. The lowest scores were given on the capability delivering results with an average of 3.16. This score was particularly low on qualified staffing, infrastructure, and effectiveness. A first conclusion is that this points at the lack of a human resource system, risk policies and training of staff. This could be a first point of attention to focus capacity building activities on: developing a strategic and functioning human resource policy which includes a training strategy for staff. A second conclusion is that the M&amp;E system could be developed further at CMD-K. Activity plans need to be measured and lessons need to be drawn from past experiences. M&amp;E could be a second focus point for capacity building under the SP programme the coming years. Finally, a low score can also be seen on the healthy financial position and in specific CMD-K scored low on the question on a stable income. This touches on the most immediate worry of the organization to become financially healthy again. The conclusion of this exercise is that the capacity building activities for CMD-K under the SP will focus on three aspects: 1. Increasing the financial sustainability of the organization. This means help with cost cutting for sustainability in the short term and increasing capacity to fundraise for sustainability and developing the organization in the medium term. 2. Creating a strategic human resources policy. Which includes a staff training programme. 3. Developing the M&amp;E system and to learn as an organization from past experiences.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of functional interparty dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">CMD-K Board gender composition is 6 male, 5 female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="242">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Divided over 8 county workshops. 143 male, 99 female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of thematic policy issues discussed and brought to parliament</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of civic actors consulted on policy issues</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of civic actors consulted on policy issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="200"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies and proposed amendments jointly formulated for submission to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties taking part in the dialogue platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies and proposed amendments jointly formulated for submission to Parliament by the ruling and opposition parties taking part in the dialogue platforms</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="6"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
