<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-GUA16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GUATEMALA&#x2019;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND Guatemala is part of an area of Central America that is characterized by inequality. Even though it is a low middle income country, there are still a lot of people who live in poverty. This, together with very high crime rates and high levels of impunity is causing a lot of (young) people to emigrate. A large part of the population is indigenous and these people are particularly affected by a lack of employment opportunities and access to social services such as healthcare and education. These are issues that need to be addressed by politicians. However, political parties in Guatemala tend to be based on the personalities of their leaders rather than on a programme of policies. There is a high level of corruption and a lack of transparency. Politicians frequently move from one party to another and many political parties have short life spans. Guatemala is also affected by the increasing cost of electoral campaigns, which makes it difficult for people without access to large amounts of money to participate in national politics. At the same time there is a growing popular demand for change and a growing consensus to fight against corruption and change the political system. THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN GUATEMALA Facilitating multiparty dialogue NIMD&#x2019;s work in Guatemala started in 2002. NIMD&#x2019;s first major project was facilitating multiparty dialogue, together with UNDP, between all the political parties over an 18-month period which resulted in the signing of a development plan for the country called the &#x2018;shared national agenda.&#x2019; This was a plan for recovery following the armed conflict, which had continued in Guatemala for 36 years. Since that first project, NIMD has continued to facilitate interparty dialogue around themes of shared concern including political party reform, security, environmental governance and the inclusion in politics of underrepresented groups (such as women, young people and indigenous people.) In addition, NIMD has been working with Congress on facilitating interparty dialogue, especially on political party and electoral law, the rules and regulations of Congress and civil servant law. As a result of this work several changes have been made and other changes are pending. NIMD has also provided advice and training to Congress, including a training programme for Members of Parliament and their assistants, with the aim of increasing the quality of legislation drafting. Furthermore, NIMD works with several thematic commissions of Congress, making sure that demands and concerns of civil society organizations are known by the commissions and included in their legislative proposals. As well as working with Congress and political parties at a national level, NIMD has also been running democracy schools for young people, with special attention for the inclusion of women and indigenous people, in order to give more people the knowledge and skills to play a role in political decision-making. Political system reform In 2015, Guatemala faced a major political crisis, which led to the stepping down of the President, the Vice President, and several other high-level politicians who were accused of corruption. More transparency in political decision making was just one of the demands of the people who demonstrated. The newly elected Members of Congress, sworn in on 14 January 2016, responded to these public demands by reforming the Rules and Regulations of Congress. These changes include barriers for floor crossing (changing political parties and taking your seats with you), regulations that fight nepotism, and a reduction in the number of staff working in Congress. These reforms were made possible due to the consistent work of the Technical Commission of Congress, which was supported by NIMD in preparing and debating the different reform proposals. For more information, read this document (in Spanish). Raising gender issues on the national agenda in Guatemala Violence against women is one of the big problems Guatemala is facing. NIMD has contributed to a law against femicide by facilitating discussions between the different political parties and between civil and political society to enable a consensus to be reached on the content of the proposed legislation that was later adopted by Congress. The conservative &#x2018;macho&#x2019; culture in Guatemala does not allow much space for women&#x2019;s political participation. NIMD&#x2019;s programme in Guatemala supports the Forum of Political Parties (FPP), a multiparty dialogue platform. Specifically, we have made resources available for the activities of the Commission on Full Citizenship for Women, or Women&#x2019;s Commission, which aims to advance women in politics and leadership, independent of partisan ideologies. Women&#x2019;s civil society organizations in Guatemala have long been pushing for a special law to punish the killing of women, or femicide. Guatemala has the highest femicide rate in Latin America: between 2000 and 2012 over 5000 women were murdered. With the support of NIMD&#x2019;s political analysis and technical support, the Women&#x2019;s Commission worked with civil society and women&#x2019;s groups in the drafting of a law against femicide. After a long and intense dialogue process, the law was approved in 2008. It contributed to sensitizing Guatemala&#x2019;s political culture to this important gender issue. Environmental dialogue NIMD also seeks to encourage a continuous and inclusive dialogue about environmental policy formulation. Additionally we aim to strengthen the capacity of women and other stakeholders to prevent and resolve conflicts related to environmental threats. This programme is implemented together with Cordaid and is being carried out in Colombia, El Salvador, and Guatemala.   Programme deviations/ToC update: During the beginning of 2016, the Congress managed to play a significant role in the change agenda that was established after the 2015 mass demonstrations. However, at the end of 2016, the MP&#x2019;s that represent the old way of doing politics, manage to regain the power in Congress, blocking the reelection of the more progressive Taracena as president of Congress.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD Guatemala</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD, Passage 31, 2511 AB The Hague, The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">198000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-08-25">61882</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Ghana August 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-20">25000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Guatemala Dec 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-19">63997</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Guatemala February 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-14">52798</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Guatemala July 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-27">2850</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Guatemala July-2 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-19">50005</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Guatemala May 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-06">51450</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Guatemala October 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-07-28">198000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala budget 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">6345</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capability to attract and relate of political actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guatemala has a system of dispersed political parties that are hardly institutionalized. The ability of political actors to negotiate and/or bring together different agendas does not revolve around a programmatic vision, but depends on interests and privileges of groups and actors involved in the issue. In this context, and given the absence of a government plan, the Congress has taken the initiative during 2015/2016 to define and further a political agenda for the country. The issues that are included in the agenda are determined by the following factors: the popular demands that were voiced during the La Plaza demonstrations; the CICIG-MP-US Embassy agenda (fight against corruption and security and justice); the interests of the traditional economic power. While UNE and FCN are the biggest parties in Congress, their interests are divergent. Political alliances with the smaller parties were established to determine the legislative agenda and its (partial) implementation. Multi-actor alliances were also established, including Congress, Social Organization and State Institutions. This allowed for progress on specific legislative and policy issues.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of active alliances between political actors and/or between political actors and CS stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unit of measurement 2 active partnerships (on relevant issues for NIMD) among political stakeholders and/or among political and CSO stakeholders: Among political stakeholders 0 Among Political stakeholders and CSO 1. 1. Security and Justice workgroup. This is an initiative from the Congress Commission on Legislation and Constitutional Issues to promote the agenda of Justice, Security and Human Rights together with Civil Society. 2. National Workgroup on Climate Change. This mechanism is institutionalized through the National Climate Change Law and consists of representatives of Government, civil society and think tanks. Qualitative Data The Workgroup for Security and Justice [Mesa de Seguridad y Justicia] is integrated by the MPs, civil society, the Office of the Human Rights Solicitor, Public Prosecutor&apos;s Office, Ministry of the Interior, the Judicial Branch, Criminal Public Defense [Instituto de la Defensa P&#xFA;blica Penal], UNICEF, and the Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights. During 2012-2015, the Workgroup prioritized the following topics: Reforms to the Judicial Career, Reforms to the Organic Law of the Public Prosecutor&apos;s Office, Reforms to the Civil Service Act of the Judicial Branch, age limit for marriage and Public Order Act. The National Workgroup of Climate Change [Mesa Nacional de Cambio Clim&#xE1;tico &#x2013; MNCC] emerges when the State adopts a Law on National Climate Change. As a result of this law, the National Workgroup is established consisting of civil society organizations, the Ministry of Environment and Natural Resources, the National Woods Institute, the Ministry of Economy, the General Planning Secretariat and the Ministry of Finances. Congressmen from the Commission on Climate Change are observers in this workgroup.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are more aware of and have internalised democratic values, rule of law and gender sensitive &amp; inclusive politics.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Many studies have demonstrated that Guatemala lacks a democratic political culture, where the citizens are actively involved in political, social or community organizations and feel they can influence public decision making. Machismo and discrimination are manifest in Guatemalan society and become clear in power structures and relations. Furthermore, political parties, social organizations and citizens very often show these negative values in their way of treating other people but also in the way they organize their organization and take decisions.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that reference the following topics in their manifesto/public statements, other publications - democratic values and/or rule of law and/or gender sensitive &amp; inclusive politics</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="63" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 63% of political and CSO&apos;s stakeholders who in the monitoring period made reference to democratic values, rule of law and/or gender &amp; inclusive politics, in their public statements and manifestos. 94% of politicians and civil society leaders believe that the rule of law is a sine qua non requirement for democracy strengthening. 56% of the interviewed people are sensitive to inclusive models for youth, women and indigenous peoples. Qualitative data: The study was carried out from July 12 to 27, 2016. Two instruments were applied: A survey conducted to the 5% of participants of the Democracy School and a Focus Group that addressed in depth the conclusions derived from the survey. The following variables were used: democratic values, the rule of law, and inclusion. These reveal qualitative information on how the person values and perceives the democratic situation in the country. From this perspective, the qualification on the democratic situation in Guatemala showed that 44% perceives that is regular, while 6% thinks that is good. However, 25% stated that it was bad and another 25% very bad. In the end it shows a pessimistic environment about the quality of democracy in the country. Nevertheless, it is important to note that the study evidences patterns of thought and analysis that have been, if not acquired, definitely strengthened, by the training programmes of the Democracy Schools.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partners (based on adapted 5 Core Capabilities of NIMD&apos;s scan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD Guatemala was established in 2003. The office grew in size until 2013, while after that a reorganization process led to the reduction of staff. The office in Guatemala supported the setting up of country offices in Honduras and El Salvador and provided input for those programs. A new director is heading the office as of may 2015 continuing the process of strengthening internal communication and coordination. The country office works closely together with a # of other organizations and institutions, both national and international. During the first 10 years of working in Guatemala, NIMD focused on the strengthening of political parties, multi-party dialogue and political system reform. Nevertheless, in the last couple of years, given the &#x201C;new&#x201D; citizens&apos; demands and the weakening of the political system, we identified the need for accompaniment and training in lobby and advocacy of civil society organizations and citizens collectives. Based on its broad political network and expertise, NIMD facilitates and supports dialogue tables between those civil society organizations and political actors. Working with civic and political actors, NIMD pays special attention to gender mainstreaming and the inclusion of those groups that are discriminated and that lack effective representation in the political system. During 2015 NIMD has worked with political parties represented in Congress, CSO&#xB4;s and other key stakeholders related to the mandate of the Institute. Among them may be mentioned: 6. Legislative power: within Congress, NIMD works specifically with the Commissions of Electoral Reform, Climate Change, Hydric Resources, Youth, Women, Technical Support, Legislation and Constitutional Issues, Human Rights. 7. State organizations: Ministries of Environment and Natural Resources, Culture and Sports, and Energy and Mining; The General Planning Secretariat; The Public Management Institute; The Supreme Electoral Tribunal; The Ministry of Foreign Affairs. 8. Non-Governmental Organizations: CONAREP, MOLOJ, CONVERGENCIA CIVICO POLITO DE MUJERES, ASOCIACION POLITICA LA CUERDA, FUNDAJU/ASODEJU, JUSTICIA YA!, UUGT, ICEFI, FUNDACION ESQUIPULAS, FUNDAECO, CALAS, CONGECOOP, CECODE, COLECTIVO RIO, FUNDACION PROPAZ, 9. Academic institutions: &#x201C;Rafael Landivar&#x201D; University, ASIES, FLACSO, School of Political Science - USAC. 10. Development cooperation entities: Sweden Embassy, Norway Embassy, M&#xE9;xico Embassy, IRI, NDI, KAS, FES, USAID, UNDP and UN Women. 11. Regional Entities: PARLACEN.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partners increased their scores on NIMD&apos;s organizational scan (BART), which is based on the 5 C model</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.68" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this section an analysis of the Organizational Performance Scan of NIMD on each of its components is presented. The average rate for NIMD-Guatemala was 3.68 based on the self- assessment of staff. C1. Commit and Act: The transition between the PP2 and the SP program affected the organization due to the lack of a clear strategy. Furthermore, NIMD decided to finalize its programme with the Multiparty Forum of Political Parties that it had been supporting since its establishment in 2003. These developments and the decline in financial resources required the office to make important adjustments. C2. Deliver Results: There is a gap between administrative and program staff when it comes to the appropriation of the strategic objectives of the SP. Due to the change in strategy and limitations of financial resources, the presence of NIMD has decreased, mostly in the bilateral relations with political parties and outside the capital city. C3. Adapt and Self-Renew: NIMD is less present in social media than it issued to be. It is necessary to improve the communication about the programs and results of NIMD Guatemala, so public opinion, beneficiaries and donors are aware of the activities undertaken and the results achieved. Additional attention for communication on financial processes is important for headquarters and other donors. It is also important to establish and adequate process of Monitoring &amp; Evaluation which is essential to monitor the programme implementation and to assess if the goals are being met. This is also important for NIMD as a learning organization. C4. Attract and Relate: NIMD has the versatility and ability to cooperate with other agencies, such as NDI, UN Women, Konrad Adenauer in order to create greater impact. On the other hand NIMD maintains the legitimacy of being a neutral partner to politicians and civil society organizations. A weakness is noticed in terms of attracting donors for long-term processes on strengthening democracy. C5. Balance Coherence and Diversity: NIMD is a coherent organization with the values of impartiality, inclusiveness, diversity, local ownership and long term commitment, which is noted by its partners in civil society and political parties.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 2015 demonstrations in Guatemala against corruption and impunity also called for political reform. Responding to these demands, the Congress initiated a series of consultations with civil society amongst others on reform of the Political Party and Electoral System. These consultation processes included the traditional, well established civil society organizations, but also the more loose network type organizations that came into existence in the summer of 2015. In September 2015 elections took place. This led to an outsider becoming president, whose political proposals and priorities were not yet clearly defined. The president does not have a majority in Congress. During the first half of 2016, the president of Congress, member of an opposition party, continued the legislative debate on the reform proposals demanded by civil society. Mistrust in politicians and the political system is high. People perceive politicians to be corrupt and thinking about their own well-being rather than that of the country. After the elections the public demonstrations diminished greatly. However, the population continues to be alert and is willing to voice their discontent if a new corruption scandal or political mismanagement arises. In this context, there have been several spaces for dialogue and discussion between civil and political society (especially Congress) on electoral reform and on Constitutional Reform of Security and Justice provisions. In these spaces, civil society organizations specialized in the issues have presented concrete proposals, given the importance of political reforms to change the system. Meanwhile, the Executive has invited civil society organizations and think tanks to develop proposals on issues that were not included in the last electoral reform, such as gender parity and ethnicity, internal democracy and models of representation.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of inclusive law making processes with active CS consultation</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="6" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative Data Between 2012 - 2015, 6 processes for law initiatives existed in which civil society was consulted about the issues relevant for NIMD&#x2019;s Central American program 2016 &#x2013; 2020 that are political reforms, fiscal reform, climate change, and water management. Political Reform (4) - The Electoral and Political Parties Law was discussed in 2 consultation mechanisms established by the Congress of the Republic: Legislative Working groups and the working group convened by the Electoral Supreme Court. - The Organic Law of the Legislative Branch was developed through a series of seminars with CSO consultation. - The Civil Service Law was discussed by the working group consisting of civil society and political representatives convened by the Congress of the Republic. Fiscal Reform (1) The civil society consultation on fiscal reform was organized by the Commission on Finance and Currency. A variety of think tanks, foundations, and especially business associations participated in the seminars. Climate Change (1) The Commission on Climate Change organized a series of public hearings to identify gaps in current policy and legislation and to identify legal amendments and policy measures to strengthen the system to deal with the effects of climate change. Water Management (0) Qualitative data: Between 2012 - 2015, 6 processes for law initiatives existed in which civil society was consulted about political reforms, fiscal reform, climate change, and water management 1. The Electoral and Political Parties Law [Ley Electoral y de Partidos Pol&#xED;ticos &#x2013; LEPP]: Guatemala witnessed a year of political turmoil in 2015. The president and vice-president were accused of corruption and resigned after massive demonstrations by a wide variety of Guatemalan society. One of the demands of the demonstrators was the reform of the political system in order to combat corruption. As a result both the Congress and the Electoral Tribunal organized a dialogue with civil society on the reform of the political party law (4974). Civil society provided substantial input during these two consultation processes and their comments were incorporated into the reform proposals. 2. The Legislative Internal Regime Law [Ley de R&#xE9;gimen Interior del Legislativo &#x2013; LOOL]: during the same period, fifteen (15) initiatives were presented in Congress on reform o fthe LOOL. These were analyzed by the Technical Support Commission supported by NIMD, but after that the process did not receive any attention from the MPs. Social pressure and the demands of civil society organizations for a more transparent and efficient Congress forced the new legislature to take up some of the recommendations and make changes to its internal regulations improve its legitimacy. 3. The Civil Service Law: from 2012 - 2015 only two (2) initiatives were submitted; one with a favorable opinion scheduled in the agenda and the other created in the framework of the workgroups that Congress established in 2015 in the midst of the political crisis. Congress received the input of almost 50 civil society organizations, including Trade Unions. However, there was no follow up of the process to ensure the initiative would become law. The new Congress has not included this issue in the legislative agenda as it was not one of the main demands of the 2015 &quot;La Plaza&quot; demonstrators. Furthermore, the issue of Civil Service Legislation is sensitive as there are several key actors and therefore diverse interests to be dealt with. 4. Water and environment: In Guatemala there is no Law on Comprehensive Water Management, this being a key issue to the country&apos;s development and environmental conservation. The interests at stake are high, given the economic model of the country. In this sense the issue of water management was almost nonexistent in the past 4 years, since there was not even a single law initiative submitted. 5. Regarding climate change, one law initiative was submitted and heard before the Plenary, but there was no opinion issued by the related commission. The Environment and Natural Resources and the Climate Change Commissions organized roundtables with environmental organizations to come up with proposals to amend the Forest Law. The lobby from civil organizations managed to include incentives for forest communities organizations and Municipalities in the new legislation. The following organizations participated: UtzChe, Association of Forest Communities of Pet&#xE9;n [Asociaci&#xF3;n de Comunidades Forestales de Peten &#x2013; ACOFOP], CALMECAC Foundation, Foundation for Eco-development and Conservation [Fundaci&#xF3;n para el Ecodesarrollo y Conservaci&#xF3;n &#x2013; FUNDAECO], Environmental and Human Resources Organizations Association [Asociaci&#xF3;n de Organizaciones Ambientalistas y de Recursos Humanos], National Association of NGO&#x2019;s of Natural Resources and Environment [Asociaci&#xF3;n Nacional de Organizaciones No Gubernamentales de Recursos Naturales y Medio Ambiente &#x2013; ASOREMA]. 6. Tax reform was absent in the legislative agenda 2012-2015. The new president came up in August 2016 with a proposal for tax reform and that put the issue back on the agenda of Congress and of the civil society organizations. A bill of particular relevance in the Guatemalan context in light of the corruption scandals is the institutional strengthening of the Superintendency of Tax Administration [Superintendencia de Administraci&#xF3;nTributaria &#x2013; SAT]..</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased trust in the political process by different groups and citizens, including % of Latino and Afro barometer responds</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="17" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The most recently available 2015 LatinoBarometer measured public trust of respondents in political parties overall. Collapsing the categories of &#x201C;somewhat&#x201D; and &#x201D;a lot&#x201D;, we see that there is very low trust in political parties in Guatemala.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe (and institutionalized) space for dialogue between all relevant political (and civic) actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of structural changes opening up space for greater engagement by political and civic actors, including # of structural changes and new mechanisms for greater engagement by political and civic actors + # of laws and mechanisms ensuring safe engagement between political and civic actors;</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of structural changes and new mechanisms for greater engagement by political and civic actors</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 new consultation mechanisms (Technical dialogue workgroups) with civil society were established in light of the 2015 events related to the Political Party and Electoral framework: 1. The initiative presented by the Supreme Electoral Tribunal to the Congress of the Republic with the participation and technical assistance of civil society organizations devoted to the subject. 2. The workgroup convened by the Congress of the Republic, where 168 civil society organizations participated. 3. The platform for State Reform, convened by the University of San Carlos of Guatemala, that became a multi-sectorial civil instance. Qualitative description: 1. The political party reform initiative presented by the Supreme Electoral Tribunal to the Congress was made in consultation with civil society. Different CSO were heard representing a variety of views on electoral reform. 2. After the 2015 demonstrations, the Congress convened a workgroup on political and electoral reform. 168 civil society organizations participated and the workgroup gathered input on the following themes: 1) Political financing and access to media; 2) Organization and internal democratization of political parties; 3) Strengthening the Supreme Electoral Court; 4) Electoral Process, null vote vinculante (binding); 5) Sanctions regime; 6) Electoral system. 3. The University of San Carlos is heading a multiactor platform for State Reform. The platform includes universities, professional associations, research centers, churches, indigenous peoples, trade organizations, organized private sector, cooperations, student organizations, unions, women, youth, farmers, NGOs, environmental organizations, social forums and human rights organizations. Its main purpose is to reach agreements and present proposals regarding a comprehensive process of State Reform. Their recommendations were taken into account by the workgroup on Political and Electoral Reform of the Supreme Electoral Court</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women involved in politics that feel they are able to take part in decision-making processes</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of women involved in politics that feel they are able to take part in decision-making processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="100"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">#  of participants in capacity-building activities</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="101"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="149"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies formulated based on consultation with interest groups, local experts, CS</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of policies formulated based on consultation with interest groups, local experts, CS</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates from democracy and political education schools (disaggregate sex, age, social group etc)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of graduates from democracy and political education schools (disaggregate sex, age, social group etc)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="234"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="30"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political parties that experience that their contribution to policy processes are more effective</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political parties that experience that their contribution to policy processes are more effective</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="62.5"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of civic actors that indicate that they experience an increased willingness-to-interact from political actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of civic actors that indicate that they experience an increased willingness-to-interact from political actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="66.67"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
