<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-UKR16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ukraine Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2016 -2020 NIMD will launch a new intervention in Ukraine. In 2016 NIMD - through its Eastern European Neighbourhood office based in Tbilisi - will set first steps by establishing its presence in Kyiv, securing its network among stakeholders and donors, commissioning baseline studies, initiating preliminary capacity-building activities with receptive beneficiaries, and exploring other avenues of cooperation. In this way, NIMD is building on the yet existing capacity and valuable lessons learnt from working in Post-Soviet countries. NIMD will assess this piloting phase (January-December) by the end of 2016 and gain insights in the windows of opportunities in that rapidly changing political climate. On this basis, it will deploy a full-fledged multi-year intervention for 2017-2020 focused on inclusiveness for political processes and legitimate and responsive actors in Ukraine, for which the Dialogue for Stability instrument of Dutch MFA and other funding will be used.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD Eastern European Neighbourhood</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UA" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">137082</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-19">87000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Ukraine May 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-10-06">66443</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Ukraine October 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-09-23">8500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Ukraine September 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">3606</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">23280</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-DFS-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Existing safe spaces hosting a functional dialogue and/or cooperation platforms</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In spite of the consolidation of some spaces for inter-party exchange (for example the Euro-Optimist platform), the mechanisms for dialogue and trust building continue to be established fundamentally on an inter-personal level. A well-oiled culture of transactional politics seems to be dominant, while a genuine culture of structured political dialogue and compromise is much more elusive. Here the multiplication of &#x201C;ad-hoc dialogue spaces&#x201D; and the influence exerted by international actors and domestic civil society, whereas helping to advance the agenda of legislative reforms, may pose additional challenges to the consolidation of a culture of political dialogue.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of relevant issues discussed by political parties in an institutionalized dialogue setting</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key definitions: Relevant issue: Issues of national importance. The questionnaire focused almost exclusively in policy making at the national level. In particular around the key policy and institutional reforms, which have been taking shape in the country in the aftermath of the Dignity Revolution. Institutionalized dialogue setting: Regular multiparty dialogue meetings Political parties: The study includes all political parties represented in Parliament and important parties and platforms not present in Parliament but which hold seats at the local level.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="12" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Qualitative description: Political party members were asked to identify which amongst the 12 most important reforms approved in the last 2 years had been discussed in multi-party fora. They were given the option to mark as many as they deemed necessary. They could also mark the box all of them or none of them. According to the results of the questionnaire and the interviews, all the 12 reforms were addressed in one form or another in a multi-party dialogue platform. Whereas elements of a well-oiled culture of transactional politics are easy to find, a culture of structured political dialogue and compromise is much more elusive in current Ukrainian politics. This is so for the following observable reasons: Firstly, the multiplication of &#x201C;ad-hoc dialogue spaces&#x201D; in recent times represents a significant challenge for the establishment and consolidation of true multi-party dialogue efforts, which can yield a much needed consensus around a broader agenda of reforms for the country: &#xF0A7; It disincentivizes political actors when it comes to the development of their own knowledge generation and knowledge management structures and serious sustainability challenges for dialogue efforts; &#xF0A7; It exacerbates dynamics of competition amongst potential &#x201C;facilitators&#x201D;, thus limiting the overall capacity of the system to generate the incentives for true consensus-building activities. &#xF0A7; It extends a rather limited understanding of what multi-party dialogue and consensus-building really entails. Thus, preventing the possibility for further development of a truly party-based dialogue platform on issues of relevance for the future development of the country. Secondly, whereas the ability of international actors and domestic civil society in bringing actors around the table to pass specific reforms remains one of the key drivers of change in current Ukrainian politics, it may be hindering the development of a more endogenous culture of compromise and political dialogue. Taking into consideration the extent of international pressure exerted in order to achieve some of the key reforms (particularly in the anti-corruption area), one can question the real weight that the process of inter-party and inter-faction dialogue played in all this. Score Number of relevant issues discussed 1 Functioning of mechanisms for individual cooperation and dialogue 1 Culture of compromise -1 Number of spaces for policy debate -1 Functioning of structures for inter-party dialogue -1 Total score for policy dialogue in institutionalized settings -1</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Higher recognition and approval ratings of political actors by citizens</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political parties continue to endure a bad reputation in Ukraine, with trust rates hitting a historical low score in 2015. Nevertheless, 70.2% Ukrainians consider political parties and important factor for the adequate functioning of a democratic regime in the country. Mistrust in political parties is rooted in the perception of the political parties as lobby structures for the interests of their leaders (37% of respondents) and their financial donors (58% of respondents); rather than as organizations defending and articulating both the policy views of their voters and the national interest (only 11% agreed that parties represent citizens&#x2019; interests).</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of respondent citizens that express trust in political actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 12% of Ukrainians reported to trust in political parties Furthermore: 79% of Ukrainian citizens do not trust political parties Qualitative description: Two years after the Revolution of Dignity, political parties continue to endure bad reputation in Ukraine, with trust rates hitting a historical low score in 2015. Nevertheless, 70.2% Ukrainians continue to consider political parties and important element for the adequate functioning of a democratic regime in the country. Mistrust in political parties is rooted in the perception of the political parties as lobby structures for the interests of their leaders (37% of respondents) and their financial donors (58% of respondents); rather than as organizations defending and articulating both the policy views of their voters and the national interest (only 11% agreed that parties represent citizens&#x2019; interests). 63% of Ukrainians believe that political parties do not follow democratic standards in their activities. Similarly, the parties&#x2019; failure to adhere to their programmes and a lack of effective communication with citizens are both named as factors contributing to the overwhelming mistrust to political parties among the public. Legislation reforming party financing (opening parties to receive public funds for the first time in history and enhancing the levels of accountability and transparency on the public and private funds and donations received by parties) has not translated yet in a change in the long established mistrust vis-&#xE0;-vis political parties. 77% of Ukrainians would never consider supporting a political party financially. The majority of Ukrainians also seem to oppose the idea of parties receiving any public funding (only 15% supports this measure). Citizens also show their opposition to the parties receiving funds from oligarchs (only 14% in favor). Finally only one third of the population (31%) believes that parties should be financed directly by their supporters. There is an overwhelming demand for a new breed of political parties in the country (71% of respondents consider new political parties as the only hope for the country&#x2019;s future). Yet, the field seems to remain quite evenly split between those who see general differences in the political parties emerging after Maidan (42%) and those who do not see any difference (35%). What is more, when it comes to trust levels pre and post-Maidan parties enjoy very similar levels of trust (12% for pre-Maidan vs 15% for post Maidan). Leadership renewal is a top priority for Ukrainian citizens (55% considers that the country needs new leaders). In this regard, all parties competing in the early Parliamentary elections in 2014 headhunted for liberal professionals and individuals with a track record in civil activism to show a renewed face. Yet, an important share of people included in the parties&#x2019; lists continue to be cadres from previously existing political structures, thus contributing to a extending perception of business as usual. Score Trust in political parties -1 Capacity to communicate, represent and articulate interests -1 General willingness to support to parties (financially) -1 Democratic standards and transparency in parties -1 Perception of the importance of political parties in democracy 1 Total score for perception of political parties -3 Secondary sources &#xF0A7; &#x201C;Perception of Ukrainians on political parties and sources of their funding,&#x201D; Ilko Kucheriv Democratic Initiatives Foundation and Razumkov Center, November 2015, Available at: http://razumkov.org.ua/eng/files/category_journal/2015_Partiyi_8_ENG-1.compressed.pdf</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="12" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A more open and inclusive political system that contribute to stability</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of political actors that have introduced or reformed internal party regulations on the inclusion of women in decision-making bodies</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key definitions: Political actors: The study includes all political parties represented in Parliament and important parties and platforms not present in Parliament but which hold seats at the local level. &#xF0A7; &#x201C;Attitudes Towards Women&#x2019;s Political Participation in Ukraine&#x201D; National Democratic Institute - February 2016. Available at: https://www.ndi.org/files/NDI%20Gender%20Research%20FEB%202016%20-%20ENG%20vf.pdf</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 0 &#xF0A7; 0/8 - Parties do not have specific policies in place to facilitate women participation, beyond the compliance with the 30% gender quota recommendation established in the Law. Furthermore: &#xF0A7; For the last parliamentary elections, 2/8 (Samopomich and Batkivshchyna) adjusted its candidates lists to comply with the recommended threshold in legislation of at least 30% minimum gender quota. &#xF0A7; For the local elections 75% of the lists presented by all the parties in the country complied with the 30% quota Qualitative description: Women still face constraints in practicing their political, economic and social rights. Yet, political parties, across the political spectrum do not seem to consider gender equality a pressing issue or one in which they would think reform is necessary (whether at the statute or party policy level) or urgent. Low participation of women in party lists or party decision-making bodies is not particularly socially sanctioned, nor it seems to be specially rewarded by voters when more women are included. At the social level, there is not a very significant level of explicit opposition to women participation in politics (only around 13% of respondents to a recent survey). But just about 38% of the population would express their preference for equal participation of women and men in politics. The prevailing vision of the role of women in politics is constructed over an implicit dominant association of women with the private sphere and the perception/assumption of women&#x2019;s lack of interest in politics, which would ultimately explain why they are less involved. Women MPs interviewed for this baseline study did not distance themselves greatly from this analysis, even though they were able to identify instances of sexism in their interaction with male MPs and gender based discrimination in some practices of political parties. Yet, generally, parties are not perceived by women politicians as blocking the entrance of women into the political sphere. This speaks volumes of how ingrained gender inequality is in the societal mainframe and also about the difficulties to move parties beyond the current status quo on this issue. As noted by many of the experts interviewed for this baseline study, one positive aspect, which may favor greater women participation in politics is the linkage established between parties&#x2019; access to public financing and the compliance with minimum gender quotas recommendations. This type of positive incentive seems to be slowly transforming the practice of parties. Score Perceptions of women in society -1 Policies developed to address gender imbalances -1 Compliance with 30% minimum gender quota 1 (partial compliance but positive impact) General role of party structures 0 Willingness of political parties to address gender imbalances -1 Total score for women participation -2</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Concrete proposals for an accepted and equitable political system proposed and accepted</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors that experience an enabling environment in which they are involved in inclusive policy making</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enabling environment: Legal, political and cultural conditions that impact the capacity of political actors to influence policy Political actors: Political parties and cross-party caucuses. The study includes all political parties represented in Parliament and important parties and platforms not present in Parliament but which hold seats at the local level. Inclusive policy-making: All parties are involved and participate in policy making at the national level. Even if the participants in the questionnaire and the interviews included parties, which main institutional roles unfold at the local level, the questionnaire focused almost exclusively in policy making at the national level. In particular around the key policy and institutional reforms, which have been taking shape in the country in the aftermath of the Dignity Revolution</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 0 &#xF0A7; None of the political actors currently experience an enabling environment in which they are involved in inclusive policy making; &#xF0A7; Average score for polarization is 3 in a 1-10 scale where 1 represents maximum level of polarization Qualitative description: Parties qualify the political environment as a competitive arena rather than one in which political and social actors are enabled to work together in order to address the country&#x2019;s significant challenges. Similarly, most actors perceive a process of deterioration of the political environment as compared to the political situation in the immediate aftermath of the Dignity Revolution. The political process remains to a large extent driven by key personalities and the capacity of special interests to influence and accommodate the policy process to their own priorities. The dominant political culture continues to be one of short-termism, behind-the-closed-doors-deal-making and quid pro quo. A culture of compromise remains largely absent. Coalitions are not structured around clear party axes or ideological cleavages. The positions of individual politicians fluctuate across the whole range of options almost on an issue-by-issue basis so that party representatives who may adopt a progressive position on a certain policy area, may become, the staunchest defendants of the status quo on another. The resulting environment is one where the mechanisms for dialogue and trust building are established almost on a personal level, with political parties and party factions in parliament or the adscription to government or opposition camps playing a limited or no role at all in defining the policy positions. Nevertheless, as noted by our interviewees there are exceptions to the above-mentioned dynamics. These include: &#xF0A7; The Euro-Optimist group as a multiparty platform for advancing reform; &#xF0A7; The Inter-faction Union for Gender Equality; &#xF0A7; The ad-hoc (albeit limited) multiparty discussions taking place in the context of specific initiatives by the Reanimation Package of Reforms (RPR). &#xF0A7; The work carried out in the Parliamentary Committees. &#xF0A7; The spaces facilitated by the international community in order to support the process of adoption of specific legislation. Score Experience of an enabling environment -1 Polarization and perception of general evolution of the political environment -1 Functioning of mechanisms for individual cooperation and dialogue 1 Culture of compromise -1 Existence of spaces for inter-party dialogue 0 Total score for enabling environment -2</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Personal trust between rivals improved.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Score of trust in the political leadership of rival parties by different political actors</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key definitions: Trust in political leadership of rival parties: Trust whether they will keep their word. Political actors: The study includes all political parties represented in Parliament and important parties and platforms not present in Parliament but which hold seats at the local level. The activities of cross-party caucuses are also examined for this indicator.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="2" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 2 The average score of trust in a scale between 0 (no trust) to 10 (total trust) is 2, which lies right in the middle of our scale for very limited trust (1-3); Please see methodology for specific considerations about the validity of this indicator. Qualitative description: To measure trust between the political leadership of other parties, we asked party representatives to define their trust levels to other political parties politicians in a scale of 0 to 10. This question was included also in the on-line questionnaire, where respondents could attribute specifics score to each political party (again between 0 and 10). Figures were distributed across five categories. The distribution was as follows: 0 = no trust at all; 1-3 = very limited trust; 4-6 = limited trust; 7-9 = trust; 10 = complete trust The results of this indicator are consistent with the levels of perceived political polarization and the overall characterization of the current political juncture as one dominated by competitive dynamics. This raises our confidence in the accuracy of this indicator in spite of the limitations in the process of data collection. As mentioned in previous indicators, trust seems to be generated on a personal level, through specific interactions in the fora enumerated in indicator S2.1. Many party representatives have highlighted the importance of the work in Parliamentary Committees, but also the interactions in the fora established by international organizations and civil society to discuss and address specific reforms. Score Total score for trust amongst parties -3 (See methodology for an explanation of the way in which scores have been adapted)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of political actors in fragile settings to effectively and legitimately participate in political (dialogue) process.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of published political documents by political actors based on real inputs from a defined support base</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key definitions: Political documents: Manifestos, statutes, position papers, policy proposals etc. Real inputs from a defined support base: Known support base for a PP such as CSOs, NGO&#x2019;s and public in general Political parties: The study includes all political parties represented in Parliament and important parties and platforms not present in Parliament but which hold seats at the local level. &#xF0A7; &#x201C;Perception of Ukrainians on political parties and sources of their funding,&#x201D; Ilko Kucheriv Democratic Initiatives Foundation and Razumkov Center, November 2015, Available at: http://razumkov.org.ua/eng/files/category_journal/2015_Partiyi_8_ENG-1.compressed.pdf</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="3" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: 3 &#xF0A7; In 3 cases (Batkivshchyna, Syda Lyudey and Democratic Alliance) party manifestos developed in consultation with other actors. &#xF0A7; None of the parties included in the study have published relevant sectorial policy documents, which have been developed in consultation with a support base. Qualitative description: The progressive loss of importance of the policy and ideological component has been a characteristic of Ukraine&#x2019;s party system for a long time. In the aftermath of the 2014 elections, parties have continued to ignore the need to develop party programmes and policy documents. In addition, there has been a significant process of simplification and, to a higher degree, a unification of the content of the electoral programmes of all political parties. The result of this process is that between 59% and 74% of the population (depending on their adscription to various sociological groups) would not feel their interests represented by any of the political parties competing in the 2014 elections. Party ideology/vision rarely influences the public activity of politicians and MPs. Policy directives, when they exist, seem to be established as a combination of political opportunism and the vision of the political leader of the party/faction. This results in parties not developing specific units in charge of policy development, beyond the legal support department. Similarly, MPs also find it difficult to install capacity for policy analysis in their own offices due to the lack of economic resources available to hire supporting personnel. In this context, civil society and international experts (sponsored by international actors) have come to play a key role in providing policy expertise for the development of specific policy proposals and legislation. This is creating powerful disincentives for parties to engage in a more consistent approach to programmatic development, notably when it comes to the development of their own research and analysis sections/departments. New parties established after the last Parliamentary elections have shown a predisposition to look at some of these issues differently. According to the results of our interviews and the survey conducted for this baseline study, those parties seem to better understand and value the importance of having a clearer policy and ideological stance as a means to communicate with voters. Also, due to their origins in civil society, the integration of civil society expertise in the party structures is much more organic than in other parties. Score Capacity to differentiate themselves through their political manifestos 0 Number of sectorial policy documents produced -1 Structures within the parties/parliamentary factions in charge of policy development -1 Consultation processes with party&#x2019;s base 0 Mechanisms for consultation with policy experts -1 Total score for development of policy positions -3</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
