<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://iatistandard.org/203/schema/downloads/iati-activities-schema.xsd">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-27189542-IND16</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia Programme 2016</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INDONESIA&#x2019;S POLITICAL BACKGROUND In 1999, Indonesia held its first democratic elections since 1955. Elections are popular in Indonesia. They are well managed by the Elections Commission (KPU) and have high levels of voter turnout. Indonesia has the second-largest one-day election in the world (after the USA) and since 1999 there has been a huge growth in the number of political parties contesting the elections, although the number of parties that actually meet the threshold for a seat in parliament is much lower. However, most political parties are based around the personality of their leader rather than having a programme of policies and there is widespread corruption. Governments are usually a coalition of many political parties and the politicians involved are usually more focused on gaining power than representing the people. Indonesia has a relatively young population. 43.3% of the population are younger than 24 and 85.6% are younger than 54. However, the political scene is populated by the same familiar faces which have dominated Indonesian politics for the past decades. They tend to still be representing powerful vested interests. There is a glimmer of hope, however. In 2014 a new president was elected who is a complete political outsider, a former governor of Jakarta who is known for his pragmatic reform-minded style. THE APPROACH OF NIMD IN INDONESIA Until 2015, the core of NIMD&#x2019;s programme in Indonesia was democracy education. By the end of 2014, the Democracy Schools had produced 1738 alumni in 8 regions. In the 2014 general elections, 179 Democracy School alumni ran for office and 16 were elected. 77 alumni were involved in the elections as officials. The alumni are organized in alumni organizations which engage in lobby &amp; advocacy to address local issues like education, healthcare and pollution. In 2016, NIMD will be starting a new programme working with young politicians at the national level. Our aim is to equip young politicians with better political skills to fulfil their democratic role as elected representatives, as well as stimulating inclusive inter-party dialogue on democratic renewal. This programme will be implemented by Kemitraan &#x2013; Partnership for Governance Reform.    Programme deviations/ToC Update: The Indonesia programme started in April 2016 with signing a contract with our new partner in Indonesia, Kemitraan. Firstly, the baseline measurement of the outcome level indicators was done, followed by an induction workshop at NIMD HQ in The Hague.
The results of the programme in 2016:
1.Secured commitment of the leaderships of 10 political factions in the House of Representative/Parliament (Dewan Perwakilan Rakyat &#x2013; DPR) on the proposal to establish a theme based inter-party dialogue forum for young Members of Parliament;
2.Availability of short videos on issues related to tolerance, diversity and counter extremism to be used as triggering materials/themes/issues for inter-party dialogue;
3.Established network of video makers in 15 cities who can produce video messages on local or national issues to be shared in inter-party dialogue;
4.Established engagement between Kemitraan with the alumni of Sekolah Demokrasi through Forum Demokrasi Nusantara; and
5.Trained selected civil society activists on web-scrapping skill for data collection and analysis from social media (Twitter)

Unfortunately, the programme progress does not exactly match with the initial thought laid out in the annual plan 2016. This was because the contract was signed only in Q 2 of 2016 but also because engaging with politicians in Indonesia proved to be more difficult than initially thought. An important lesson learnt during 2016 is that engagement with political parties and politicians is not as easy as it was thought during the design of the program. Kemitraan&#x2019;s experience in conducting advocacy in the parliament is different from the need to get the parliamentarians engaged in activities being prepared under INSPIRE program. There is a need for Kemitraan&#x2019;s INSPIRE program team to really get itself familiarized and engaged with the &#x201C;routine&#x201D; of the MPs to get the program noticed and being prioritized. Establishing getting the buy-in of political leadership therefore took more time as anticipated (due to full parliamentary schedules). 

Because of this the originally planned IPD training has logistically also been postponed to 2017. However, one round-table was organised for young MPs and their staff to discuss priorities and expectations for the interparty dialogue platform. Due to conflicting agenda&apos;s and party priorities however, there were not so many MPS present, mostly their technical staff took part.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political actors are defined as the combined main target group of the Strategic Partnership: - (representatives of) political parties - politicians - (Members of) Parliament and its Committees - Other elected representatives at local levels. NIMD will primarily focus on political parties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-27189542" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NIMD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>info@nimd.org</email>
   <website>http://www.nimd.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">190423</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-04">48801</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement Indonesia May 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-05-04">190423</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia Budget 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">local partner</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">8653</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Programme monitoring</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">37500</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">programme advise and support</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-27189542-SP16" ref="NL-KVK-27189542"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-27189542-SP-Programme" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A level playing field, for all political actors, based on trust, including civic actors wanting to influence politics</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The enabling environment for lobby &amp; advocacy is obstructed by the closed nature of the political system. The formal political system in Indonesia is largely dominated by political elites and vested interests. It is nearly impossible for outsiders to enter into politics without doing so in the context of one of the established political parties. In addition to this, parties must win at least 3.5% of the vote in order to be eligible for seats in the DPR. As a result, it is very difficult for new parties to get a foothold in the political system. The parties that are able to contest the national elections are dominated by strong leaders, often with business ties, and provide few opportunities for new leaders or ideas. In addition to this, state subsidies for political parties are insufficient. As a result, the parties are largely financed by wealthy businessmen, giving them serious political influence. Members of parliament are organised into eleven commissions whose role it is to draft laws of its own as well as approve government initiatives. It is not uncommon for members of political parties to work together in parliament if they have common interests, even political parties in opposing coalitions. Parliament has extensive powers to scrutinise and influence the policies of the executive government, but members of parliament are often unprepared for the task at hand and little training is available. Political parties, even those in opposition, thus potentially play an important role in terms of policy influencing and the generation of alternative policies that reflect the views of all groups in society. Civil society organisations (CSOs) also play an important role in connecting citizens with political actors. However, in recent years the ability of civil society organizations to effectively influence policy and engage in constructive political activity has been limited. This is partly due to the closed nature of the political system and the influence of business interests.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased trust in the political process by different groups and citizens</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="42" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The most recently available 2012 AsiaBarometer measures public trust in institutions in Indonesia. We choose the level of trust in parties as our baseline measurement, collapsing the categories &#x201C;a great deal&#x201D; and &#x201C;quite a lot&#x201D;. (Source: Zhang-Xu Wang, Institutional Trust in East Asia, Paper for the 2013 Asia Barometer Conference on Democracy and Citizen Politics in East Asia&#x201D;.)</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># of consensual law making processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">The youth (under 45) Parliamentary caucus has not started yet, hence the score of the baseline measurement is zero.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interest in consulting, collaborating, harmonizing, being responsive and a sense of trust and mutual understanding among and between political and civic actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is generally a low level of civil-political consultation in Indonesia. There are exceptions: a number of large NGOs are consulted on a regular basis by government agencies. However, political parties tend to be less responsive to civil society. This is cause for concern in a representative democracy where political parties should be responsive to citizens&#x2019; needs and interests. Likewise, citizens have few avenues to directly voice their concerns and opinions except by voting in elections, which, as discussed above, has little impact when it is always the same familiar faces running for office. Furthermore, the other available avenue for interest aggregatoin from the support base in the post-election such as the recess has not been maximally utilized by the MPs. One specific constraint in this regard is the geographical distance between politicians in Jakarta and their constituents which are dispersed across the enormous archipelago that Indonesia is. Another is that there is an utter lack of trust in the political parties. The general public views political parties as corrupt and ineffective and civil society actors are hesitant to engage with them, afraid to be tainted by association with the political elites. The gap between political parties and civil society is undoubtedly one of the largest obstacles to the development of a democratic culture characterised by responsiveness and accountability.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">% of political actors who indicate that collaborate with other political actors at least 2 times per month</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="100" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">This baseline indicator was measured on the basis of the definition of &#x201C;collaborate&#x201D; in the form of engaging with other political actors through consultation, implementation, in the form of meetings and/or joint action on social/economic/political/religious issues. It was also measured on the basis of how many times did this collaboration happen and how many times did something substantial come out it? From the interviews with 21 young members of parliament belonging to different parties, each one of them indicated that they had conducted at least 4 to 7 times of collaborative activities every month. Some of the interviewed members of parliament said that they conducted it in more than 10 times in a month. However, as already identified as possible limitation in the indicator reference sheets the risk for socially desirable answers is present. When asked in more detail it became clear that these monthly activities not necessarily resulted in concrete results. Only 1 to 2 substantial results came out from these monthly collaborative activities and the rest in some cases led lead to the formulation of follow up recommendations or proposals that would be presented to relevant stakeholders or in the parliamentary processes such as the plennary sessions and commission meetings.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved capacity of local partners (based on adapted 5-Capabilities scan)</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local implementing partner (Kemitraan) increased their score on organization scan (adapted BART)</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="3.84" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative data: Kemitraan&#x2019;s BART Scores 11 April 2016 Capabilities Results Max C1 Commit and Act 3.9 5 C2 Deliver Results 4.0 5 C3 Adapt and Self-Renew 3.5 5 C4 Attract and Relate 4.1 5 C5 Balance coherence and diversity 3.7 5 Qualitative description: Kemitraan shows a relative balance in scores for each of the five capabilities. Such balance can be interpreted as a sign for a healthy organisation. The organisation seems to be strongest in the capabilities that are related to external capabilities, like &#x201C;to attract and relate&#x201D; and &#x201C;to deliver results&#x201D;. The organisation scores the weakest in the more internal capability &#x201C;to adapt and self-renew&#x201D;. Results of organisational scans of other organisations have shown that such slight imbalance of the capabilities is a sign of a transitioning organisation, one that is either expanding or contracting. Kemitraan staff in fact shared that the organisation over the past months of operation has been working on a decreasing number of projects, from 32 projects previously to 17 in 2016. The &#x201C;spider web&#x201D; diagram below provides a more detailed picture of where Kemitraan scores highest and where the organisation scores lowest.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
