<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-25757</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EBG Ghana PCG</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Consistent with the objective of supporting sustainable private sector development, the RSF contributes to high development impact in two key, high-priority areas:   - Development of the financial sector in Sub-Saharan Africa.   Improving the capacity of banks can lead to increased efficiency and stability in the financial markets.  A sound financial sector contributes to the development of the local economy and attracts foreign investment.   - Development of the SME sector.   The SME sector makes up a large share of Ghanas economic output and makes several vital contributions, including the creation of jobs and increasing economic activity. Increased access to finance and capacity building for this sector, facilitated by the program, can lead to higher levels of entrepreneurial activity, private sector development and improvement in economic output.  Furthermore, the project would support the GOGs objective of accelerating poverty reduction by furthering sustainable, equitable economic growth and will:   - increase SME access to medium term finance;  - promote the competitiveness of selected industries, including enhancing linkages and know-how transfer between large businesses and SMEs and working within high potential value chains to alleviate critical bottlenecks identified through careful supply chain analysis;  - promote a conducive business environment for domestic and foreign investment;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a joint project involving IDA, IFC and the Government of Ghana (GoG), consisting of a Risk Sharing Facility (RSF) of up to the local currency equivalent of $6.25 million ($12.5 million portfolio size) for Ecobank Ghana Ltd (EBG) to be used to support lending to Small and Medium Enterprises (SME).  The RSF will cover up to 50% of the credit risk of Ecobanks portfolio of new SME loans, with IDA funds of up to $1.25 million covering up to 10% of the first loss risk. Ecobank will assume the 50% of the balance of the credit risk of the portfolio.  In addition to the guarantee, the project envisages two technical assistance (TA) components:    - TA to Ecobank, with the objective of transferring the necessary skills and procedures to better service the SME sector and thus enhance the banks capacity to underwrite new SME loans on a profitable and sustainable basis; and   - TA to SMEs, which aims to help bridge the gap between the SMEs and the banks by providing some basic financial and management training to the SMEs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECOBANK GHANA LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-25757" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-11-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head SME, Ecobank Ghana Ltd 19, Seventh Avenue Ridge West P.M.B , GPO Accra, Ghana  Tel: (233)-21- 681146-8, 680426-7, 681166  Dir: (233)-21- 681182</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="GH-Ghana">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project site is located in Accra at the following address: Ecobank Ghana Ltd, 19, Seventh Avenue, Ridge West, Accra, Ghana. The project company is headquartered in Accra and has 25 branches across the country.  The investment will be made across all the branches of the Bank.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.1000004000 -1.2000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AC - Commercial Banking - Microfinance and Small Business</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $6.28 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="912"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2008-11-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-11-27">6280000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2008-11-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2008-11-27">6280000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ECOBANK GHANA LTD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="912"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/25757/ebg-ghana-pcg">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
