<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-30228</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TICO Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project consists of the conversion of the Takoradi II (T2 or TICO) plant from its current 2x 110 MW simple cycle configuration to a 330 MW combined cycle plant through the addition of a 110 MW steam turbine (in addition to two heat recovery steam generators and other related equipment). T2 is currently being converted to dual fuel capability, to run both on natural gas and Light Crude Oil (LCO) -the plant has a 10-year history of successfully running on LCO only. The conversion of TICO to combined cycle operation will allow the plant to generate an additional 110 MW of power without any incremental fuel consumption.   TICO is the developer, owner and operator of the existing T2 plant.   The Project is located in Aboadze, Takoradi, in the Western Region of Ghana, on a site adjacent to an existing 330 MW thermal power plant (&quot;Takoradi I&quot; or T1) owned and operated by the Volta River Authority (VRA).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is expected to have a number of major benefits, including:  (a) Increased supply of electricity to support Ghanas growing economy at a more efficient cost  the Project involves the increase of the existing plant capacity from 220MW to 330MW, with no additional fuel requirements (since a combined cycle operation utilizes waste heat from the simple cycle generation)- with the ultimate benefit of a lower cost of energy for the consumers. (b )Further diversification of Ghana electricity supply away from over-reliance on hydro power generation (with the attendant rainfall driven variations in supply), as well as utilization of gas resources from Ghana and the region, with the planned conversion of the plant to dual fuel mode  gas and LCO.  (c) Supports the growth of private sector investment in Ghanas power sector, with positive signals for future investments. (d) Positive climate impact through avoided C02 emissions, by increasing the plants energy output capacity with no incremental fuel requirements.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TAKORADI INTERNATIONAL COMPANY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-30228" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-07-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-02-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Osafo Adjei, General Manager, Takoradi International Company LLC, P.O.Box 2204, Takoradi, GHANA  Telephone: : +233 24 3866733</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="GH-Ghana">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is located in Aboadze, Takoradi, in the Western Region of Ghana, about 220 km southwest of the nations capital, Accra.  Takoradi is home to a major port, Takoradi Port, and is connected to the 678 km West Africa Gas Pipeline, which will supply gas from Nigeria. Takoradi is located about 140 km east of Bonyere, from where a gas pipeline is planned to transport gas from Ghanas recent off-shore discoveries.   The Project will be developed on a brown-field site which currently houses the T1 and T2 plants. T2 is located adjacent to, and west of, T1. The site is easily accessible through existing roads.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.1000004000 -1.2000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AD - Light Fuel Oil - Thermal Power Generation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $105.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-07-13"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-07-13">105000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-07-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2012-07-13">105000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TAKORADI INTERNATIONAL COMPANY</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/30228/tico-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
