<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-9681</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AEF PHARMA CARE PRODUCTS LIMITED</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SUMMARY OF PROJECT INFORMATION (SPI)     Project Name			Ghana  Pharmacare     Region			Sub-Saharan Africa	    Sector				Manufacturing    Project No.			009681    Projected Board Date	June 25, 1999    Company Name		Pharmacare Industries Limited    Major Shareholders   	Messrs Ghopal Valecha, Ghanaian, and Mahesh Bhojwani, Indian are sponsors of the project and equally own Pharma Care.    Project Cost including proposed IFC investment   	Total company capital expenditure is estimated at US$1.4 million.  IFC has been approached to provide a loan of  US$0.5 million.    Location of project and Description of site   	The company is located in Accra, the capital of Ghana.  The project will be sited on a 1.5 acre in the South Industrial Area of Accra..    Description of Company and Purpose of Project   Pharmacare is the second company in Accra, other than Lever Brothers Limited, set up to manufacture and distribute toothpaste for both domestic and export markets. The company started production in May 1997.   	The project is an expansion to increase production of toothpaste from 40 tons/month to about 100 tons/month and produce about 1.5 million empty collapsible tubes/month. This will involve the acquisition of equipment, construction of a new warehouse and renovation of the existing factory.    Environmental Categories and Issues    This is a Category B project according to IFCs environmental review procedure because a limited number of specific environmental impacts may result from this project.  The following potential environmental, social, safety and health impacts of the project were analyzed:    &#xB7;	  site selection and previous use;   &#xB7;	  water and power supply;   &#xB7;	  effluent disposal and solid waste management;   &#xB7;	  fuel and chemical storage;   &#xB7;	  general housekeeping and equipment safeguarding; and   &#xB7;	  fire protection, workers health and life safety.    The information about how these potential impacts are addressed by the sponsor is summarized in the paragraph that follows.    The previously developed site is located in an industrial estate, adjacent to the South Ring Road.  The site is surrounded by others industries. Water and electric power will be supplied by the existing local utility infrastructure (GWSC and ECG), although 350 KVa back-up power generation will be provided on-site. Sanitary sewage, factory effluents and office wastewater are treated on-site in two septic tanks with appropriately designed drainfield systems.  Clean wastewater from other sources will be discharged to a storm drain connected to the drainage network of the industrial area.  Domestic solid waste generated will be periodically collected by the municipal authorities and industrial refusals are collected by a private waste management. An intermediate waste disposal area is located on site.  All raw materials in clearly labeled containers will be stored in a newly constructed warehouse adequately ventilated. No Ozone Depleting Substances (e.g., CFCs) will be used in refrigeration, air conditioning, or fire-fighting equipment on the premises. Adequate fire protection and fighting equipment and life safety measures are incorporated into the buildings. Employees will be trained in all environmental, health, and safety issues associated with the operation.    Based on its review of available information regarding potential environmental impacts and proposed mitigation measures, IFC concludes that the proposed project will meet World Bank Group environmental, health and safety policies and guidelines and Ghanaian environmental requirements. IFC will monitor ongoing compliance with World Bank environmental, health and safety policies and guidelines during the lifetime of the project by evaluating monitoring reports submitted annually to IFC by the sponsor and by conducting periodic site reviews during project supervision.    Date SPI sent to PIC		May 25, 1999    For additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit     telephone (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365.  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PharmaCare Industries Company Limited</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-9681" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-03-29" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-07-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="GH-Ghana">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>8.1000004000 -1.2000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FA - Pharmaceuticals and Medicine</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $0.40 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-03-29"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-03-29">400000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-03-29">400000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PharmaCare Industries Company Limited</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/9681/aef-pharma-care-products-limited">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
