<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-40781218-DAPGMMM</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-40781218" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund for Nature Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar Energy Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for a situation where civil society is influencing policies and monitors enforcement to ensure that natural resources are used sustainably; a situation where policy frameworks contribute to increased renewable energy and energy access where private sector actors are increasingly acting responsible; all together underpinning a green economy approach that leads to increased human wellbeing both in programme intervention areas and in Myanmar in general. A transformation to a green economy that doesn&#x2019;t harm the local communities and the natural resources they depend on but support them will require a shift in energy policy and planning to an increased focus on renewable energy and off-grid electricity generation that can deliver energy to remote areas. Hereby an improved effort on solar and wind power, of which Myanmar has great potential. For WWF to influence energy policy and planning in Myanmar it will require strong strategic partnerships, and alliances with civil society and private sector, and the development innovate pilots, particularly in off-grid, that can be replicated and demonstrate the possibilities of renewable energy to government stakeholders. The two main components are therefore, i) National level policy advocacy, and ii) Energy access using sustainable power within Dawna Tenasserim Landscape.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-40781218" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund for Nature Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the &#x2018;Myanmar Energy Programme&#x2019; WWF is engaged at both a national and regional scale, especially focusing on Kayin State and Tanintharyi Region.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="7: AFFORDABLE AND CLEAN ENERGY" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-01-01">1375000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2019-01-01">1325000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2020-01-01">1325000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2021-01-01">1325000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
