<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-40781218-DAPGMVNEG</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-40781218" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund for Nature Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam Energy Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam has had the fastest growing greenhouse gas emissions level in the Greater Mekong Region over the last ten years and the country continues to rely heavily on coal power. According to government plans, coal power will further increase in years to come. As demand grows, and the share of fossil fuels in the energy supply mix increases, environmental impacts and challenges will increase significantly, along with detrimental health issues. In addition, security of energy supply is impacted as Vietnam becomes dependent on imported coal. Vietnam is highly vulnerable to climate change, ranking eighth in the Global Climate Risk Index, which considers cost in loss of gross domestic product and human lives. Despite the devastating facts the climate change mitigation commitments are relatively low. To key challenges are lacking public awareness concerning negative impacts caused by unsustainable energy production and the decision-making processes on energy sector lacking transparency and mechanisms to include CSO, the private sector, and other stakeholders. Therefore, it is WWF&#x2019;s vision to engage civil society to advocate for a socially just transition to a green energy sector, with reduced dependence on fossil fuels, for the long-term sustainable development of people and nature in Vietnam.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-40781218" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund for Nature Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The &#x2018;Vietnam Energy Programme&#x2019; is primarily advocating at a national level. At a regional level the programme has activities in An Giang, Soc Trang, Bac Lieu, Ca Mau and Hu&#xE9;.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="7: AFFORDABLE AND CLEAN ENERGY" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-01-01">1040000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2019-01-01">980000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2020-01-01">980000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2021-01-01">980000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
