<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="DKK" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>DK-CVR-40781218-DAPEAKEMA</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="DK-CVR-40781218" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund for Nature Denmark</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya Marine Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim for a desired situation where civil society influence policy and market decisions to ensure that the marine resources are used and managed in a sustainable way to the benefit of the marine resources and the resource dependent communities in the Coastal Kenya region. For the fisheries sector, unsustainable fishing practices, illegal, unregulated and unreported fishing, unsustainable financial flows and market failures are identified as key challenges. Many important marine species are either fully exploited or overexploited and mangroves, sea beds and coral reefs are highly impacted or destroyed, harming not only the marine biodiversity but also the livelihoods of coastal communities. Beyond the impacts caused directly by marine activities, there are also several land-based threats (e.g. sedimentation, pollution and water abstractions) as well as the global phenomenon of climate change that is increasingly being felt in the coastal and marine areas. WWF expect to contribute to the following outcomes i) Partner CSOs/CBOs/coalitions and platforms within the marine and energy sectors have been strengthened and consolidated to analyze, monitor and advocate for sustainable use and management of natural resources. ii) WWF and partners are engaging more effectively and play a larger role in decision making in policy dialogues within marine and energy sectors especially regarding the use of, rights to and management of marine resources. iii) Increased equity and rights for young and adult women and men in decision making regarding use and management of natural resources in the energy and marine sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="DK-CVR-40781218" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Wide Fund for Nature Denmark</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The programme is centered around four counties; Lamu, Kilifi, Mombasa and Kwale located in Kenya&#x2019;s coastal region.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="14: LIFE BELOW WATER" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2018-01-01">1730000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2019-01-01">1640000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2020-01-01">1640000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="DKK" value-date="2021-01-01">1640000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
