<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/SA1/WASH-P/NGO/16533</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of Multi sector integrated Protection and WASH interventions for  vulnerable IDP returnees , Refugees and Host community a in North Abyie</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Interventions is designed in line with GAH 2020 HRP, it aims at to contribute in improvement of the general conditions and enhances resilience through improvement of restoring access to basic protection and WASH services for 46,456 vulnerable people (nomads, Host communities, Returnees, SSR and IDPs) in Abyei PCA and reduce mortality and morbidity related to water prone diseases, as well to build North Abyie communities resilience and improve their access to basic services as well enhance the prevention and mitigation of protection risks and respond to their protection needs through quality and principled humanitarian action intervention through a mult-sectorial and integrated interventions. The project will improve access to CP emergency and prevention services to reduce the incidents and effect of violence, exploitation and abuse. Vulnerable children will be provided with adequate psycho-social support at constructed/rehabilitated CFSs, schools and at the community level. GAH will also enhance the protection capacity of the of communities to identify, report , respond and prevent different protection risks and concerns by sensitization and training of CBCPNs to act and respond better to CP issues, strengthening referral and working with other community based structures.
In WASH the project will enhance the access to safe water supply in Abyie through rehabilitation, operation and maintenance of existing water points, improve the capacity of community committees members to manage and take care of WASH services through establish and training of WASH committees, conduct Water Hygiene awareness and household hygiene sessions, organize clean-up campaigns, Distribution of cleaning and sanitation tools and kits. Rehabilitation and replacement of existing School and HF latrines and hand washing unites. GAH ensure that all WASH interventions will be accessible by all community including children , PLM and persons with disability. For GBV identified and selected vulnerable  women  will be provided with cash support to empower their purchase  power   to pay for their essential goods and services , more over community base structures ,  service providers  CBO will be trained  on how to mainstream the gender during the service provision,In general protection  vulnerable persons with specific need  will be supported with cash assistants, persons with disability will be supported with assistive devices  because Abyei area has history of conflicts between the ethnic groups peace building and community stabilization will be mainstreamed although project interventions and activities to insure that the provided services are not doing any harm and not raising any dispute between the communities in the area.This project will complement the efforts and investment through the other SHF funded project to ensure the aspect of integration and utilization of the provided funding. As well the protection interventions will also be complemented by the UNICEF proposed interventions in th coming period especially with regard to the Family Tracing and Reunification hence we did not included in this project</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abuzar Abdallah</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249912155946</telephone>
   <email>gah.su.director@globalaidhand</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SD19101006">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abyei</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>9.59500000 28.43600000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="31" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="11" percentage="69" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-09-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-17">187706.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-08-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-17">376965.07</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-16533">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-17">564671.95</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304742857">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-09-22">338803.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Aid Hand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
