<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-20/HSD20/ RA6/FSL-E/INGO/17959</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New accessible areas in the Two Areas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children is among the first organisations to respond to the humanitarian situation in South Kordofan (Nuba mountains). SCI will take an active role in the coordination effort for the responses in the areas, to avoid duplication, secure better coordination and make sure efficient/timely responses to the needs. 

FSL Intervention
SCI will implement activities to support families in producing food that can be harvested in a short period of time. The team will assist farmers to access early maturing varieties, adaptable to the existing climatic situations and help to improve the food consumption of the households in a short period of time. The main focus will be in creating capacity to produce food through the input support (staple crops and some vegetable kits) and farm tools to accelerate the land preparation/harvesting of the crop. Farmers will be trained in better farming techniques and improved post-harvest management systems. SC will encourage the participation of women attending the trainings to improve women&apos;s participation and agency in decisions. The market related interventions will contribute to create stronger ties between the producers and buyers, that helps to increase their income. 
The FSL intervention will reach 20,000 people (4,000 households with an average family size of five). 
&#x27A2; Improved seed supports such as sorghum, ground nut, vegetable seeds (Okra, Onion, tomato, watermelon)
&#x27A2; Farm tools support (hand hoe, spade, fork, wheelbarrow)
&#x27A2; Training on farming techniques
&#x25CB; conservation farming and post-harvest management 
&#x27A2; Market linkage and facilitation
&#x25CB; Market price sharing and networking with wholesalers and retailers 
Local suppliers will be selected and interested traders will be invited to be involved in the voucher fair. All participants who accept the code of conduct and respect the policies of the organisation will be allowed to take part. The target community will be trained on how to exchange the vouchers and the timeline will be agreed. Field officers and development workers will help the target community if they face any technical difficulties. The voucher fair will be open for a few days to avoid any duplication or theft of the printed vouchers. After the fair days, the suppliers will submit their documents, payments will be made after verification of the documents. 
Farmers will be trained by extension agents in collaboration with the ministry of agriculture on conservation farming and better storage methods. Practical visits and farm demonstrations will be conducted to facilitate the learning process. 
Markets will play a critical role for the success of the farmers. By creating and strengthening bridges with buyers and sellers, farmers will be able to improve their incomes, which will help to equip the producers with up-to-date market price and increase their profit margins. 

Education Intervention:
This intervention aims to increase the access to safe, inclusive and quality education for vulnerable girls and boys. The Education authority in Kauda has prioritized five schools in five Payams of Heiban locality Jangul, Karindi, Sarbule, Hajar-bago and kulbira in Kauda, Heiban, Kumbur, Alazraka, Dabbi Payams respectively. The total students of these nine schools are 2757 (1384 boys, 1373 girls). Also a total of 75 teachers (56 males, 19 females) and 76 PTA member , in addition to newly mother group established of 50 women going to be to be directly supported, through different capacity building programme, as well as necessary teaching and kits materials.:
&#x27A2; Construction/Rehabilitation of schools&#x2019; classrooms, sensitive latrines and other facilities.
&#x27A2; Capacity building for teachers and schools&#x2019; headmasters
&#x27A2; Provision of school supplies include learning, teaching and recreational materials.
&#x27A2; Enhance the community engagement to support improving the quality of education, through establishment/reactivation of PTAs as well as to establish MG to support learning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-18" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Davina.Jeffery</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PDQ Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+44 7887 520027</telephone>
   <email>davina.jeffery@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Waeil Musa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Specialist PDQ</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249912536800</telephone>
   <email>waeil.musa@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yusra Rahmatalla</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PDQ Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249916583379</telephone>
   <email>yusra.bashir@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU18">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Kordofan</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>11.19901920 29.41793240</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="50" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-18"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-05">499963.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-17959">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-05">499963.5</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3304911811">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-02-09">299978.1</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2020" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
