<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-36627</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myingyan Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">-	Reducing power deficit: the Project will help to address the current severe power shortage in Myanmar.  -	Energy efficiency: The combined-cycle gas turbine to be built is much more energy efficient than the other single-cycle gas power plants in the country and will help to reduce overall GHG Emissions. -	Employment generation: The project will create significant employment opportunities during the construction and operational phases. -	Private sector development: The project is the first IPP project in Myanmar to be awarded on the basis of a competitive bidding process.  The success of the project will demonstrate the sustainability of public and private sector partnerships in the power sector in Myanmar to power developers and operators, and help attract more capital flows into the country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation (IFC) is considering up to US$ 45 million of debt financing to build, own and operate a greenfield 225 MW Combined Cycle Gas Turbine (CCGT) power plant in the Mandalay region of Myanmar (the Project). The Project will be developed by a consortium of Sembcorp Utilities Pte. Ltd. (Sembcorp Utilities or Sponsor) and MMID Utilities Pte. Ltd. (MMID) under a special purpose vehicle which will be established in Myanmar for the sole purpose of developing and operating the Project (Project Company).   The 225MW CCGT will include two sets of Gas Turbine (GT) units; two sets of Heat Recovery Steam Generator (HRSG); one steam turbine generating unit with associated auxiliary equipment; a switchyard area; cooling Water System; demineralized Water System; and wastewater treatment facility.  The gas supply pipeline will connect the power plant to an existing gas receiving station located approximately 1.6 km away. A 230kV overhead transmission line, approximately 3 km in length, will connect the power plant to the upgraded Myingyan Steel Mill sub-station located within an existing adjacent steel mill complex.   Construction is expected to start in the first quarter of 2016 and be completed in approximately 22 months, with commercial operations targeted for the first quarter of 2018. A consortium of EPC contractors will be appointed to undertake the engineering, procurement and construction activities of the project.   The Operation and Maintenance (O&amp;M) of the project will be undertaken by the sponsor with the support of a long term service agreement (LTSA) for the GT with the manufacturer.   Core project facilities will together occupy a footprint of about 11.6 hectares. The power plant site is situated within a larger 280 ha Government owned and operated steel mill site.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SEMBCORP UTILITIES PTE LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-36627" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-08" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Name: Aung Lwin Oo Email Address:  mailto:alo.mdy70@gmail.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">To be determined.</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="MM-Myanmar">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project is located in Taungtha, a township of Myingyan District in Mandalay Division.  It is 108 km to Mandalay City and 226 km to Naypyitaw, the administrative capital of Myanmar.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>21.0000000000 96.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="2211" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">V-AB - Gas - Thermal Power Generation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $75.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/36627/myingyan-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SII/36627/myingyan-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
