<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-26678</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Topic Tunisia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Fit with the World Bank Group Strategy:     The World Banks most recent Country Assistance Strategy (CAS) for Tunisia, proposes to help the Government of Tunisia (GoT) address three challenges:   - strengthen the business environment to support the development of a more competitive, internationally integrated private sector and improve competitiveness of the Tunisian economy;  - enhance skills and employability of graduates and labor force in a knowledge economy; and  - improve the quality of social services through increased efficiency of public expenditures.  IFCs strategy in Tunisia is to focus on where IFC can add value and foster private sector development especially in sectors currently not properly serviced by Tunisian commercial banks, including the oil and gas sector. The proposed IFC investment is therefore fully consistent with this strategy.  - Development Impact:    - Benefits to Government of Tunisia The project is expected to provide GoT with considerable revenues from TOPICs operations in HelM, through the collection of a 10-15% royalty and a 50-75% profit tax (current estimate of about $133 million in revenues to GoT by end of 2012 under IFCs base case).  TOPIC will also have an obligation, as per Tunisias Hydrocarbon Code, to sell 20% of its oil production to the local Tunisian market at a 10% discount to international prices.  - Direct and indirect local employment and training:    The proposed project and continued growth of the company is expected to bring direct and indirect local employment and training.  It is estimated that the development of HelM alone will generate 200 direct and indirect jobs during construction and 100 during operations. All TOPICs staff are currently Tunisian and it is expected that at least 90% of direct and indirect jobs created will be local.  - Local supplier linkages / community development:    The proposed project is expected to benefit local communities by way of purchases of local goods and services.  For example, the construction of the production facility for HelM will be built at the port of Sfax, in Tunisia, and will require substantial inputs from local industrial and marine subcontractors.  Over 50% of Project capex is expected to be sourced locally.  - Promoting local independent player:    The project will support one of the very few locally-owned private sector North African upstream companies and help it grow and reach international best practice on environmental and social issues and corporate governance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOPIC, S.A. (TOPIC or the company) is a small Tunisian oil and gas exploration and production (E&amp;P) company, with interest in three oil and gas blocks in Tunisia:   - 100% interest in the offshore Halk el Menzel (HelM) concession block;  - 15% interest in the onshore Jelma exploration block; and  - 50% interest in the onshore Douleb West prospecting block.    The company is not currently producing from any of its blocks.   IFC has been requested to provide a financing package to the company to partially fund TOPICs 2008-2011 investment program, which includes:   - the development of an oil discovery in HelM;  - acquisition of seismic data and drilling of exploration wells at HelM and TOPICs other blocks; and  - further business development activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOPIC SA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-26678" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-01-05" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2009-12-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Mohamed Toumi Chief Executive Officer TOPIC SA  Immeuble SAADI , Tour AB, Appt 26  1082 El Menzah IV Tunis  Tunisie     T&#xE9;l : (+216) 71 23 05 03  Fax : (+216) 71 23 05 13 www.topic-energy.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tunisia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="TN-Tunisia">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">IFCs financing will be used for further exploration and development of TOPICs various assets. The HelM concession block covers an offshore area of 570 km2 in the Gulf of Hammamet in northern Tunisia. The field lies approximately 70 kilometers north east of the city of Monastir. The Jelma onshore exploration block covers 7,216 km2 and is located in central west Tunisia. The block neighbors the mature Douleb, Semmama and Tamesmida fields that have been in production since the mid 1960s.  The onshore 224 km2 Douleb West prospecting block is also located in central west Tunisia.  The company is headquartered in Tunis, Tunisia.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>34.0000000000 9.0000000000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Oil and Gas Production (Includes Development)</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="510"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-01-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-01-05">11500000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2009-01-05"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2009-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-01-05">18500000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-01-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-01-05">11500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOPIC SA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2009-01-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2009-01-05">18500000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TOPIC SA</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="510"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/26678/topic-tunisia">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
