<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SSD208</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for church-led peacebuilding in South Sudan 2020-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be implemented by CA as lead agency in partnership with CAFOD and Tr&#xF3;caire in Partnership (CTP), working closely with the SSCC to support the APP (Action Plan for Peace), with other partners and technical experts providing expertise related to specific activities. It will continue to build on the two years and five months of implementation and accompaniment, enabling the partners to capitalise on strong relationships and maximise the impact of work completed during previous project phases. 
This project will support both ICCs and national level reconciliation to:
- Increase technical and core capacity through the roll out of the universal tools and methodologies based on capacity strengthening framework  and MandE framework  (completed in the previous project phase) across SSCC structures, supporting improved coordination and information sharing through regional platforms of ICCs, and strengthening sustainability. 
- Deepen grassroots engagement through accompanying ICCs to implement the APP to address conflict and build peace at the local level through targeting of remote and mobile communities and effort will be placed to make use of the underutilised potential of women and youth desks at the Secretariat to mobilise critical mass of women and youth at state level to regular rallies, raise awareness and advocate for peace and local issues affecting women and youth. 

The SSCC also coordinates with other actors, and its ability to do this will increase as capacity increases. At the national level, its representatives meet with a wide range of stakeholders (NGO and humanitarian actors, academic institutions, other faith actors, UNMISS, government and opposition representatives, diplomats and donors) and participate in different fora, including representation in peace mechanisms such as RJMEC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD208" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD208" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSD208" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-16">59944.54</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="54129">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-17">59944.54</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
