<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SSD272</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD Food Crisis Appeal for vulnerable households in Tonj North and South</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will target 1,000 vulnerable households recently affected by the flood crisis and as well, scale-up famine response in Tonj North and South. This project will be implemented in complementarity with other funding; CAFOD Appeal, CGF and Tr&#xF3;caire E10% grant. The project will target highly vulnerable households and individuals including women, older people, children, adolescents and young people, people living with disabilities (PLWD), internally displaced people, households from host community hosting large number of IDPs and facing similar level of vulnerability, and individuals with low economic status who experience a greater level of risk. Children, women, and girls who lost or are separated from primary caregivers due to conflict are at increased risk of neglect, abandonment, health risks, violence, and exploitation, and are more likely to suffer mental health and psychosocial distress, and malnutrition; as such, they will be targeted for intervention. The recently displaced persons as a result of the current flood crisis in Tonj will be key focus of this project. Targeting will be based on humanitarian principles of humanity and impartiality, to save lives and alleviate suffering with aid being provided based on need, in proportion to identified needs. In addition to community-based targeting mechanisms, the project will employ institutional targeting mechanisms and for this it will collaborate with nutrition and health actors to identify households with malnourished children. A participatory and consultative approach will be used to agree targeting criteria that ensures the most vulnerable individuals/households are identified and benefit from this support, building on the methodology used in previous CTP interventions. Clear vulnerability criteria will be set and during the process. The targeting criteria will also be informed by the various IRNA reports and OWG response review meetings reports of Greater Tonj.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD272" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD272" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSD272" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14030" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-08-01">1224.64</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="55366">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-10-10">1224.64</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
