<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SSD176</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Financial support for the position of Administrative Officer and Finance Officer</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The South Sudan Council of Churches (SSCC) is in the process of implementation of the Action Plan for Peace (APP) through delivery of 4 programme outcomes relating to advocacy, neutral forum, reconciliation and institutional capacity strengthening. Through this church-based, nation-wide and multi-stakeholder engagement action, the South Sudan Council of Churches envisage the realisation of a peaceful resolution of conflict and restoration of peace in South Sudan.  The first phase of the Action Plan for Peace 2016-2017 has ended and SSCC is now implementing a new phase 2018-2021 through annual funding of ecumenical partners including Norwegian Church Aid, Catholic Relief Services, Finn Church Aid, CAFOD and Trocaire Partnership (CTP) and Christian Aid, and PAX, all working collaboratively under the structure Core Group whose work is to mobile funding and provide technical support to SSCC in the implementation of the APP. 
Given the peace agreement signed, the SSCC would like to scale up its operation in Equatorial region and Malakal. The council under capacity strengthening outcomes, would like to request Caford/Trocare partnership to support administration officer at head office and finance officers for Equatorial region.
The position of Administrative Officer existed since 2016 when the APP was launched and followed by the recruitment. This position offers overall administrative support to the General Secretary and generally to SSCC Secretariat. It is conveniently located within the office of the General Secretary offering day to day clerical and administrative duties to support the effective functioning of the office of the head office. The position contributes to the effective work of the head office, hence contribute to the overall efficient management of the APP. This position was previously covered by the EU grant support to institutional strengthening of the SSCC but this funding will formally ends in December 2018, and no confirmation has been made for renewal.
The stability in all l regions is paving the way for full implementation of APP activities in all the location. Secondly, if the peace process holds and return of refugees from Uganda is effected, there will be high expectation on the council to promote reconciliation among communities. As part of preparedness, SSCC would like to recruits finance officer for equatorial region who will be based at the head office. The finance officer will be responsible for managing all financial records of the region including partners and donor funds for implementation of activities in the region and also give support to the finance department at the head office. The finance officer will report directly to Finance manager at SSCC headquarters and shall administrative supervised by regional coordinator equatorial region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD176" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD176" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Council of Churches</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSD176" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="60" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">30000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="51595">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">12000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="51594">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">18000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="66063">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">30000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Sudan Council of Churches</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
