<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-285776-SSD140</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-285776" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support for church-led peacebuilding in South Sudan pilot</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will be implemented through a partnership between CA and CTP, with CA as lead agency, working with SSCC to strengthen APP implementation at local level.

The national secretariat facilitates the implementation of its APP. Through its national structure, regional offices, and community-level Inter-Church Committees (ICCs), and the hundreds of local churches within its membership, the SSSC reaches millions of South Sudanese. Membership of the ICCs comprise local representatives of SSCC member churches. CA and CTP will work closely with the SSCC and its member churches to support ICCs through accompaniment, building capacity, and enabling them to connect with and inform the national strategy for the APP. As part of this, CA and CTP will also work with the national secretariat to further strengthen overall implementation of the APP at the national level.

The SSCC Core Group  is a loose forum of ACT Alliance and CARITAS network members and other faith-based organisations whose role is to accompany the SSCC as it strengthens its organisational capacity and implements the APP. CA and CTP will prioritise effective coordination with implementing Core Group partners to maximise ability to deliver positive results.

This pilot project will focus on support for two local ICCs and their associated Regional Office to assess and build their capacity to implement the pillars of the APP. This five month pilot phase of the project will build the foundation for a two-year programme of support for the APP, including: best practice in capacity assessment and support for ICCs in developing training modules around pillar methodologies; learning from how the four pillars interact and inform each other when implemented at local level to inform national strategic approaches; demonstrating how voices and experiences from the local level should feed back into national implementation and analysis &#x2013; especially advocacy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD140" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="SSD140" ref="GB-CHC-285776" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Catholic Agency For Overseas Development (CAFOD)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="GB-COH-04105827-AIDMATCHII" ref="GB-COH-04105827" role="3" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MannionDaniels</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-1" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK government</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="SSD140" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>cafod@cafod.org.uk</email>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15180" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="50" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="99810" percentage="20" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-15">8517.24</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="50626">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-15">8517.24</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-CHC-285776">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAFOD General Funds</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
