<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-9-VN-F13AP00915</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-based habitat preservation for the Yellow-cheeked Crested Gibbon within Vietnam&apos;s Bu Gia Map National Park</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. Programs in this element should be integrated with the Agriculture Area under Economic Growth and Conflict Mitigation and Reconciliation Area under the Peace and Security Category, when applicable and appropriate.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This award strives to conserve biodiversity and manage natural resources in ways that maintain their long-term viability and preserve their potential to meet the needs of present and future generations. Activities include combating illegal and corrupt exploitation of natural resources and the control of invasive species. This includes The purpose of this project is to maintain the habitats of the yellow-cheeked crested gibbon within the Bu Gia Map National Park by changing local people&#x2019;s attitudes regarding wildfire prevention and suppression. This will be done by: 1. continuing to improve the relationships between communities and forest rangers as a way to prevent wildfire in Bu Gia Map National Park; 2. training at least 50% of local people to effectively manage fire inside the park&#x2019;s forests; 3. training at least eighty percent of the households residing near the park&#x2019;s forests to understand the risk of wildfire and how to suppress fires; 4. regularly monitoring the most flammable sites in the park to prevent wildfire during the dry season; 5. and equipping the most flammable areas in the park with signboards to help local people prevent wildfires..</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XI-DUNS-555341655" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BU GIA MAP NATIONAL PARK</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>555341655</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Fish and Wildlife Service/Office of International Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>888-678-6836</telephone>
   <email>feedback@ios.doi.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.doi.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11849 C Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20240</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. assistance will support governance reforms that broaden economic participation, make growth more sustainable, improve labor conditions, facilitate engagement by the private sector and civil society, promote respect for human rights and the rule of law, and expand accountability and transparency. U.S. assistance will help the government address climate change and remediation of contaminated sites, promote biodiversity conservation, combat HIV/AIDS, and make significant investments in higher education and health to improve the livelihoods and well-being of vulnerable groups, particularly persons with disabilities (PWDs). U.S. assistance will also promote regional stability and security by increasing bilateral military cooperation on maritime security, maritime law enforcement, border security, and counter-terrorism; addressing unexploded ordnance; and building capacity in the justice sector, law enforcement, counternarcotics, and nonproliferation of Weapons of Mass Destruction (WMD).</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-01">47100</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-10-23">23000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">One-time obligation</narrative>
   </description>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2013-08-22"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
