<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-21/HSD20/SA1/P-E/INGO/18845</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated life saving education, GBV and Child protection for  vulnerable flood affected and refugee  in El Salam, Kosti, Al Jabalain, AD Diwaim and Guli localities  in White Nile State(GBV 25%,CP 25%).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">White Nile hosts for over 175,000 refugees living in nine camps, where roughly half of  the refugees are women and girls, who are disproportionately affected by both disasters and violent conflicts. During and after crises, pre-existing gender inequality and discrimination create particular challenges for women and girls. They face particular protection risks such as heightened risk of violence, exploitation and abuse, as well as high levels of stigma, social norms forced early marriage, FGM etc. Large parts of white Nile have been affected by above average floods last year, destroying homes, schools and livelihoods creating critical humanitarian gaps.  The project targets prioritized localities Guli, Kosti, Ad Dweim, El Salam Al Rawat and El Jabalain- El Genaa camp with under-funded sectors CP, GBV and Education.The project targets 4947 individuals of which 1497 are refugees 90% of them children who require case management, CP referral and family placement for UASCs 2527 are children(1000 boys and 1527 girls) and 3450 other flood affected community members. It aims to support women, girls and boys so that they feel protected and safe and are willing to return to education. This will be achieved by increasing access to education facilities and improving child protection and GBV services to support children and survivors of GBV in four localities in White Nile, specifically, El Salam, Al Jabalain, Kosti, AD Diwaim and Guli. Plan International will rehabilitate 8 classrooms in the White Nile, provision of recreational and teacher kits, classroom furniture, and teachers&apos; and Parent Teacher Training (PTA)s training in Teacher in Crisis Context (TiCC). This will be done with the aim of increasing school enrolment. Gender sensitive latrines will also be rehabilitated ensuring the needs of children with disabilities are considered. The schools will also be safe spaces for children through adequate COVID-19 prevention measures as well as establishing Child Protection (CP) and GBV referral systems that link schools to community protection structures. Furthermore, Plan International will provide case management services for unaccompanied and separated children, other vulnerable groups such as child headed households, child and adolescent survivors of GBV, capacity building mentoring of frontline workers Community Based Organisations (CBO)s and Civil Society Organisations (CSO)s on CP minimum standards, caring for child survivors of GBV, psychosocial support services, mental health and life skills interventions for children and adolescents/ referral pathway for child protection will be updated in the two localities through service mapping. Plan will provide life-saving services to vulnerable women and girls including GBV survivors (referrals), by strengthening referral pathways in the two localities that lack such mechanisms. Frontline GBV service providers, social workers and CBO/CSO members will be trained on Prevention of Sexual Harassment Exploitation and Abuse (PSHEA), GBV, gender main-streaming, psycho-social support, and case management including clinical management of rape using case management and GBV minimum standards.  Women will be supported to organize into groups creating safe spaces around community centres to actively work against GBV among their peers, demystify the social stigma of reporting such cases and empower them by establishing,  linkages informal and formal system between women&#x2019;s groups, community based child protection networks (CBCPN)s, family and child protection units (FCPU), other relevant police departments, trauma centres, and clinics treating GBV survivors to ensure GBV survivors are referred to appropriate services in the targeted localities. The project will ensure accountability to affected populations through tailored CFRM mechanisms that are accessible to children, women, PSNs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Massar Charity Organization for Nomads Development and Environmental Conservation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aaron Broyde</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grants Officer</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+353830673248</telephone>
   <email>aaron.broyde@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anika Krstic</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249900921404</telephone>
   <email>anika.krstic@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Misgana Amanuel</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Business Development</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249123508852</telephone>
   <email>misgana.amanuel@plan-international.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU25">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">White Nile</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>13.24038810 32.53727410</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="3" percentage="29" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="71" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-12-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-27">35027.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-11-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-27">389973.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-18845">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-27">425000.61</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305357086">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-29">255000.37</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plan International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
