<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-21/HSD20/SA1/WASH/INGO/18744</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Darfur WASH and Integrated Emergency Rapid Response  Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Central Darfur WASH, and Integrated Emergency Rapid Response and Anticipatory Actions   is designed to address core humanitarian issues affecting most vulnerable among Returnees, IDPs, and Host community.
Firstly, poor access to WASH services under HRP (HSDN21-WSH-172768-1) WASH project in North Jabel Marra and Umdukun localities, and Secondly the Emergency rapid response  in entire Central Darfur State. 

This project will address the core problem affecting community mostly women, and girls in North Jabel Marra and Umdukhun of poor access to safe drinking water resources an violence against women and girls while trying to access the limited water services. The project aims to enhance the protection, health and well-being of the conflict induced IDPs, returnees and affected host communities, and will be focusing on increasing the ability to access safe water supply, improved hygiene and sanitation practices and increased accessibility of protection services in a rights-based manner through context specific approaches that take into consideration the limited access for WASH and basic protection services.
 If WASH services are delivered within close proximity to women and girls, then cases of gender based violence and sexual harassments will be reduced. This project main focus is to work closely with the most vulnerable including women, men, girls and boys, to get their views and to ensure water, sanitation, hygiene, general protection services are delivered within their proximity as much as possible. 
The project will ensure active participation of the targeted beneficiaries and stakeholders throughout the project cycle. Selection of any new activities will be together with the beneficiaries particularly women participating in decision making and the intervention will increase access to women and children in particular. Protection and safety concerns will be given priority and considered providing safe and easy access to the facilities by women and children as well as GBV survivors. protection key priority activities will be in line with the protection cluster areas of concern including improving safety and protection improved awareness on protection issues including GBV and empower vulnerable groups to claim their rights as well as enhance access to protection and related services.  Under GBV and protection sector, the Survivor-Centered Approach will be used to ensure the survivor&#x2019;s rights, needs and wishes are prioritized in accordance with the GBV guiding principles. To ensure sustainability, the community-based approach will be used at all stages of project implementation to ensure that affected populations are actively engaged as partners in developing strategies related to their protection and the provision of humanitarian assistance. Additionally, the project is design to mitigate risks hence ensuring reduced risk of exposure to GBV. For instance new water sources will be located to reduce walking distances for women and girls. 

The project targets 78,655 (16,565men, 18,577 women, 20,624 boys and 22,889 girls) IDPs, Returnees and Host community in Central Darfur. Under stardard WASH interventions, targeted villages in UMD includes Dar-Alsalam, Almunora, Angira ,Khashkhashsa, Mando-Alkhalwa, Royana Alkhalwa, Deba-Jamos, Fuda, and Tarjarib with12,549 individual (Men 2706,Women 2816, Boys 3443,and girls 3584). And Rokero locality villages are Sabay ,Salla, Rongo Rongo, Bouly, Ronga, Birka-Twasi, Kirtinga, and Hilat Dokta with 2,866 Individuals (Men 618,Women 643, Boys 786, and girls 819) in Boulay Cluster. And in Mohamedeen amp Arsheen Clusters targeted villages includes Nomay, Fundo, Foray, Deba, Arinja, Yara, Bouray, Somira, Anjamina, Burunga, Koray, Kwirko, Kora, Modonga, Tambarand and Nasingo with 46,000 individual (Men 9919,Women10,322, Boys 12622,and girls 13138.

This project will ensure COVID19 measure are strictly observed and well integrated in all interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hope and Friendship for Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Relief</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="HSDN21-WSH-172768-1" type="A9">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-FTS">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations OCHA Financial Tracking Service (UN OCHA FTS)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gemta Birhanu</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0900998377</telephone>
   <email>AGemta@wr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rose Moraa</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finance and Admin Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0900998385</telephone>
   <email>Rmoraa@wr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stephen Gatimu Njoroge</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">WR Central Darfur Area Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249900998384</telephone>
   <email>SGatimu@wr.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU26">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>12.33330000 23.41670000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSDN21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-10-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">147920.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-10-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">551338.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-18744">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-12">699258.91</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Relief</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305283861">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-11-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-11-17">419555.35</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Relief</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
