<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD-21/HSD20/RA9/H-N/INGO/21035</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health and Nutrition Reserve for Emergency response to Sortony&apos;s conflict</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the official withdrawal of UNAMID (The African Union - United Nations Hybrid Mission in Darfur) on 8 April 2021, tensions returned between Government forces against Sudan Liberation Army/Abdul Wahid (SLA/AW) reportedly over the control of the UNAMID base in Sortony. In particular, on 15 July armed clashes erupted in Sortony between the Sudanese Armed Forces (SAF) led by Sadiq Al Fuka, former SLA/AW adherent and now a signatory with Government of Sudan (GoS).  SAF led by Al Sadiq Al Fuka took control of Sortony on 18 July, although attacks and fighting continued, including shooting on 25 July in Sortony gathering site and an ambush on his forces on 26 July.  Heavy clashes have also taken place between rival SLA/AW rival commanders both in North and Central Darfur.

Fighting including through the use of heavy artillery has led to reports of several civilian casualties, mostly of elderly and disabled persons as well as small children, as well as injuries and burning of villages.  As a result, IDPs fled the area, including to the surrounding mountains and other communities including in Central Darfur.  The control of the area by SAF/Al Fuka has been associated with severe protection concerns including SGBV, abductions, arbitrary detainment and forced recruitment.  Furthermore, there has been widespread looting and destruction of service facilities, including health clinics and schools, as well as humanitarian agency offices and warehouses.  Access to Kobe, the main water point was also blocked for some time. 

This project aims to meet the most urgent life-saving health and nutrition needs of the conflict-affected population in and around Sortony.  No health services have been provided in Sortony since mid-July 2021.  Health service operation was highly impacted by the de-registration of NNGOs working in the sector and armed clashes which led to looting of supplies and equipment in the health and nutrition facilities. The prolonged lack of services, chronic lack of clean water, and a recent increase of vectors in North Darfur, provides a dire health situation where the population of Sortony is susceptible to diseases endemic in the area including Malaria and Typhoid fever. The state has also recently confirmed cases of Dengue Fever and Hepatitis E and is still battling the COVID-19 pandemic.

Through this project, Save the Children will re-establish primary health and nutrition services.  SC will rehabilitate existing health and nutrition facilities, procuring essential medicines, equipment, and furniture and supplies.  To improve the quality of care, SC will provide training to health and nutrition staff and volunteers, including on Integrated Community Case Management (ICCM) for health workers and on Community-Based Management of Acute Malnutrition (CMAM) and Infant and Young Child Feeding (IYCF) in Emergencies for nutrition workers, as well as regular supervision, on-the-job training and provision of learning aids.  People with additional or specific needs will be supported.  SC will conduct distribution of long-lasting insecticide treated mosquito nets (LLIN) to pregnant and lactating women and will support referral to secondary health services for those that need it, as well as the appropriate clinical treatment and referral of SGBV cases.  Severe acute malnutrition cases with complications will be supported through inpatient care.  

Community health committees will be established to further support health promotion, including on COVID-19, to encourage behaviours which reduce disease transmission, and encourage health-seeking behaviour.  SC will conduct mass nutrition screening (MUAC &#x2013; middle upper arm circumference) and re-activate or set-up mother to mother support groups and nutrition volunteer networks to improve Infant and Young Child Feeding (IYCF), community screening and referral, as well as establishing or rehabilitating breast feeding corners (BF</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-09-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Arshad Malik</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Country Director</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249912395174</telephone>
   <email>arshad.malik@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yusra Bashir</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business Development Manager</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+249 916583379</telephone>
   <email>yusra.bashir@savethechildren.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SU13">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">North Darfur</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>15.76619690 24.90422080</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="7" percentage="60" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="9" percentage="40" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-16"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-09-15"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-11">858000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="SUD15-21035">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-02-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-02-11">858000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3305473299">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-03-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-03-14">514800</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Save the Children International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sudan BI 2021</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-SUD15-2021" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
