<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC-19/HCG10/UR3/PROT/UN/14897</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Gender-Based Violence within the Centrality of Protection in Humanitarian Action in the Democratic Republic of Congo</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">According to the Humanitarian Needs Overview 2020, 15.6 M people are in need of humanitarian assistance.  8.6 million people have specific protection needs. 7.6 million people mostly women and girls might be exposed to gender based violence or live with the fear of experiencing it. These populations have needs in terms of risk mitigation, response services and violence prevention. Gender Based Violence is largely and systematically reported in relation with other emergency crisis and humanitarian actors in the DRC and assistance is able to reach between 30,000 and 40,000 survivors yearly. Women and girls, in DRC can experience sexual violence, including conflict related sexual violence. Some vulnerable women and girls adopt negative copying mechanisms such as the use of survival sex to access health, food or shelter lastly they might be forced to marry someone to reduce their vulnerability caused by a crisis situation. Internally displaced persons, women and girls living with disabilities, adolescent girls, unaccompanied minors and children associated with armed groups might be particularly vulnerable to these forms of violence. The GBV sub-cluster has recorded high prevalence of GBV in Nord Kivu, Ituri, Kasai central and South Kivu. Tanganyika and the Kasai continue to record high levels of child marriage, including as a consequence of food insecurity. Sexual Exploitation and Abuse has also been indicated as concerns for many women and girls. 

The Humanitarian Country team has endorsed a Protection Strategy and is engaged in the National Roadmap on the Call to Action(CtA) for the protection on GBV in emergency. The HC, UNFPA, Save the Children and ECHO are the leading champions on the CtA. The HCT use the various channels including its Protection Cluster, its dynamic GBV sub-cluster as well as reporting channels like the National GBV database, the Monitoring and Reporting Arrangements (MARA), the Monitoring and Reporting Mechanisms (MRM), the Emergency Response Mechanism as well as the Protection of Civilians spearheaded by MONUSCO to compile data and effectively respond to protection needs. Nonetheless, use of protection mechanisms by other part of humanitarian response is still insufficient, and this impact the centrality of protection. At the mid-term review of the CtA in August 2019, the HC committed to reinforce GBV within the centrality of Protection to ensure that humanitarian action focuses on women and girls. However, the Protection Cluster and its GBV sub-cluster alone cannot ensure the maximum needed support for the implementation of the Protection Strategy throughout the whole humanitarian action. Furthermore, the humanitarian country team has been working on a nexus approach with GBV being identified as one of the four main pillars of intervention. 
In that regard, the Humanitarian Country Team following various levels of consultations, reached a consensus to engage a Senior Protection Advisor (SPA), through the PROCAP roster to support DRC to increase its advocacy on protection, resource mobilization and protection risk mitigation while ensuring that GBV is strongly taken into account within the centrality of protection. 
The Senior Protection Adviser will be deployed as an Inter-agency resource to ensure additional protection expertise, address capacity needs in protection efforts, in addition to providing training and influencing policy and practice. The mission will last for 12 months to humanitarian leadership and the governments of DRC in the development and implementation of comprehensive protection strategies and mechanisms, particularly in situations of internal displacement. 

The SPA will be hosted by UNFPA, the GBV leading agency, to ensure that the linkage with the GBV sub-cluster and the work on Call to Action is duly exploited in reinforcing the centrality of protection. The SPA will be reporting directly to the Humanitarian Coordinator and UNFPA will intervene as a technical support agency</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC24-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC24" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRC Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HEAL AFRICA</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TPO RDC</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Anita AKUMIAH</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBV Specialist</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+243820003002</telephone>
   <email>akumiah@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sennen Hounton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resident Representative</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+243819505038</telephone>
   <email>hounton@unfpa.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="902">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kasai Central</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-6.15000000 23.59998900</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="10">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kinshasa</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-4.33950200 15.30948300</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="61">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nord-Kivu</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-1.68820000 29.23710000</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="62">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sud-Kivu</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-2.50002100 28.86666700</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="706">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanganyika</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>-6.25556800 29.51077100</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">239421.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">9549.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="00011787">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-08">248971.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC24-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC24" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRC Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="DRC24-14897">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-09">248971.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC24-2019" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC24" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRC Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Population Fund</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRC BI 2019</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-DRC24-2019" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
