<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>BE-BCE_KBO-0447404580-BELUEJI13210IN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0447404580" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="FR">Avocats Sans Fronti&#xE8;res</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting the full implementation of the Rome Statute principles</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Individual and community victims of international crimes, especially women; 
- Civil society actors and associations of legal professionals; 
- National legal systems; 
- The ICC;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Every year, new conflicts arise around the world and thousands of people become victims of serious human rights violations. They are often far from national and international judicial institutions, and are deprived of their right to access to justice (right to participate in proceedings).

Avocats Sans Fronti&#xE8;res (ASF) is involved in facilitating the work between local populations and tribunals, and has developed a variety of strategies to make the right of access to justice a reality for the most vulnerable sectors of the world&#x2019;s population. Through the project &#x201C;Promoting the full implementation of the Rome Statute principles&#x201D;, ASF seeks to apply the principle of complementarity. ASF&#x2019;s objective with this project is to contributing to the full implementation of the Rome Statute principles by strengthening access to justice.

ASF developed its expertise in fighting impunity for international crimes through its work in DRC since 2005. Through a project started in 2010, ASF has be able to give victims access to legal proceedings before national courts and the ICC in the DRC, Burundi, Uganda, Nepal, Colombia and in Guatemala in partnership with ASF-Canada.

Activities of the project:

- Advocacy workshops aimed at the ICC, national authorities and regional organisations for ratification and implementation legislation; 
- Trial monitoring; 
- Capacity building of lawyers, law students and CSOs through trainings, individual coaching and moot courts; 
- Volunteer coaching missions for lawyers in Colombia and Guatemala; 
- Legal assistance for victims before the ICC, especially for women; 
- Legal representation for the most vulnerable people before national courts;
- Advocacy meetings and publications aimed at national authorities and regional organisations for cooperation.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Specific objectives of the project:

- Strengthening national legal frameworks by promoting ratification of the Rome Statute, contributing to its effective implementation within national legislation, and increasing target groups&#x2019; awareness of the Rome Statute system. 
- Improving the effective exercise of rights before the ICC and national jurisdictions in accordance with the principle of complementarity and standards of fair trial.

Expected impact:
- Progress toward the ratification of the Rome Statute, adoption of implementation legislation, and necessary structural reforms aiming at guaranteeing the full implementation of the Rome Statute principles in the targeted countries. 
- Enhanced application of the Rome Statute in national jurisdictions and increased awareness of the most affected communities. 
- Improved capacities of lawyers to litigate cases under the Rome Statute and of the key stakeholders to address international criminal cases before the ICC and national jurisdictions.
- Increased implementation of the ICC&#x2019;s decisions and requests for cooperation.;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Avocats Sans Fronti&#xE8;res Canada</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0447404580" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Avocats Sans Fronti&#xE8;res</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="BE-BCE_KBO-0447404580" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Avocats Sans Fronti&#xE8;res</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Union</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Informal Sector Service Center (INSEC)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MacArthur Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-22" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Avocats Sans Fronti&#xE8;res</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Luc Meissner</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <telephone>International Justice Programme Coordinator</telephone>
   <email>lmeissner@asf.be</email>
   <website>www.asf.be</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">rue de Namur 72
1000 Brussels
Belgium</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BI" percentage="15"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="30"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="15"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="10"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="15"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="15"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-10-22"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-04-21"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2013-10-22">1900000</value>
  </budget>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="http://aidstream.org/public/files/documents/ASF_FP_MULTI_SDR_2013-2016_EN.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project-sheet &quot;Promoting the full implementation of
the Rome Statute principles&quot;</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A02"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
