<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-222655-PO5242</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-222655" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evidence Building and Synthesis Research - Effective Health Care Research Consortium</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Consortium informs policy and influences change through increasing the number of evidence-informed decisions. This is to improve health and health care for the poor in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs). We synthesise relevant and reliable research, contributing to a global evidence base that enables health care to become more effective, thereby improving the health of populations, and avoiding public and providers wasting money on ineffective health care or poorly informed research questions. We strive to build the capacity of groups worldwide, equipping them with the skills and knowledge to prepare, interpret, and utilise these reviews.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for Evidence-based Health Care at the University of Stellenbosch (South Africa)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Centre for the Development of Best Practices in Health (Cameroon)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chongqing Medical University (China)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cochrane Asia at the Christian Medical College (India)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cochrane Effective Practice and Organization of Care Group, at the Norwegian Institute of Public Health (Norway)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cochrane Nigeria at the Calabar Institute of Tropical Diseases Research and Prevention, UCTH (Nigeria)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cochrane South Africa at the South African Medical Research Council (South Africa)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KEMRI - Wellcome Trust (Kenya)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">School of Public Health, Fudan University (China)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact: More effective healthcare based on application of reliable research summaries</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cochrane Nigeria at the Calabar Institute of Tropical Diseases Research and Prevention, UCTH, are an official partner within the Consortium&#x2019;s African Network. Cochrane Nigeria&#x2019;s main interests are: evidence synthesis in infectious tropical diseases, maternal and child health; capacity building in research synthesis and evidence-based health care; and practice guidelines, clinical audit and clinical trials (mostly on treatment of malaria). Consortium work areas undertaken by Cochrane Nigeria are: preparing systematic reviews and training/supporting other Nigerian authors to prepare and update Cochrane Reviews; evaluative research and clinical trials mostly for malaria; and supporting and promoting development and use of evidence-based clinical practice guidelines.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="7">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KEMRI-Wellcome Trust are an official partner within the Consortium&#x2019;s African Network. KEMRI-Wellcome Trust&#x2019;s main interests are: knowledge translation in newborn and child health (systematic reviews and clinical practice guidelines). Consortium work areas undertaken by KEMRI-Wellcome Trust are: preparation of systematic reviews and GRADE summaries to inform update of national guidelines for child and newborn care in Kenya; implementation of updated clinical guidelines through change in undergraduate medical training, and in-service training of health care professionals; and training/sensitization in GRADE methodology for evidence synthesis and clinical guideline development.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CM" percentage="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Centre for the Development of Best Practices in Health (CDBPH) are an official partner within the Consortium&#x2019;s African Network. CDBPH&#x2019;s main interests are: promotion of evidence-based decision making, production and dissemination of scientific publications (policy briefs, systematic reviews, evidence assessment, rapid responses, newsletters and internet content) on local health issues. Consortium work areas undertaken by CDBPH are: translation of abstracts of systematic reviews into French to enrich and improve evidence availability in the French language; producing evidence assessments of Cochrane Reviews on high priority health issues; to establish evidence-based practice task forces in health facilities to coordinate demand and supply of evidence in health care; and to provide training and support for health personnel, media and members of civil society on evidence-based healthcare, clinical trials and systematic reviews.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NO" percentage="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Cochrane Effective Practice and Organization of Care Group (EPOC) at the Norwegian Institute of Public Health are an official Partner within the Consortium. EPOC&#x2019;s main interests are: preparing, maintaining and ensuring the accessibility of systematic reviews of the effects of health system interventions that are relevant to low- and middle-income countries (LMICs). Consortium work areas undertaken by EPOC are: preparing new and updated Cochrane Reviews in health systems relevant to LMICs; and collaborative methodological work in evidence synthesis.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Consortium has two Partners within China, the China Effective Health Network based at the Chongqing Medical University and the School of Public Health at Fudan University. The China Effective Health Network&#x2019;s main interests are: preparing new and updated Cochrane systematic reviews and non-Cochrane systematic reviews as well as conducting field studies in TB, child health, neglected tropical diseases and health system issues. Consortium work areas undertaken by the China Effective Health Network are: preparing new and updated Cochrane Reviews and non-Cochrane systematic reviews in TB, child health, neglected tropical diseases and health system issues and providing evidence for decision-makers; and conducting field studies in TB, child health and health system issues. The School of Public Health, Fudan University&#x2019;s main interests are: preparing new and updated Cochrane Reviews in reproductive health; and disseminate health evidences of reproductive health to grass-root audience and community health providers through innovative media approaches. Consortium work areas undertaken by the School of Public Health, Fudan University are: the involvement of experts on reproductive health and family planning areas of China; rewriting the health evidence to plain language and disseminating the information to grass-root people and health providers; capacity building of team members on making health evidence; and the comprehensive topics of disseminated evidences, including perinatal care, early child health care, family planning, menopause health care.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="19">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Consortium&apos;s African Network lead is based at the Stellenbosch University and they also work jointly with Cochrane South Africa who are based at the South African Medical Research Council. The official SA partnership is the Centre for Evidence-based Health Care (CEBHC). CEBHC&#x2019;s main interests are: preparing and conducting systematic reviews, provide training and support to systematic review author teams, promote the use of systematic reviews by researchers, clinicians, guideline development teams and policymakers. Consortium work areas undertaken by CEBHC are: conducting and supporting relevant robust Cochrane Reviews and non-Cochrane systematic reviews; engaging decision makers and influencing national policies in TB, nutrition and essential drugs; and provincial health staff demanding, accessing and using evidence synthesis in their decision making (proof of concept project in one province in Cameroon and one in South Africa).</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="16">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Consortium&apos;s South Asian Network lead is based at the Cochrane South Asia, Christian Medical College, Vellore. Cochrane South Asia&#x2019;s main interests are: preparing and updating Cochrane Reviews in malaria, TB and other infectious diseases particular to the South Asian region; and training, facilitating and supporting Cochrane systematic reviewers throughout the country. Consortium work areas undertaken by Cochrane South Asia are; updating and maintaining the South Asian Database of Controlled Clinical Trials; preparing new and updated Cochrane Reviews in malaria, TB and other infectious diseases; and providing training and support for review authors in preparing and updating reviews.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GB" percentage="48">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main Consortium Office is based at the Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine (LSTM) which covers: the planning, management, monitoring the strategy, work-plans, outputs and expenditure of the Consortium; management of the output-based budgeting of the Consortium; assuring value for money and risk management across all Partners; assembling official reports and communication with DFID; and the communication between Partners. Also, one of the Consortium Partners, the Cochrane Infectious Diseases Group (CIDG) is based at LSTM. CIDG prepares new and updated Cochrane systematic reviews in malaria, TB, neglected tropical diseases, diarrhoeal diseases and HIV/AIDS, important in low- and middle-income countries.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="121" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health, general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12182" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical research</narrative>
  </sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-11-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2011-03-31">374690.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2011-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2012-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2012-03-31">1057568.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2012-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-03-31">1072444.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2013-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">1043184.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">1059215.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-31">797748.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">892943.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-31">1116431</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-05-14"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-14">585548</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="UK &amp; Networks Yr3">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">40000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds for current Partners (new supplements) or new Partner requests or Gold OA (new DFID requirement following original award 2010)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK &amp; Networks Yr4">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds for current Partners (new supplements) or new Partner requests or Gold OA (new DFID requirement following original award 2010)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK &amp; Networks Yr6">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-31">20000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Funds for current Partners (new supplements) or new Partner requests or Gold OA (new DFID requirement following original award 2010)</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EPOC Network Inception">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2011-03-31">2625</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="China Network Inception">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2011-03-31">28902.26</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South Asian Network Inception">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2011-03-31">44866.5</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="African Network Inception">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2011-03-31">72801.25</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK Inception">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2011-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2011-03-31">225495.48</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South Asian Network Yr1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2012-03-31">108650.08</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="African Network Yr1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2012-03-31">342762.25</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EPOC Network Yr1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2012-03-31">9375</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="China Network Yr1">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2012-03-31">94486.62</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK Yr1">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2012-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2012-03-31">502294.84</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="African Network Yr2">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-03-31">371610.07</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EPOC Network Yr2">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-03-31">8000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South Asian Network Yr2">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-03-31">84860.92</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="China Network Yr2">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-03-31">85688.6</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK Yr2">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-03-31">522284.8</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South Asian Network Yr3">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">168599.33</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South African Network Yr3">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">287129.23</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="China Network Yr3">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">54371.8</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EPOC Network Yr3">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">8000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK Yr3">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-03-31">485083.86</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South Asian Network Yr4">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">166600</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="China Network Yr4">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">22544.16</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="African Network Yr4">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">331477.18</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EPOC Network Yr4">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">8000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK Yr4">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-31">510594.6</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="African Network Yr5">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">264565.18</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="China Network Yr5">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">5663.2</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South Asian Network Yr5">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">71792.88</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="EPOC Network Yr5">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">8000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK Yr5">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-31">447727.66</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South African Network Yr6">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-31">268305.8</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="China Network Yr6">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-31">31555.52</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="South Asian Network Yr6">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-31">76232.42</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction ref="UK Network Yr6">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-31">496849.85</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
