<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140091</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame Agreement with NGO (Finn Church Aid)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia?s 2001 Land Law attempted to limit encroachment into state land (technically about 80% of Cambodia?s land area) while providing for legal expansion of smallholder agriculture through the distribution of up to five hectares of state land as ?social
 land concessions? which would be eligible for title after five years of continuous occupation and use. In 2003, Sub-Decree 19 on Social Land Concessions (SLCs) was enacted which provided for a locally initiated and managed process of planning and implemen
ting SLCs. In late 2005, the State Land Management Sub-Decree provided the legal basis for district and provincial levels of Government to work with communes to identify and officially allocate state lands for SLCs.Land and Advocacy Development Project (LA
DP) has been prepared to provide capacity building on Alternative Dispute resolution (ADR) Land Rights and Land Registration, Advocacy, Women Rights, and relevant laws to ensure that the people are aware of ADR and the responsibilities of government and ot
her duty-bearers to fulfill, to protect and respect communities? rights. In addition, the capacity of the duty bearers will be strengthened to be able to fulfill their obligations to realise concerned communities? rights. Objectives:? To promote democratic
 participation and human rights at the grassroots level by educating and supporting vulnerable groups, victims of land dispute and local government (Commune Councils) to become more effective at advocating their communities? needs.? To ensure the most vuln
erable groups are able to access to their agriculture land and control over productive resources and assets for enhancing their livelihood activities. Rights- holders /beneficiaries: Approximately 1 000 households located in 25 villages at selected LWD pro
gramme areas in Kampong Speu, Kampong Chhnang, Pursat, Battambang provinces will benefit from the project. The district Cadastral Commission, local authority and LWD staff will benefit from the project through capacity building on Alternative Dispute Resol
ution. Implementing partner: Life with Dignity (LWD)LWD has been working together with FCA in partnership for over 20 years to improve the livelihoods of the poor and marginalised in rural Cambodia, engaging both rights-holders and duty-bearers. Since 2011
, the partners have been implementing a land rights awareness project in Kampong Chhnang and Kampong Speu provinces with the aim at increasing awareness on land rights and land registration of vul</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Provinces of Kampong Speu, Kampong Chhnang, Pursat"></location>
  <sector code="43040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">15000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">15000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">9060</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
