<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2012000323</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Brigde of Cultural Traditions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to support the cultural diversity of the minority nationalities in Vietnam through researching and festival cooperation. The project will create an international net of research institutes to support the continuation of the unique oral mus
ic tradition among the nationalities living in the mountains and through that reinforce the  cultural identity and living circumstances of the minority nationalities.The festival collaboration will create preconditions for music export which may have posit
ive economical consequences for the minorities in the mountains  living now in rather poor conditions.The project response well to the programme aims of the countries. Finland is changing towords normal bilateral relationship in the development cooperation
 with Vietnam.  With assistance of the project  - with Finnish expertice and knowhow  -  preconditions to utilize the cultural heritage of minority nationalities will be created by using principles of sustainable development  giving economical advantage to
 the minorities. To develop research and festival collaboration and utilizing the results by the modern music technology is a branch to both of the countries to have considerable economical achievements. Music export is one of the most remarkable increasin
g branches of export in global scale.  Both Finnish and Vietnamese cultural traditions are based on a strong oral tradition.  Knowhow and technical equipments are innovated and created in Finland to have economical impact. The oral music culture has had a 
great impact to many brances of arts in both countries and has created internationally respected research institutes into both countries. The basis to the fruitful collaboration which will have impact in both countries is existing.The mountain minority nat
ionalities in Vietnam will be the main beneficiaries in the project. A model for economical activities on the basis of their own cultural premises will be created in the project.  With research and festival actions the living area of those people will be k
nown and will  thus open possibilities to develop culturally sustainable cultural tourism. At the same time appreciation towards minorities  inside Vietnam will increase when people realize that a cultural basic of own will serve a possibility to preserve 
the vitality of a rural area.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Juminkeko-saatio</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="16061" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">55034</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">55034</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">55034</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
