<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2012000062</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Micro and Small Enterprises (MSME) Support Programme in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims at the creation of employment among the young micro-entrepreneurs of the informal economy and the development of a training programme for the unemployed underprivileged youth in technical and entrepreneurial skills in Nairobi. The program
me will enhance the participants&apos; entrepreneurial skills and help them to start and consolidate their business. More specifically the action aims at: 1. Reinforcing the technical and managerial skills of the small and micro-entrepreneurs operating in the i
nformal economy, 2. Establishing the Department of Small Businesses of the Eastlands College of Technology so as to have appropriate means to conduct the training,3. Designing a modular system of technical training so as to make it suitable for the informa
l sector actors,4. Designing hands-on tools for teaching business (case study) and teaching technical skills in accordance with the needs of the informal sector5. Increasing the income and improve the socioeconomic outlooks of the small and micro-entrepren
eurs, The particular results expected from the launching of the action are:- Implementation of modular and flexible technical and professional training,- Design of pedagogical instruments in cooperation with the micro-enterprises (SMEs) and other actors of
 the formal and informal economies such as ?case study? hands-on practice dedicated business mentoring. It will benefit the poor young and adult workers either already working or about to enter the labour market. The beneficiaries live Nairobi suburbs or s
maller towns: therefore the action targets suburban and urban populations including population of the rural exodus.The Informal Sector Business Institute  (ISBI) has been operating in Nairobi for the last 9 years prepared and offered modular professional a
nd management training sessions and individual follow-up (in the field) to micro-entrepreneurs of the informal economy. This institute will form a department of the Eastlands College of Technology (ECT).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inter-Cultur ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Nairobi"></location>
  <sector code="11330" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">34500</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">34500</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
