<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2013130337</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CRPE ? RM Building public support for anti-corruption efforts of the National Integrity Commission</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Corruption is embedded in Moldova&apos;s public institutions and is cited as a stagger block to European Integration ? Chisinau?s fundamental objective. A successful anti-corruption policy is a benchmark for EU visa liberation as well as for successful implemen
tation of the future Association Agreement with the EU. Thanks to EU pressure key anti-corruption institutions were created in 2012, law no. 180 of 19/12/2011 established the National Integrity Commission (NIC) aiming to control officials? wealth.The proje
ct will lead to changes in Moldovan society by clearly identifying  the gaps of the appropriate activity of the NIC to address corruption in Republic of Moldova and in the same time by proposing clear and thorough processes for engagement with stakeholders
 - civil society mass-media and officials in order to ensure the assessment of the anti-corruption institutions. Civil society will be enabled to monitor the anti-corruption effort and to provide a useful and objective supervisory tool that can check on ac
tivity of NIC and its own objectivity and integrity. More so the project will contribute to the strengthening of the professional values and quality journalism so as the Moldovan journalism will represent an impediment to corruption.As an outcome of the pr
oject the NIC will have better chances to improve their activity due to the communication and transparency procedures that will enhance the cooperation and collaboration with mass-media and civil society. Furthermore Moldova&apos;s civil society institutions an
d mass-media will be empowered in developing and monitoring the national anti-corruption policy development processes through exchange of information and expertise with the government agencies responsible for preventing and fighting corruption.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-10-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15113" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">21965</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
