<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2013130292</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Better Governance for Adaptation to Climate Change</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall objective of the project is the community-based coastal resources with adaptation to climate change in Cat Hai island district Hai Phong City is sustainably managed contributing to poverty reduction and socio-economic development for the local peop
le.Specific objectives of the project are as follows:- To raise awareness of local government and community on issues of environment climate change and sustainable development.- To improve local governance by promoting co-management of natural resources an
d mobilizing participation of local in making decisions related to their life. - To protect environment  and build local capacity to adapt to climate change (preparedness against natural disaster) for sustainable livelihoods and development of Cat Hai dist
rict in generalThe 4 expected results of the project include: Expected Result 1: By December 2014 the awareness of 100% of aquaculture households 80% of the government officers of DPC and 50% of the bays? coastal households are raised on climate change and
 environment for sustainable development, 100% of aquaculture households adjust their behaviors to more friendly to sea water environment.Expected Result 2: By December 2014 the ?co-management? mechanism between local people and Cat Ba Bay Management is es
tablished and enhanced. The local regulation of water management and action plan will be prepared and implemented with participation of local people.Expected Result 3: By December 2014 the sanitation of the sea water in Cat Ba Bay and Lan Ha Bay is improve
d according to environment standards in comparison with the situation in October 2012.  The water environment is fine enough for keeping aquaculture sustainableExpected Result 4: By December 2014 sustainable livelihoods for households of aquaculture and es
pecially for poor households or households having sea dependent livelihoods are strengthened. The new model of feeding fish with industrial foods will be successfully piloted and studied by 80% of the aquaculture households. The income will be improved for
 more than 50% of the aquaculture households.?100% aquaculture households will well prepared for potential typhoon.?</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-04-25" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">29278</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
