<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2013130142</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Dry Sanitation Initiative in Monze Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Dry toilet Association of Finland along with the local partner Green Living Movement (GLM) plan to improve the environmental sanitation standards and contribute to poverty alleviation in Freedom compound in Monze Zambia. The project focus is to impr
ove sanitation and hygiene practices and give environmental education resulting to poverty alleviation. During the project implementation dry toilets will be built in public places such as markets schools health outposts and churches and selected social cl
ubs and few selected demonstration toilets at household levels. To improve the accessibility to clean water also communal water points will be built. The project is designed to ultimately address poor environmental sanitation problem of accessibility to sa
fe drinking water inadequate community environmental health education and poverty. In addition hygiene and health education is given as well as promoting of dry toilets in the area.In a long term project will benefit the whole Monze town but main beneficia
ries in the first stage will be women children and youth as well as disabled people. The project fits well into the long term objectives of the GDTF, sustainable improvements on environmental sanitation and hygiene practices. The project also supports stra
tegic goals of the local partner GLM Zambia such as goal to improve the livelihoods of local in a practical and balanced manner. The project also addresses Millennium development goal number seven (7), to insure environmental sustainability and to halve th
e population of people suffering from lack of water and sanitation. It also fit well to the Finnish cross cutting development policy objectives namely human rights gender equality and climate proofing. It is promoting water and sanitation as a human right.
 a) Human rights: the project activities focus on the least priviledged community in the town of Monze, it provides them better environment and sanitation + hygiene conditions which improve the life of people in many ways. b) Gender equality: Women groups 
are the main beneficiaries of the project and WASH in schools benefits especially girls.c) Climate proofing: Dry toilets are flood and drought proof and thus adapted to climate change and variability as well as reduce the risk of disasters such as groundwa
ter contamination and disease epidemics. Dry toilets save water and give free nutrients to improve the soil quality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Dry Toilet Association of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-17" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="14032" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">43545</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">41420</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-05-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">43545</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
