<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2006060159</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADULT EDUCATION SUPPORT</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objectives of this Adult Education Support Project are to fight against illiteracy and develop the Somalia education . The project?s immediate objectives are to teach how to write and read 800 students consisted of 250 men and 550 women each ye
ar. Next 3 years of the project the direct beneficiaries would be 2400.The practical means through which these objectives are to be reached are: * Teaching the illeterate  people how to write and read. Knowledge is light.* Preparing students to go further 
studies into the formal schools.* Teachers will be trained to increase their knowledge.* Awareness seminar will be held for understanding the importance of education.* Project implementation period will be monitored by Sahan how to follow project progress.
* Self evaluation will be implemented how to make sure if the goal reached.* Local community local partner authorities and Sahan will arrange meetings to discuss how the       project will be successful and continue for sustainibility.* Security of the Fin
nish personnel is very important and we had local community gurantees that no   one will be hurt during monitoring.* Educational Board provides free school classes each town after local partner and the board    agreed.* Old schools will be renovatedAfter t
hat Sahan co-ordinator will visit the project field how to monitor the project implementation and then the students will be taught how to write and read and then will be given more advanced studies of English Somali and mathematics.During the implementatio
n period Sahan International and its partner Horsed Women and Children Care Organization contacted the local community elders the other local NGOs and Internationa NGOs about the project transfer in the future.The local community elders is ready to receive
 the project for continuation. The other local NGOs such as NDO Darwiish and Daldhis are also interesting to take part the continuation of the project. In 2016 this project will be transfered to the local community elders who with the help of local NGOs an
d International NGOs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Sahan International relief association ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-11-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11230" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">60000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">60000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
