<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2013130225</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishment of a Psycho-Social Support Center Tomorrow is Ours for Children</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The preparatory phase of project by Najda Now is expected to run for 6 months starting in July 2013 and ending in December 2013.In order to induce the Syrian refugee children?s and adolescents? capabilities to overcome sufferings and psycho-social entailme
nts of war and armed conflict the NNI introduced the invitation to establish a psycho-social support center in Aleppo area (Bustan Al Qasr). The project will form a nucleus centre where more centers are expected to be established throughout Syria to reach 
to a wider number of potential beneficiaries and to be able to contribute towards the crisis of the Syrian displaced community.It is expected and during the first year 2014 of this project that it will provide psycho-social care to approximately 300 benefi
ciaries of the Syrian displaced children and adolescents residing in the Aleppo Area in the locality of the Bustan AlQasr and contributing to the psycho-social self-reliance of the Syrian children and adolescent displaced in the Aleppo Area.The overall cos
t of the project is EURO90000 to finance establishment and running of the psycho-social support centre based in the Bustan Al Qasr for one year months. The cost will also cover the administrative overheads of the project salaries of the project manager ass
istants school support teachers volunteers therapist and psycho-social support team. It also includes cost of office furniture and computers in addition to the utilities materials and rewards for the various workshops.  The center will be established in a 
poor and overcrowded geographical area in Aleppo where need and necessity are quite essential and pressing.The gender in this project is very balanced and the NNI will stress on this in the call for registering the little children and adolescents. The NNI&apos;
s experience in Beirut for a similar project is witnessing a 53% of females compared to 47% of males. The NNI expects the same proportion to approach the center.The climate is tolerated and there is no kind of pollution whatsoever touched upon in the flow 
of this project.Democracy is the base in recruitment of staff on board of the project and the NNI will also be keen to register the children on base of democracy without any discrimination of any ethnic racial or religious background. The principles of dem
ocracy will be also taught to the children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Suomi-Syyria Ystavyysseura ry (SSYS)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">20000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">20000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
