<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2010100151</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening livelihood and food security of rural communities in Mali prefecture the Republic of Guinea</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Mali prefecture Guinea the small farmers face challenges such as drought poor soil pests and poor quality of agricultural materials leading to small crops, high level unemployment deepening absolute poverty and food shortage, and the region?s desolation
. In addition a warming climate is changing crop conditions and results which requires the development of agricultural methods. The project?s aim is to strengthen long term human security and resilience of the rural communities in the face of unstable envi
ronmental and economic circumstances. The main goal of the project is to improve local livelihood strategies and food security by increasing equality self-sufficiency ownership and planning in the villages. The aim is to approach the project?s target in a 
holistic way in which the communities? social human ecological and economic capital are strengthened in diverse ways: 1) by carrying out a baseline study and scrutinizing the causes of malnutrition among women and children (food quality sufficiency equal d
istribution and storing), 2) by developing innovative agricultural and forestry methods to be adapted in local conditions, these methods will be gathered into a good practices resource bank, 3) by creating conditions for collective action such as co-operat
ives and food groups, 4) by offering material assistance to implement the activities, 5) by organizing multidisciplinary training to support the activities. By increasing  community resources and collective action together with training poverty and local c
onflicts can be alleviated. The special aim is to improve the employment of women and the children&apos;s living conditions. The project continues many activities that have been implemented in the previous project such as regeneration of natural resources and b
enefiting from their environmental resources and knowhow. The previous project focused on environmental protection which has improved the land productivity. The central principle in the continuation project is to address the connection between environmenta
l protection and food security of which importance has been observed in the Mali villages. The aim of the project is also to create new practices based on the existing ones. The new practices include collective action groups (co-operatives unions food grou
ps) and the generation of a regional resource bank of which livelihood methods can benefit the villages in the long-term.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Kehitysmaayhdistys Indigo ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="GN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">30320</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">27540</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">25920</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">30320</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
