<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140132</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame Agreement with NGO (Finn Church Aid)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The northern governorates of the West Bank, oPT have historically been restricted in development due to the Israeli occupation. The communities in these governorates have lost a significant amount of their land, much of which was agricultural. Thus, many p
eople have turned to sporadic casual labour at low pay, while others have turned toward developing agricultural activities using whatever land remains available to them. Many remain without any stable source of income and depend on aid from local and inter
national organisations and the Palestinian Authority.Unable to reach their main agricultural plots, those who can do so are compensating for the loss of access to their farmlands by cultivating smaller, accessible plots, usually home gardens or something o
f similar size, if available. Additionally, those who do find casual work in Israel are in many cases taking a significant risk, since many work without permits, allowing them to be easily exploited. However, the implementation of the Women?s Bank project 
during the past two and half years, helped many vulnerable women to sustain some stable income through the selling of their agricultural projects.  Discussion with beneficiary women of the targeted rural communities indicated that there is a need to expand
 on the current activities and help promote marketing of their own products. Yet, further and additional support and input is needed, including material support, as well as training and capacity building. Additional support expressed was the need to help c
reate linkages, especially with organisations that can help promote and market the beneficiary products.Objectives:? Improve the economic opportunity of 80 female households through support to help expand their agricultural project and marketing their prod
ucts.? To create linkages for 80 female households through capacity building and establishment of women?s agricultural collective enterprises (cooperatives).Activities: ? Coordinate with the local authorities and the village councils on the implementation 
of the project? Selection of beneficiaries? In-kind support for existing home gardens and beekeeping projects? Around 60 capacity building training sessions will be conducted in marketing, cooperative works, etc.? Establish networking for marketing purpose
s? Follow-up with monitoring and evaluationRights-holders /beneficiaries: Estimated number of direct beneficiaries: 80 female headed-households (600 family members). The direct beneficiaries inclu</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="West Bank, OPT"></location>
  <sector code="31166" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">180000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">180000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
