<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2013130065</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tax Justice Network-Africa - transparent and citizen tax driven system that promotes equality participation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Tax Justice Network - Africa (TJN-A) is a Pan African initiative and member of the Global Alliance for Tax Justice. TJN-A was launched at the World Social Forum in Nairobi in January 2007. TJN-A aims to promote socially just democratic and progressive 
taxation systems in Africa. It advocates for tax systems which are favourable to the poor and finance public goods. TJN-A challenges harmful tax policies and practices which favour the wealthy and which encourage unacceptable inequality. One of the main pu
rposes of the initiative is to mainstream tax justice in the economic policy and development discourse in Africa. TJN-A provides a platform dedicated to enabling African researchers campaigners and policy makers to cooperate in the struggle against illicit
 capital flight tax evasion tax competition and other harmful trends in tax policy and practice.TJN-A aims to foster strong partnerships between its members and other actors in promoting tax justice in Africa. To achieve this the organization seeks to esta
blish and strengthen national platforms and coalitions on taxation. Currently there are existing platforms in Cameroon Ghana Sierra Leone South Africa Kenya Uganda Tanzania and Zambia. The East African Tax and Governance Network an East African initiative 
emerged from this process.The East Africa Tax and Governance Network (EATGN) was formed out of a process that started in late 2009 and has since expanded to include 13 member organizations1 with the initial aim of increasing stakeholder engagement and publ
ic debate on tax and governance issues in Kenya and across East Africa. The overall goal of the network is to ?contribute to a just transparent and citizen-driven tax system that promotes equality participation and accountability in East Africa?.Since ince
ption the network has engaged on a number of tax issues mostly in Kenya, through conducting research and carrying out follow up advocacy activities targeting different stakeholders including policy makers in Government Legislators in the East African Regio
n the media and the public.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-28" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15111" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">40000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
