<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2013130073</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InformAction Limited - A vision for change: Mobilizing Communities in the Counties for Accountability</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposal is based upon the second phase project carried out by InformAction in partnership with the Embassy of Finland on Social Justice Vision: Mobilizing communities through Film. The project uses a field-based approach to enhance citizen?s participa
tion in human rights governance and democratization. Its main output is film and community discussions. Social justice films are used to mobilize and spark discussion- they are a practical tool to carry forward the ideology of change and accountability.The
 newly devolved government structures bring a whole new spectrum of opportunities and challenges. There has been insignificant public information on devolution making interventions around devolved structures crucial. The dismissive attitude of the central 
authorities towards devolution has resulted in inadequate resources to the counties and the appointment of parallel power structures that report to the presidency.  There are efforts by the centre to ?supervise? the counties claiming ?financial and results
-based management.? This tug-of-war between the center and the regions will have significant impact on freedom of expression association and assembly.At the same time issues affecting Kenya pre-election phase continue: terrorism isolation and insecurity in
 Northern Kenya, marginalization and political isolation of Luo Nyanza, rising political violence in Western Kenya, extra-judicial killings by the police and a rise of criminal gangs, and paralysis of security sector reforms. The recurring problem of ethni
c divisions and animosity are now aggressively fought out on social media mirroring the underlying anxiety and tensions. A sense of empathy understanding and common cause urgently needs to be inculcated across the country.By creating formal networks of hum
an rights defenders and community organizers IFA will work to organize communities in more structured and effective ways emphasizing the benefits of joint actions. Reaching across ethnic and political divisions to create a progressive national outlook from
 the bottom up is critical. Old models of civic education and ?top down? civil society engagement are not enough, CSOs will need to connect more and better with ordinary people at the grassroots in order to be more effective as well as generate a measure o
f protection when under siege.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-11-18" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">20000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
