<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140110</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame Agreement with NGO (Finn Church Aid)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HIV/AIDS implications on the Mozambican communities are dire. For example, it has led to a reduction of life expectancy at birth and consequently to the reduction of the HDI. At present, 15% of pregnant women between 15-49 years are HIV positive. Demograph
ic impact of AIDS for 2008 estimate that in 2009, nearly 1.6 million people were living with HIV/AIDS. These included 55.5% women + 9.2% children younger than 15 years. The project aims at supporting communities to reduce risk and vulnerability to HIV infe
ction and to alleviate the impact of the epidemic on the affected households with a strong focus on women, through development of the economic capacities of the most vulnerable households and promotion of human rights, particularly the rights of PLWHAs (Pe
ople Living with HIV/AIDS) and OVCs (Orphaned and Vulnerable Children) in the urban districts of Kamatova and Kamaxaquene. These are high density suburbs located in the outskirts of Maputo City in Mozambique. The area has high poverty rates and prone to pa
ndemic diseases such as cholera, malaria and HIV/AIDS. In addition, the area is one of the central when it comes to domestic violence and other human rights violations, prostitution, and sexual abuse against women and young girls due to poverty.Objectives:
1. Improved food security2. Improved knowledge on pandemics at household level3. Strengthened capacities of Community Based Organisations4. Increased access of communities to Credit 5. Increased capacity of staff in implementing the  project Activities: a.
 Promoting home gardeningb. Promoting income generationc. Facilitating and supporting  savings and credit schemesd. Promoting access to education for vulnerable childrene. Promoting vocational training for vulnerable youth f. Supporting  community based gr
oups and organisationsg. Raising awareness on  harmfulness of domestic violenceh. Home-based care to HIV-patients and psycho-social support to HIV-affected familiesThe main right-holders /beneficiaries of the project are 1500 vulnerable households from the
 urban districts of Kamavota and Kamaxaquene in Maputo City. These are vulnerable households from mainly women headed households, OVCs, Elderly and handicapped people. The project aims to reach at least 60% women beneficiaries. The project reaches also Dev
elopment Committee Members in each of the 6 villages, Peer Educators, members of HIV Associations and activists from the selected areas, and locals school students.Implementing partner: The Ecumen</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Mosambique"></location>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">120000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">120000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">65887</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
