<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014141200</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame agreement with NGO (Siemenpuu)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mother Nature organization, a volunteer movement made up of local indigenous communities, youth activists, and members of civil society, has been successfully opposing the proposed Areng hydroelectric dam, which would seriously damage the unique biodiversi
ty of the Central Cardamom Protected Forest in Koh Kong province, and seriously infringe on the human rights of local indigenous communities. With the strong relationship with members of the local communities and other activist groups, effective one-step-a
head-approach, and through the use of a savvy media campaign, Mother Nature has been able to delay the process and make the Areng Valley a talking point. During this project, Mother Nature will continue taking advantage of its rapport with influential comm
unity members to ensure that the communities at large are fully informed of what their rights are, and feel empowered enough (with the necessary tools, contacts and strategies) to publicly oppose the project. Also, Mother Nature will increase its media cam
paign to highlight the massive inconsistencies with the dam, pointing at not just the usual human rights violations and the massive ecological footprint, but also highlighting the fact that it has been classed as ?uneconomical? by two large dam builders. T
his will be done through the use of a newly created network, which will concentrate its efforts in punctual, public, and innovative activities / campaigns. Mother Nature organization was created in February 2013 in the village of Ta Tay Leu, Koh Kong provi
nce, which was seeing massive deforestation of its ancient sacred spirit forests. Mother Nature has successfully campaigned agaist illegal logging, and has built a broad-based movement to stop the proposed Chhay Areng dam, as it would severely damage the u
nique biodiversity of the area and seriously infringe on the human rights of local indigenous communities. The goals of Mother Nature are: 1) To prevent the proposed Chhay Areng hydroelectric dam, or any other-large scale development projects, from being a
pproved inside the Central Cardamom Protected Forest (CCPF), 2) Protect, reinforce, and promote the unique culture, traditions, and livelihoods of the Cardamom Mountain&apos;s remaining forest-dependant indigenous communities, 3) Lobby the Cambodian government 
to declare the whole of the CCPF area a UNESCO World Heritage Site, 4) Increase international pressure on protecting the forest area by leveraging national and international civil society networks</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Siemenpuu</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">7650</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
