<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140511</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame Agreement with NGO (Foundation for Human Rights/KIOS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Workshops to activate Dalit councils at the Sylhet region, a national press conference of human rights violations experienced by Dalits, training of organizational skills, advocacy and human rights awareness for Dalit councils, theatre campaign, informatio
n material, legal aid for Dalits, training of Parittran?s staff in project management. Dalits (Dalits) are experiencing widespread discrimination and serious human rights violations in Bangladesh, even if the caste based  discrimination is prohibited in th
e country at the constitutional level (Article 28). The majority of the approximately 3.5 to 5.5 million dalits live in abject poverty in the slums as ghettos without state-provided education, health and social services as well as access to justice. In par
ticular, Dalit women are discriminated because they are discriminated by their own community. Women do not have the same rights as men and women do not traditionally considered to be heard in a Dalit community decision-making body, panchayet. The project&apos;s
 main objective is the promotion of the rights of Dalits and the strengthening of human rights work of Dalits. The project final beneficiaries are the Dalits in the Sylhet region, where the project activities are carried out. Activities of the project aims
 at reaching district?s service providers, Dalit committee members, local government and representatives of the law and the Dalit community representatives. The project will support the Dalit Sylhet district councils, where the council is weak circuit at t
he municipal level. The project aims to promote the role of the Council in promoting the rights of Dalits and advisor. Parittran was established in 1993 by a number of Dalit students Satkhira, Khulna and Jessore area, with the aim of promoting the rights o
f Dalits living in the margins and their livelihood. The organization is working for equality, the abolition of the caste system, and trying to empower the most vulnerable communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO Foundation for Human Rights</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">9960</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
