<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140914</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAPIE / Support to inclusive education reform</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">KAPIE is an organization established in November 2008 and its main objective is the promotion of inclusive education. The organization was established with the aim to gather and use the expertise of people who have gained knowledge and knowhow in different
 international education projects in the field of inclusive education implemented in Kosovo. Despite the support provided for inclusive education system in Kosovo the education system remains quite segregated. Most of the children with disabilities are att
ending in special schools/resource canters and attached classes. KAPIE staff has a long experience in the field of special needs and inclusive education and in other fields of education as well. Key staff members of KAPIE have worked as Advisors on inclusi
ve education in International educational Projects such as: Finnish Projects- FSDEK II FSIESK and GIZ projectThere are no exact statistics about the number of children with special needs who are outside the school and there is an assumption that a great nu
mber of children with disabilities are not going to school at allKAPIE will work with 4 four model schools. At least one of the Model Schools will have RAE children. The Model Schools ? MS will be supported with intensive trainings on reading and writing d
ifficulties and other trainings in the field of inclusive education such as TESFA (Basic training on Inclusive education)Schools will be supported in establishing support groups and in producing alternative learning materials to support their students in l
earning. With the support of the project MS will provide individual support for students experiencing reading and writing difficulties. Project in a close collaboration with MEST will work in developing further the idea of teaching based on activity areas.
 This is something new for Resource Centre staff and teachers form attached classes.Beneficiaries of the project will be four (4) primary mainstream schools students with disabilities and learning difficulties and Roma Ashkalinj and Egyptian  studentsThe o
verall objective of the project is to strengthen the support system and increase inclusion of children with disabilities and learning difficulties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-24" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="RS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">49420</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">49420</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">40000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
