<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140919</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abo Akademi Human Rights training</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participation of approximately ten Ph.D. students and scholars from developing countries to the professional training organized by the grant recipient is supported   by the discretionary government grant. The professional participant will be chosen amongst
 researchers teachers government officials and jurist. The participants are given the opportunity to deepen their knowledge of the latest developments of the international human rights protection and of different national mechanisms for implementing human 
rights. During the previous years the participants have possessed key positions in universities governmental offices and non-governmental organizations. The participants come from ODA-eligible (the OECD list of development assistance countries ODA-DAC) cou
ntries in Africa Latin America and Asia. Therefore the training benefits mostly an enlarged group of people in developing countries. The government grant will enable the recipient to organize two different trainings1) Advanced Course on Realizing Human Rig
hts through Criminal Law (18.-22.8.20142) Advances Course on Justiciability of Economic Social and Cultural RightsOne aim of the first mentioned course is to find ways for improving women?s rights by punishing engendered criminality based on international 
criminal law. In addition gender equality is considered as a cross-cuttingly in other components of the course.The second training aims at developing legal remedies for implementation of economic social and cultural rights on national and regional levels. 
The training aims at advancing the enforcement of ESC-rights by teaching effective use of legal remedies. Both of the courses correspond contentually to the Human rights Strategy for the Foreign Service of Finland in the aspect of aiming at advancing  and 
strengthening the justiciability of ESC-rights as well as improving women?s and girl?s rights and their opportunities of participation. Gender equality and reducing inequality are crosscutting themes in Finland?s Development Policy Programme and Government
 report on development policy. The realization of ESC-rights is a key component in reducing inequality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="3" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abo Akademi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-29" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">42155</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">42155</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">42155</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
