<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140692</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forestry Society of Kenya - Stregthening Forestry Profession and Governance Structures for Sustainable Forest Management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the increased and unprecedented recognition and interest in forestry issues at national and global levels, especially those touching on poverty reduction and food security FSK membership has been on the forefront on contributing to domestication of In
ternational Treaties Conventions and Processes while recognizing the need for the country to attain Millennium Development Goals 3 4 7, 8 and National Vision 2030.During the project second phase the society made considerable milestones in setting up infras
tructure and governance mechanisms to enhance its mandate.  However the knowledge sharing and monitoring mechanism has not been put in place. This has made it futile to manage the code of practice and good ethical behaviour of errant foresters..For the Soc
iety to effectively perform her mandate and build on past achievements the Professional Foresters Bill has to be enacted by parliament. Without the Bill the gains made over the last years will be at risk of being eroded since members may never feel legally
 accountable. The Society must therefore lobby parliament to enact the Bill.  Further for the Bill to be effective it requires tools and instruments that will ensure enforcement. The Society has drafted a Continuous Professional Development Guidelines as w
ell as a professional Code of Conduct. The policy manuals need to be activated to enforce professional development and penalties for professional misconduct. To enforce Continuous Professional Development guidelines a software will be purchased and appende
d to the Society?s website.  The project will addresses some of the fundamental/root causes of forest degradation in Kenya ? malpractices by professionals entrusted to lead conservations of Kenya&apos;s forests. By addressing governance structures in forestry p
rofessionalism it contributes to improvement of leadership in the forestry sector. The project will also provide for promotion of life-long education in the forestry career a move that guarantees that quality and up-to-date knowledge in forestry sector is 
maintained.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="11000" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embassy of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-03-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31210" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">72200</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">72200</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">57760</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
