<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2013130080</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children and Youth with Epilepsy Development Programme</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the project is to promote human rights of children and young people with epilepsy in Malawi. The objective is to decrease discrimination and increase gender equality by strengthening girls? school attendance. The objectives 1) raising awareness 
2) advocacy to local school authorities and 3) training of school teachers. 4) Furthermore the objective is to empower children and young people with epilepsy to see their human and patient rights for equality and good care. The project gives tools to chil
dren and young people with epilepsy and their parents to tell openly about epilepsy. The project takes place in four rural districts of Malawi: Southern Mulanje (525 429 people) and Karonga (272 789) Mchinji in Middle (456 558) and Northern Chikwawa (438 8
95). There are about 33 700 persons with epilepsy of whom 17% are under 15 years according to a research on epilepsy by Lorraine Wapling and Action Amos (2009). The areas where chosen because of high incidences of malaria due humid and their dryness.The pr
oject enhances collaboration between Malawi and Finland Epilepsy Associations that started already in 2009. The project supports activities and lobbying of Malawi Epilepsy Association in the long run by teaching bookkeeping and audit practices. The benefic
iaries are children and young people with epilepsy their families teachers and local school authorities. The project operates two years. It is coordinated by the volunteers of Malawi Epilepsy Association registered in 2012. Background: The project effects 
on significant problem of disabled people. Epilepsy is a common neurological disease that is more than seizures. Also cognitive mental health and social problems are common in epilepsy. Furthermore status epilepticus (seizures over 5 minutes) is life threa
tening. Appropriate medication helps many patients and they become seizure-free. The problem is the commitment to medication of the patients and their families because of stigma and wrong information about epilepsy. More than 80 % of people with epilepsy d
o not have appropriate medication for their condition. This is mainly because of the stigma and also because of weak infrastructure in Malawi. Children with epilepsy in Malawi are denied the opportunity to attend school. They report painful experiences of 
isolation discrimination ridicule abuse and exclusion by teachers and peers even the family members. The project will effect also on the availablity of mediacation in the long run.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Epilepsialiitto ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-03" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">10000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">14250</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">10000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
