<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2012000229</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecuador ICI-cooperation in the field of meteorology</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The National Institute of Meteorology and Hydrology of Ecuador INAMHI is an authoritative statutory body with legal status under the national Secretariat or Risks (Secretaria Naconal de Riesgos). It acts as the source of necessary hydro-meteorological data
 and services to different target groups for support in decision making. INAMiHI operates a nationwide observation network and maintains hydro-meteorological data records for climatic and environmental research. The main service products of INAMHI are hydr
o-meteorological forecasts including warnings and alerts on severe conditions.The institutional cooperation&apos;s overall objective is to reduce risks for the loss of human life and property caused by hazardous weather and changing climate in Ecuadorian societ
y. The project purpose is to improve readiness and capacity at INAMHI to manage and produce safety services on extreme natural phenomena for the Ecuadorian society. The cooperation focuses on building the capacity on know-how on hydro-meteorological observ
ation networks incl. data handling adoption of new observation technologies incl. weather radars and enhancing of weather and early warning services to mitigate impacts of natural hazards in Ecuador.The project beneficiaries are the INAMHI staff whose capa
city and know-how is strengthened. Other beneficiaries include different economic sectors of society e.g. agriculture energy with better agro-meteorological information and weather and climate services to plan and promote the use of hydro- solar and wind-p
ower facilities and generators. The availability of enhanced reliable and accessible weather services benefit the local population and their livelihoods and living conditions as well as resilience against climate induced risks.The implementing parties are 
Finnish Meteorological Institute and The National Institute of Meteorology and Hydrology of Ecuador INAMHI. The duration of the project is two and a half years 2012-2013 and budget 250 000 Euros.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="51000" role="3" type="60">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University research institute or think-tank</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-04-16" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="EC" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">103448</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
