<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2012000106</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Organizational Capacity Building for Environmental Education and Community Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project continues to further enhance the two goals: to strengthen the organisational capacity of Green Living Movement Swaziland (GLM Swaziland) and to increase knowledge on environmental issues in the cooperation communities. During the first project 
GLM Swaziland has gained skills in several organisational areas and know-how on project management. They have made valuable networks on national level with such high-level actors as the Ministry of Health Ministry of Agriculture University of Swaziland and
 the WASH-forum to name a few. However two years for a newly established organisation to become an acknowledged actor in Swaziland requires more time and effort. E.g. GLM Swaziland is involved in extending of PELUM Association to Swaziland which is a major
 regional network for members of the civil society in Africa. Moreover NGO members of WASH have approached the project with requests on training themes to develop their organisational and project management skills.In the project communities various trainin
gs have been provided on e.g. dry sanitation agroforestry and waste management. Especially in Dlangeni acceptation has been enthusiastic and communities are asking for practical training and input so that they can actualise the lessons learnt. Furthermore 
the Ministry of Health has requested GLM Swaziland to facilitate on dry sanitation to mandated committees of rural communities attending regularly their workshops on water systems. Cooperation with another local NGO Vusumnotfo has lead to inclusion of Ngon
ini region in dry sanitation extending GLM Swaziland&apos;s area of operation spatially further.The project will continue with its Training of Trainers (ToT) in spreading of educated themes further. Through actualisation and visible results of the trained theme
s will attract even more target groups.The project will develop the already existing structures in Msunduza and in Dlangeni whereas cooperation is extended to a new project area Ngonini. Additionally the network created during the first project with the WA
SH-forum and the Ministry of Health enables inclusion of new beneficiary groups to GLM&apos;s trainings.During the first phase of the project GLM has worked with the communities emphasizing women participation and their empowerment resulting in workshop partici
pants and Trainers of Trainers consisting mostly of women. Promotion of gender issues and support of the rural women will continue in the second phase of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Green Living Movement (GLM) Swaziland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41081" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">10455</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">14884</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">13413</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">10455</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">28297</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
