<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014141201</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame agreement with NGO (Siemenpuu)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project continues the work on climate justice and community rights that Siemenpuu supported through DISHA during 2012-2013 (11018AAS). In this new project the RVC will function as the host organization and legal holder, but the project involves support
 to the same network, India Climate Justice (ICJ) forum. Also the person responsible for the project, research-activist Soumitra Ghosh, is same as in the previous DISHA?s project.  The project will be implemented by a group based in North-East India, with 
a long track record of working on climate and natural disaster issues.In spite of the revival of the ICJ and the work made by other groups, however, climate change has not become a mainstream political issue and neither do the affected communities perceive
 it as a life-threatening chain of extreme weather events, which it really is. The process needs a continuous support to remain visible and effective. The present project is conceived with the limited but strategic focus of making the ICJ (or any other col
lective programme that might lead to a strong climate justice movement in India) effective and ensure that the work made under the previous projects is followed up adequately and more collectively. This would ensure that affected communities and the Indian
 civil society can come together on the crucial climate justice issue.       In the present project the aim will be to build on the previous work and reach out to more groups and people to strengthen peoples? understanding and response to the interrelation
ship between the prevailing neo-liberal model of unbridled energy and capital intensive economic development with the climate crisis. Efforts will include studies and collective campaigning with emphasis on thermal power and coal mines (mainly Maharashtra)
, hydro power (mainly Arunachal Pradesh, Assam, Northern Bengal and Sikkim), large-scale wind and biomass energy projects (mainly in Maharastra and Karnataka)and also the methods of adaptation and disaster readiness of the communities in mountain areas. On
e important task will be to exchange information and experience with groups/movements engaged in similar programmes in other parts of the globe, including global networks like Financilization of Nature, World Rainforest Movement, and Global Forest Coalitio
n, as well as more regionally focussed groups such as MEE Net in the Mekong region.The project is expected to generate new knowledge on the impacts of large-scale energy projects, foster the clima</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Siemenpuu</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="41010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">23500</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
