<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2006060185</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving the reproductive health and quality of life of girls and women in the Eastern Province of Zambia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project Improving the reproductive health and quality of life of girls and women in the Eastern Province of Zambia a continuation of the 2011-2013 project focuses on a broad scale of problems related to reproductive and maternal health. This rights-bas
ed project focuses on preventing teenage pregnancies and early marriages but also helping teens who are already pregnant.The project aims to prevent teen pregnancies and early marriages which continue to be serious problems in the Eastern Province of Zambi
a. The project aims at addressing these by targeting the youth who are in school and educating them using a participatory Theatre for Community Action.  Out of school youths are reached through focus group discussions conducted by community facilitators an
d will be taught about the importance of education. Parents and traditional leaders will also be educated and informed on the law against early marriages their disadvantages for youths and the importance of keeping girls in school. The project aim is to re
duce the number of school dropouts in accordance with the government re-entry policy that allows young mothers to return to school.The project also focuses on aiding young mothers and pregnant teenagers in rural villages. Young mothers and pregnant teenage
rs are identified either by community volunteers from Safe Motherhood Action Groups or through focus group discussions conducted by community facilitators. They are informed about the school re-entry policy importance of education available options and att
ending health services. They will receive life skills training and information on their reproductive rights.The project will complement government efforts by forming Safe Motherhood Action Groups in project areas. The Groups will be provided with bicycle a
mbulances and they will educate pregnant women and new mothers about reproductive health. Pregnant women will be educated on the importance of attending health services and provided with information outside clinics as well. Safer deliveries in clinics are 
encouraged. Postnatal clinic visits are also encouraged for maternal and new-born health. These issues are addressed in interactive community based drama sessions and focus group discussions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Student Union of the University of Helsinki</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2006-11-07" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15160" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">68196</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">69500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">66803</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">68196</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
