<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2012000076</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening of the network of graduated teachers ? for improved primary school education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will establish a network of 40 primary schools in Blantyre Rural and Thyolo Districts in Southern Malawi with the overall objective of improving the quality of primary school education and the level of learning of the pupils. The immediate obje
ctives of the project are: 1) To increase the capacity of primary school teachers to use methodologies adequate and more appropriate to the situation on the ground incl. resource constraints and to mobilise support to help children learn better 2) To incre
ase the participation and the engagement of the communities in school catchment areas in primary education management and individual child support 3) To improve the conditions and facilities of 40 primary schools to make them more child-friendly. 4) To red
uce barriers for gender equality at primary schools. The expected key results are: better problem solving capacity skills and support of the involved teachers, higher learning outcomes of the pupils, and a reduction in children dropping out especially girl
s. The primary schools to participate in the project will be selected in cooperation with the Malawi Ministry of Education based on the schools&apos; willingness to be part of the project and on the presence of DAPP TTC graduated teachers in the school. The pro
ject will establish a network of the primary schools and make each participating school a centre of project activities. The Parent Teacher Associations of the schools will determine what the schools need and the graduated DAPP teachers in each school will 
be responsible for implementing the activities at the schools.  They will be the desk officers for coordinating project activities at each primary school and will lead the network in which lessons experience and good practices are shared to improve the qua
lity of education.  The two project offices and management team will support the teachers. The key project activities will be hands-on training of the participating teachers workshops producing educational materials sharing of experiences and practices tra
inings and events for parents and the wider community - all leading to improve learning results for the pupils. The beneficiaries will be 80 DAPP graduates working at the 40 primary schools the approx. 200 other teachers and especially the approx. 40000 pu
pils in the 40 schools. The indirect beneficiaries will be the parents and the siblings of the children and teachers / pupils from other schools in the zones.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, U-landshjalp fran Folk till Folk i Finland rf (UFF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Blantyre Rural and Thyolo Districts"></location>
  <sector code="11130" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">243115</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">258303</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-10-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">243115</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
