<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2012000075</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promotion of sexual and reproductive health and rights and education of girls in rural Malawi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is implemented by Vaestoliitto Mannerheim League for Child Welfare (MLL) Youth Empowerment and Civic Education Family Planning Association of Malawi and College of Medicine University of Malawi. Its activities are in the Republic of Malawi in D
edza and Mangochi districts in 6 schools. There is a high school drop-out among girls aged 10-18 which is as a result of unfriendly school environment unsupportive community environment lack of empowerment of girls and poor sexual health. Reasons for drop-
outs are e.g. sexual harassment early marriages and pregnancies family responsibilities and long distances. The aim of the project is to develop capacity of the partners develop models and strengthen the already existing structures in the project area. Fur
thermore the aim is to improve the implementation of the national policies within youth and girls sexual and reproductive health and rights and education on the local level especially in the project area. The specific objectives are, 1) CSO capacity buildi
ng 2) Girl friendly and safer schools in project area 3) Supportive community environment for girls? education and sexual and reproductive health and rights in project area 4) Girls are empowered in the project area.The outputs are: 1) Comprehensive approa
ch by partners in development of well-being and health of girls in the project area 2) Model of SRHR friendly school is established 3) Model of safe school environment is established 4) Community members promote actively education and well-being of girls i
n the project area 5) Girls have responsible role in project implementation. The development objective is to contribute to the improvement of well-being and health of Malawian girls. The Finnish cross-cutting goals are taken into consideration in monitorin
g and evaluation. The focus is on human rights and gender equality. The project focuses on training key groups in communities on project themes develops models for schools on safe and supportive environment and sexual education conducts research analyses c
ollected data and strengthens existing structures. In the implementation such models are adopted as Integrated Area Based Approach peer support and school peace of MLL and Steps of Sexuality -sexuality education of Vaestoliitto. The beneficiaries on the pr
oject area are girls aged 10-18 years teachers boys community leaders and parents. Project sustainability is secured a.o. by working with existing structures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vaestoliitto ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-11-08" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="13030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">164252</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">148778</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">164252</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
