<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2014140090</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Frame Agreement with NGO (Finn Church Aid)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By building capacity among Cambodian youth, KYA is empowering the next generation of leaders and agents of change. In Cambodia, 65 % of the population is under age of 30, and therefore youth empowerment is an imperative. KYA is dedicated to advocate the go
vernment with active and meaningful participation of youth in the decision-making and political process. Robust youth participation is perhaps the strongest mechanism that builds a more democratic society in Cambodia. KYA&apos;s core objectives are focused on e
mpowering vulnerable youth, who are at-risk because of conditions such as poverty, limited access to education, unemployment, disability, and/or sickness.Objectives:? To enhance space and opportunities for youth to be actively involved in the society and p
olicy making process ? To increase knowledge, skills and awareness of youth on human rights, education and peace.Activities: ? Capacity Building in advocacy skills, thematic contents, media advocacy skills, team building, research skills, public speaking, 
fundraising strategy and proposal writing, constitutional law and law on peaceful assembly? The launch, assembly and meetings of Cambodia Changemaker Network ? Monthly advocacy or awareness activity that the network members will implement e.g. via social m
edia and YouTube, which will support the main campaign (2 per year) decided by the network.Rights- holders /beneficiaries: Cambodia Changemaker Network has identified the core to establish the network in 2014, consisting of 22 members (from 7 provinces). K
YA has established earlier about 60 Community Youth Networks (CYNs) all over the country (including some of FCA?s existing target areas) which actively participate in community development. The youth group members aged 15-35 years are the rights-holders of
 the project, as well as the wide youth population in Cambodia through campaigns, awareness raising, etc. In addition, the local authorities, government and UN will be targeted.Implementing partner:Khmer Youth Association (KYA) is a humanitarian, non-gover
nmental and non-partisan organization established in 1992, registered by the Ministry of Interior (MoI), Cambodia. KYA is Cambodia?s leading non-partisan youth organization working on issues of human rights, democracy, gender equality, and sustainable deve
lopment. In October 2013 FCA facilitated an exposure visit for a group of Cambodian youth, including one FCA employee and KYA staff, to Finland. The aim was to share knowledge and experiences of C</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Finnish Church Aid</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="Cambodia"></location>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">15000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">15000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
