<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2010100209</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank administered KP/FATA/Balochistan Multi-Donor Trust Fund</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pakistan&apos;s border regions of Khyber Pakhtoonkhwa (KP) Federally Administered Tribal Areas (FATA) and Balochistan suffer from prolonged conflict and social instability. The socio-economic development in these areas is significantly lagging behind the rest o
f the country. The lack of economic opportunities and public services as well as weak governmental structures has created a breeding ground for extremist Islamist ideology the development of a variety of terrorist groups and crime. Also the status of women
 is particularly poor in these areas. The Multi-Donor Trust Fund (MDTF) administered by the World Bank supports the development of Pakistan&apos;s border regions and the implementation of Pakistan?s reconstruction program. It also reduces the possibility of an 
escalation or recurrence of conflict. The Fund complements and strengthens the Pakistani government?s action in the following areas: (i) efficient sustainable and reliable provision of basic services, (ii) community-based development of livelihoods infrast
ructure and services, (iii) creating market opportunities and revenue-generating activities, (iv) recovery from the crisis supporting peace-building and reconstruction, and (v) capacity development institutional performance and efficiency. The MDTF benefit
s 4.87 million people in the region. Supporting Pakistan&apos;s border areas is part of a regional approach and is in accordance with Finland?s action plan for Afghanistan. Supporting the development of the border regions of Afghanistan and Pakistan is a logica
l and coherent part of Finland&apos;s efforts to support the development and consolidation in Afghanistan. Carrying out efficient development interventions in the turbulent Pakistani border areas is very challenging but at the same time necessary for the stabil
ity of South Asia. Finland has granted 5.6 million euros to the MDTF in 2010. By replenishing the Fund with 2 million euros in 2014 Finland will continue to support the Fund&apos;s activities until 2020.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="44000" role="3" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Bank Group</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-04-06" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PK" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">2000000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">2000000</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">2000000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
