<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2010100012</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing nursery and primary education in Yala District</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promote education (including information society skills) well-being and health of children and young people at risk of social inclusion. Promote good governance and leadership as well as participation / ownership/entrepreneurship.The main objective of the 
project is to create a strong basis for high-quality educational services for children and young people in the area. The objective is to ensure quality education for vulnerable children and young people (ia AIDS orphans girls) and thereby further gender eq
uality and human rights. The focus is on strengthening the local agent?s skills in good governance and leadership and school staff?s skills in teaching and education. The aim is also to strengthen the participation and ownership of the local community.Sust
ainable use of environmental resources is promoted by using alternative energy sources as well as composting. Employees are trained on ecological practices and principles. Participation and green economy principles are taken into account in project design 
and in refurbishing the building. The project will create new jobs in the region. Human development is supported by paying attention on local employees? working conditions and employment contracts as well as on their training. Visibility of administrative 
culture will be increased which prevents corruption.Local agent has been active in planning and evaluating the project and its objectives which are still evolving. This will contribute to democratic and responsible society activities. The vision and object
ives of the second period of the project have been designed in collaboration with a local agent.The project is based on the structures that were created during the first period of the project. The structures will be further developed during the second peri
od.The direct beneficiaries of the project are children of Furaha Rianna&apos;s Children Home and the preschool and primary aged children in Yala area. The school will have 300-400 students.The whole community will benefit of the health care services as well as
 of the library and ICT class.The main activities of the project are:1) promoting sustainable leadership 2) promoting good governance procedures and project ownership 3) strengthening staff?s skills in  special education participation sustainable developme
nt 4) providing high-quality educational services:renovating and equipping the school the E-library the health care facilities 5) develop structures for participation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Seed Ry</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-11-04" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="11220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">55000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">55000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">49000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">55000</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
