<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>FI-3-2014-2008080122</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="FI-3" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable livelihoods for farmers in Sulawesi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Sustainable Livelihoods for Farmers in Sulawesi ?project will be carried out by the Student Union of the University of Helsinki and Payo-Payo in 2013-2015. The project is the continuation of a previous project of HYY Payo-Payo and LPTP on the same them
es. This project aims at influencing agricultural policy providing better agricultural methods for farmers improving post-production methods and teaching farmers to work collectively. The main themes of the project are environmental sustainability self-sus
tainability and the empowerment of farmers. The project is directed at smallholders and landless and near landless farmers in three villages in South and West Sulawesi Indonesia. The project plans to form villages that are decently self-sufficient and sove
reign in their livelihoods. This means that the villagers should be more empowered and free from dependency on governmental institutions. The project works towards sovereignty in the use of natural resources and agricultural production by the villagers. Th
is way the villages should be able to provide sufficient livelihoods in terms of both income and food in a healthy and sustainable environment. Also the idea is to give the villagers a sense of security from the availability of basic social services in the
ir own villages to become pools of knowledge that are a source of pride for villagers and to sustain harmonious relations of villagers by keeping up collective social traditions. Payo-Payo will enhance sustainable production and agricultural practices at t
he village level. Working through farmer groups in three villages the project will strengthen the financial basis of farmer groups by improving their post-production methods and creating new forms of income. Project activities will take into account the di
fferent characteristics of each village. Tombobulu village will concentrate on post-production. In Bonne-Bonne the main theme is to continue promoting organic farming methods and in Soga to find ways to increase household incomes. The project will also cov
er policy advocacy and public education at the district level to influence government policies that in turn will support work in the field through sound policies and programs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="22000" role="3" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Finnish NGO, Helsingin yliopiston ylioppilaskunta</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="FI-3" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ministry for Foreign Affairs of Finland</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2008-11-14" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Planned end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="31120" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">62370</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">64068</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2014-01-01">62370</value>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
