<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41078390" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No News is Bad News - Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTEXT ANALYSIS: Kenya is classified as a low-income country; ranked 147 out of 187 in the Human Development Index. Freedom of expression in Kenya has continued to decline under President Kenyatta. Ranked 57th in the 2015 Freedom of the Press Index, Kenyan media continue to operate in a precarious environment following new laws that are increasingly giving the state greater control over media. There has also been a rise in the number of journalists harassed or attacked by politicians, the police or other state actors and the number is projected to rise as the country approaches the 2017 general election. Hate speech in the media is also increasing, as the elections get closer. Kenya is among the most corrupt countries in the world, with the Transparency International 2015 report ranking it 139 out of 168 countries. Kenyan media focus heavily on politics with little attention to development issues such as food security and health. A study by the Media Council of Kenya concluded that there is very little experience in covering specialised topics such as environment, health and agriculture. PROBLEM ANALYSIS: Between 2013 when the current government came to power and 2016, the space for freedom of expression in Kenya has shrunk considerably. Through a slew of new legislation, the government has continued to gain greater control of media. For example, the Media Council of Kenya was established as a self-regulating body, but now is a statutory organisation that receives government funding and the Cabinet Secretary for Information has the right to reject names submitted for appointment to the Council board. The President appears to have a personal distaste for the media and has said publicly that newspapers are only &#x2018;suitable for wrapping meat&#x2019;. Harassment of journalists is increasing. Between July-September 2016, politicians and the police attacked five journalists. A photojournalist was killed over a picture he had taken. Journalists work in an atmosphere of fear and intimidation. Kenya has a vibrant media that tries its best to work in the public interest. However, in reality, the media walks a tightrope trying to balance commercial interests and political pressures with the public interest. Many media outlets are now owned by or have links to politicians, which prevents them from being truly independent especially during elections. Corruption has permeated the media sector with journalists often induced to drop stories critical of some individuals or organisations caught in wrongdoing. Playing the watchdog role is becoming harder and sometimes dangerous for journalists. The result is diminished motivation and capacity to hold power to account. This is reflected in the very limited number of active investigative journalists in Kenya. Journalists lack the skills to effectively report on accountability, good governance, citizens&apos; rights, business, gender and ethnicity issues. Also, they lack the skills to translate socioeconomic and political news and information into engaging reporting that is of interest and understandable to the general public, particularly to youth- which is the largest segment of the population. Universities lack resources and practical curricula to adequately train journalists on development and good governance topics. Lack of skilled staff often results in sensationalist reporting. Media houses hardly invest in training and educational institutions lack sufficient curriculum on topical training for journalists. Editors continually express their frustration over the poor skills of those who graduate from media schools. The situation is much worse when it comes to specialised reporting on critical development issues such as health, agriculture, security and energy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EJC has been collaborating with its partner, AfricaonAir since 2011 through MFSII and was one of its first supporters. AfricaonAir has quickly become a leading centre for journalism training specifically on development/investigative issues as well as an advocate for embedding development reporting in university journalism curricula through EJC&#x2019;s work with 14 journalism faculties. Through its partnership with AfricaonAir, EJC has collaborated with other stakeholders that actively lobby the government for increased accountability, transparency, press freedom, security and women&#x2019;s issues such as the Kenyan Correspondents Association, African Media Initiative, Association of Media Women in Kenya, Code for Africa and media environment, Science, Health and Agriculture.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media professionals, journalism students, CSO stakeholders</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STRATEGY FOR L&amp;A: EJC will collaborate with its partner to support increased government accountability and transparency, press freedom and safety/security, to empower youth to become engaged media literate citizens, to improve quality and perception of journalists and to empower citizens to increase their engagement in the democratic process. This will be accomplished by: creating an enabling environment with safe/encrypted platforms where development and investigative journalism can thrive (such as Kenyaneditor.com, Afrileaks) and perform its watchdog role; champion best-practice solutions for journalism and higher quality development journalism; support youth-focused media literacy initiatives; implementation of community debates and commissioning of investigative journalism pieces aimed at uncovering government corruption. STRATEGY FOR CAPACITY DEVELOPMENT FOR L&amp;A: EJC&apos;s strategy for capacity development for L&amp;A of partners will focus on the following key themes: Support and improve journalists&apos; role as civil society watchdogs by increasing their capacity to produce and securely place high-quality impact of multimedia content on important development issues, including investigative and accountability reporting; Improve ability of media to use data and innovative digital tools and platforms in accountability journalism; Strengthen the capacity of AfricaonAir to interact and strategically integrate into pan-African media networks and work more closely with local CSOs; Support increased media literacy among university-age youth and overall perception of the journalistic profession through the production of youth-generated content, curriculum development, mentor-ship and internship programmes, Increase the capacity of AfricaonAir and its partners to effectively lobby and advocate government bodies to strengthen press freedom, journalist safety/security and freedom of expression, especially in the current atmosphere of threats to Kenya&apos;s security by terrorist groups and the government&#x2019;s willingness to utilise the situation to clamp down on press freedom. GENDER EQUALITY will be approached through two kinds of interventions: Increasing awareness among the BP of the necessity of instituting gender policies and exploration of a developing a formal gender policy in order to ensure that current hiring practices, communications and all in-house materials/resources reflect gender sensitivity; Gender mainstreaming will be reflected in content production during capacity building on all levels: speakers, experts, sources of information and topics on gender will be highlighted and utilised in all interventions including small grants TORs programs. Emphasis will be placed on specific safety/security situation of female journalists. SAFETY ASPECTS will be approached through three kinds of interventions: Safety and security measures (physical and cyber) will be mainstreamed into internal policies as well as external capacity building training materials; Safety/security matters will be monitored regularly and reported; Safety/Security/Ethics resources will be produced and made available to Kenyan journalists</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="0"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">165250</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">167500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">144800</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">144500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">74500</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">73500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">167500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">144800</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">144500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">96800</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFRICAONAIR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">80000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AFRICAONAIR</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">110000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir (AoA)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">110000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir (AoA)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">95000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir (AoA)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">114000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir (AoA)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">39000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-30">39000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">202755</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">131150</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">72125</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-01">165250</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-01">103917</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir (AoA)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">88480</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir (AoA)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">114250</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">155605</value>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-KE" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of AoA website began as part of a long-term strategy as repository for journalists and journalism students tools and resources. Staff procurement began as part of AoA internal capacity development. Preparations for the April launch of the Top Story, weekly investigative journalism serial on Kenya Broadcasting Corporation 1 were started as part of AoA commitment to accountability journalism and media literacy in Kenya.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">see outcomes</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Development in strategic engagement: Media and CSOs are capable to relate strategically to achieve common goals in Lobby and Advocacy.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media serve the interests of the public and act as a watchdog on their behalf</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir strengthens and institutionalise relationships with local CSOs advocating on matters of national developmental interest, safety and security. Media professionals routinely source and interact with CSOs as credible sources of information on reportages of public interest.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016: Workshop for journalists on food security included inputs and expertise from CSOs active in the field (Nairobi, 14-16 December 2016). 2017: Introductory steps taken by AoA toward communication training with Human Rights Watch. Preparatory work taken with Media Council of Kenya and Article 19 to collaborate on delivery of election reporting and safety training for Kenyan journalists. Top Story competition journalism teams regularly work with local CSOs in production of their investigative reportages on vital development issues including health, education and the environment. Q4: AoA has a good working relationship with CSOs. That&#x2019;s how they managed to attract high profile people including a Minister and CEOs to take part in Top Story. Through the nine personalities who were interviewed, AfricaonAir has expanded and strengthened its network to include leading banks, civil society organisations such as the Kenya Red Cross Society, the Kenya Film Classification Board and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. 2018: Q1 Due to the nature of work that AfricaonAir is involved in, safety considerations are paramount. AoA has security consultants who advise on its physical and digital initiatives, including deployment of personnel and work involving members of the public. Q3: AoA briefed the Netherlands Embassy in September regarding its operation. The embassy connected AoA to a number of other Dutch-funded CSOs where there&#x2019;s potential for collaboration around development reportage production and sources of information for Top Story Africa participants. 2019 Q1: AoA has a good working relationship with media in Kenya, CSOs, the government as well as the private sector. The government-owned Kenya Broadcasting Corporation is about to start rebroadcasting Top Story Season 2. Participants of Top Story are required to work with local CSOs as sources of stories and of information in reportage production. AoA continues to be actively involved in the journalism ecosystem in Kenya and Africa generally. Its director is a regular analyst on TV discussions regarding media. He has now been tasked with the job of helping to develop a governance framework for a new association of African journalists who work for international media in different countries across the continent. Q2: AoA now has a direct link to the media industry in Kenya and will benefit from the deep insights it will get regarding the media environment. The appointment of its director to consult for the Nation Media Group also puts AoA in a great position to develop innovative ways of telling stories and reaching audiences as well as a chance to influence the growth of media in Kenya. The reality journalism feature on Al Jazeera&#x2019;s Listening Post programme in May gave AoA a huge boost. https://www.aljazeera.com/programmes/listeningpost/2019/05/mix-journalism-reality-tv-190504104518880.html The network received numerous messages from people who did not know about Top Story. It also raised interest among the university community in Kenya. AoA Director also regularly appears on TV and radio discussions about media in Kenya and Africa. One of the shows analysing the media and politics of East Africa had one million viewers. Q3: AoA has an excellent relationship with the media industry in Kenya. It is often called upon to provide training or recommend potential employees from its experience of working closely with over 25 universities in Kenya. Participants of Top Story Season 3 are again required to work with local CSOs as sources of stories and of information in reportage production. Q4: AoA continues to enjoy a very good working relationship with the media industry in Kenya. As a result, AoA is often called upon to provide training or recommend potential employees from its experience of working closely with over 25 universities in Kenya.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability development: Media increasingly operate as efficient and self-sustaining organisations.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AoA has a sustainable strategic business plan and is a hub for continuing education and journalism training in Kenya.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016: An office manager and a research/social media assistant have been hired to improve audience and stakeholder engagement as well as keep track of media developments in Kenya and the East Africa region; AfricaonAir website is upgraded for fund-raising visibility purposes, new partnerships inc IREX International and co-funding donor strategy. Long term sustainability strategy has led to production of job profiles including Office and Programme Manager, Multimedia Producer, Research Assistant. Development of AoA and Top Story websites and branding, continued upgrading of visibility strategy. 2017: new staff was hired as part of AoA&apos;s long term sustainability strategy: Multimedia Producer , Social Media/Websites Administrator, Office Assistant and Production Runner. AoA and &apos;Top Story&apos; launched new websites and greatly expanded their social media presence. AoA and Top Story continue to be highly active on social media for its audience engagement and marketing and regularly trends in Kenya on twitter #TopStorySn2. 2018: Q1 Top Story has a successful digital media component that has helped it to build and interact with a growing number of followers online. Top Story trends regularly on social media through the efforts of its dedicated digital team of former contestants. Q2: The Top Story national impact survey was carried out in June by an independent research organisation which included a qualitative study. According to the survey the Top Story Show, launched in 2016 and aired twice a week on KTN TV (previously on KBC), is currently known across the country by more than a third of the population (approximately 36%) and has been watched by 25% of the population. The weekly reach/viewership number for the programme has grown from 6% since launch to a current 10%. This translates to 5 million Kenyans who watch the programme every week.&#xA0;&#xA0;Top story show largely appeals to young people; more than 50% of its audience are the youth i.e. those below 30 years, both in rural and urban areas. The show&#x2019;s appeal across gender is uniform but skewed towards educated audience. Q3: AoA has been actively seeking new partnerships with donors and commercial organisations and CSOs to make its activities sustainable. Many of the student participants have secured jobs in the media industry after taking part in Top Story Africa: the show has both raised the capacity and skills of young journalists to be employed and raised the visibility of their personal abilities. Q4: AfricaonAir continues to increase and diversify their sources of income through the prep work around the launch of a training school &#x2013; the Top Story Academy &#x2013; and the construction of a studio that will be used for in-house productions but also available for commercial use. AfricaonAir began the process to develop a new business plan with the goal to become self-sustaining over the next three years. 2019 Q1: Work to establish the Top Story Journalism School has started. The school will comprise a Radio and TV studio for practical work and a newsroom for the trainees. Architectural plans for the studio have been finalised and submitted for planning permission to the Nairobi City Council. A firm of broadcast studio consultants has been contracted and the preliminary work on the site has started. AoA has 20 applicants waiting to join the first group of trainees when the school opens in September 2019. AoA has contracted Research Group Africa to design and carry out a series of short surveys throughout the length of the Top Story Season 3 competition. This will create a continuous feedback loop that will help track and measure the impact of Top Story and also attitudes to investigative/in-depth journalism in Kenya. Q2: Work is still ongoing to establish the Top Story Academy, a journalism finishing school that is part of AoA&#x2019;s sustainability initiative. The refurbishment work is scheduled to be completed in Q3. AoA has carried out surveys in preparation of Top Story Season 3. Lecturers gave their feedback during their training day and contestants are currently completing their survey. The data will be compiled into a report and recommendations that will inform the design of Top Story Season 3, which is currently in pre-production phase. AoA&#x2019;s sustainability strategy is mainly pegged on its journalism finishing school, which continues its development path. The idea is to offer short refresher courses to new and serving journalists at a fee. Once completed, the radio/TV recording studio will also be available for commercial hire. In addition, AoA has applied to be officially registered as a filming agent. This licence will allow AoA to act as an agent for overseas film crews planning to work in Kenya, thus expanding our revenue streams. Q3: Training curriculum for the school is currently being developed with support from academic experts. The refurbishment work was delayed by planning permission hitches, but this has now been resolved. The first intake of trainees will be in Q1 of 2020. In TS SN3 AoA has established a quality monitoring system. At each level of the competition, students and lecturers are asked to give feedback on the quality of the training, mentors and other processes with a view to make improvements. AoA now keeps a detailed database of the student&#x2019; progress during and after the competition. This helps to keep track of the impact that Top Story is having on them and their work and assists AoA in taking a long-term approach to sustainability of the programme. Through AoA director&#x2019;s new consulting role with East Africa&#x2019;s biggest media house (Nation Media Group), AoA is receives heightened visibility and recognition. It also gives AoA a close view of how the industry works, which then feeds back to the design and delivery of its projects including Top Story so that they are further aligned with the needs of the industry. Q4: Sustainability is going to be one of the main areas of focus in 2020. They exploring a number of options starting from launch of the journalism school to partnering with relevant organisations regarding Top Story. The aim is to ensure production of Season 4 of Top Story by raising supplementary funding from other sources. 2020 Q1: AoA&#x2019;s main strategy for sustainability is finding corporate organisations to partner with, including hotel chains, airlines, campaign groups whose issues resonate with AoA&#x2019;s interests. We also aim to lean on our close relationships with the 25 universities that take part in the competition and come up with an appropriate cost-share model for running the competition. In Season 3, AoA partnered with the government-owned Kenya Railways Corporation to provide subsidised transport for students, lecturers and film crew attending the bootcamp in Mombasa. Q2: In Top Story Season 3, AoA entered into partnerships with different organisations to help in various aspects of training and production. BBC donated a fake news and verification trainer from its Factfinder programme. The Kenya Railways Corporation supported AoA through discounted train tickets to and from Mombasa, while PrideIn Hotel in Mombasa offered subsidised rates. The Kenya Cultural Centre in Nairobi also supported the production through discounted rates for the hire of a venue to film the judges&#x2019; sessions.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accountability: Media hold power-holders to account and are accountable to their public</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenyan journalists regularly produce investigative journalism reportages that have positive society impacts and hold political leaders and decision-makers accountable specifically through the field of development reporting and a media literate citizenry.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016: Top Story (media literacy initiative) - development journalism competition for university students and media literacy TV serial continued planning and pre-production activities. Focus group of 19 University journalism students: study of youth view of media&apos;s role in democracy. Focus group of 20 University non-journalism students: study of youth view of media&apos;s role in democracy. The first competition took place in 2016. 2017: sixty journalism students from twenty Kenyan Universities compete in investigative journalism competition &apos;Top Story&apos;. Teams produce reportages on vital developmental issues in Kenya. Development of audience baseline/media literacy survey in preparation for premiere of &apos;Top Story&apos; on Kenyan Broadcasting Corporation (KBC). In Q2 a quantitative baseline survey to assess the current public literacy level on role of the media and investigative journalism and issues relating to accountability and good governance in Kenya was carried out. The survey had a sample size of about 1100 people who were all interviewed at their homes in all the 8 regions of the country. The aim of the survey is to inform decisions by AoA as it seeks to address the challenges faced by investigative journalists by initiating projects that help improve the quantity and quality of in-depth, researched and compelling stories on good governance, citizen empowerment, gender and development issues. 9 university teams that qualified for the next stage of the Top Story competition conducted TV interviews with Kenyan decision makers at the national level. Among those interviewed are Kenya&#x2019;s Foreign Affairs Minister, Amina Mohamed and the CEO of the most successful bank in East Africa. The AoA Top Story TV reality show on Kenya Broadcasting Corporation premiered in April and airs every Sunday/Tuesday nights. It continues to be highly active on social media for its audience engagement and marketing and regularly trends in Kenya on twitter. AoA started its Kenya general election-related activities by identifying and recruiting five community radio stations that will benefit from tailored training to help them produce and broadcast public debates in which the local community will come face to face with their leaders/aspiring leaders and hold them to account. The recording of the debates begins in mid-July and will run until election time. A call for applications for the Carey Institute non-fiction mentoring program was announced with many applications from Kenya reviewed by AoA. Q3: Top Story Season 2 moved from the state-owned Kenya Broadcasting Corporation (KBC) to the leading TV news station in Kenya, KTN. At KTN the programme was given a prime slot at Thursdays 7.30pm. With KBC still running repeats of Top Story Season 1, it means that the show has been airing in two stations at the same, reaching different audiences nationwide. Top Story Season 2 is reaching a weekly audience of 800,000 &#x2013; 1,000,000 viewers on KTN. Early audience feedback is positive with recognition of the value of the show in promoting professionalism in the media at a time when Kenyan media has been criticised for abandoning its watchdog role. Q4: The Top Story university journalism challenge entered the semi-final stage in this quarter, during which the competing teams were each required to identify a high-profile personality who has made a difference in Kenya and interview them for TV. This a variation of the normal format of producing development stories from the field. It has had the effect of stretching the skills of the student journalists, especially in conducting high profile interviews. In this quarter, the Top Story audience continued to grow, reaching a peak of 1.8 million homes in October. One Kenyan journalist was selected to take part in the Carey Institute non-fiction mentoring programme. With this support, she will produce a documentary on the healthcare system in Kenya. 2018: Q1 The Top Story University Investigative Journalism Competition and TV show season 2 came to an on 25th March with the announcement of winners. There were four finalists and each team of 3 students had produced their own 3-minute TV report for the judges on an issue of public concern. At a well-attended gala finale, Mount Kenya University were declared the winner for their story that investigated the cartels that work in collusion with city water authorities to create artificial shortage of water in Nairobi suburbs and make a huge profit from selling the residents water. The highlight of the event was a presentation by one of Africa&#x2019;s leading investigative journalists, Anas Aremeyaw Anas from Ghana. He received a standing ovation from the audience for his thought provoking and inspiring presentation that challenged the young journalists to take up investigative journalism and tackle the big issues affecting the Kenyan society today. As a result of the huge interest that Top Story show has attracted, the number of universities applying to participate in Season three has jumped from 20 to 30. The ability of the show to reach a big national audience continues to highlight the importance of a free and independent media in holding duty bearers to account. Q2: A Top Story national impact survey was carried out in June of over 1000 Kenyan households. It also included a qualitative study. The show was watched by approximately 5 million Kenyans every week. Q3: Top Story Africa Season 2 completed its broadcast on the KTN national TV network. It was on air for 54 weeks including repeats. Top Story reporting teams produced real-time investigative reportages that reached a nationwide audience which averaged over 900,000 viewers weekly. Through a detailed national audience survey on Top Story, viewers gained insights into the importance of a free and independent media in holding duty bearers to account. Due to Top Story&#x2019;s popularity, AoA director Joseph Warungu has become a regular guest on the KTN TV show that reviews news events in East Africa and includes a special focus on global best practice of journalism. Q4: Top Story began its outreach phase by launching tours into universities across Kenya. The aim is to extend the value that competitors get from the mentorship project to a wider group of students a faculty. The tour offers the Top Story experience of public lectures on topical themes such as fake news, safety of journalists and public accountability. The tour also exposes the young journalists to professional ways of working including giving them the opportunity to see and handle modern television equipment and facilities. The first tour at Technical University of Kenya 28 October focused on the theme of digital self-publishing. Industry professionals including Top Story mentors gave talks and shared best practice when using social media and other digital platforms like YouTube and video blogs to tell stories. The event, which was fully practical and interactive, was attended by over 400 students and lecturers (~230 male, ~180 female). It was filed and broadcast live on Facebook. 2019 Q1: Top Story Season 3 went into pre-production in January - March, starting with the process of recruiting the universities that will take part in the new competition. 24 universities have confirmed participation in this year&#x2019;s Top Story Season 3 competition. There will be 72 students taking part, with each university selecting its best three final-year journalism students. It is mandatory for each team to ensure that there is a mix of gender. Q2: Top Story Lecturers Workshop &#x2013; the one-day workshop was held on 26th April 2019 in Nairobi and was attended by 25 lecturers from the 25 different universities that will be taking part in Top Story Season 3. There were 19 male and 6 female lecturers in attendance. The aim of the workshop was to review Season 2 and to brief the lecturers about the requirements of Top Story Season 3. This included competition rules, criteria for team selection and a discussion on the themes that will be covered. The lecturers received some basic training on data journalism as well as storytelling tips that the students will be required to apply. Some of the key themes for season 3 include fake news, safety of journalists and the importance of gender-nuanced approach to sourcing stories. Season 2 Winners Media Internship/Tour to UK &#x2013; The top prize for the winners of Top Story season 2 was a week&#x2019;s sponsored media mentorship trip to London. The winners, Mount Kenya University, travelled to London accompanied by Joseph Warungu of AoA as well as the show&#x2019;s director, Bonnie Katei who documented the entire trip on video. The trip was from 19th &#x2013; 26th May 2019. The team were hosted at BBC headquarters in London, the Aljazeera London studios at the Shard and Colourful Radio at the Africa Centre where they were interviewed live on air. The winners also travelled out of London to visit the University of Central Lancashire in Preston, which collaborates with AfricaonAir in Kenya. Q3: Filming and production of Top Story Season 3 started on 4 September 2019 with the judges assessing the entry videos for each university team, which were produced by the students followed by bootcamp training in Mombasa for the 17 teams that qualified. 25 universities entered Top Story Season 3, 75 students in total started the competition. Q4: Top Story Season 4 premiered on 4th November 2019 on a new channel, NTV. It&#x2019;s owned by the biggest media house in East Africa, the Nation Media Group. NTV broadcasts nationwide and is available across Africa on the Multichoice DSTV satellite channels. Top Story was given a prime evening slot of 7.30pm, which is straight after the early evening news at 7pm. Top Story won Silver award in the Global Youth and News Media prize 2019. Two Top Story season 2 finalists were in Paris in November to receive the prize, accompanied by the Top Story Executive Producer. The award presentation took place at NewsXchange, an annual meeting that gathers hundreds of news executives, journalists, bloggers and start-up entrepreneurs from around the world to share, learn and cross-pollinate ideas with an array of experts, scientists, artists and thought leaders. News of the Top Story award was broadcast on NTV News at prime time and published in the Daily Nation, Kenya&#x2019;s leading newspaper as well as online. The Top Story TV show and online audience engagement remain the biggest tools of visibility for Top Story and AfricaonAir. It&#x2019;s the only show in Kenya that is being broadcast on two separate national TV channels at the same time. A repeat of the entire Season 2 is on air every Saturday evening on the state-owned Kenya Broadcasting Corporation TV, while Season 3 is broadcast on Monday evening on the rival NTV station. 2020 Q1: Top Story Season 3 entered the semi-final stage in February with six universities competing for a slot in the finals, which will feature only four universities. The semi-finals involved 18 contestants. They all attended a training workshop an East Africa Correspondent for the South African Broadcasting Corporation (SABC) based in Nairobi. The training was aimed at equipping the students with relevant skills to produce a quality TV feature story. The stories the teams tackled were: 1. Mental health and young people in Kenya. 2. How universal free education disadvantages pupils in rural schools in Kenya. 3. The impact of climate change on Lake Naivasha, one of Kenya&#x2019;s largest fresh water lakes. 4. How art is being used to capture and retell Kenya&#x2019;s history 5. Upcoming Kenyan athletes&#x2019; battles for world fame 6. The rising cases of medical negligence in Kenya These stories took the contestants to different parts of Kenya, including Eldoret in the west, Naivasha in the Rift Valley and Kajiado in the south. Each team was provided with a professional film crew, but the students had to direct the filming and editing of the material for their TV feature story. The biggest threat to Top Story Season 3 and AoA&#x2019;s activities in general has been the outbreak of Covid19. The closure of hotels and meeting places has hampered the filming of the finalists&#x2019; stories. Q2: Top Story SN3 concluded its semi-final stage in May and took a break due to the Corona virus situation in Kenya. The imposition of travel restrictions between Nairobi and the rest of the country in mid-March made it impossible for the final stage of the competition to take place. The broadcast of the programmes on the national NTV channel was therefore put on hold until the final stages of the competition are filmed. However, on 6th July the president lifted the ban on travel to and from Nairobi to other regions of the country. They are therefore beginning to plan for the resumption of filming. As of May 2020, a total of 23 episodes of Top Story Season 3 have been broadcast at prime time each Monday night on the national NTV channel. The Monday night show and the repeat on Saturday late afternoon helped AoA reach a combined audience of about 1.4 million people in Kenya. Nation Media Group offered promotion for the Top Story show on TV and the Daily Nation newspaper.
Q3: The programme is back on prime time every Monday evening at 7.30pm. They will have produced a total of 30 episodes for Top Story season 3 by the time the season ends.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Development in Lobby &amp; Advocacy: Media developed the skills to work as change catalysts in Lobby and Advocacy.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Journalists work professionally/ethically and safely through capacity building at post-graduate level and on specialised reporting topics. Challenges are increasing security, legal and physical threats to independent media actors.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016: Implementation of Security Training for Journalists in cooperation with IREX International and the National Centre for Counter Terrorism (September, 11 participants). Implementation of Food Security workshop for 14 Kenyan journalists in cooperation with food security CSO reps (December 2016, 14 participants). 2017: Sixty Kenyan journalism students were trained on the following topics: Video production, Editorial guidelines, Safety/Security, TV presenting and Reporting, Digital management, Ethics, Interviewing/Investigative techniques and Gender reporting in preparation of &apos;Top Story&apos; Investigative Journalism Competition (20-24 February 2017). Sixty Kenyan journalism students receive in-the-field practical journalism training as they produce investigative reportages. Students are continuously mentored and critiqued by AoA and Top Story journalist staff. Q3: AoA conducted a series of training sessions before the general election in August to support community radio stations hold local leaders to account, through public debates. AoA chose to focus on marginalised regions or places at risk of political violence, such as the Mt Elgon area in Western Kenya. The debates involved a studio audience drawn from the local community, who interacted directly and question their elected and potential leaders directly. Over 150 people took part in the debates, which were broadcast to large audiences. The topics tackled included the role of the local County Assembly; accountability and funding the right development priorities at the local level. Youth and women were the majority in the audience. AoA will publish a localised version of a handbook developed by EJC on &#x2018;Reporting on Development&#x2019;. Safety has now become one of AoA&#x2019;s most important priorities. At the start of each Top Story competition, all competitors now must undergo a mandatory intensive digital safety training session conducted by one of Kenya&#x2019;s leading experts. In addition, AoA has put in place physical safety measures for crew and competitors when travelling to different places for fieldwork. This includes a ban on night driving, inspection of locations and means of transport in advance to ensure they meet safety requirements and the presence of police/security guards at all filming locations. In addition, a group personal accident insurance policy is always in place at all stages of the competition. AfricaonAir is very safety-conscious. We follow international standards of safety adopted from BBC when planning filming/public events. This includes doing a safety audit on venues and hotels before booking. AoA finalised the publication of a localised version of the EJC Reporting Development Handbook. There is a lot interest for it and it will be distributed soon, including during the awards ceremony for Top Story winners. Q4: AfricaonAir Director was a key speaker and panellist at a media event in Nairobi in December. It was to launch a report on how Kenyan media covered the general election in Kenya. The overall assessment was that media did not do a great job of covering the election. A combination of intimidation of the media and self-censorship resulted in the lack of critical reporting during the election. 2018: Q1 The Reporting Development Handbook, produced in collaboration with EJC has been published and is now available for distribution. There will be a formal launch in June. AoA completed a first print run of the EJC Reporting Development Handbook distributed to participants at Top Story Finale. Q2: The handbook on Reporting Development was published in March and was distributed to the 20 universities participating in the Top Story competition. It continues to be distributed and has been well received among the media and journalism community. Copies have also been sent to media stakeholders, including journalism trainers. AfricaonAir featured prominently in the inaugural Symposium on the Future of African Journalism organised in Nairobi (26-27 June) by the University of Central Lancashire and its partner universities in Kenya. The winners of the Top Story Season 2 competition (Mount Kenya University) were invited as panellists to one of the key discussions of the day. In addition, the winning stories from Top Story were screened at the event. Q3: AoA continues to find opportunities for distributing the development reporting handbook, especially events that bring together key media institutions and practitioners. Preparation began in August for the upcoming October kick off of the Top Story Africa &#x201C;Roadshow&#x201D; which will share best-practice journalism methodologies in regional Kenyan cities and rural communities, where the handbook will be one resource discussed and distributed to universities and other institutions that will be involved in the tour. So far over 300 copies of the handbook have been distributed within the media community. AfricaonAir supported the Kenya Media Week, which was organised on 12-14 September, by Media Focus Africa, a Kenyan NGO that supports improvement of standards in media through public events and dialogue. A number of high profile media personalities attended the event and shared their experience. AoA was among the media organisations that took part in the exhibition during Kenya Media Week. Q4: AoA continues to find opportunities for distributing the &#x2018;Reporting Development, A guide for African Journalists&#x2019; handbook and raise the visibility of AfricanOnAir in the region. The guide was utililsed by AoA trainers in Zambia and was a key component of a a training workshop on reporting energy. The 20 journalists from different media houses in Zambia who took part each received a copy of the handbook for use in their newsroom. 2019 Q1: Top Story Season 3 preparation includes development of intensive capacity building sessions on investigative journalism reporting techniques, ethics, digital/physical safety, for journalism student participants that will take place at the Top Story bootcamp in May. Q2: The safety of journalists will be a key theme in Top Story Season 3. There will be specialist training for contestants and lecturers focusing on both physical and digital safety. AoA will also be vigilant in ensuring the safety of contestants carrying out sensitive investigations during the competition. Q3: Safety is an integral part of AoA organisation and activities. Before any filming activity takes place or any event involving members of the public or done in public places, a security appraisal is conducted. Additionally, AoA advocates for safety (physical/cyber) to be mainstreamed across all journalism curricula of participating universities. 2020 Q2: AoA&#x2019;s production and filming activities are conducted in accordance with the high standards of safety in place in international media organisations such as the BBC and Aljazeera. A thorough recce and audit of safety at proposed filming locations is carried out in advance and the teams travelling to film in such locations are always accompanied by a security specialist. In addition, competing teams undergo digital safety training at the initial bootcamp that is run at the start of each season of Top Story.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and Inclusiveness: Media content is increasingly gender-sensitive and reflects social and cultural diversity and participation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">AfricaonAir embeds reporting on issues of gender and diversity in their training materials and resources.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q1: Sixty Kenyan journalism students were trained at the &apos;Top Story&apos; bootcamp on reporting on gender and diversity, how to look for stories on gender issues and reach out to sources of information on these themes (Limuru, 20-21 February 2017). Development of distance learning module in cooperation with Foreign Policy Interrupted as part of their international gender fellowship programme. Two female journalists were selected to take part in the upcoming four-week programme. Q2: Four-week gender fellowship distance learning module completed with feature story and op-eds produced by Kenyan female journalists led by Foreign Policy Interrupted. Planning steps taken to establish Kenya-based media gender communication advocacy tools for team of female journalists. Reportages related to gender issues continue to be investigated as part of Top Story university journalism competitions. Q3: AfricaonAir and EJC have been collaborating with Foreign Policy Interrupted,&#xA0;on the first FPI Genders&#xA0;Fellows&#xA0;programme designed specifically for Kenya. AoA nominated two Kenyan journalists who underwent distance-learning sessions and individual reportage mentoring by FPI. The FPI rep later traveled to Nairobi for a workshop to finalise feature story outputs for publication on women&apos;s issues. The two Gender Fellows will create their own monthly version of FPI&#x2019;s weekly newsletter, carefully curating and showcasing Kenyan female journalism talent, disseminating to stakeholders and media outlets across the country. The overall aim is to increase women&apos;s overall voice and visibility in the media in Kenya. Q4: Top Story journalism challenge is the flagship project and it routinely integrates gender. University teams taking part in the competition are required, as a rule to observe gender equity. The big following for the show has also seen Top Story begin to receive ideas and suggestions from the general public on development stories that they would like to see featured, including the fight against female genital mutilation (FGM). The Kenyan monthly version of FPI&#x2019;s weekly newsletter was published twice. Kenya Interrupted is produced by two Gender Fellows who curate and showcase Kenyan female journalism talent. Using its big database and wide network, AfricaonAir helps distribute the newsletter to stakeholders and media outlets across the country. The main objective is to increase women&apos;s overall voice and visibility in the media in Kenya. This is the first initiative of its kind in Kenya that amplifies women&#x2019;s voice and it reaches many influential people. The AoA team itself is constructed on the principle of gender equality. 2018: Q1 AfricaonAir has now fully adopted a policy of integrating gender in its initiatives. All universities taking part in the Top Story competition are required to ensure that their teams have gender balance and this includes the production teams that work on the TV show. Based on strategy meeting in Nairobi in March Meeting, Kenya Interrupted will be expanded to East Africa (in cooperation with Tanzanian Media Foundation), more frequent newsletter and preparation for social media presence. Q2: Kenya Interrupted (KI) continues to be distributed through AfricaonAir&#x2019;s growing mailing list and now that the AoA website has been revamped, the newsletter will also be made available on the site. At a meeting (organised in Dar es Salaam on 8 June) led by the KI curators and Kenyan strategist several issues were discussed, that included the addition of Tanzanian female journalist produced content, social media presence, collaborative visibility events and continued expansion of content from additional countries in East Africa. AoA continues to receive and analyse feedback from the monthly newsletter. Q3: Preparations for an Interrupted Africa meeting in Dar es Salaam on 31 Oct-02 November about expanding the initiative (incl. more countries). Q4: Interrupttr Africa meeting, was held on 31 Oct-2 November in Dar es Salaam. A monthly newsletter by women journalists/experts on important issues in Africa will be published. Three experts from Kenya are part of the team. 2019 Q1: AoA has integrated gender in its activities. It is a condition of the Top Story Season 3 competition that all university teams taking part must have a mix of gender in their teams. In addition, AoA has instituted a requirement that the film crews involved in the competition must have mixed gender. The same principle is being observed in the recruitment of judges and mentors for the competition. AoA through its director published an informative article on the obstacles that stand in the way of gender equality at the decision-making level in Kenya and proposed ways to push forward a bill tabled in parliament to ensure gender equality in leadership. The article was published by BBC Online: https://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-46507685. As a result of this article, AoA was approached by Women Deliver, a global organisation that champions gender equality about the possibilities of providing training to Kenyan journalists on gender equality in late 2019. Q3: AoA policy of requiring student teams must be of mixed gender was successful. In Season One of TS the teams were hugely male-dominated but now the gap is closing. 43% of the student participants were female and 57% were male. Q4: AoA has a firm commitment to gender equality at AfricaonAir and are continuously looking for opportunities to further integrate gender in operations and projects. Top Story relies on a filming crew of freelancers, but unfortunately in Kenya the number of women working in certain areas of production such as camera and sound operators is still very low. In Season 3 of Top Story we managed to promote one of the film personnel to become a senior director and head of content. 2020 Q2: AoA continues to work in accordance with its gender polices which aim to achieve a 50/50 gender balance in all its activities. The Top Story competition rules ensure that no one gender occupies more than two thirds of the slots in competing teams.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD4: # of advocacy initiatives carried out by CSOs, for, by or with their membership/constituency</narrative>
    </title>
    <baseline iso-date="2020-07-29" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD1: # of laws, policies and norms, implemented for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2: # of laws, policies and norms/attitudes, blocked, adopted, improved for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 # of times that CSOs succeed in creating space for CSO demands and positions through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or creating space to engage</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="13"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5: # of CSOs with increased L&amp;A capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="23"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6: # of CSOs included in Strategic Partnership programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="29"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
