<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41078390" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No News is Bad News - Paraguay</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Context and Analysis The 1992 Constitution of Paraguay guarantees freedom of the press, freedom of expression, and people&#x2019;s right to access information. However, in practice, Paraguayans are increasingly finding it hard to enjoy those rights. A growing concentration of media ownership, violence against journalists, and public policies that facilitate censorship are limiting the expression of a plurality of voices. Fake news has become a major challenge in Paraguay, and the 2018 presidential campaigns were marred with false information and the massive use of social media to disseminate it. All these factors are undermining the availability of truthful information in the public space and the quality of political debate in the country. As a result of the existing economic model in Paraguay, the ownership of large states is reflected directly in a monopoly also in the Media. Currently, merely three business groups (with interests in agribusiness) are owners of the largest quantity of television, radio, and press news media in the country. This gives them ample power to influence the public opinion and the design of public policy of the government itself. At the same time, it only allows a thin margin for the expression of the plurality of voices concerned with public affairs. Furthermore, despite the fact that the country is beneficiary to a demographic bonus (29% of the population is between 15 and 29 years old, 2 million people), the majority of the media is not concerned with producing content focused on this age group, overlooking their importance to the present and the future of the country. In this manner, civic space, a pillar of the democratic system, is weakened in its capacity to balance power. Currently, conventional media excludes diversity of voices. Therefore, there are fewer opportunities for citizens to have access to information that is diverse, truthful, responsible, balanced, and systematic. Particularly the information that involves people under 30. Also, the standards of public debate are lowered, and democracy is weakened, since it&#x2019;s difficult to access systematic information in order to hold public entities to account or to propitiate civic organisation. Faced with these challenges, there is an eminently young population that has already been a protagonist for its claims of structural changes and that has the potential to generate the changes that the country needs. In the last presidential elections (2018), 500 thousand young people were qualified to vote for the first time. The productive, creative and change capacity is concentrated in this segment of the population and this project aims to reach this segment through the provision of accurate, challenging and relevant information. The growing number of people accessing the Internet does not necessarily mean that they are better informed. One of the reasons is the quality of the education system, rated by the World Economic Forum as one of the worst in the world. The PISA test shows that only 32.2% of students reach the minimum required in reading comprehension skills, well below the OECD average of 79.9%. This means that they can barely identify the main subject of a text or the intention of the author. Added to the problem is the enormous amount of misleading information circulating on social networks, these being the main channels through which people access news. There are also established prejudices and myths that lead to discrimination and inequality. Without skills to verify the reliability of the information they consume or to question beliefs, people run the risk of being manipulated and perpetuating situations of injustice. Power groups have also shown that they can assemble infrastructures of trolls and bots that proliferate social networks to attack, give more visibility to the contents of certain profiles and to disseminate false data or biased information. These accounts discredit the work of journalists or disseminate disinformation that affects the quality of public debate on key issues, such as a democratic parity law to increase the representation of women in Congress or a law to prevent sexual abuse of minors. On both occasions, congressmen rejected these bills with arguments similar to those disseminated by these accounts on social networks. These accounts are behind the agenda that promotes the retrogression of minority rights. Information on external funding environment: The Ministry of Foreign Affairs informs that international cooperation in Paraguay is &quot;financial (reimbursable or not), technical, called Official Development Assistance (ODA), South-South or triangular cooperation, through bilateral agreements, or multilateral organisations, or can be decentralised and include other actors from civil society and the private sector, in addition to government agencies, but in any case it is transversal&quot;. The majority of international cooperation is aimed at programmes to combat poverty, technical development of productivity, education and health. There are few programs that support projects associated with the promotion of freedom of expression, civic technology and journalism. The concentration of mass media limits the expression of a plurality of voices. Currently, no more than three business groups own the largest amount of television, radio and print media in the country. This gives them broad power to influence public opinion and the design of government policies. In addition, with the incursion of the business group of former president Horacio Cartes, which today has about ten media outlets, a media capture phenomenon emerges. Cartes continues to practice politics and through its media promotes the agenda of authorities such as legislators, governors or mayors who are loyal to his leadership. One of the consequences of this reality is the discrediting of journalistic work and the growing distrust and devaluation of audiences towards the press. At the same time, the low level of education in the population increases the risk of media manipulation, to the benefit of the same power groups that legislate against the well-being of the majority. Halfway to digital equality: Audit yields mixed results from Paraguay: A national strategy to eliminate Internet violence against girls and women and implement policies to overcome barriers to Web access and use are some of the recommendations of a study by TEDIC. The Gender Digital Divide Audit Report Card is a tool developed by the World Wide Web Foundation - an organisation founded by the creator of the Web, Tim Berners-Lee - that evaluates and qualifies governments and companies in their efforts to reduce what is known as the gender digital divide. This is the first time it has been implemented in Paraguay. The country receives a global score of 50%, below Colombia, which has 60%, and above the Dominican Republic, with 44%.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">media professionals, women, CSO stakeholders</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" role="4" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latitud25</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memetic Media</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-04-01">92500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">47100</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">92500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-LA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">47100</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-LA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">53000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memetic Media &amp; Latitud25</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">44275</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memetic Media &amp; Latitud25</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">27100</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memetic Media &amp; Latitud25</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-30">24403</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Memetic Media &amp; Latitud25</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">63932</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">51675</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-PY" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accountability: media hold power-holders to account and are accountable to their public</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latitud25/El Surtidor journalists regularly produce investigative journalism reportages that have positive society impacts and hold political leaders. Media practitioners are committed to serving the public interest with the proper accountability, inclusiveness, participation and act as watchdogs through in-depth reportage production and other accountability formats, which are tracked and measured for impact.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Q2: El Surtidor: At least 60 graphic pieces have been published, one per day from Monday to Friday during the reporting period. The piece with major impact focused on menstruation&#x2019;s economic cost to young women in Paraguay. https://www.instagram.com/p/ByDCKuHj0Mb/. It addresses a subject that affects a young audience, which for the first time was covered by public discussion due to publishing of the story. The reaction was so positive, that for the podcast season El Surti will do a follow-up piece on the collective experience of women who are part of the audience. The use of El Surtidor&#x2019;s pieces by policy makers is also notable to sustain their positions on different aspects of the discussion, especially in Paraguay&#x2019;s National Congress. This happened twice: in the debate about electronic voting and another on tax reform. Twelve in-depth pieces, including scrolls, photojournalism, and report have been published. A further piece with major impact has been the photographic report on the overpopulation in jails of Asunci&#xF3;n. https://elsurti.com/presos-sin-condena/. In addition, El Surti was awarded the first ever Planet Award for excellence in climate change reporting at the Eurasia Media Forum in Almaty, Kazakstan 23rd May, specifically for their reportage on deforestation in The Chaco region of Paraguay &#x201C;Los Desterrados Del Chaco&#x201D;. Q3: El Surtidor: More than 90 illustrated pieces have been published during the reporting period. The reportage with the greatest impact covered the violence that members of the LGTBI community in Hernadarias suffered (east of the country) Paraguay. 20 in-depth pieces were also published using various multi-media formats, including posters, photojournalism, videos, reports and scrolls. A further report focused on Fundajoven, an evangelical NGO that provides mental health care without having professional credentials. El Surti also took part in several regional collaborative journalism projects &#x2013; e.g. #TransnacionalesdelaFe published with news outlets such as Univision, Agencia Publica, El Tiempo, CIPER On August 1, they launched the podcast season. It is published once a month exclusively for WhatsApp. It is then available on traditional podcast platforms (iTunes, Spreaker, iVoox, Spotify). The launch episode of the podcast season had high listenership and was widely shared re the history of the Ykua Bolan&#x303;os supermarket fire, which happened 15 years ago. El Surtidor&apos;s pieces continued to be utilized by policymakers to maintain their positions on different aspects of public debates, especially in the National Congress. This happened several times: including the debate on electronic voting, tax reform, public transport, religious interference in education and obstetric violence. Recently, the Ministry of Education and Culture announced that it will cancel the distribution of the magazine Decisions in public schools, since they consider that its content is unscientific, as El Surtidor had denounced in an investigation published in February this year. Collective live fact-check: This is the first live check of the presidential report on the history of Paraguay, which marks a milestone at the journalistic level. Training aimed specifically, at the audience of El Surtidor, with the aim of training volunteers for the live check to the 2019 presidential report. More than 100 people applied, 10 were selected. A workshop was conducted with a focus on the fact-check methodology. During the report - which lasted a little more than an hour, the team composed of journalists, volunteers and specialists checked 13 statements by President Mario Abdo, all were published in real time in a Twitter thread , on Instagram Stories and in a special section on the web . Among the most relevant checks, It highlights the false statement about the scope of the digital agenda in public schools , a check that could be made with the help of the audience. After the event, a brief article was made as a check balance, which was shared in a special section of the Radio Fe y Alegr&#xED;a and sent by WhatsApp to the more than 300 people who subscribed requesting the summary . Q4: El Surti: More than 70 graphic pieces have been published, one per day from Monday to Friday, and Sundays. The graphic piece with the greatest impact has been one that covered the money laundering scheme that involves the ex-president Horacio Cartes https://www.instagram.com/p/B5C6kowjkpA/ They took part in two regional collaborative journalism projects. We want to highlight #MitosESI, a collective, regional fact-cheking initiative about the falsehoods about comprehensive sexuality education (ESI, in spanish) in Latin America https://elsurti.com/chequeoesi They published the two (2) final podcast of the season on medical cannabis, in the country with the highest illegal production of weed and prohibition legislation. The first part is about Edgar Martinez Sacoman, the first Paraguayan in history sentenced to prison for producing and giving away cannabis oil for the sick https://elsurti.com/presoporcurar. The second part is about the organization Mam&#xE1; Cultiva, a network/union of women and their families that faces the pharmaceutical industry, the State and the narco to be able to produce medical cannabis oil that relieves the pain of their children https://elsurti.com/mamacultiva L25: With their space in a broad-spectrum national radio, they been able to reach more people, and are starting to raise awareness on some delicate matters, such as teenage pregnancy, LGBT+ rights and environmental awareness. They began making the young audience interested in politics, which was their main goal, from the start. 2020 Q1: El Surti: has focused mainly on coverage of the coronavirus pandemic in Paraguay, especially on fact-checking to combat false news about the coronavirus. More than 70 graphic pieces have been published, about two per day since the coronavirus quarantine start in Paraguay. They have produced more than 30 fact checks about coronavirus in Paraguay, about one per day in the quarantine times. They have launched a special microsite on coronavirus (elsurti.com/coronavirus) They also produce about 5 scrolls about coronavirus in Paraguay, They took part in two regional collaborative journalism projects about coronavirus They have identified that the greatest source of misinformation about the pandemic are the audios that circulate via WhatsApp. For this reason, they have decided to publish a podcast with fact checks on these fake audios and verified information about the virus. L25: Health &amp; Environment: Audiovisual report on access to drinking water in rural communities with high poverty rates. Interviews with community leaders, social leaders and public authorities to understand this complex problem that affects 82% of the country&apos;s population without sanitation facilities. Focus on Gender - International Women&apos;s Day Report: Published video including interviews with leading scientists, representatives of scientific research in Paraguay. Coverage COVID19 - Educational content on hygiene measures and prevention of the pandemic, through visual, textual, and auditory means. Q2: El Surti: During this period, El Surtidor continued to focus mainly on coverage of the coronavirus pandemic in Paraguay, especially on fact-checking to combat false news about the coronavirus. More than100 graphic pieces have been published, about two per day since the coronavirus quarantine started in Paraguay. More than 50 fact checks about coronavirus in Paraguay, about one per day in the quarantine times. They have launched and continuing updated the special microsite on coronavirus (elsurti.com/coronavirus). They also produced +20 scrolls about coronavirus in Paraguay. They took part in two regional collaborative journalism projects about coronavirus #CoronaVirusFacts Alliance, a global effort lead by the International Fact Checking Network. We are the only Paraguay media outlet #LatatamChequea, a Latin-American network of factcheckers working together against the coronavirus infodemia . Creation and launch of a new podcast (daily, then weekly) with checks on disinformation about the coronavirus Joined the #Coronavirus Alliance IFCN Facts Poynter Institute. Confirmation of a team dedicated to illustration checks the network LatamChequea. In the Coronavirus pandemic in Paraguay, they have identified that the greatest source of misinformation about the pandemic are the audios that circulate via WhatsApp. 25 podcasts with verified information distributed via Whatsapp, social media and popular podcast apps such iTunes, Google Podcast, Spreaker, Sopityf. Alliance with Radio N&#x303;anduti&#x301; for a precise section on a weekly platform. Another important impact to highlight is the verification of El Surti and #LaPrecisa accounts on social networks. This not only provides greater confidence to the audience in times of an infodemic, it is also the result of the processes of transparency and improvement of institutional communication that they are working on. L25: COVID19, economic consequences - Monitoring realities of communities in vulnerable situations, to understand the needs they are facing, so that we can help them make their situation visible. Content design about the reality of the gay, trans, indigenous community, as well as other affected communities such as micro-entrepreneurs. Content Production about Coverage COVID19 - Educational content on hygiene measures and prevention of the pandemic, through visual, textual, and auditory means. Latitud 25 aims to position itself in the political media environment, working to maintain a close and intimidating relationship with political power. The content we generate allows us to influence the political agenda based on reliable sources in the different governmental instances.
Q3: L25: Covid-19 Coverage: Human rights during the pandemic, exploring the reality of vulnerable communities.
Environmental Coverage: They are monitoring and covering the urgent environmental crisis unfolding in Paraguay.
El Surti: During this period, they continued to focus primarily on coverage of the coronavirus pandemic in Paraguay, especially fact-checking to combat fake news about the coronavirus.
Launch of #Latingor&#xE1;ficas, a regional program for the training and production of visual journalism against disinformation (elsurti.com/latinograficas)
They have launched and continuing updated the special microsite on coronavirus (elsurti.com/coronavirus)
Theyalso produce +20 scrolls style info about coronavirus in Paraguay.
More than 250 graphic pieces have been published, about two per day since the coronavirus quarantine start in Paraguay. 
More than 80 fact checks about coronavirus in Paraguay, about one per day in the quarantine times.
They took part in two regional collaborative journalism projects about coronavirus
#CoronaVirusFacts Alliance, a global effort lead by the International Fact Checking Network. They are the only Paraguay media outlet
#LatatamChequea, a Latin-American network of factcheckers working together against the coronavirus infodemia
Creation and launch of a new podcast (weekly) with checks on disinformation about the coronavirus 
Release the section blog live transparency and meetings with the audience.
In the Coronavirus pandemic in Paraguay, they have identified that the greatest source of misinformation about the pandemic is the audios circulating on WhatsApp. For this reason, they continue to publish a podcast that is mainly distributed on this platform, with verified info. 15 podcasts with verified information distributed through WhatsApp, social networks and popular podcast applications such as iTunes, Google Podcast, Spreaker, Spotify&#x2026;
Weekly space on radio &#xD1;anduti AM 1020. 20 chapters total.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-05-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability development: media increasingly operate as efficient and self-sustaining organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latitud25/El Surtidor have a sustainable strategic business plan</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Q2: Latitud25: focus on brands advertising, sponsorship and making branded content for companies and organisations, expansion strategies focused on its YouTube audience in order to monetise videos on the platform. The outlet&#x2019;s commercial consultant works closely with staff in order to improve the outlets overall strategic plan together with growth needs. Investment funding was applied for during the reporting period. In August El Surtidor will launch the alpha version of the membership programme (the first 100 members). The target is that in 2022 this source represents at least 20% of income. In August the organisation will launch the alpha version of the online store. It is expected that in 2022 the store represents at least 5% of income. As one of the activities of this project, by the end of the year it will be introduced product or service co-created with the community that will represent at least 1% of income. Q3: El Surtidor is one of the 75 pre-selected media of the Speed Fund run by SembreMedia which focuses on development of sustainability models. Q4: El Surti: As a result of this project, they have now editorial product (print magazine) co-created with the community. It will represent at least 1% of the revenue sources. They are one of the 10 selected media of the Velocidad Fund (SembreMedia, ICFJ and Luminate), the only one from Paraguay. They will receive funds and consulting for the development of our sustainability model. They are currently redesigning the visual communication consultancy department, which they expect will generate revenues of around 5 to 10% by 2020. L25: are still focusing on brands advertising, sponsorship and making branded content for companies and organisations. Our commercial consultant works closely with us in order to improve our business plan according to our growth needs. 2020 Q1: Latitud25 has three parallel sources of financing: Traditional advertising on the radio and television programme, the radio program is broadcast from Monday to Friday by a local FM station at 12 PM and the TV program on an information channel on Sundays at 8 PM. Branded Content: Latitud25 offers production services on topics of interest from different companies. Coca Cola, Nivea, Petrobras, WWF, UNDP have been allies in generating these stories. International Cooperation: This source of financing is subject to specific objectives that allow us to achieve short-term goals. The idea is not to depend on this source of financing, but to use it as a way to show new realities that would otherwise be very difficult for us. Parallax S.A., audiovisual production services for companies that wish to create corporate audiovisual materials for the promotion of their businesses. However, the pandemic caused L25 enormous damage in terms of financial planning, the resources they had planned for investment in equipment, they had to revert to current expenses and postpone the planned investments until the situation re-establishes itself. Q2: L25: Since COVID-19, traditional advertising has been reduced considerably, so L25 had to explore new mechanisms of financial sustainability. That is why they not only started and focused on an intense search for international cooperation funds, but also managed to provide audiovisual services for companies that needed visual material to communicate their actions during the pandemic. They started offering services as a production company, which allowed them to go through the first months of the pandemic with a slightly safer projection than what they initially planned. The reality in Paraguay is very uncertain, which makes it difficult to have an accurate perspective of what may happen in the months to come.
Q3: El Surti: Since March 2020 they have implemented a Design Studio Agency, which serves organizations in Paraguay and Latin America that need to communicate with digital native audiences. The Studio already worked with its first 15 clients.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media implement policies and actions to foster gender equality in their organisations</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latitud25/El Surtidor are aware of the need of a gender balance in their organisations and are working towards this.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Q2: Latitud25: has been promoting gender equality from its founding. 40% of our staff and 50% of its hosts are female. El Surtidor: Gender perspective is cross-sectional in coverage, as well as in events and in team selection. In this period, three women joined the staff, now making up the majority in the editorial team. Q3: El Surti: Another women joined the staff, being now the majority of the team. 2020 Q1: The gender component has always been an important aspect for the Latitud25 team. Their crew of hosts is made up of two males and two females. This allows L25 to maintain a constant awareness and consideration for approaching gender with the work they do. Q2: El Surti: The gender perspective is cross-sectional in coverage, as well as in events and in team selection. In this period, another woman joined the staff. Now women are the majority of the team.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and inclusiveness: media content increasingly is gender-sensitive and reflects social &amp; cultural diversity and participation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Innovative journalism content of the media in Paraguay is more diverse and participatory with a focus on gender/diversity issues and other under reported topics.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Q2: Latitud25: has been promoting gender equality from its founding. 40% of our staff and 50% of its hosts are female. Latitud25 give coverage to gender equality news and initiatives LGBTI+ community including housekeeping minimum wages, Pride events, and family diversification. El Surtidor: Gender perspective is cross-sectional in coverage, as well as in events and in team selection. In this period, three women joined the staff, now making up the majority in the editorial team. Q3: During the reporting period, L25 worked with United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) to produce reportages on teenage pregnancy, a long-standing problem in the country, to raise awareness of the issue. El Surti: 100% of the volunteers participating in the collective check-up to the presidential report were women. https://youtu.be/QupdMzwA86A. Q4: El Surti: published an in-depth piece on &#x2018;when the state rapes women&#x2019; - a group of female farmers denounced sexual violence in an eviction commanded by former Interior Minister Walter Bower 19 years ago https://elsurti.com/un-crimen-de-poder/. Women are the majority of El Surti&#x2019;s audience: 60% on average. In the demographics of 18-24 years old, this percentage is up to 65%. El Surti editor was invited to be part of The Festival Cocuyo, in Venezuela. She made a lecture about covering gender issues. 2020 Q1: L25 Focus on Gender - International Women&apos;s Day Report: Published video including interviews with leading scientists, representatives of scientific research in Paraguay. All the content generated by Latitud25 is subject to editorial control in order to preserve the gender perspective and inclusive language. The production of content on gender and human rights is always included in the production schedule, although for the duration of the pandemic, this type of content has been temporarily suspended due to reduced operational capacity. That being said, Latitud25 always keeps this topic a priority in its content. Q2: L25 tells stories about the testimonies of women who are changing their realities in different ways. To do this, they hired an indigenous and feminist leader as a reporter, to help them correctly understand the realities of vulnerable communities and whose needs must be visible. She will join the team not only for these matters, but also to allow L25 to incorporate a wider perspective of how to talk about these issues related to basic human rights, gender diversity and women leadership. L25 is about to open more opportunities for young female journalists with a strong view of gender and equality perspective, to increase our capacity to tell stories about different faces of poverty and discrimination, but also inspirational stories about people whose stories are worthy to tell. El Surti: The gender perspective is cross-sectional in coverage, as well as in events and in team selection. In this period, another woman joined the staff. Now women are the majority of the team. Also, women are the majority of our audience: 60% on average. In the demographics of 18-24 years old, this percentage is up to 65%.
Q3: L25 carried out a coverage exclusively on gender, exploring the reality of the trans community during the global pandemic, facing growing needs and a lack of governmental support. The story can be seen on this link. The coverage was carried out by Conny Oviedo, the newest host of L25. Conny is a communicator and feminist activist of indigenous origins. In addition, they did a coverage on new masculinities, adding analysis elements to dismantle the cultural construction surrounding machismo and its societal impact in Paraguay. The reportage can be seen on this link.
El Surti: Women are the majority of their audience: 60% on average. In the demographics of 18-24 years old, this percentage ups to 65%. More than 60% of the 150 registered for Latinograficas are women. 6 of 7 fellows from Latinograficas are women</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development in lobby &amp; advocacy: media developed the skills to work as change catalysts in lobby and advocacy</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latitud25/El Surtidor editorial staff acquire capacity to work as effective watchdogs utilising innovative, data-based techniques, safety, security and protection mechanisms. Management acquire knowledge to increase outlet viability, expand audiences and innovation in content production/distribution.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Q2: Latitud25: has upgraded its content release frequency from six videos to 15. Additionally there has been a steady daily release frequency of news podcast, to over 1500 subscribers. With the combination of its online platforms, and nationwide tv programming Latitud25 is now able to reach a much bigger segment of population. Viewers&#x2019; numbers have increased from an average of 60.000 to 90.000 individuals each week. This has been a result of a further focus on training staff in reaching new audiences with engaging content utilising innovative digital solutions. El Surtidor: The reach went from 300,000 monthly views in social media (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter) to 400,000 weekly. Web views went from 2,000 monthly to 4,000 weekly. The growth in Whatsapp subscriptions is remarkable. It went from 1,200 to 3,000 with an active participation of tihs community. This has been a result of a further focus on training staff in reaching new audiences with engaging content utilising innovative digital solutions. Q3: During the reporting period, L25 reached a frequency of launching 15 new reportages per month with wider audience due to increased content flows through social media networks. In September L25 launched an FM radio programme that now allows further amplification of their content at a broadcast nationwide level. El Surtidor reportages were republished in two local mediums and 10 international ones with weekly reach on all social media channels achieved 5,500 views. 4,000 people are now subscribers to the Whatsapp list and nearly 20,000 weekly interactions in all digital channels. Two new platforms are in collaboration with the Latamchequea network: On the candidacy of Argentina, Uruguay, Paraguay and Chile for the 2030 World Cup focuses on sex education in countries of the region (to be published at the end of October). Participation in the Clip network on the influence of conservative Christian groups in these Latin American states. In addition, El Surti is producing a collaborative report on agrochemicals together with the Brazilian Agencia Pu&#x301;blica. Q4: Q4: El Surti: The reach went from 550,000 monthly views in social media (Facebook, Instagram, Twitter) to 650,000 weekly. The growth in Whatsapp subscriptions went up from 4000 to 6500. Most of the new subscribers are thanks to the podcasts. Almost 300 new subscribers to the WhatsApp list every time a podcast is published. Podcast distribution by WhatsApp allows to reach a new audience: young, from the suburbs and with strong oral culture. They have a new channel (a print magazine) capable of generating genuine income for the environment, thus improving our sustainability and identity. L25: are now settled on radio and it&#x2019;s becoming the main way people are getting to know and it&#x2019;s a far more effective way to interact with their audience, since the radio programme is live, and TV wasn&#x2019;t. L25 have also began making some podcasts with diverse content and published it on Spotify, so this will become another of expanding their content release frequency. 2020 Q1: El Surti: The weekly reach in social media is approximately of 600.000 views, the website receives 4,000 visits weekly. 8,000 people are subscribed to the Whatsapp list. Close to 25,000 weekly interactions in all digital channels. Q2: El Surti: An average reach in networks (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram) of 450 thousand people per publication Estimated average reach in messaging systems (WhatsApp + Telegram) of 15 thousand people per publication. It is also the channel with the most interaction.) During the quarantine period (March to May), only the special on the coronavirus received more than 35 thousand visits. The exclusive feed #LaPrecisa (@elsurtichequea) already has more than 10,000 followers and continues to maintain sustained growth. Instagram feed grew by 5% from the start, going from 35,000 to more than 46,000 followers, with a good participation in interactive publications on fact check. The average interactions per publication has increased, adding up all social platforms, especially in messaging, where we have received hundreds of messages requesting information verification.
Q3: El Surti: During this period they launched #Latingor&#xE1;ficas, a regional program for the training and production of visual journalism against disinformation (elsurti.com/latinograficas), aimed at independent digital native media in Latin America. +150 registered for lightning talks and master classes (about 10 from Bolivia) and +7 fellows selected for visual production.
Collaboration with 3 transnational journalistic networks: Salud con Lupa, Connectas and LatamChequea
160 applicants from 140 media from 55 different cities in Latin America, Spain and the USA have signed up for the activities of Latinogr&#xE1;fica 2020
More than 15 panellists and teachers from Latin America, USA, Australia and America.
They estimate an average reach in messaging systems (Whatsapp + Telegram) of 15 thousand people per publication. It is also the channel with the most interaction.)
During the quarantine period (March to August), only the special on the coranavirus received more than 85 thousand visits.
The exclusive feed #LaPrecisa (@elsurtichequea) already has more than 10,000 followers and continues to maintain sustained growth.
The Instagram feed grew by 5% from the start, going from 35,000 to more than 47,000 followers, with a good participation in interactive publications on fact check.
The average interactions per publication has increased, adding up all social platforms, especially in messaging, where they have received hundreds of messages requesting information verification.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development in strategic engagement: media and CSOs are capable to relate strategically to achieve common goals in lobby and advocacy</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latitud25/El Surtidor strengthen relationships with local CSOs which advocate on matters of national developmental interest. Staff routinely source and &#x2018;cooperate&#x2019; with CSOs on reportages of public interest.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latitud25: regularly works with local civil society organisations that focus on issues of human rights, the environment and education. The organisation is currently pre-producing materials for the UN on teenage pregnancy in Paraguay. El Surtidor: At a local level, El Surti partners on reportage productions with Serpaj, Koga, Base IS, and others. 2019 Q3: L25 continued to work closely with CSOs, focused on Human Rights, Environment and digital security. L25 also worked with UNFPA in a series of audio-visual content targeting teenage pregnancy. El Surti&#x2019;s visual editor Juan Heilborn was a speaker at EJC&#x2019;s News Impact Summit: A New Era for Climate Change Reporting, held in Birmingham on October 7. Editor Jazmi&#x301;n Acun&#x303;a was awarded a scholarship to participate in the Global Investigative Journalism Conference 2019 in Hamburg. Ms Acuna was invited to be a founding member of the Latin American Network of Female Journalists, held in Panama. Alejandro Valdez Sanabria was invited to be an assistant facilitator at the Workshop on Scientific Journalism organized by the Gabo Foundation in Cartagena. He presented the relationship model with the audience in the StartUp Gathering of PIJ/OSF held in Kathmandu. 2020 Q2: El Surti: Networks, alliances and groups of close readers: Product of #LaPrecisa&apos;s work, in this period they have joined a new regional journalism network, which increases the quality, scope of coverage and prestige of the medium. The only Paraguayan media member of the IFCN Coronavirus Facts Alliance, the largest global network to combat disinformation during the pandemic. The only Paraguayan media member of the #LatamChequea network for coronavirus coverage. The only Paraguayan media member of the #Centinela network for state control in times of pandemic The process of forming a LATAM visual journalists network promoted by El Surtidor continues, despite the fact that the first meeting was postponed by the pandemic.
Q3: Latitud25 has partnered with two emerging spaces which have created further platforms for the concerns of the population, Paraguay Ahora and Todas las Voces, which not only seek to provide inclusiveness for people of all backgrounds, but also provide structure to the ideas that arise in those spaces. 
El Surti: Networks, alliances and groups of close readers: Product of #LaPrecisa&apos;s work, in this period they have joined a new regional journalism network, which increases the quality, scope of coverage and prestige of the medium.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD1: # of laws, policies and norms, implemented for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-01-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2: # of laws, policies and norms/attitudes, blocked, adopted, improved for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5: # of CSOs with increased L&amp;A capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6: # of CSOs included in Strategic Partnership programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD4: # of advocacy initiatives carried out by CSOs, for, by or with their membership / constituency</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 # of times that CSOs succeed in creating space for CSO demands and positions through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or creating space to engage</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="7"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
