<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41078390" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No News is Bad News - Tanzania</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTEXT ANALYSIS: Tanzania is classified as a low-income country; ranked 159 out of 187 countries in the Human Development lndex. Although a multiparty state, it has been ruled by Chama Cha Mapinduzi (CCM) since independence in 1961. Tanzania&#x2019;s relative political stability has provided a solid foundation for economic growth, and raised its profile in the region and the world. The media industry in Tanzania has grown rapidly since its liberalisation in the early 1990s. The media sector now consists of a combination of actors with diverse interests. There are more than 800 registered newspapers, more than 120 radio stations and 26 registered TV stations with concentrated ownership by business tycoons, politicians and religious. The Freedom of the Press Index have categoriSed Tanzania as &quot;partly free&quot; since 2002, with little change in scores. Although there has recently been a move to address outdated media laws, two newly introduced bills - Media Services Act and Access to Information Act- have been widely criticiSed as draconian. The Electronic and Postal Communications Act is now used to suspend publications, which were free to publish online before the law was enacted. Access to information Bill has already passed the Parliament and is now waiting a Presidential signature for it to become law. The Media Services Bill, which was initially defeated, will be read for the second time in October 2016. The planned law is aimed to oversee the media&#x2019;s professional and ethical conducts, licensing of journalists, confiscation of assets of offending media house and granting wide-ranging enter-and-search powers to junior police officers. PROBLEM ANALYSIS: The country has witnessed new laws being enacted such as the Statistics Act, Cybercrime Act and Access to Information Act. The Media Services Bill will be read again in the parliament before the end of 2016. Media stakeholders are not comfortable with some clauses as they impinge on freedom of expression. Once laws are passed in parliament, the media&#x2019;s only recourse for appeal is to challenge them in the High Court. Some of the clauses in the Cybercrime Act for instance, are now being challenged in the High Court as unconstitutional. Financial and legal support is needed to challenge undemocratic laws in the High Court in order to ensure media and journalists to fulfil their role as change catalysts Tanzanian media content focuses largely on urban stories and political issues, giving ordinary citizens little opportunity to express their views. There is low usage and not much diversity in terms of sources and perspectives, limiting the media&apos;s ability to perform its watchdog role. Low capacity of journalists is a major part of the problem as well as a lack of influential women journalists. Strengthening media journalists&#x2019; ability to develop well researched, evidence-based reporting is crucial in order to serve the interest of the public and hold authorities to account. The media in Tanzania is facing lack of editorial independence, low professionalism and financial instability. Graduates often enter the job market with few practical skills and ill-equipped to analySe and creatively manipulate complex data to tell meaningful and engaging stories. Regular utiliSation of online resources and data remain stubbornly uncommon. Transforming the media sector needs to begin from inside the newsroom through mentorship programmes and training in quality media content production, business, marketing and newsroom management and leadership. Nurturing of young talented journalists and manufacturing of evidence-based stories would enhance professionalism, attract audience/readership, and increase revenues to improve financial stability. Attention to overall media sector sustainability can strengthen its editorial independence and professionalism.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EJC has been working with its partner, the Tanzania Media Fund since early 2015 implementing data journalism courses for journalists and providing training, supporting data-driven story production and access to its on-line resources and data journalism handbook. These efforts have increased the use of data/statistics among trainees and overall awareness among media outlets. A try-out BASELINE workshop was conducted in Tanzania between 22-24 February. Together with similar workshops in Bangladesh and Indonesia, this was designed to obtain baseline information and simultaneously test and refine the instrument we are using for this purpose. The results of these three workshops are currently being processed, and the baseline information will be included in the next update.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STRATEGY FOR L&amp;A: EJC will implement activities focusing on creating data journalism experts and mainstreaming knowledge within Tanzanian newsrooms and training institutions; EJC will support Tanzania&apos;s contribution and participation within the larger, global open data movement and Open Data Partnership Programme; EJC will organise forums to reflect, take stock and set a course for future L&amp;A actions on open data in the region; EJC will strengthen the capacity of media to interact and strategically network with CSOs and key international stakeholders involved in the open data movement. STRATEGY FOR CAPACITY DEVELOPMENT FOR L&amp;A: EJC will partner with the Tanzania Media Fund to support L&amp;A activities aimed at increasing government accountability, transparency, press freedom, access to open data and attention to gender based discrimination. This will be accomplished by focusing on the following key themes: Strengthen the capacity of Tanzanian journalists and media outlets to engage in data driven accountability journalism through training, mentorships and master classes, with special emphasis placed on engagement and recruitment of women journalists; Support and improve journalists&apos; role as civil society watchdogs by increasing their capacity to produce high-quality investigative and accountability reporting and reporting on issues that directly challenge gender-norms and discrimination. GENDER EQUALITY will be approached through two kinds of interventions: Increasing awareness among BP organisations of the necessity of instituting gender policies and exploration of a developing a formal gender policy in order to ensure that current hiring practices, communications and all in-house materials/resources reflect gender sensitivity; Gender mainstreaming will be reflected in content production during capacity building on all levels: speakers, experts, sources of information and topics on gender will be highlighted and utilised in all interventions including small grants TORs programs. Specific safety/security situation of female journalist will also be focused on. SAFETY ASPECTS will be approached through two kinds of interventions: Safety and security measures (physical and cyber) will be mainstreamed into internal policies as well as external capacity building training materials; TMF will continue to play a &#x2018;neutral platform&#x2019; role for press freedom/journalism safety/security civil society organisations to L&amp;A on these issues.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">media professionals, national and rural media outlets, CSO stakeholders</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="1" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="2" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Media Foundation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="0"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">102000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">77500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">108500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">119500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">45000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">77500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">108500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">119500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">45000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">60000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TANZANIA MEDIA FOUNDATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">37630</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">TANZANIA MEDIA FOUNDATION</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">23000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Media Foundation &amp; Media Space Tanzania</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-30">23108</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Media Foundation &amp; MediaSpace Tanzania</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">70000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Media Foundation (TMF)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">43400</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Media Foundation (TMF)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">40000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">0</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">80248</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">103820</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">76664</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">50315</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-01">102000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-01">50000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Media Foundation (TMF)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-02-01">34725</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania Media Foundation (TMF)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">82780</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-52957535-SP-TZ" ref="NL-KVK-52957535"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Development in strategic engagement: Media and CSOs are capable to relate strategically to achieve common goals in Lobby and Advocacy.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media professionals routinely source and interact with CSOs as credible sources of information on reportages of public interest.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016: Data teams utilise local CSOs as sources of information and story ideas in production of data journalism reportages. 2017: A media communication workshop was held in cooperation with a local CSO network of health organisations (15 participants). It included networking sessions with 10 local journalists from key media outlets (15-17 February 2017). Q2: Media communication advanced workshop planning with CSO health network. Preparation for printing of EJCs Swahili language version publication &#x201C;Making the Media Work For You: A Guide for CSOs&#x201D;. 2018 Q2: Five TMF staff Members had a security training in May organised by the Frontline defenders. All equipment in the Media Lab will be updated with the security system. Q3: TMF maintains and continues to strengthen relationships across the civil society organisations spectrum. A new project partnership was launched during Q3 with the Global Road Safety Partnership/Bloomberg Philanthropies (GRSP) project to strengthen efforts for change of the Tanzania&#x2019;s Road Traffic Act through increased quality and quantity of reporting on the topic. 2019 Q1: TMF has an excellent relationship with media stakeholders, government and even the private sector. TMF often collaborates with them in areas of technical support and training to leverage on their skills and expertise; for example, TMF is currently working closely with the organisation HakiRasilimali to implement a project on extractive sector with Hivos. Q3: TMF participated in Women@web stakeholders meeting. 2020 Q2: TMF partnered with Nukta Africa and Hamasa Magazine to conduct one innovation workshop on 11 March during the Human Development Innovation Fund (HDIF) innovation week in Dar es Salaam. 60 participants in total attended the workshop; 28 female and 32 male, 39 organisations were represented from media, business, digital and online security, training institutions, civil society. TMF&#x2019;s presentation, Approaching media sector challenges as opportunities for innovation covered the value and opportunities for journalists in Tanzania to develop an innovator mindset, examples of media innovators that others can learn from in Tanzania and media sector challenges for media development actors to address through innovation. Nukta Africa&#x2019;s presentation, Recognising existing local and international digital media innovations, explored global trends and areas of interest in media sector innovation, particularly in content development. Hamasa Magazine&#x2019;s presentation, Data: relevant business models start here, covered opportunities and challenges for data-driven innovation in media business models. TMF planned to hold a follow up workshop with a smaller group of participants to discuss insights from the March workshop and way forward to strengthen media sector innovation. However, instead of a follow up workshop, they held a strategic meeting on 1 July, after it could not be conducted on the previously planned dates in April and June (due to COVID-19).</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Little in-depth accountability journalism exists in the Tanzanian media landscape, and even less utilising new online tools/resources and data-even as Tanzania moves in the direction of making more government data/statistics available as a signature of the Open Data Partnership.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Development in Lobby &amp; Advocacy: Media developed the skills to work as change catalysts in Lobby and Advocacy.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzanian journalists adhere to high standards of professional and ethical standards while utilising new tools and data/statistics to create impactful reportages.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016: Nine Tanzanian journalists participated in a second round of data journalism and excel spreadsheet usage capacity building workshops in July; Three TMF data journalism &apos;mentors&apos; participated and co-trained with lead trainer in further training of trainers in July; Planning is underway for final presentation of data projects at TMF in November; Translation of EJC&#x2019;s Data Journalism Handbook into Swahili is underway. 10 Tanzanian journalists participated in a data journalism reportage workshop where final stories were presented and strategised for maximum publication/broadcast impact. Advanced data journalism tools were utilised in practical sessions. EJC&apos;s Data Journalism Handbook translation/editing/review for publication and printing in 2017. 2017: The Swahili version of EJC&apos;s Data Journalism Handbook was published in cooperation with Tanzania Media Foundation. A workshop was conducted in the newsroom of Mwananchi daily newspaper for eight journalists. The programme focussed on DDJ skills building and practical reportage outputs utilising data for publication (22-24 February 2017). Preparation for workshop to continued development of 15 data journalism instructors that will form the core of TMFs data hub trainers team. EJC&#x2019;s two Verification Handbooks (&#x2018;A Definitive Guide to Verifying Digital Content for Emergency Coverage&#x2019; and &#x2018;Verification Handbook for Investigative Reporting&#x2019;) are being translated into Swahili and prepared for publishing and distribution to Tanzanian media community in cooperation with Tanzania Media Foundation. Workshop (13-16 Nov) to continued development of 15 data journalism instructors that will form the core of TMFs data hub trainers team. 2018: Q1 Data journalism club engagement session was held on 28th March 2018 (7 female/14 male). Q2: Establishment of TMF&#x2019;s newest initiative with EJC &#x201C;Media Lab&#xA0;was officially launched on 7 June at TMF headquarters in Dar es Salaam. The current Media Lab space is opened and is designed to play a key role as catalyst for innovation in reporting for young journalists. Equipment includes five laptops, four Tablets, and a user-friendly space for young journalists. The 7 June Launch was officiated by the Deputy Head of Mission of the Royal Embassy of the Netherlands, Ms. Lianne Houben. The Launch and a turnout of over 1000 attendees sets precedence on the value and potential that the Media Lab represents Tanzania&#x2019;s next generation of journalists. &#xA0;Fellowship Young Journalists: The call for the fellowship will be made in August 2018 for a period of one month as per TMF policy on fellows&#x2019; identification. The programme, including pitch reviews and a competition will launch in September 2018. Media Coffee Chats (informal discussions between journalists and topical experts) on Press Freedom and Data Journalism occurred during the reporting period: -A Coffee Chat on Press Freedom was facilitated by an advocate of the High Court of Tanzania who is also a seasoned journalist. He talked about the Media Laws and how they affect Press freedom in Tanzania with the title &#x201C;Media under New Laws: Watchdog or Lapdog?&#x201D;.&#xA0;25 participants (15 male/10 female) attended among which were 4 development partners, Media development organisations Journalists, students of Journalism and TMF staff. -A second Coffee Chat was on Data Journalism and education: University curricular presented by a experienced Data trainer and this event was attended by deans/ lecturers and students of journalism from the local universities. It was attended by 25 people (13 were male/11 female); students, journalists, lecturers/ deans and students of local universities. Data Journalism workshops took place early June: -A Data Journalism Training that focused on assessing club members&#x2019; skills on data journalism after the engagement session took place. 9 journalists attended (4 male/5 female). -A Training of Trainers was conducted.&#xA0;12 journalists attended (2 female/ 10 male). -A Data Training for young journalists focused on young reporters from Schools of Journalism in Tanzania namely; The University of Dar es Salaam, Tumaini University, St. Augustine University of Tanzania and Practical School of Journalism. Q3: Fellowship for Young Journalists/EJC Fellows Programme: The call for applications was announced on 31 July 2018 and it was closed on 31st August 2018. Sixty (60) applications were received and reviewed. A pitch competition for 17 applicants who were shortlisted, will take place in October. Procurement for an independent producer who will document the pitch session is in process. Upon selection of the 5 fellows, the fellowship is expected to commence by 30 November. TMF continues to organise Media Coffee Chats around media development and press freedom issues of national importance. Preparation for one around Tanzania&#x2019;s Statistics has started for implementation in October. TMF&#x2019;s Data Journalism Club was officially launched in July 2018. The goal of the programme is to build awareness and skills of young Tanzanian journalists around the role and processes of utilising data to tell stories. Through TMFs School of Data&#x2019;s pipeline, at a session on 31 July, participants were engaged via practical reporting the entire process of producing data journalism stories. Q4: Tanzania Media Foundation&#x2019;s Media Lab/EJC Fellowship programme recruitment took place during the month of November. A pitch competition was conducted where 28 candidates were shortlisted, with 18 final candidates went through an on-site jury competitions. After a review, 5 candidates were selected for the six-month fellowship at Media Lab (3 female, 2 male journalists) TMF continues to organise Media Coffee Chats on a regular basis at the Media Lab facilities: &#x2022; Investigative journalism in Tanzania: Are female journalists the missing link? A panel of two journalists; Paul Mabuga and Florence Majani, both experienced journalists, took place on 5 October 2018. 28 participants in attendance (12 male, 16 female) &#x2022; Are the amendments of the National Statistics Act likely to affect data journalism in Tanzania? The lively discussion session was led by Advocate Oscar Mangula, Head of Legal Unit, National Bureau of Statistics on 1 November 2018. 31 people participated (19 female and 12 male) A Data Journalism Training was conducted on 31 Oct &#x2013; 1 Nov by data journalism expert Peter Verweij from the Netherlands. 14 journalists (11 male, 3 female). 2019 Q1: TMF continues to organise Media Coffee Chats on a regular basis at the Media Lab facilities with prep beginning for first one in 2019 scheduled for May. Set up and preparation activities of launch of Bloggers Incubator to promote diversity of media voices and enhance choice for media consumers as part of strategic push back on the concentration of media ownership and market. The product will enhance/promote citizen journalism. The incubator will become active in Q2 MediaLab FactCheck: A team of young journalist fact checkers, to balance and support bloggers&#x2019; incubator. Potential partners Africa Check identified and approached; other partners - dLab identified and opportunities for collaboration in implementing the activity are also under development Preparation underway for first Young Voices Master Classes on Data Journalism &amp; Data Verification and Safety &amp; Security for Journalists in May as part of initiatives to prepare local journalists reporting on the elections in 2019 and 2020 in Tanzania. EJC/TMF Fellowship programme continues. Journalists&#x2019; induction training conducted in February and attended by five fellows (2 male/3 female), In addition One male and one female journalist from the Young Journalists Fellowship attended a climate change hackathon in Finland in cooperation with The Lookout Station. Q2: Blogger Incubator: Redrafting of concept note and development of participant selection criteria in progress. Media Lab Fact-Check: three potential regional and local mentors and trainers identified Media Lab news Series: Stories from the Young Journalists Fellowship are still in progress due to context related challenges faced by participants such as accessing relevant sources, including authorities from government. Within the reporting period, seven reportages were submitted to Mlimani TV, Radio Saut, TBC Taifa, Mwananchi Communications and Star TV. Young Journalists Fellowship: Mentorship and training provided to five young journalists in investigative journalism, data journalism and multi-media reporting. Q3: Master class III was conducted from 26t to 30 August at Media Lab. The EJC/TMF fellows learned story production techniques under coaches such as Richard Mabala (creative writing), Mahadia Tunga (data journalism), Baraka Kiranga (data journalism), Ndimara Tegambwage (investigative journalism), Aisha Sykes (gender), Fred Nyantori (digital filmmaking) and Allan Lawa (mentor). Eight stories were published. Journalists in the young journalists&#x2019; fellowship were coached on safety and security while doing investigative reporting. This was covered by Ndimara Tegambwage a senior investigative journalist. One coffee chat conducted under the theme &#x2018;Towards developing digital and tech-based solutions for the Tanzanian media space;&#x2019; was embedded in the information session for the media digital solutions challenge held on 13 September 2019. Three panellists presented on media sector challenges (Rosemary Mwakitwange, formerly Freedom House), innovation and its role in addressing these challenges (Edwin Bruno, founder SMARTlab and SMARTcodes, M-paper - https://web.mpaper.co.tz/) and how young people can play a key role in media in Tanzania (Annastazia Rugaba-Marondo, Twaweza/founder of online radio Deep FM). Eleven journalism students engaged in discussion on innovation and opportunities to address media sector challenges, particularly in relation to generating and distributing relevant media content. Media Digital Solutions: This activity is structured as a public competition through which young people will submit ideas for digital or tech-based solutions to current media sector challenges. The following sub activities were done: preparation of the digital media challenge - announcements, launch and conducting an information session for registered participants. The challenge was announced to the public through TMF website, networks and on TMF social media pages where it was boosted to reach 10,000 people within the 18-24 target. 16 groups registered to attempt the challenge; TMF restricted registration to just 15 groups of two to three participants between the ages of 18 and 24 because this is the first time they are conducting this kind of activity. The launch and information session were done on 13 September 2019. It was attended by a total of 19 participants 11 participants in the challenge, 3 panellists and 5 invited guests. The information session was conducted to orient the participants on the requirements of the challenge and the steps that shall be followed through out and to give them the opportunity to understand and ask questions before they develop their ideas. Q4: Bloggers incubator: Due to challenges in the identification of relevant participants, this activity was not implemented. Following the 2018 online content regulations blogging activity significantly reduced. The concept strategy was to work with the Tanzania Bloggers Network to identify 10 bloggers (five male and five female) to improve their accountability related content production and financial resource management and mobilisation. However, preliminary meetings with the Tanzania Bloggers Network General Secretary Krantz Mwantepele revealed that the association was not able to mobilise bloggers in the current environment as most of the leaders had taken to focussing on their own economic survival. Media Lab news series: The series aimed to employ various strategies to amplify mainly youth voices and agenda in the media. One young voices news agenda workshop was held on 22 November in the TMF MediaLab; attended by eight student journalists (four male and four female) from University of Dar es Salaam School of Journalism and Mass Communications, Tumaini University, Saint Augustine University and Raida College of Journalism. The workshop involved a presentation by Youth Partnership Countrywide representatives Israel Illunde and Freddy Mtei and discussions led by Clouds Media Editor and Tanzania Media Women Association Joyce Shebe TMF media lab was also used for activities with other partners such as setting up a road safety reporting corner and producing 45 stories on road safety, conducting a collaborative journalism workshop which identified 16 story ideas and for conducting individual mentorship and reflection meetings with four participants in young journalists fellowship on 27 November 2019 Media Coffee Chat: Follow up on 13 September panel discussion Towards developing digital and tech-based solutions for the Tanzanian media space conducted with shortlisted participants in the digital media challenge on 1 November 2019. Young Voices Masterclass: Introduction to data journalism master class conducted on 12 December 2019 in Dar es Salaam and attended by five young journalists, two females and three males Training was provided by Mahadia Tunga from dLab. Young Journalists Fellowship: Reflection session and project closure meeting held with four out of five young journalists engaged as 2018/2019 fellowship participants. One journalist only attended the first master class and then did not respond to TMF follow up efforts. Thus, in total, four out of five young journalists engaged in March this year completed the programme in November 2019. Three master classes conducted, and fellows provided with practical lessons in journalistic research and field work, interviewing and news gathering, production (film and audio), documentary making, data journalism and writing. The fellows produced eight media products that meet TMF quality content criteria in themes such as sports and disability, health, children on the street and poverty; though they also produced other stories, these did not meet TMF quality content criteria as they were published or broadcast without a final check by TMF mentor. Media Digital Solutions: The media digital solutions challenge was launched on 13 September 2019 in the form of a public competition through which teams of two to three young people (18 to 24 years old), at least one being female and one being a journalism student or recent graduate were invited to submit ideas for digital or tech-based solutions to current media sector challenges. A media coffee chat cum information session was organised to discuss media sector challenges and the role of innovation in resolving them. Registration for the challenge was restricted to 15 teams who were invited to submit ideas by 11 October 2019. Ideas for digital solutions were submitted by seven groups and judged on 1 November 2019. The winning group, which comprised of two males and one female, were awarded in December 2019 along with the first and second runners up. In total, five males and three females were awarded and invited to further develop their ideas through an innovation mentorship programme to be conducted in 2020. During 2020, three out of the seven solutions that emerged from the competition will be further developed and copyright registered. For greater sustainability, TMF will submit a concept note to the Human Development Innovation Fund in Tanzania to hold a media innovation week to showcase the media digital solutions. Digital solutions conceptualised as listed below: &#x2022; Digital system for freelance-journalists to publish and sell their media-related products &#x2013; most highly ranked &#x2022; Digital system which reduces the rate of fake news and news inaccuracy among editors and reporters &#x2013; first runner up &#x2022; Mobile application for comics as a medium for freedom of expression in Tanzania &#x2013; second runner up &#x2022; Digital repository/database of media laws and other media-related resources. &#x2022; E-learning system for media studies in Tanzania. &#x2022; Digital system to ensure the safety and security of journalists doing investigative journalism. &#x2022; Social media platform specifically for journalists. 2020 Q2: TMF Data journalism learning and practice group with six full time participants established in order to support journalists to build confidence and capacity in the production of data driven stories focused on women and children. Schedule of activity and story production will run from May to August 2020. Full time participants include three female and three male journalists from two media houses. Five participants from TMF road safety programme &#x2013; two male and three female &#x2013; will audit the class to gain data-driven journalism skills to apply to road safety reporting. The target was that journalists would publish three stories each in May, June and July. However, practically this was not possible due to the low level of data journalism competence exhibited by participants and challenges accessing relevant data sets. Between May and July, TMF therefore conducted six classes which involved identifying new story ideas after analysing and cleaning data sets available. Stories will run in the media in August 2020.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Professional and ethical standards are low, in part due to the lack of formal journalism schools at the university level. Data journalism/online tool use capabilities are rarely utilised in the country.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accountability: Media hold power-holders to account and are accountable to their public.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzanian journalists utilise data/online tools as a regular component of accountability journalism, utilise freedom of information laws to create impactful reportages.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2016: Series of accountability reportages are produced and published by data journalism teams on issues of land rights and water/sanitation; Audience engagement and impact are currently being assessed. Accountability reportage series published in major Tanzanian print media (hygiene and sanitation) and broadcast media (road fatalities). Audience engagement and impact continue to be assessed. 2017: Q2 Planning and selection of journalists for upcoming Data Leaders capacity building course. EJC&#x2019;s Data Driven Journalism handbook is translated into Swahili and printed. EJC&#x2019;s two Verification Handbooks (&#x2018;A Definitive Guide to Verifying Digital Content for Emergency Coverage&#x2019; and &#x2018;Verification Handbook for Investigative Reporting&#x2019;) are being translated into Swahili and prepared for publishing and distribution to Tanzanian media community in cooperation with Tanzania Media Foundation. 2018: Q1 The handbooks were translated and reviewed. Currently, the translator is working on the after-review comments. The handbooks are expected to be printed in April. Q2: Two handbooks on Data verification and Data verification for Investigative Journalists were translated into Swahili and are currently being printed. &#xA0;The newly published handbook &#x2018;Reporting Development: A Guide for African Journalists&#x2019; was distributed at the Media Lab launch on 7 June. Attendees received the guide and was also widely distributed to CSO stakeholders and members of the journalism community. Q3: EJC&#x2019;s Data and Verification handbooks for journalists are both translated into Swahili, print layouts have been finalised for launch and nationwide distribution to media during Q4. EJC&#x2019;s Verification of Investigative reporters guide are currently being edited, localised and translated into Swahili. A research study on Tanzania&#x2019;s complex media law landscape is completed for use as research and internal distribution among stakeholders. New changes to the Statistics Law are being prepped for use as an appendix to be added during Q4 with inputs from the National Bureau of Statistics. Q4: EJC&#x2019;s Data and Verification handbooks for journalists translated into Swahili, print layouts finalised, prep for launch and nationwide distribution to media during Q1 2019. A research study on Tanzania&#x2019;s complex media law landscape is being finalised for use as research and internal distribution among stakeholders in Q1 2019. Q3: EJC&#x2019;s Verification handbook was published in Swahili.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development for an enabling environment: CSOs are capable to support and defend the enabling environment for media as a condition for lobby &amp; advocacy</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media literate citizens act as a successful check and balance of citizens on political and business elites. Youth become sophisticated media consumers and participate in political and social life.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 Q2: MediaSpace programme had to be redesigned because of COVID -19 and upon receipt of approval May-June, the following has been done: Designing and advertising a call for applications to the media literacy programme for students. The call is still on and the training will take place on Zoom platform in July. Digital Media comic Handbook for students is being designed. Sample materials already received. Official Agreement to be signed in July for the development of the material to commence.
Q3: MediaSpace: The media literacy programme was done on 10th, September 2020 at Mama Salma Kikwete Secondary school, 50 students were trained on importance of media literacy, proper use of internet, and better optimisation social media networks. Also, they were trained on the challenges and dangers of social media for students and how they can protect themselves on the social media.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and Inclusiveness: media content increasingly is gender-sensitive and reflects social &amp; cultural diversity and participation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">TMF and MediaSpace embed reporting on issues of gender and diversity in their training materials and resources.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2 2018: A Kenya Interrupted (KI) meeting was organised by TMF in Dar es Salaam on 8 June. It was led by the KI curators and strategist. Planning issues discussed included expansion of female journalist-produced content, social media presence, visibility events. TMF was brought on board to assist in integrating female curators from Tanzania that will support visibility of underreported topics by Tanzanian female journalists. A mailing database is currently being put together as well as planning for inclusion of content from other East African countries. Q3: Preparation for the Interrupted Africa meeting, to be held on 31 Oct-2 November at TMF&#x2019;s media lab. Q4: Interrupttr Africa meeting, was held on 31 Oct-2 November at TMF&#x2019;s Media Lab. A monthly newsletter by women journalists/experts on important issues in Africa will be published. Three experts from Tanzania are part of the team. 2019 Q1: - Gender was considered in the selection of the Young Journalists Fellowship participants. - In identification of trainers and mentors, TMF is careful to ensure both men and women are represented to avoid the propagation of gendered stereotypes. - TMF has guidelines for ensuring our work contributes to gender equality and the advance of women&apos;s rights. In relation to media content, we have a requirement for at least 50 percent of sources in TMF supported stories to be female; this criteria for establishing the quality of media content is presented to all TMF grantees. There will be a gender analysis in relation to each story idea generated by the TMF-EJC young journalists fellowship during the 23-27 April master class to avoid missing any opportunity for our work to promote gender equality. - TMF will contribute to achieving gender balance by being gender sensitive, gender responsive and gender transformative with respect to the following: &#x2022; Who makes the news and who has decision making power concerning the stories that are told and how they are told: TMF aims to increase women in decision-making roles in the media &#x2022; Who has access and why: TMF aims to understand and mitigate the access gap between men and women, particularly online. &#x2022; Who is represented and how: TMF considers when and how women are represented in the media and will aim to specifically increase use of women as expert sources for instance to change social norms around women&#x2019;s economic, political and social participation. - Gender was considered in the selection of the Young Journalists Fellowship participants. - In identification of trainers and mentors, TMF is careful to ensure both men and women are represented to avoid the propagation of gendered stereotypes. - TMF has guidelines for ensuring our work contributes to gender equality and the advance of women&apos;s rights. In relation to media content, we have a requirement for at least 50 percent of sources in TMF supported stories to be female; this criteria for establishing the quality of media content is presented to all TMF grantees. There will be a gender analysis in relation to each story idea generated by the TMF-EJC young journalists fellowship during the 23-27 April master class to avoid missing any opportunity for our work to promote gender equality. - TMF will contribute to achieving gender balance by being gender sensitive, gender responsive and gender transformative with respect to the following: &#x2022; Who makes the news and who has decision making power concerning the stories that are told and how they are told: TMF aims to increase women in decision-making roles in the media &#x2022; Who has access and why: TMF aims to understand and mitigate the access gap between men and women, particularly online. &#x2022; Who is represented and how: TMF considers when and how women are represented in the media and will aim to specifically increase use of women as expert sources for instance to change social norms around women&#x2019;s economic, political and social participation. Q3: TMF participated in Women@Web stakeholders meeting on promoting women&#x2019;s online participation in Tanzania and safe digital spaces. Networking with other actors working on increasing women&#x2019;s (online) safety and online participation; follow up meeting with country director of the Human Development Innovation Fund to discuss collaboration on promoting innovation in the media sector. Q4: - Focus was on promoting access to opportunities for male and female journalists while taking into account that women have been historically disadvantaged. For this reason, TTMF emphasised the inclusion of female beneficiaries in all its Q4 programmes such as the 2019 digital media solutions challenge which required that each participating group included at least one female member. - TMF also engaged women trainers/facilitators and participants in the collaborative journalism workshop - were heading in Tanzania as well as aspect has been a matter of priority in our activities; gender awareness is one of the TMF&#x2019;s eight quality content criteria which we apply when working with journalists on media products. During master class sessions fellows get to be coached on how to integrate gender in their reporting. During master class three we engaged a gender expert to coach the young fellows on gender in the media. - TMF is currently engaging with other stakeholders such as Women@Web Tanzania to see how as an organisation we can contribute to creating safe online spaces for women&#x2019;s participation - To ensure that our media solutions challenges does not contribute to negative perceptions regarding women&#x2019;s engagement with technology and digital transformation, each team had to include a female participant. 2020 Q2: TMF All data driven stories being produced support from TMF focus of issues related to women and children because these stories are under-reported and because of the opportunity to influence and advocate for gender equality by telling stories using a gender lens. TMF has secured funding to conduct a study on gender and media from August to November 2020 and will distribute the insights within the media sector to simulate discussion and action for gender equality. MediaSpace: Women in hard news programme: Ten women journalists have been engaged. Also, because of COVID 19, WhatsApp group was formed, and conversations were shared in the group. Journalists will participate in the Master Classes from 06th July to 17th July, then work on their stories focusing on water, energy, and food security. 30 investigative, data driven, and solution-based stories will be published on print, radio and online.
Q3: MediaSpace: Ten female journalists were trained visually and physically on how to report on water, energy, food security issues also they were impacted with skills on investigative reporting, Critical Thinking and Practical Aspect for Journalists as well as podcast production.</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5: # of CSOs with increased L&amp;A capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="14"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6: # of CSOs included in Strategic Partnership programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="14"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD1: # of laws, policies and norms, implemented for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2: # of laws, policies and norms/attitudes, blocked, adopted, improved for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD4: # of advocacy initiatives carried out by CSOs, for, by or with their membership/constituency</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 # of times that CSOs succeed in creating space for CSO demands and positions through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or creating space to engage</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="7"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
