<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-41078390" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">No News is Bad News - Senegal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONTEXT ANALYSIS: Senegal is considered as one of the democratic &#x201C;models&#x201D; in Sub Saharan Africa. In its recent history it has undergone three important political changes without major troubles. The country has a long democratic tradition and the principles of liberal democracy and liberalism are deeply embedded in the political institutions. Senegalese citizens were introduced to multi-party politics during colonial times. From that time on, Senegal has been considered a &#x201C;model of democracy&#x201D;, even though the political leadership is very much criticised for not being &#x201C;principled&#x201D; and for its lack of consistency and ethics. Since 2012, the country is led by a president who was supported by a coalition to win the elections. The country is heading towards new parliamentary elections in July. The country&#x2019; economy is making progress with huge infrastructure projects started back in 2000. However poverty remains high affecting 46 % of the population, according to the World Bank. The &#x201C;GDP growth is well below the rates necessary for significant poverty reduction&#xBB;, says the World Bank. The social situation is characterised by huge social inequalities, increasing poverty amongst large parts the population and the deterioration of people&#x2019;s living conditions. Early in may 2017, the government has to recognise that about half a million people might be affected by food insecurity in some parts of the country. Unemployment rate is high among the youth, and the country also faces a low economic inclusion of the most vulnerable people and a a low level of education. PROBLEM ANALYSIS: In parallel with its political stability, Senegal has traditionally enjoyed a reputation of a country where freedom of the press is respected. Actually it is, in principle, guaranteed by the Senegalese constitution, along with other rights and liberties such as the right to plural information, the right to freely express and disseminate opinions. However, this statement can be misleading as the media is facing harsh times. To the point that between April and May 2017, a large coalition of media organisations (editors&#x2019; groups, trade-unions, reporters&#x2019; associations, etc.), felt it necessary to launch a nationwide campaign to protest against the plight of the media in the country and the status of the journalists. Among their main claims, the lack of support and real recognition by the State. They were also protesting against the long delay in adopting a new proposed media law, which has been on the table of parliament for several years now. This campaign culminated with a protest march on May 3rd, (International Press Freedom day). Though currently there is no journalist in jail, in the past some journalists have been imprisoned, harassed, attacked and the media still practices self-censorship on some issues considered as taboo in the country. The media can still be sent to court for defamation or other criminal offences if what they publish or broadcast is considered offending to the government, state, or private citizens. In the RSF 2017 report, Senegal ranks 58 and gains a few points: &#x201C;The 2001 constitution guarantees freedom of information, and abuses against journalists have been relatively infrequent in recent years. But some subjects continue to be off limits and the staff of several media outlets have been summoned and subjected to intimidation for covering corruption. In 2016 &#xBB; (RSF, Report 2017) Numerous constraints including religious ones restrict the freedom of press in Senegal. Offences such as dissemination of false news and offence to the head of state or religious leaders are still included in the press code. In recent decades, there have been significant developments in the media field, in particular due to technological advances, liberalisation, and globalisation. The 1990s marked a major turning point in the media sector. Senegal embarked on a process of liberalisation, which enabled the development of a &#x201C;vibrant press&#x201D;, the privatisation of companies, the growing importance of new players in this field and the end of the State monopoly in the sector. However this development of multiple privately owned media groups - some of which with little resources, others owned by politicians, others by ruthless businesspeople - have come with less control over quality, ethics, independence and therefore credibility. This has put journalists in a very weak position and has deteriorated the public image of the profession. The technological advances have also had an impact on the media. The development of new technologies set the pace of information production, increased the speed of information dissemination and magnified the amount of information accessible. The advent of online publications and social media, is also having a negative impact on the way the media operates and on the way people receive and consume media. Information is now disseminated at a fast pace without being checked or processed. Besides, there are now a growing number of distribution channels (online press) and modes of reception. There are also new players in the media field, including telecom operators, resulting in diversification of the offer. The changes in the media field are also due to economic constraints. The new economic environment is characterised by economic concentration, strong competition (communications industry is highly competitive) and privatisation. This situation is calling for further regulation in the media field. There is a lack of skills in the media industry. Except for a very few specialised schools, the journalism training is of poor quality, resulting in poor ways of informing and disseminating news or entertainment programmes. Furthermore, accessing the job is not regulated under the current laws, which makes of it an open space for any unemployed person. As a consequence, some media owners prefer to hire those not qualified and give them a low pay, rather than those who are trained professionals with higher demands. The media is not corruption free either at the level of owners/ editors or young reporters, and this is a source of serious concern when it comes to its credibility. There are numerous other challenges that need to be addressed in the media industry including an appropriate legal framework, a better representation of the most vulnerable groups in the reporting (and in the newsrooms), such as youth and women and other disadvantaged segments of the population. There is also space for more progress particularly when it comes to transparency, access to information, ownership, and long forms or new types of reporting: investigations, fact-checking, data-journalism. New Press Code Adopted June 2017: The latest development has been the vote on a new &#x201C;press code&#x201D;, adopted 20 June 2017 by the Senegalese parliament. The new text includes innovations that will lead to significant changes in terms of organisation, the business structure of the media houses and the legal status of the media houses. One goal of the new law is&#xA0;to enhance professionalism in the media field and improve the work environment through journalists being required to undergo training to exercise their profession: going forward journalists must be graduates of a recognised journalism school or holders of a university degree and undergo a few years of &#x201C;traineeship in a newsroom&#x201D; before applying for the &#x201C;national press card&#x201D;.&#xA0; Only the holders of this press card will be considered as professional journalists. &#xA0; The new code aims to improve the quality of information: &#xA0;it includes the establishment of the Conseil National de R&#xE9;gulation de l&apos;Audiovisuel (CNRA) as the supervisory body responsible for regulating the media field. It will ensure that broadcast media content &quot;adheres to the rules of professional ethics and conduct&quot;. The online media will henceforth be under surveillance in Senegal.&#xA0;The law also aims to improve journalist working conditions. The previous State Subsidy (allocated to media houses) will be replaced by a Fund for the support and development of the press with the goal of providing media professionals with better economic opportunities. The press code supports further control of the funds allocated to the media. &#xA0; The new law has drawn very strong criticisms particularly from some civil society organisations, numerous media professionals and press freedom activists, who are concerned about the repressive portions of the new code.&#xA0;According to media associations, the new press code retains the repressive elements of the previous text. Of particular concern to the media community is article 192 of law 14/2017 which states that government representatives can suspend a media house or its programme, or confiscate its equipment, or shut down a media house, if any press or media publication is deemed to be a &quot;threat to national security.&quot;</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EJC has been collaborating with partners, E-jicom and Ouestafnews on ad hoc media development and communications projects since 2010. Starting in January 2017 both organizations became the primary Boundary Partners for EJC&#x2019;s press freedom and media development initiatives in Senegal as part of the No News is Bad News consortium of the Strategic Partnership. A Baseline workshop was conducted in January 2017 where a commitment to strengthening ethics, professional standards, investigative skills and fact-based journalism reportage outputs among Senegalese media professionals was prioritized. A platform facilitated by Boundary Partners where press freedom/freedom of access to information initiatives can be developed and advocated is also a key result of the Baseline.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media professionals, journalism students, CSO stakeholders, women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STRATEGY FOR L&amp;A: Through its partnerships with E-jicom and Ouestaf News, EJC will support lobby and advocacy initiatives focused on the media environment and increasing government accountability, access to information and open data, and citizen engagement in media platforms via regular interactions with CSO stakeholders including Article 19 West Africa, Synpics, AfricaCheck and the Publishers/Broadcaster Council (CDEPS). The media partners will cooperate closely with civil society groups to promote women empowerment in the country. Government accountability&#x2014;media&#x2019;s watch dog role--will be supported through the production of investigative journalism reportages; champion best-practice solutions for journalism and higher quality development journalism; commissioning of investigative journalism pieces aimed at promoting good governance. STRATEGY FOR CAPACITY DEVELOPMENT FOR L&amp;A: Strategy for capacity development for L&amp;A of its partners will focus on the following key themes: Support and improve journalists&apos; role as civil society watchdogs by increasing their capacity to produce high-quality, ethical/fact-based impactful accountability/investigative reports and coverage of under-reported social issues; Build local journalist capacity on safety &amp; Internet security issues; Strengthen the capacity of media to interact and strategically network with CSOs; Improve the ability of media and citizen journalists to use data, innovative and fact-checking digital tool platforms in accountability journalism; Build capacity of partners to monitor and push back against biased/unprofessional journalism and self-censorship. GENDER EQUALITY will be approached through two kinds of interventions: Increasing awareness among BP organisations of the necessity of instituting gender policies and exploration of a developing a formal gender policy in order to ensure that current hiring practices, communications and all in-house materials/resources reflect gender sensitivity; Gender mainstreaming will be reflected in content production during capacity building on all levels: speakers, experts, sources of information and topics on gender will be highlighted and utilised in all interventions including small grants TORs programs. Specific safety/security situation of female journalist will also be focused on. SAFETY ASPECTS will be approached through three kinds of interventions: Safety and security measures (physical and cyber) will be mainstreamed into internal policies as well as external capacity building training materials; Safety/security matters will be monitored regularly and reported; Safety/Security/Ethics resources will be produced and made available to Senegalese journalists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-Jicom)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">European Journalism Centre</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="SN" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15153" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="3" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">82800</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">113100</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">104500</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">53000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">53000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">82800</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">113100</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">104500</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">50300</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-Jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">36095</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-Jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">65000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-Jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">58070</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-Jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">30000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-Jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-30">30000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-Jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">70850</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">59185</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecole Sup&#xE9;rieure de Journalisme des M&#xE9;tiers de l&apos;Internet et de la Communication (E-jicom)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">85462</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">103665</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">87915</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-09-30">90097</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-SN" ref="NL-KVK-41078390"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-41078390-SP-DA" type="2"></related-activity>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accountability: Media hold power-holders to account and are accountable to their public</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senegalese journalists are committed to serving the public interest with the proper accountability, inclusiveness, participation and act as watchdogs through in-depth ethical/professional reportage production and other accountability formats, which are tracked and measured for impact. E-jicom representatives regularly track and fact-check mainstream media output, reporting results.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A new website was launched for E-jicom representatives to specifically fact-check the mainstream media and reported on publicly: http://www.ejicom-info.net/category/e-check/. One example: A statement made by the Senegalese minister of Interior, Abdoulaye Daouda Diallo, ahead of the Senegalese legislative elections was &quot;fact checked&quot; and proved false by E-jicom students being trained at fact checking, in partnership with Africa Check. Two E-jicom interns have been placed at Ouestaf News and are regularly contributing as research assistants. Three young Senegalese journalists received grants toward production of high quality reportages. E-jicom students working under Africa check&#x2019; supervision are regularly producing fact-checking articles. Q4: The partnership with Africa check continued. Students are being coached and have started producing their first stories. One student was nominated at the African Fact Checking awards. The support to Ouestaf is helping more story production on serious development /governance issues: in-depth reportage on the issue of young people leaving school to become workers in the gold mines (Eastern Senegal), in-depth reporting on food insecurity in Northern Senegal published in Le Quotidien, story on the survival strategies of a local community (in Lac Rose) (Senegal7.com), story on water distribution service/delivery and the inequalities and inequities between Dakar and other regions, (Ouestaf News, three-part series), in-depth reportage on the environmental challenges at the &#x201C;Baie de Hann&#x201D;, one of the populated suburbs of Dakar with a coastal area highly affected by human and industrial pollution. 2018: Q1 Seven stories have been produced on issues such as governance, health, education, diplomacy. Among the stories &#x201C;fact-checked&#x201D;, are some statements made by top leaders as French president Emmanuel Macron and Senegalese Prime minister Mahammad Boun Abdallah Dionne. The stories can be seen here : http://www.ejicom-info.net/category/e-check/. A few stories were published thanks to the Ouestaf news grant. One journalist travelled to the eastern part of the country to produce a series on the small scale gold mining and its negative impact on education, and also on the poor governance of the health sector. Sample of some of the stories : https://www.ouestaf.com/kedougou-l%E2%80%99orpaillage-vide-les-classes/ https://www.ouestaf.com/senegal-retour-silencieux-de-la-lepre-une-maladie-tropicale-negligee/ https://www.ouestaf.com/portrait-el-hadj-ngom-le-lepreux-qui-refuse-la-fatalite/ Q2: Preparation for the first public call for a new Investigative Journalism Fund open to all Senegalese journalists, titled: &#x2018;Fonds d&#x2019;appui au journalisme d&#x2019;investigation&#x2019; began in April/May. An international jury is being constituted.&#xA0;http://ejicom.com/fonds-dappui-au-journalisme-dinvestigation/ Continued collaboration between E-jicom and AfricaCheck: E-jicom students fact-check stories on development issues.&#x2028; Topics: West Africa&#x2019;s contribution to the world cocoa production, after claims by the African Development Bank President (http://www.ejicom-info.net/2018/06/21/lafrique-de-louest-assure-t-elle-75-de-la-production-mondiale-de-cacao/). A health story on the number of Senegalese smokers (http://www.ejicom-info.net/2018/06/08/10-de-la-population-du-senegal-fume-le-tabac/) The exaggerated numbers on poverty rates in Kedegou, Eastern Senegal (http://www.ejicom-info.net/2018/06/06/plus-de-78-de-pauvres-a-kedougou-plutot-exagere/) &#xA0; 12 stories were published by Ouestaf News and other mainstream media in the country during the reporting period through the Ouestaf News Grant. E-jicom interns benefitted from this grant and produced stories/radio broadcasts published. Additionally&#xA0;two radio productions were supported by the grants focused on climate change and health: &#xA0; The Dakar desk of Alerte Info, a website with a pan African reach, published On May 27, 2018&#xA0;a piece on the unauthorized and disorderly connection to the national power grid&#xA0;in the poorest suburbs of Dakar link or image capture to be provided (no free access).&#xA0; &#xA0; On&#xA0;ouestaf.com: Return of leprosy, a neglected tropical disease - Published 03/04/2018 https://www.ouestaf.com/senegal-retour-silencieux-de-la-lepre-une-maladie-tropicale-negligee/ S&#xE9;n&#xE9;gal: the missing fish -&#xA0;&#xA0;Published 16/05/2018 https://www.ouestaf.com/senegal-le-poisson-se-fait-rare-dans-les-quais-de-peche/ Resistance to antibiotics, a public health challenge - Published 15/05/2018 https://www.ouestaf.com/resistance-aux-antibiotiques-un-vrai-defi-de-sante-publique/ Employment: little ray of hope for the visually handicapped - Published 25/05/2018 https://www.ouestaf.com/emploi-petite-lueur-chez-les-deficients-visuels-ils-en-veulent-plus/ In southern S&#xE9;n&#xE9;gal, a controversial factory - Published 12/06/2018 https://www.ouestaf.com/au-sud-du-senegal-une-usine-cree-la-polemique-le-gouvernement-se-terre/ Handicrafts in S&#xE9;n&#xE9;gal: the house of&#xA0;resourcefulness - Published 27/05/2018 https://www.ouestaf.com/artisanat-au-senegal-lantre-de-la-debrouillardise/ Q3: An international independent jury established by the EJC and E-jicom selected the first eight investigative journalism project teams to benefit from the first round of the EEJ accountability journalism fund. They are currently working in their stories on issues ranging from issues of local corruption to underreported development issues and minority communities. Continued collaboration between E-jicom and AfricaCheck: E-jicom students fact-check stories on development issues. Two students were nominated again this year for the African Fact Checking Awards. Winners and runners-up will be announced at a ceremony in Johannesburg in October.&#x2028; Accountability stories were published by Ouestaf News and other mainstream media across Senegal During Q3 via the Ouestaf News Grant. E-jicom interns benefitted from this grant and produced stories/radio broadcasts published on petrol and gas, health etc. Q4: Continued collaboration between E-jicom and AfricaCheck resulting in weekly &#x201C;fact-check&#x2019; bulletins distributed throughout Senegal and Francophone West Africa. A number of accountability stories were published by Ouestaf News and other mainstream media across Senegal during Q4 via the Ouestaf News Grant and the Investigative Journalism Support Fund. Six projects supported, two for Ouestaf and four from other media outlets. Seven stories were also published as part of the Investigative Journalism Support Fund. Topics included reportages on environment, gender, the impact of development projects, the environment and impacts of climate change, the contribution of migrants on local development. 2019 Q1: Stories continue to be published from the first competitive Investigative Journalism Support Fund round and Ouestaf News grants on issues of local corruption, migration, climate change and other pressing socio-economic development issues. Journalist recipients Continued collaboration between E-jicom and AfricaCheck resulting in weekly &#x201C;fact-check&#x2019; bulletins distributed throughout Senegal and Francophone West Africa. First team (2 female/1male) started working in March. Q2: A number of stories published during the reporting period, including a successful series on the trade of illegal medicine by Ouestaf journalists (three stories). Other mainstream media houses also benefitted from the grants and produced development related stories, from maternal health and child mortality in the southern part of the country to pollution in the coastal fishing areas of the capital city. The number of award-winning stories supported by the grant also expanded. Mamadou Sakine, reporter from the daily &#x201C;le Quotidien&#x201D; received a prize for a story on the governance of natural resources at a national competition, this is the fourth time a story supported by the project is nominated or awarded a prize. Links to selected stories below: https://ouestaf.com/senegal-ces-projets-de-developpement-que-refusent-les-populations/ https://ouestaf.com/medicaments-de-la-rue-ca-continue-de-plus-belle/ - Abdoulaye Diao :&quot;la mortalit&#xE9; maternelle et n&#xE9;onatale / S&#xE9;dhiou &quot; (published in Dakar Times) - Fatou Ndiaye: &quot;Pollution et salet&#xE9; des quais de p&#xEA;ches : Quel impact sur l&#x2019;environnement et les ressources halieutiques&quot; published in Sud Quotidien, print and online. - Jean Michel Diatta &quot;L&#x2019;absence de neurochirurgien &#xE0; Ziguinchor : risques d&#x2019;augmentation de la mortalit&#xE9;&quot;. (published in Sud quotidien, print/online) A health-related story &#x201C;fact-checked&#x201D; the allegations that the green stains on potatoes which are said to be toxic. http://www.ejicom-info.net/2019/05/27/les-taches-vertes-de-la-pomme-de-terre-sont-elles-toxiques/ Q3: Q3: Ouestaf News: Two articles and a major report are being/were produced: A series of stories on rice production and land issues in Senegal. One of the stories generated interest from a Canadian private company working on agricultural information and knowledge. https://ouestaf.com/autosuffisance-en-riz-au-senegal-1-belles-annonces-realite-paysanne-ardue/ (Do we normally include links? I think not? So let&#x2019;s leave out..) A story on migration and tragedies of the Libyan border crossing. The story was told by a former migrant who returned home. https://ouestaf.com/migration-moi-tidiane-camara-revenu-ampute-de-libye/ A major report on the surveillance of the Senegalese waters in Senegal. The story was run on the number one radio (in terms of audience) in Senegal. http://www.rfm.sn/podcasts/grand-reportage-sur-la-surveillance-les-eaux-senegalaises-2046 Digital News media Lab: A YouTube channel has been created and the first videos uploaded. Five videos from the &#x201C;Invit&#xE9;s du mercredi&#x201D; category are online. https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC5mrs85hjTWuPSUvIt0TCeg/videos https://www.facebook.com/ejicom/videos/459122951301803/ https://www.facebook.com/ejicom/videos/459122951301803/ https://www.facebook.com/ejicom/videos/314038842839178/ Q4: Ouestaf news grants: An investigation on &quot;the establishment of an underground bus station in Grand Yoff&quot;, an article on unequal access to health care in Senegal, an article on illegal transport on the Mbour-Dakar and Dakar-Thi&#xE8;s road axis. The complicity (corruption) of some local authorities and the police allows this practice, which harms the formal transport sector. According to the journalist, this illegal transport has a negative impact on the country&apos;s economy and has also an impact road accidents. Stories supported with these grants in previous quarters came under the spotlight, winning awards, including the Ejicom Journalism Grand Prize, won by Ibrahim Olou Ndiaye From Ouestaf for his series on rice production in northern Senegal. Investigative journalism Fund: Birane Ndour, from the &#x201C;IGFM&#x201D; information website wrote an article about the deadly consequences of cyanide, used by the mining sector. Seydina Bilal Diallo of the daily newspaper &#x201C;l&apos;As&#x201D; wrote a series of articles on the plight of forgotten victims of the old Senegal-Mauritania conflict. The story centred around the rights of people displaced during this conflict, draws the attention on the consequences of this conflict, particularly on the situation of refugees and the problems they face in terms of administration, education, access to health care etc. Papa Alioune Sarr, journalist at &#x201C;ITV&#x201D; made a TV report entitled &quot;In the kingdom of the unknown dead&quot;. He reports about the plight of the unidentified bodies in hospitals and the work done by an association to give them a decent burial Moussa Ngom journalist at &#x201C;La Maison des Reporters&#x201D; made a video report on the impact of corruption in Senegal. Mariama Djigo, journalist at &#x201C;Sud Quotidien&#x201D;, wrote an article about drug dealing in Tambacounda (eastern Senegal). Traffickers use this cross-border area to hide drugs in trucks, public transport vehicles and motorcycle taxis. Babacar Gueye Diop from &#x201C;Le Quotidien&#x201D; carried out an investigation on the failure of the implementation of the &quot;Rufisque - Saly&quot; maritime connection, despite public funds being allocated to this project. Gaustin Diatta of the daily newspaper &#x201C;Enqu&#xEA;te&#x201D; worked on the selling-off of the Senegalese maritime public domain, more precisely in Kayar. Fatou Ndiaye from &#x201C;Sud Quotidien&#x201D; conducted an investigation into the illegal traffic of weapons in Senegal. She noted the resulting security problems in urban areas and border areas. Nando Gomis from &#x201C;Sud Quotidien&#x201D; carried out an investigation on the economic impact of corruption of public agents and the road hassles faced by the people in the Ziguinchor-Guinea Bissau road axis. Fact-checking: One story published debunking some popular misconceptions, about Cotonou described as the third city in West Africa where it is good to live. Several criteria were used to make this ranking, including security, socio-cultural and political environment, medical and health infrastructures, education, transport, housing, consumer commodities, leisure activities, etc. Ouestaf was also recognized at the West Africa Excellence In Media Awards in Accra with two of its reporters being recognised, one as a finalist (Diomma Dram&#xE9;, human rights category) and one award winner (Momar Niang, African Union, pan African category). 2020 Q1: A reporter from the daily L&#x2019;Enquete, received an advance to cover the following topic: the misuse of synthetic chemical pesticides and fertilisers in the context of global warming. The publication of his report is yet due and may have been delayed by the Covid-19 outbreak. Two more funding requests have been approved, but the funds not disbursed, due the decision to suspend activities. The Journalism Fund call for applications was launched and the first applications were received. However due to Covid-19, the applications were not processed and the whole activity is suspended. At Ouestaf News has focused on in-depth reporting about Covid-19 and other health related stories. Q2: Two journalists benefited from the small grants programme: reporters at the daily &#x201C;Vox Populi&#x201D; and &#x201C;le Quotidien&#x201D;. Their stories are yet to be published. This programme will be resumed properly in July and August now that activities are coming back to normal. Ouestaf published a number of stories on COVID-19: One month of Covid-19 in West Africa https://ouestaf.com/un-mois-de-covid-19-en-afrique-de-louest/ West Africa: Mali, Guinea, Eco, Souma&#xEF;la Ciss&#xE9;, in the shadow of the Covid-19 tragedy https://ouestaf.com/afrique-de-louest-mali-guinee-eco-soumaila-cisse-a-lombres-de-la-tragedie-covid-19/ Living with the Covid-19 (part 1): lessons from Accra, Lagos, Monrovia, and Freetown https://ouestaf.com/vivre-avec-le-covid-19-1ere-partie-lecons-daccra-lagos-monrovia-et-freetown/ Living with the Covid-19 (part 2): Dakar, Niamey growl! Ouaga, Cotonou, in relax mode https://ouestaf.com/vivre-avec-le-covid-19-2e-partie-dakar-niamey-ca-grogne-ouaga-cotonou-on-relache/ Afrique-Sant&#xE9;: when will pharmaceutical independence become true? https://ouestaf.com/afrique-sante-a-quand-lindependance-pharmaceutique/ Education: the Covid-19 blast! https://ouestaf.com/education-lestocade-du-covid-19/
Q3: Several in-depth stories on key development issues, were produced and published in the Senegalese mainstream media. Below a few links:
&#x2022;	https://www.lequotidien.sn/exploitation-du-basalte-la-mine-sombre-de-ngoundiane/
&#x2022;	https://www.enqueteplus.com/content/non-r%C3%A9habilitation-des-sites-miniers-poussi%C3%A8re%E2%80%A6-l%E2%80%99enfer-au-fond-des-mines-de-lam-lam-0
&#x2022;	https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tT5PL-6twTM&amp;feature=share&amp;fbclid=IwAR2baY8Q-nEWeaB8NP5j2hgQ4ETJs437xHVQJ6FM1jcAtCxWyS42szoLfVU

Fact checking stories by E-jicom students, including stories on health (countering fake news about Covid); gender rights (women and land issues, early pregnancies), etc.  
&#x2022;	http://www.ejicom-info.net/2020/09/04/les-candidats-aux-epreuves-physiques-du-bac-2020-courent-ils-des-risques-daccidents-cardiovasculaires/ 
&#x2022;	http://www.ejicom-info.net/2020/09/10/luemoa-peine-t-elle-a-transformer-2-de-sa-production-de-coton/ 
&#x2022;	http://www.ejicom-info.net/2020/10/06/le-president-doit-il-refaire-une-declaration-de-patrimoine/ 
&#x2022;	http://www.ejicom-info.net/2020/10/06/coronavirus-le-hoquet-comme-nouveau-symptome/ http://www.ejicom-info.net/2020/10/06/la-region-de-sedhiou-enregistre-la-plus-grande-proportion-de-grossesses-precoces-au-senegal/

Journalism Fund: After the selection by the jury, the four top applicants were convened to a preparatory workshop on august 11, 2020. They were given some refresher training and guidelines on how to conduct the investigations. Following the training they were awarded the requested funding, based on their proposals:   
Stories produced :
&#x2022;	https://www.lequotidien.sn/enquete-deboisement-et-constructions-sur-la-bande-des-filaos-course-sur-la-vdn/   
&#x2022;	https://www.lequotidien.sn/vente-clandestine-de-carburant-la-zone-des-niayes-sur-une-poudriere-installation-anarchique-dune-centaine-de-depots-dhydrocarbures/ 
&#x2022;	https://www.seneplus.com/societe/lescroquerie-fonciere-du-siecle</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and inclusiveness: Media content is increasingly gender-sensitive and reflects social and cultural diversity and participation.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-jicom embeds reporting on issues of gender and diversity in their trainee selection processes, training materials, resources and criteria for grants programming. In all activities, E-jicom strives to have good balance between male and female journalists/participants.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A workshop on &#x201C;Gender perspective in economic news&#x201D; was held on 18-20 September. It provided 10 young media professionals with the necessary skills and knowledge for a gender-sensitive media coverage.The &#x201C;grants&#x201D; have so far benefitted more female journalists than male journalists (3 out of four) The reporting on Ouestaf is becoming more and more gender sensitive, with issues affecting women taken into account (water, education). 2018: Q1 A new person hired to assist in project implementation: she is female. More reports on Ouestaf focussing on women to counter their under-representation in the Senegalese media landscape https://www.ouestaf.com/profil-fatou-sarr-le-petit-poucet-a-lassaut-du-marche-du-cosmetique/ https://www.ouestaf.com/quotidien-dune-poissonniere-fatou-badji-ou-quand-le-travail-prive-de-vie-sociale/ Gender balance is also observed in the choice of students benefitting from the mentoring programme (four young girls and three boys) . One mentor (out of three) is a woman to ensure female representation in the team). Many beneficiaries of the training are female journalists. Q2: A Master Class on gender and stereotypes in the media was held in Dakar on 25 June. The class was led by Lisa Essex, EJC trainer. 20 E-jicom students attended (gender breakdown was 50/50). E-jicom implemented a mentoring and production programme featuring SP produced materials and resources, focusing on gender and women&#x2019;s rights in cooperation with Panos Institute in West Africa in Mali and Senegal. E-jicom was represented at a meeting by the Panos Institute in West Africa, on media and gender (Bamako, 3-6 April). Q3: Recipients of E-jcom&#x2019;s Accountability Fund support are currently working on investigative stories that include issues around gender. They will be published in local media outlets and tracked for engagement and impact during Q4. Preparation was begun for an EJC implemented Diversity and Media training that will focus on building the skills of a group of local CSOs that advocate for diversity and unbiased reporting of underreported communities in Senegalese media&#x2014;set to be implemented in October. During the entire month of September, two local online mainstream media outlets were monitored daily and analysed by EJC expert for negative representations of women and minorities in their content. The results will be presented in October. E-jicom&#x2019;s one year partnership with The Panos Institute for West Africa, which has started earlier in the year covering two countries (Senegal and Mali) has now been extended to Niger. This also extends the coverage to issues of gender and intolerance in a &#x201C;radicalised&#x201D; environment subjected to violent extremism. Q4: Recipients of Ouestaf News Grants and Investigative Journalism Support Fund regularly included women as sources of information in their reporting, as well as focusing specifically on issues of gender equity. 2019 Q1: Encouraging women in leadership roles in E-jicom activities and hiring processes. The moderator chosen for a roundtable was one of the few female editors of a mainstream media group. Recruitment of a female manager of academic affairs in February. Q3: Women were amongst the beneficiaries of the investigative funds, which has been a male dominated journalistic genre. In addition, more women benefitted from the small grants Ouestaf /production fund call during Q3. Q4: A new partnership has just been established between Osiwa and E-jicom for a period of two years in order to create a reflective framework and content production on gender issues and women&#x2019;s rights. The final objective to have a better representation of women in the media. 2020 Q2: A separate programme on women in the media is currently going on.
Q3: An online panel was organized on October 28, 2020 as part of the media and gender programme (Femmes &#xE0; la Une).  It was an opportunity to discuss on the responsibility of women in the media. Discussions revolved around the role and place of women in editorial offices.  Women are well represented in number but most of them occupy subordinate positions. There are no opportunities for them to occupy positions of responsibility: desk manager, editor-in-chief, publication manager or media director.  Live link of the panel : https://www.facebook.com/ejicom/videos/763052037584560</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainability development: Media increasingly operate as efficient and self-sustaining organisations.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-jicom has a sustainable strategic business plan and is a hub for continuing education and professional journalism training in Senegal.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">As part of its long-term sustainability and visibility strategy, E-jicom officially launched its Ethics and Excellence in Journalism (EEJ) programme 11 May. The event served as an opportunity to discuss with a team of 17 local stakeholders (13 male/4 female) - media owners, editors, trade unions, professional associations, experts and respected veteran journalists - the issues affecting journalistic practice in Senegal focused on ethics, the lack of skills among young professionals, editor&#x2019;s role and responsibility. The event offered buy-in from local media houses, raised the visibility of E-jicom and the EEJ programme in the media and allowed for meaningful recommendations from stakeholders. 2018: Q1 The new Ouestaf website has been launched and is functioning, the EEJ twitter account is active and the student experimental platform is 100% online. Q3: A new partner (potential investor) has expressed high interest in the school. This will help equip the school and enhance the capacity of the premises (power generator, new training spaces/offices to be added, more advertising for the new academic year). Q4: E-jicom director attendance at a strategic-level meeting in Niamey (Niger) on &#x201C;Media in the Sahel region - partnerships and sustainability strategies&#x201D; 6-7 December. Some contacts were made an idea to explore possible partnerships shared. Potential partners approached for collaboration included Global Parenthood, Rosa Luxembourg Foundation, B&#xF6;ll Foundation, International Media Support (IMS). A long-term Fundraising/business plan strategy launched by Ouestaf News in Q4 with expertise support coming from OSIWA. 2019 Q1: E-jicom concluded a new partnership with the German Heinrich B&#xF6;ll to organise regular public debates on issues of general interest. Activities to be launched in April. Q2: A partnership was signed with the Paris based ESJ (journalism school). E-jicom has become an official member of EJS&#x2019;s global network of 12 journalism training institutions across the globe. E-jicom has been approached by the Coalition on Media and Education for Development Africa Forum (CAFOR, based in Addis Ababa) to become a member. Q3: A partnership with AfricaJom Center (a pan African think tank) is being considered for potential collaboration on issues of media, governance and security in Senegal. The Deutsche Welle Akademie visited E-jicom and expressed interest in the EEJ programme. Q4: In January 2020, E-jicom will launch an executive programme in communication and media dedicated to communication professionals, corporate executives, managers, in a bid to generate more income. A new business model for Ouestaf has been proposed by a consultant supported by Osiwa, the governance, management and business models are likely to change, but its core mission, will remain: being a west African platform dedicated to in-depth reporting and investigations. 2020 Q2: The newly acquired zoom platform (professional subscription) will allow the organisation of online trainings and activities. It is hoped that some of these trainings might generate income for the future. It also provides a tool for teleworking and management, to counter the slow-down in productivity during the pandemic. New short courses to be launched with the hope to generate income.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development in L&amp;A: Media develops the skills to work as change catalysts in L&amp;A.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Senegalese journalists and students work ethically and safely through capacity building on specialised reporting topics. Media professionals acquire knowledge and capacity to work as effective watchdogs utilising innovative techniques.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In July, a three-day workshop dedicated to building reporting capacity and knowledge of the upcoming Senegalese elections was implemented and 16 journalists participated. The practical training enabled journalists to acquire the knowledge and know-how necessary to ensure adequate election coverage and discuss issues related to security and elections, journalists&#x2019; safety, the responsibilities of the press during elections. In October E-jicom and Africa Check organised two workshops for Senegalese/African journalists based in Dakar to encourage the Dakar based media houses to include fact checking stories in their reporting. Q4: E-jicom director was part of the participants at the Bloomberg African Media Innovators programme held in Accra, Ghana from November 12-14, 2017. The conference provided an insight on how some African media houses are innovating to stay ahead of the curve. Q4: A training workshop on health reporting was organised (13 Dec) for young journalists and E-jicom students in their final year. Ten people attended and the objective was to allow the participants to better understand that &#x201C;health&#x201D; is not only about the sick people, but also about health systems, policies and governance (budgets, spending, access, facilities, corruption, etc.). Experts from the medical field and experienced journalists specialised on health issues contributed. In December a workshop on fact checking organised by Ejicom in partnership with Africa Check. 2018: Q1 Two training workshops were organised at E-jicom. The first training covered &#x201C;media ethics, governance and accountability&#x201D;. The second one was on &#x201C;covering petrol and gas&#x201D;. Both training sessions brought together journalists from the Senegalese mainstream media. Q3: A training on digital safety was organised for the E-jicom team. Training workshop on migration for the journalists from the mainstream media. 10 people attended. The topic was on new ways of covering the migrant issue, with a focus on diversity and pluralism in information. E-jicom participated in an event organised by Facebook in Senegal on privacy and protection of personal data. Africans Rising, a PanAfrican movement working for peace, justice and dignity, has decided to renew its offer of two scholarship to outstanding African students to attend the Master&#x2019;s programme. Q4: A workshop on Climate Change took place 12-14 December at the E-jicom premises led by specialists in environmental issues and journalistic ethics. Eleven Senegalese journalist participated (6 male, 5 female) and included a field visit to Bargny, a seaside town, for on-site reportage production on rising sea levels and coastal erosion taking place in the area. 2019 Q1: On 28 March a round table on the Senegalese media&#x2019;s coverage of the February 2019 presidential election was organised. More than 20 editors, reporters and citizens gathered to discuss at E-jicom, the implications for the media and the lessons learnt from their coverage of the electoral process. Recommendations were made on how to improve reporting and combat disinformation during future elections. Q2: A workshop on &#x201C;Reporting on Violence&#x201D;, was implemented from 27 to 29 May, with a group of 13 E-jicom students and working journalists participating. Q3: Two-day workshop (30 September-01 October) to prepare the beneficiaries of the 1st phase of the investigative fund. Six beneficiaries, selected by a jury, attended and were briefed on expectation on the projects in terms of standards and ethics at E-jicom headquarters. Q4: A three-day workshop on &#xAB; media and powers &#xBB; was held at E-jicom. The workshop, which took place from 21 to 23 November 2019, created the opportunity to seriously discuss this issue. Five experts with different and varied backgrounds gave to practising journalist and students a practical approach to the subject through hands on exercises and case studies. (12 participants &#x2013; 6 women/6 men) Training workshop on &quot;Governance of extractive industries&quot; was held in E-jicom from 4 to 6 November 2019. E-jicom students as well as six journalists from print, online and TV media took part in the workshop. The objective was to improve the quality of media productions and content on this topic. (10 participants &#x2013; 1 woman/9 men) A panel on &#x201C;media independence and viability &#x201C;was held on the sidelines of the E-jicom journalism awards ceremony on 21 December 2019. The panel discussed issues related to the media business models, public funding and the possibility of implementing citizen funding mechanisms that are applied elsewhere in the world. It also touched on the citizens involvement on the running of state-owned media. (98 participants &#x2013; 53 women/45 men) A workshop on &#x201C;youth media and corruption&#x201D; took place on 18 December 2019 at E-jicom. In partnership with UNODC, Unitar and the J-Gen association (Women Global entrepreneurship), 50 young professionals and students have been sensitised on the central role of the media in the fight against corruption, for the promotion of governance, integrity, transparency and citizen participation. (57 participants &#x2013; 30 women/27 men). 2020 Q2: Due to Covid-19 and the preventive measures decided by the authorities (schools and universities closed, gatherings banned, etc.), E-jicom was unable to carry out training activities.
Q3: On October 28, 29 and 1 november, 2020, 14 students from Ejicom&apos;s students attended a workshop on: &#x201C;media coverage of a health crisis: the case of Covid 19&#x201D;. The topic and target group were chosen based on the current Covid-19 context. 

Two production workshops on fact checking were held with Ejicom students. The workshops allowed the publication of some fact checking stories on the platform of the Ejicom students (Ejicom-info-net).
The first workshop was held on 12, 13 and 17 August 2020. 11 students attended.
The second was held on October 22, 23 and 26, 2020. 11 students attended.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity development in strategic engagement: Media and CSOs are capable to relate strategically to achieve common goals in L&amp;A.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Media practitioners routinely source and interact with CSOs as credible sources of information on reportages of public interest.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Workshop on &#x201C;How to cover elections in a context of fake news and social media&#x201D; (3-5 July). 14 young journalists were trained on more professionalism in elections coverage. Panel discussion on &#x201C;Relations between communication and press services/officers and journalists&#x201D; (21 September). 35-40 journalists, communication officers and students discussed challenges and shared good practices with regard to professionalism and ethics. The main newspapers reported about this event (examples: http://bit.ly/2ggWgfH, http://bit.ly/2hDHufM). 2018: Q1 Grants for reportages and many are on Development issues so E-jicom is working with CSOs to do the reportages. Q2: Due to the required criteria on reporting of under reported developmental issues of a newly initiated investigative journalism fund, the grantees are encouraged to work with CSOs as a source of stories and information. Q4: Through the competitive Investigative Journalism Support Fund&#x201D; and Ouestaf News grants, journalist recipients regularly work closely with and utlise as sources of information representatives from the CSO community that focus on pressing socio-economic issues including health, education, gender equity, the environment and economic development among others as a core component of reportage production. Q4: Through the competitive Investigative Journalism Support Fund&#x201D; and Ouestaf News grants, journalist recipients regularly work closely with and utlise as sources of information representatives from the CSO community that focus on pressing socio-economic issues including health, education, gender equity, the environment and economic development among others as a core component of reportage production. 2019: Q3 A partnership with AfricaJom Center (a pan African think tank) and prep for a panel on media, governance and security in Senegal. Q4: A potential partnership with the Association of Online Press Professionals of Mali (Appel Mali) is currently under discussion, for a training workshop on fact-checking. A new partnership has just been established between Osiwa and E-jicom for a period of two years in order to create a reflective framework and content production on gender issues and women&#x2019;s rights. The final objective to have a better representation of women in the media. 2020 Q2: During this quarter partnerships and activities requiring third party involvement drastically slowed down due to Covid19.
Q3: Six civil society organisations (Article19, Osiwa, Wetlands Africa, Ashoka Sahel and reporters without Borders) have agreed to join E-jicom in the annual journalism awards ceremony (Prix Ejicom de Journalism). These partnership agreements represent a recognition of the work done so far under EEJ and give a real boost to an activity started three years ago and which is becoming the main platform to showcase excellence in journalism. This is one of the main outcomes of the EEJ project which have a chance to become sustainable.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CSO capacity development: CSOs are capable to support and defend the enabling environment for media as a condition for L&amp;A</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">E-jicom strengthens and institutionalise relationships with local CSOs advocating on matters of national developmental interest, safety and security. Media professionals routinely source and interact with CSOs as credible sources of information on reportages of public interest.</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">In December a panel discussion was organised with media professionals, the country&#x2019;s main press union, freedom of expression advocates, civil society organisations, lawyers, bloggers and other key stakeholders on access to information laws. There was a rep from EJC. 2018 Q2: E-jicom organised the &#x201C;Communication Professional Days &#x2013; Jprocom&#x201D; on 27-28 June. This was a series of activities including an inaugural lecture, a Master Class, and three panels. One of the panels was EEJ branded and focused on the relations between communication officers and journalists. Q3: Joint E-jicom-Africa Check panel (5 July) on access to information on health-related issues brought together health professionals and media practitioners The EEJ project, through the small grants and the newly launched Investigative Fund, is giving a good opportunity to build strong ties with the Senegalese mainstream media and local CSOs. Preparation was begun for an EJC implemented Diversity and Media training that will focus on building the skills of a group of local CSOs that advocate for diversity and unbiased reporting of underreported communities in Senegalese media - set to be implemented in October. Q4: First edition of the E-jicom Journalism Prize launched An event was organised awarding excellence in local journalism, echoed in local media and on social media. More than 80 participants from the media and civil society attended the awards ceremony. Five young journalists were recognised. Two Senior E-jicom lecturers also received recognition certificates. A panel discussion, jointly organized with the Senegal Association of Bloggers, on &#x201C;fake news in election periods and impact on democracy&#x201D; proceeded the ceremony. Q2: On June 12-13, E-jicom organised the second edition of the communication professional days. About 60 people attended the event. Q3: During Q3 a former journalist was jailed after accusations of &quot;insulting the president&quot; following alleged publications on his Facebook wall. This has heated the debate on freedom of expression and the security of data on social media networks. He was granted a provisional release pending his trial. Debates are ongoing. Ouestaf contributed to the debate through the publication of an op-ed and of a in-depth story on press freedom and freedom of expression under president Macky Sall.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="1" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-02-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD Indicators</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD3 # of times that CSOs succeed in creating space for CSO demands and positions through agenda setting, influencing the debate and/or creating space to engage</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="18"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD1: # of laws, policies and norms, implemented for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="2"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD5: # of CSOs with increased L&amp;A capacities</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="26"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD2: # of laws, policies and norms/attitudes, blocked, adopted, improved for sustainable and inclusive development</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="3"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD6: # of CSOs included in Strategic Partnership programmes</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="30"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">DD4: # of advocacy initiatives carried out by CSOs, for, by or with their membership/constituency</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="6"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
