<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:linked-data-default="https://www.ngoaidmap.org" iati-activities:version="2.02" interactions-ngoaidmap:record-offset="0" interactions-ngoaidmap:total-records-available="356" linked-data-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/projects/12823" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:interactions-ngoaidmap="https://www.ngoaidmap.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-13-3287064NAM-CARE-MZ-12-12823</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM" secondary-reporter="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early Child Devolopment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Socially, economically and politically excluded women (and their under five children) experiencing food and nutritional insecurity and who are highly dependent on land and natural resources and in and out of school adolescent girls, between 10-15 years old, at high risk of early marriage, unwanted pregnancies and other forms of abuse</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of this program is to use implementation science methods to evaluate strategies that increase the effectiveness of Early Childhood Development (ECD) programming and improve developmental outcomes for infants and young children affected by or at high risk of being affected by HIV/AIDS.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will test local participatory accountability tools such as community score cards applied at various levels in the initiative (between caretakers and service providers, between caretakers and local government, between care takers and lead mothers) to assess whether such frameworks lead to improved implementation of ECD programs and ultimately contribute to better child and family outcomes. Strengthen caregiver skills in promoting and supporting optimal child development. Massungukate (MK) will receive ongoing technical support on ECD and EP tools, including initial and refresher trainings and monthly supervision sessions to promote peer support, exchange and learning, and to strengthen linkages with relevant government authorities for sustainability purposes.
To ensure safe spaces for children participating in the ECD groups, MK will receive support to make adaptations in their homes, including building latrines and hand washing facilities. Increase capacity of community-based organizations &amp;amp; relevant local government authorities to effectively support ECD programming. The main local NGO partner, in charge of implementation on the ground in both target districts, will receive ongoing capacity development on technical aspects related to ECD and accountability tools, and on issues related to organizational strengthening.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="US-EIN-13-1685039" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation(s)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="1820.0" type="B9">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-1685039">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <other-identifier ref="CARE-MZ-12-12823" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="US-EIN-13-3287064NAM">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">InterAction&apos;s NGO Aid Map</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual end date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2012-10-01" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Actual start date of the activity</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CARE</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <website>http://www.care.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="8" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://ngoaidmap.org/p/about-sector-coding">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project Reach (individuals)</narrative>
    </title>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2012-10-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-05-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2090"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
