<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:usg="http://www.foreignassistance.gov" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>US-GOV-9-SL-F13AC00835</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-USAGOV" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthing leadership for conservation in Sierra Leone and Liberia through Research and Training on the Western Chimpanzee</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This purpose of this project is to: 1) train and mentor a team of professionals for effective leadership in wildlife conservation; 2) establish a foundation for Chimpanzee conservation at Njala University; and 3) facilitate exchanges between conservation professionals in Sierra Leone and Liberia. The Chimpanzee is symbolic of the overall conservation dilemma in West Africa &#x2013; habitat fragmentation, bushmeat hunting, pet trade, and conflicts with humans &#x2013; that require innovative leaders for implementing effective and successful long-term solutions. Activities include: 1) Developing a team of wildlife conservation professionals by designing, organizing and implementing an 18-month MENTOR-CHIMP program on wildlife conservation and management through a combination of lectures, field work, team pilot projects and on-the-job training, and recruiting the team of eight working professionals (Fellows) from Sierra Leone and Liberia for dynamic mentoring by faculty members; 2) Establishing a Foundation for Chimpanzee Research and Monitoring at Njala University to facilitate long-term influence on research and academic training in Wildlife Conservation and Management; identifying long-term priorities for Chimpanzee conservation; mobilizing and engaging Njala University Staff; and establishing partnerships and institutional links; 3) Facilitating exchange visits between professionals in Sierra Leone and Liberia through engagement of Njala University faculty with counterparts at Cuttington University and the University of Liberia. As part of the Cooperative Agreement, USFWS will provide hands-on participation in strategic planning for the new MENTOR-CHIMP program; participate in regular communications; identify potential contacts and provide background on similar programs; provide technical assistance and oversight to the program; participate in the Program Committee; advise on the curriculum design and field implementation projects; review criteria and participate in selection of the Fellows; help to make decisions on program&#x2019;s management, support, leadership and future growth; help to publicize and brand the program; and leverage potential collaboration and partnerships.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NJALA UNIVERSITY</narrative>
   <usg:duns-number>565556565</usg:duns-number>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-USAGOV" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   <usg:office-name>Fish and Wildlife Service/Office of International Affairs</usg:office-name>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="US-GOV-9" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="US-GOV" type="B1">
   <owner-org ref="US-USAGOV">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The federal government of the United States</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-08-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">U.S. Department of the Interior</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>888-678-6836</telephone>
   <email>feedback@ios.doi.gov</email>
   <website>https://www.doi.gov/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">11849 C Street, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20240</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SL" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="SL">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sierra Leone</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite experiencing the most severe Ebola Virus disease outbreak ever recorded, Sierra Leone has made significant gains in consolidating peace, promoting democracy at local and national levels, encouraging economic growth and facilitating overall engagement in development processes. Nevertheless, Sierra Leone continues to grapple with serious development challenges, such as entrenched corruption, weak governmental institutions, high unemployment, slow economic growth and inadequate social services, including water and electricity. U.S. assistance will improve the daily lives of Sierra Leoneans through strategic investments in agriculture and health services, including farmer training, nutrition programs and policy reform. U.S. assistance will also target civil society and media programming, security sector reform, and rule of law programs. The U.S. government will accomplish these goals through close collaboration with the Government of Sierra Leone (GOSL), other donors, local non-governmental organizations, and the private sector.</narrative>
   </description>
   <exactness code="1"></exactness>
   <location-class code="4"></location-class>
  </location>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="A01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="3"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-10-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-09-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-10-01">134990</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-15">35000</value>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-08-02">35000</value>
   <sector code="41030" vocabulary="1">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bio-diversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <sector code="6002" vocabulary="99">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural Resources and Biodiversity</narrative>
   </sector>
   <usg:treasury-account>
    <usg:main-account code="1652">Multinational Species Conservation Fund, United States Fish and Wildlife Service</usg:main-account>
    <usg:regular-account code="14"></usg:regular-account>
   </usg:treasury-account>
  </transaction>
  <conditions attached="0"></conditions>
  <usg:mechanism-signing-date iso-date="2015-09-22"></usg:mechanism-signing-date>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
