<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12390A0101-ZWE-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veritas/Firinne trust - core support</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Veritas/Firinne trust - k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intervention is expected to contribute to a more open government, the establishment of a constitutional democracy, better laws, more impartial justice delivery and the observance of human rights. It is also expected to have a positive impact on gender equality and the inclusion of minorities,&#xA0;encourage greater social cohesion with a fairer distribution of wealth, greater access to social services, an end to impunity and to promote&#xA0;peace and tolerance over violence.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Organisationen Veritas har ans&#xF6;kt till ambassaden om ett k&#xE4;rnst&#xF6;d p&#xE5; 9 miljoner SEK f&#xF6;r att kunna forts&#xE4;tta bedriva sin verksamhet i Zimbabwe mellan aug 2018 och aug 2021. 

Insatsen &#xE4;mnar att bidra till en mer &#xF6;ppen stat, b&#xE4;ttre lagar, ett mer opartiskt r&#xE4;ttssystem, &#xF6;kad respekt f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter samt etablerandet av en konstitutionell demokrati. Veritas arbetar &#xE4;ven f&#xF6;r kvinnor och minoriteters r&#xE4;ttighter samt att motarbeta v&#xE5;ld och fr&#xE4;mja fred och tolerans. Aktiviteter innefattar informationsspridning, bevakning och f&#xF6;respr&#xE5;ksarbete. Organisationen kommer inte ing&#xE5; avtal med n&#xE5;gra andra parter men arbetar n&#xE4;ra med relevanta akt&#xF6;rer f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka sitt inflytande p&#xE5; parlamentet. 

Veritas totala budget f&#xF6;r 2018 omfattar 606 382 USD av vilka TRACE (USD 126 400),  Omidyar Network  (USD 64 900),  National Endowment for Democracy (NED) (USD 54 800) och Switzerland (USD 20 500) bidrar till. Veritas har inga enga inkomstk&#xE4;llor och Sverige kommer troligen vara den st&#xF6;rsta givaren under avtalsperioden.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veritas has applied to Sida for funding of 9million SEK to carry out project titled &quot;Working for Open Government, Democracy, Constitutionalism, Rule of Law, Justice and Human Rights&quot;   in Zimbabwe  during the period 2018-2021. 

The intervention  is expected to contribute to a more open government, the establishment of a constitutional democracy, better laws, more impartial justice delivery and the observance of human rights. It is also expected to have a positive impact on gender equality and the inclusion of minorities, encourage greater social cohesion with a fairer distribution of wealth, greater access to social services, an end to impunity and to promote peace and tolerance over violence.

The intervention&#x2019;s total budget is 606 382USD, which is contributed by  TRACE (USD 126 400),  Omidyar Network  (USD 64 900),  National Endowment for Democracy (NED) (USD 54 800) och Switzerland (USD 20 500)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing country-based NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Veritas/Firinne Trust</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.6 - Bygga upp effektiva och transparenta institutioner med ansvarsutkr&#xE4;vande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.6 - Develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687932</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">158631.119195423</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">172604.2529687931</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">158631.1191954229</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">325743.509560572</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-01">1035625.517812</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-09-28">172604.2529687932</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">158631.119195423</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-08-28">162871.754780286</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-11-28">162871.754780286</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zimbabwe/agreement_27112018083119.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zimbabwe/decision_27112018082330.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the first annual report from Veritas under the agreement. Veritas has experienced some organisational problems during the year with regards to staffing, with some staff being on extended sick leave and another programme officer moving to work with the IOM. In spite of this Veritas has managed to carry out their work with maintained quality. Besides the support from the Swedish Embassy, Veritas has also received funding from the National Endowment of Democracy, and TRACE. The work of Veritas reaches lawyers, law firms and legal institutions not only in Zimbabwe but also other countries, e.g. the Southern African Litigation Centre and the International Bar Association. Veritas is also referenced and used by the media and a number of community-based organisations to inform not only their staff but also their constituents. The activities for 2019 were planned in regular staff meetings which allowed for flexibility in changing circumstances. The Swedish contribution to Veritas supported institutional costs and the implementation of all activities.&#xA0;The contextual environment throughout the year has been difficult and unstable. With many NGOs being targeted with threats, including Veritas, the environment has been constricted and stressful. Nevertheless Veritas was able fulfil its planned activities toward the objectives. Veritas undertook activities that promoted democratic reforms, constitutionalism and citizen understanding of democratic processes. It monitored and disseminated the work of parliament, the courts and independent commissions in order to promote access to information and to strengthen civil society advocacy efforts. Veritas met with and contributed its expertise to civil society coalitions and met regularly with government officials to promote legislative reforms which need to be enacted if Zimbabwe is to become a successful democracy. The reforms include a revision or repeal of restrictions on freedom of assembly and expression; enhancement of government transparency; and making the security services accountable to parliament and the public. Veritas also provided legal technical support and advice to several institutions, as well as to members of the public and parliament. Furthermore, Veritas met duty-bearers in constitutional commissions, the courts and ministries to promote reforms by providing legal analysis and advice, and drafting progressive legislation. Veritas&#x2019;s work was used by lawyers to bring court cases against violations of civil liberties and human rights. Assistance was also given to the Zimbabwe Human Rights Commission (ZHRC) with which Veritas has a MoU. Veritas has assisted in reviewing the strategic plan for ZHRC and drawing up a new one. There are also links to other partners receiving support from the Embassy.&#xA0; For instance, as part of the NGO Forum Veritas, supports GALZ, the Women&apos;s desk is planning to share data with Spotlight, and is working closely with other women&#x2019;s organisations such as the Women&#x2019;s Coalition, and also with Legal Resources Foundation. Some other pertinent issues being worked on are improving the treatment of women miners, teaching disabled women their rights, making legal abortion easier in order to do away with the many deaths associated with backstreet abortions, and the provision of sanitary wear to girls and women. Veritas has also worked closely with a network of women lawyers on the Marriage Bill. Some key achievements during the year are listed below. More information is found in the annual narrative report.&#xA0;Improved Legislation: Veritas did direct lobbying to improve Bills and Statuary Instruments (SI) and also provided information to CSOs and often joined in with CSO lobbying. Among the Bills improved were the Education Amendment Bill, the Marriages Bill and the Maintenance of Peace and Order Bill. The criticisms of SIs were taken up by financial institutions and induced the government to rectify the law by act of parliament.Fruitful Interaction with Parliament: Veritas was asked to renew its MOU with parliament to continue with promoting democracy, making the work of parliament better known, and give assistance to parliamentarians when it comes to better understanding their role and improve the performance of parlamentarians and committees. Veritas has contributed to the review of both parliament&#x2019;s last Strategic Plan as well as to its new one.&#xA0; Public engagement with Parliament Promoted: Veritas played an important role in increasing public participation in the work of parliament, a fact that has also been acknowledged by the Speaker and by the clerks and staff of Parliament. At Veritas&#x2019;s instigation Parliament initiated an arrangement whereby members of the public who were unable to attend public hearings of parliamentary committees could send in their submissions by e-mail.Establishment of Veritas Women: Vertias has set up an interactive website and social media platform was set up to inform women, girls and all those assisting them about their rights and about possible avenues and referals for addressing when violations of their rights occur. The website has been used by other NGOs and has been welcomed as a useful source of information.Work against Death Penalty: Joint research with the Global Death Penalty Project and the Mass Public Opinion Institute was completed; a booklet on the death penalty was researched, written, produced and published; the Minister of Justice, the Speaker and individual parliamentarians were lobbied.Interaction with UN Resident Co-ordinator&#x2019;s Office (UNRCO): Veritas shared all information and bulletins with the UN Human Rights Adviser and the Resident Co-ordinator.&#xA0; Veritas also supplied information to the UN Special Rapporteur on the rights to freedom of peaceful assembly and of association. This was done before his visit and at a meeting he held with NGOs, as well as at a specific meeting he had with Veritas&#x2019;s director and legal team. Veritas was invited to meetings on identifying areas for humanitarian intervention and the human rights situation in Zimbabwe. Veritas met the team assessing the needs of women and people with disabilities.&#xA0;Veritas was also asked to assist and inform the UN Electoral Needs Assessment Team.Use of Veritas&#x2019;s Work by Courts: Veritas&#x2019;s work on legislation and the constitution was used as a basis for many key court cases, such as the case against the shutting down of the Internet in January 2019, the challenges brought against financial regulations and against illegal police cordon and search activities. During the year Veritas also finally got judgment in its favour in a case it brought in 2018 to ensure free and fair media coverage during elections.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12390" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1500000000.000000000000000000" strategy-end-date="2021-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zimbabwe 2017-2021</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zimbabwe 2017-2021</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
