<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-12433A0101-ZWE-13020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAYWHAT Youths Action for Choice 2018-2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">SAYWHAT Youths Action for Choice 2018-2021</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives1. To strengthen life-skills, agency and assertiveness of students in 10 state universities in Zimbabwe to make informed choices on their sexuality by 2021; 2. To expose students to sexuality information and education using Information and communications technology and multimedia in 10 state universities by 2021.3. Improved accountability by government and university authorities on the delivery of sexuality information and education and access to youth friendly SRH services by students. 4. To improve delivery of sexuality information and education and access to youth friendly SRH services by students in 10 State Universities by 2021.
Expected Outcomes 1. Students&#x2019; life-skills, agency and assertiveness are strengthened to make informed choices on their SRH, demand for and uptake of SRH services; 2. Students exposed and reached with scientifically proven and culturally sensitive sexuality information and education; 3. Improved relationships and supportive environment for students to make and sustain their choices on sexuality</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Organsiationen The Students and Youth Working on reproductive Health Action Team (SAYWHAT) &#xE4;r en civilsamh&#xE4;llsorganisation (registered under Private and Voluntary Organisation Act PVO 34/2017) som arbetat sedan 2003 med SRHR f&#xF6;r unga framf&#xF6;rallt inom universiteten i Zimbabwe. 

SAYWHAT arbetar dynamiskt och innovativt med unga f&#xF6;r att st&#xE4;rka unga kvinnors sexuella r&#xE4;ttigheter samt att p&#xE5;verka myndighter och regierigen. Organisationen arbetar &#xE4;ven med att p&#xE5;verka SADC (the Southern African Development Committee) och AU (the Africa Union) runt SRHR policy arbete. 

Fr&#xE4;msta m&#xE5;lgruppen f&#xF6;r Sveriges nya strategin &#xE4;r ungdomar. Denna m&#xE5;lgrupp &#xE4;r s&#xE4;rskilt relevant d&#xE5; en av tre unga flickor i Zimbabwe uts&#xE4;tts f&#xF6;r sexuella &#xF6;vergrepp innan de fyllt 16 &#xE5;r. Zimbabwe har &#xE4;ven n&#xE5;gra av de h&#xF6;gsta siffrorna vad g&#xE4;ller barn&#xE4;ktenskap och k&#xF6;nsrelaterat v&#xE5;ld i s&#xF6;dra Afrika (mer information i Global Gender Gap Report och i Girls Not Brides Report). SAYWHAT programmet inkluderar ett r&#xE4;ttighetsperspektiv och fattiga m&#xE4;nniskors perspektiv p&#xE5; utveckling, och har ett s&#xE4;rskilt fokus p&#xE5; utsatta ungdomar. 

Ambassaden bed&#xF6;mer denna insats som mycket intressant och relevant f&#xF6;r v&#xE5;r strategi s&#xE4;rskilt vad g&#xE4;ller omr&#xE5;de 1.3 St&#xE4;rkta f&#xF6;ruts&#xE4;ttningar f&#xF6;r j&#xE4;mst&#xE4;lldhet och respekt f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nskliga r&#xE4;ttigheter, med fokus p&#xE5; kvinnor och flickor; samt 2.2 &#xD6;kad tillg&#xE5;ng till och respekt f&#xF6;r sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och r&#xE4;ttigheter, framf&#xF6;rallt f&#xF6;r unga m&#xE4;nniskor. Ett st&#xF6;d till SAY WHAT inneb&#xE4;r att vi kan minska antalet o&#xF6;nskade graviditeter och &#xF6;ka tillg&#xE5;ngen till preventivmedel bland unga kvinnor i Zimbabwe. Genom denna insats kommer Sverige att bidra till att fler ungdomar kan fatta v&#xE4;lgrundade beslut om sin h&#xE4;lsa, sexualitet och reproduktion. St&#xF6;det till SAYWHAT kommer &#xE4;ven att komplettera  st&#xF6;de till Marie Stopes (PSZ) och Population Serviec International som arbetar med tillhandahavandet av preventivmedel.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The impact of the SRH challenges is worsened by structural and underlying political, socio-cultural and economic factors. Sexuality Education for young people has not been mainstreamed and standardized in the education system. Young people continue to rely on informal sources of information which are sometimes inaccurate, age-inappropriate or not scientifically proven. Decisions for non-contraception use by adolescent girls and young women are further buttressed by powerful institutions that govern young people&#x2019;s sexuality such as patriarchy, religion and cultural practises. Furthermore, some young people are faced with attitudinal and perception barriers of health service providers.Description of the contributionFollowing the above stated challenges, SAYWHAT proposes a three year, SEK16 000 000 Action for Choice (A4C) project. The A4C project is inspired by a belief in students&#x2019; power to make choices about their Sexual and Reproductive Health. It is built on an understanding that if students&#x2019; Sexual and Reproductive Health choices are broadened, there is increased potential for them to excel in other development facets such as education, professional careers and employability. The project aims to improve access to and utilisation of contraception, HIV and GBV services by students in 10 State Universities in Zimbabwe. It seeks to achieve this through harnessing the collective action of students, and strengthening their voices to make choices on SRH services that have an impact on their lives. It seeks to ensure that duty bearers craft policies and programs which are in line with students preferred choices with reference to choices that have been taken away from them on morality, religious and cultural grounds.Noting the high numbers of sexual abuse, SAYWHAT will ensure and facillitate that all universities and tertiary institutions have a Sexual Abuse and Sexual Exploitation (SASE) policy that protects that students (from fellow students and institution staff members) and details the reporting mechanisms and whistleblowing protocols.The Action for Choice Project shall primarily target as ultimate beneficiary&#x2019;s students from the 10 State Universities. The project shall not be selective in excluding students and/or young people to be key beneficiaries of the project however, special attention shall be given to students with disabilities, students living with HIV, first year students, students on internship, and student survivors of Gender Based Violence.Objectives1. To strengthen life-skills, agency and assertiveness of students in 10 State Universities in Zimbabwe to make informed choices on their sexuality by 2021;2. To expose students to sexuality information and education using ICTs and multimedia in 10 State Universities by 2021.3. To improve delivery of sexuality information and education and access to youth friendly SRH services by students in 10 State Universities by 20214. Improved accountability by government and university authorities on the delivery of sexuality information and education and access to youth friendly SRH services by students.Expected Outcomes1. Students&#x2019; life-skills, agency and assertiveness are strengthened to make informed choices on their SRH, demand for and uptake of SRH services;2. Students exposed and reached with scientifically proven and culturally sensitive sexuality information and education;3. Improved relationships and supportive environment for students to make and sustain their choices on sexuality;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAYWHAT/Students and Youth Working on Reproductive Health Action Team</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="130" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Population Policies/Programmes &amp; Reproductive Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="13020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive health care</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">805486.513854368</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180766</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">343333.6590768429</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">805486.513854368</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">528770.3973180765</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">343333.6590768431</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-01">1974822.792966</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-08-28">805486.513854368</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-06-28">528770.3973180766</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-06-28">343333.6590768429</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-28">233184.483904441</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through Resource Centres (that were established and strengthened within the Action for Choice implementing universities in 2019), the project continued to link students with critical Sexual Reproductive Health service providers. In 2020, Resource Centres became common facilities frequented by students to access SRHR information and referral for services. Although Resource Centres had to be closed end of March due to lockdown and subsequent closure of schools, more than 5 000 students had already accessed information and referrals through the Resource Centres. SAYWHAT strengthened its WhatsApp and social media platforms to continue the engagements with young people to try and fill the information gap created by the closure of resource centres. SAYWHAT needs to introduce a mandatory online induction programme especially for first year students and push for the incorporation of the same in the college induction package. This will ensure SAYWHAT is able to reach the students with vital SRHR information and assess the information gaps despite disturbances caused by emergencies like Covid-19.
With support from the Embassy SAYWHAT introduced SRHR law clinics to improve interaction and accessibility of legal services and advise to students in tertiary institutions. The SRHR Law clinic was a platform to stimulate conversations using direct interface with Legal Practitioners. The SRHR Law Clinic exposed the existing knowledge gaps among students on legal matters related to their SRHR. Moving forward Saywhat needs to have webinars or virtual conferences for these law clinics addressing different modules to broaden the reach both in geographic reach and in numbers.
With the advent of Covid-19 and the subsequent restrictions SAYWHAT with support from the Embassy manage to adapt to virtual programming initiatives that enabled the continued availability by students and young people to accurate Sexuality Information Education. The National Universities&#x2019; Quiz and Debate Competitions, the Virtual National Students Conference and Co-creation support initiatives such as the CONDOMIZE! Campaigns and Orange Day Commemorations, SAYWHAT reached out and impacted the lives of over 520, 000 young people in a space of 6 months.
The Covid-19 related movement restrictions however resulted in significant decrease in general access to and increased violations of SRHR. Existing vulnerabilities among young women were exacerbated as their access to services was curtailed away from tertiary institutions along with the support that comes with it. Although the online activities have a wider reach the activities have its myriad of challenges stemming from mobilisation and digital poverty among the most vulnerable young people. When the tertiary schools shifted from physical to online learning, SRHR information fell by the wayside and was not included in learning packages. And even where it is, with connectivity still being a luxury rather than a right and an ever-widening digital gender gap, girls and young women from marginalised, poorer households are the least likely to be able to access this information. There is need for SAYWHAT to find innovative ways to bridge this widening digital divide. This includes developing more partnerships with community-based radios to reach the marginalised young people. SAYWHAT also needs to work on strengthening and rolling out of online modules on SRHR that can be infused in the mainstream learning.
SAYWHAT with its strong influence on young people acted as a conduit of Covid-19 information. Covid-19 awareness and support were mainstreamed and ensuring that young people were given up to date information on the pandemic through the Smart Choice Mobile Application, Meet the Expert sessions, Online Competitions, Webinars and Online Infomercials on SAYWHAT Social Media Platforms. The project also facilitated the student&#x2019;s interaction with policy makers in shaping the COVID-19 discourse at National level. However, the Government in most cases continued with the tokenism approach to young people&#x2019;s participation where it made unilateral decisions affecting the young people
To strengthen real time dissemination of Sexuality Information and Education and linkages to services SAYWHAT launched a Call for Choice Toll Free Line facility /Call Centre in 2020. The facility has successfully closed the information and service linkage gap for young people in Zimbabwe and neighbouring countries like Mozambique and Zambia. Besides handling Sexual Reproductive Health issues for young people, the Call for Choice Toll Free facility managed a significant number of cases related to Child Protection and this has helped SAYWHAT to strengthen its Child Protection programming initiatives. There is however need to strengthen the referral pathway and follow up to ensure the young people who come through the toll free access the services they need.
The installation of Solar Systems in 3 SAYWHAT Provincial Satellite Offices through the support from the Swedish Embassy in Zimbabwe has improved operational and administrative efficiency of these satellite offices and will and ensure uninterrupted internet connectivity for both students and staff in those tertiary institutions. More so, the procurement and setting up of Video Conferencing equipment enabled SAYWHAT to host its first Virtual National Students Conference and will go a long way in improving SAYWHAT virtual programming given the new normal. The Embassy will have dialogue with SAYWHAT to ensure the studio is used efficiently for the benefit of the broader SRHR agenda.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="12433" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1800000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zimbabwe 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zimbabwe 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
