<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13623A0101-ZWE-16064</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mashambanzou:The Dawn: New Day, New Opportunities &amp; New Hope for PLWHA 2020-2022</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Mashambanzou:The Dawn: New Day, New Opportunities &amp; New Hope for PLWHA 2020-2022</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Mashambanzou har s&#xF6;kt 6 miljoner SEK fr&#xE5;n Sida f&#xF6;r att genomf&#xF6;ra projektet &quot;The Dawn: New Day, New Opportunity and New Hope for People Living with HIV and AIDS&#x201D; i Harare under perioden 2020-2022. Insatsen syftar till att f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra livskvaliteten f&#xF6;r m&#xE4;nniskor som lever med - och de som drabbas av - HIV och AIDS genom behandling, v&#xE5;rd och st&#xF6;d f&#xF6;r individer, samt genom att ge familjer kunskap och f&#xE4;rdigheter f&#xF6;r att effektivt hantera chockerna fr&#xE5;n HIV / AIDS och f&#xF6;rb&#xE4;ttra lokala sam&#xE4;hllens motst&#xE5;ndskraft i hanteringen av sjukdomen. Sida kommer ocks&#xE5; att finansiera installation av solpaneler. Bidraget kommer att vara k&#xE4;rnfinansierat fr&#xE5;n Sida och det kommer inte att g&#xF6;ras andrahandsutbetalningar.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mashambanzou has applied to Sida for funding of 6 417 500 million SEK to carry out the &quot;The Dawn: New Day, New Opportunities and New Hope for People Living with HIV and AIDS project in Harare, during the period 2020-2022. The intervention aims at improving  the quality of life of people living with, and those affected by HIV and AIDS through treatment, care and support of individuals, empowering families with knowledge and skills to effectively respond to the shocks of the HIV/AIDS and improve community resilience in dealing with HIV/AIDS. The contribution will be core funding  and there will be no forwarding of funds. Mashambanzou will also receive SEK300 000 for the installation of solar system to improve sustainability of power supply.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overall project objective
To improve the quality of life of people living with, and those affected by HIV and AIDS through treatment, care and support of individuals, families and communities in and around Harare by December 2022.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mashambanzou Care Trust - Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mashambanzou Care Trust - Sida</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3 - By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.3 - Senast 2030 utrota epidemierna av aids, tuberkulos, malaria och f&#xF6;rsummade tropiska sjukdomar samt bek&#xE4;mpa hepatit, vattenburna sjukdomar och andra smittsamma sjukdomar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4.2 - By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys have access to quality early childhood development, care and pre-primary education so that they are ready for primary education.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">4.2 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla flickor och pojkar har tillg&#xE5;ng till f&#xF6;rskola av god kvalitet som ger omv&#xE5;rdnad och f&#xF6;rbereder dem f&#xF6;r att b&#xF6;rja grundskolan.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">262494.9781208943</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">262494.9781208943</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">233184.483904441</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-01">479657.317827</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-28">262494.9781208943</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-28">233184.483904441</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zimbabwe/mashambanzou-grant-agreement-2020-2022.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zimbabwe/mashambanzou-decision-on-contribution.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mashambanzou has a qualified staff compliment with a Medical Doctor, Pharmacist, Registered Nurses, Social Workers, Counsellors and Physiotherapy Technician who assist with integrated patient management and this has allowed better management of the various opportunistic infections.
The programme saw the partner admitting 283 (120 Males, 145 Females, 10 Boys, 8 Girls) patients out of the target of 324. These numbers could have been higher but were limited due to the failure of patients to access Mashambanzou Care Unit (MCU) because of lockdown restrictions because of Covid19. Although there is no significant difference between the numbers of males and females admitted, but the higher number of females may indicate that they may be having better health seeking behaviours compared to the males.
In 2020, the Nenyere Day Care Centre also enrolled 60 pupils and the first term sailed smoothly until the lockdown where the Centre had to be closed.&#xA0;
Health education has been offered to the patients throughout the year and both individual and family (group) education model was utilised to ensure that family members are equipped to support the patients. Education on good hygiene habits, importance&#xA0;of eating a well balanced diet was given and there was active participation of the group members which made the health education sessions a success.
MCU through their nutritional garden and other nutrition provisions from other donors, were able to ensure that the nutritional requirements&#xA0;of each patient are met. Nutritional education was also given to the patients to encourage&#xA0;healthy eating habits and hence improve better tolerance of medications, promotion of healthy weight gain, improved muscle built and tone, enhanced energy levels and improved bowel movement and appetite.
The programme saw a discharge of 141 patients (62 Males, 73 Females, 5 Boys, 1 Girl) which translated to 57% of the target. The target was not attained due to a reduced number of patients who were admitted due to lockdown restrictions.
MCU also saw the passing on of 50 patients (19 Males, 29 Females, 2 Girls, 0 Boys) among those admitted&#xA0;at MCU. This means that the families of these individuals lost members that could have contributed to the family&apos;s&#xA0;welfare which means the children will be orphaned and vulnerable and will require continued support of which Mashambanzou will need to find ways of supporting these children.
OVC and Family Assessments&#xA0;were carried out during the period under review and the number of family assessments carried out were 221 (101 Males, 115 Females, 3 Boys and 2 Girls against a target of 350. The assessments gave an outcome of the needs of the children and families which included acquiring birth certificates, educational and nutritional support and sometimes a dire need for a place of safety as they could not remain in the home especially where the parent or guardian is admitted or has passed on. From the 64 OVCs&#xA0;need educational support, 30 were from Mbare and their parents or guardians were unable to enrol them into Early Childhood Development Centres. Through the Embassy of Sweden funding, these children have been enrolled&#xA0;for ECD and the other children were linked to other Mashambanzou Care Trusts supported projects which focus on OVC educational support.
Through the programme, discharged patients&#xA0;have received nutritional support as part of therapy since some of the patients had no source of income to support themselves and their families. A total number of 57 clients received food hampers upon discharge, however 20 of these clients continued to receive the food hampers up to December 2020 with the hope of continuing into 2021 due to the need to boost the patients immune system.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13623" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1800000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zimbabwe 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zimbabwe 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
