<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-13451A0101-ZWE-16064</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africaid-Zvandiri 2019</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Africaid-Zvandiri 2019</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africaid is a community based organisation in Zimbabwe which, through its Zvandiri programme, provides community and health facility based prevention, treatment, care and support for children, adolescents and young people living with HIV. Zvandiri aims to support national HIV systems to provide a comprehensive package of care for children, adolescents and young people living with HIV which is responsive to their clinical and psychosocial needs and experiences. HIV positive children and adolescents are at the heart of the programme, whereby they take the lead in designing, implementing, monitoring, and evaluating Zvandiri activities.

Young advocates from Zvandiri are engaged at community, national and international level in speaking out for the needs of HIV positive children, adolescents and young people. They have successfully advocated for policy change, guidance, funding and service delivery for their peers at all levels by sharing their own life experiences, as well as those of their peers across Zimbabwe.In addition to service provision, a key part of their work over the years has been to engage young people living with HIV in their own creative, participatory mixed media advocacy projects. 

In 2013, for the first time, a group of adolescents and young people living with HIV came out publicly to describe the way in which they have learned &quot;how to dance in the storm&quot;, despite the challenges in their lives. As adolescents and young people living with HIV, they called for zero HIV- related deaths, zero new HIV infections and zero stigma. Uniquely, they were joined by a superband of Zimbabwean musicians who have helped them to turn their message into a world class track and performance. The song, &#x201C;How to Dance&#x201D; has been played at various regional and international conferences including the International AIDS Conference. As of December 2018, the song has been viewed by 16, 800 viewers on YouTube. Following on from its impact and success the adolescents and young people decided that there was still more to be said, more to be shared and that this could be done by building on the &#x2018;How To Dance&#x2019; project format, creating a song with a new message and adding new exciting components to the project. These extra components will further help diversify how the message is disseminated as well engage them in new skills and reach a wider audience.

The programme will be conducted in four phases, some running consecutively or simultaneously as needed. The four phases are:
&#x2022;	Song writing + Project Development Workshop
&#x2022;	Song writing + Project Launch
&#x2022;	Pre-Production and Recording 
&#x2022;	Dissemination 

Following the completion of the programme and release of the song (July 2019) and accompanying videos, the project team will reconvene to evaluate the different project components. Taking stock of its successes and potential areas in need of improvement, it will be key to assess the impact on the contributing young people (eg. new skills learned) as well as look at the reach and scope of the project. Analysing social media reach and new contacts and support generated throughout the project will be helpful ways to examine the reach and potential future scope of the project. Therefore, an important element of the evaluation will be to discuss and decide which components could be developed as on-going activities and programmes under the Zvandiri umbrella.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Africaid &#xE4;r en lokal gr&#xE4;srotsorganisation i Zimbabwe som arbetar med barn och unga som lever med HIV. Genom Africaids program &quot;Zvandiri&quot;  erbjuder organisationen h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd och f&#xF6;rebyggande insatser, samt st&#xF6;d till familjer som har barn och/eller unga som lever med  HIV.  Unga HIV-positiva och deras familjer tar ocks&#xE5; stor del i att driva  Zvandiris aktiviteter, vilket st&#xE4;rker deras sj&#xE4;lvk&#xE4;nsla och bidrar till deras kompetensutveckling. 

Som del av Zvandiri har unga m&#xE4;nniskor varit med och skapat engagemang och kunskap kring hur det &#xE4;r att leva som ung HIV-positiv.  2013 skapade Africaid, genom Zvandiri,  en s&#xE5;ng tillsammans med HIV-positiva barn och unga, d&#xE4;r barnen tillsammans med flera v&#xE4;lk&#xE4;nda musiker i Zimbabwe ber&#xE4;ttade om sin situation genom musik och s&#xE5;ng. S&#xE5;ngen, &quot;How to Dance&quot;, blev en hit i Zimbabwe och har ocks&#xE5; spelats p&#xE5; regionala och internationella konferenser inklusive p&#xE5; internationella AIDS-konferensen i december 2018. 

Som en uppf&#xF6;ljning till s&#xE5;ngen och f&#xF6;r att forts&#xE4;tta att sprida buskapet om &quot;positive living&quot; vill Zvandiri och Africaid nu g&#xF6;ra en ny s&#xE5;ng, f&#xF6;r att  sprida ett vidare budskap och n&#xE5; nya m&#xE5;lgrupper.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project were:&#x2022; Increased dialogue among youths as well as the community at large about HIV as well asharmful norms, habits and attitudes&#x2022; Increased information and awareness about HIV&#x2022; A sense of pride among youth and the community about media produced by thecommunity for the commnuity</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africaid-Zvandiri</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="23000" role="4" type="23">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africaid-Zvandiri</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-24" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="16064" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social mitigation of HIV/AIDS</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.3 - By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.3 - Senast 2030 utrota epidemierna av aids, tuberkulos, malaria och f&#xF6;rsummade tropiska sjukdomar samt bek&#xE4;mpa hepatit, vattenburna sjukdomar och andra smittsamma sjukdomar.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">31197.4534417665</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">31197.4534417665</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-24">31197.453441</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-04-28">31197.4534417665</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, Embassy awarded a grant to Africaid-Zvandiri programme to produce a cover of the song, &#x2018;This is Me&#x2019;. The song speaks of a group of people who have been stigmatised and isolated from society but are now fighting back, saying they have been bruised, battered, but they will not let that get them down, because they are glorious. This is Me, is a very inspirational song especially for people living with stigma and discrimination. In total, a group of 23 young people living with HIV from Africaid&#x2019;s Zvandiri programme were involved in the production of the cover of this song and video which has now been shared across Zimbabwe, Africa and the global community. &#x2018;This is Me&#x2019; resonated so closely with the young people&#x2019;s life experiences as young people from Zimbabwe whose lives have been changed by HIV.&#xA0;
The production involved the engagement of&#xA0; local artists with extensive expertise as well as prior experience working with young people with HIV. The result was an advocacy message that can be used over a long period of time. The process equipped the young people with new skills in performing arts at the same time building their confidence, pride and joy as they tackle the challenges they face as young people living with HIV.
&#x2018;This is Me&#x2019; was launched at the International Conference on AIDS and STIs in Africa (ICASA) in Rwanda in December 2019. This choice of event for the launch was chosen specifically as ICASA reaches an international audience of HIV policy makers, funders, service provides, implementers, academics, civil society and people living with HIV. With support from the Embassy, two of the lead singers from the &#x2018;This is Me&#x2019; project were able to travel to Kigali, to participate in a special session led by Africaid on HIV and youth at which they launched &#x2018;This is Me&#x2019;.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="13451" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061503" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="1800000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2017-01-01">
    <sida:title>Zimbabwe 2017-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Zimbabwe 2017-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
