<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5116011001-RWA-15150</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">F&#xF6;rst&#xE4;rkning N&#xE4;rhet r&#xE4;ttvisa i Rwanda             (SPJR)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening Proximity Justice in Rwanda         (SPJR)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet Strengthening Proximity Justice in Rwanda (SPJR) syftar till att st&#xF6;dja medborgares deltagande i lokala r&#xE4;ttsprocesser; att underl&#xE4;tta en konstruktiv dialog samt &#xF6;ka medvetenheten om de r&#xE4;ttigheter och skyldigheter som medborgare har om lagen, samt om de lokala r&#xE4;ttsprocessernas funktion. Insatsen kommer att str&#xE4;va efter att skydda r&#xE4;ttigheter f&#xF6;r utsatta och marginaliserade grupper, i synnerhet kvinnors tillg&#xE5;ng till r&#xE4;ttsv&#xE4;sendet och deltagande i beslutsfattandet; fr&#xE4;mja det civila samh&#xE4;llet och &#xF6;ka kapaciteten hos civila samh&#xE4;llets organisationer f&#xF6;r att fullg&#xF6;ra sina uppdrag; ge institutionellt st&#xF6;d till rwandiska r&#xE4;ttsinstitutioner och lokala myndigheter f&#xF6;r att m&#xF6;jligg&#xF6;ra f&#xF6;r dem att fullg&#xF6;ra sina uppgifter, bland annat genom kapacitetsuppbyggnad och kunskaps&#xF6;verf&#xF6;ring; genomf&#xF6;ra och publicera egen forskning samt engagera beslutsfattare genom evidensbaserad opinionsbildning; och st&#xF6;dja utbyten p&#xE5; lokal och nationell niv&#xE5; mellan det lokala r&#xE4;ttsv&#xE4;sendet och akt&#xF6;rer fr&#xE5;n det civila samh&#xE4;llet.

SPJR  implementeras av RCN Rwanda som har l&#xE5;ng erfarenhet av liknande utvecklingsprojekt i landet. 

Projektet ska p&#xE5;g&#xE5; under tre &#xE5;r fr&#xE5;n augusti 2015 till december 2018 med en sammanlagd budget p&#xE5; SEK 49 960 000.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Support to ABUNZI II through RCN Justice et democratie aims at        continuing some activities of ILPRC project and some other            interventions to strengthen the capacities of local mediators         (ABUNZI) to handle land issues but specifically ensure women land     rights In Rwanda</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Embassy supported RCN to implement a Project to Support Proximity Justice in Rwanda (SPJR). The project implementation lasted from 1st August 2015 &#x2013; 31st March 2019. The program was originally planned to end in 2018 but extended to 2019 to cover delays encountered due to understandable reasons.
SPJR project was implemented in seven districts of Rwanda (Nyanza in the south, Burera and Gicumbi in the north, Nyarugenge in the city of Kigali, Nyabihu, Ngororero and Rutsiro in the west).
The project reached a total of 145,318 men and women. Of the total, around 65% were women. The Embassy also notes that the approach focused on behaviour change using outcome mapping so numbers were collected but not prioritised.
The programme was intended to support citizen participation in proximity justice. It would facilitate constructive dialogue and raise awareness about the rights and duties of the population, the law and the functioning of proximity justice. It would seek to safeguard the rights of vulnerable and marginalized groups in particular women&#x2019;s access to justice and participation in decision making. The programme would promote the role of civil society and reinforce the capacity of CSOs to fulfil their mandate. The programme would provide institutional support to Justice Reconciliation Law and Order (JRLO) sector institutions and local authorities to enable them to discharge their duties, including capacity building, knowledge transfer, coaching and materials. It would conduct and disseminate original research and engage decision makers with evidence-based advocacy. It would support exchanges at local and national level between proximity justice and civil society actors.
Due to the fact that the program used outcome mapping approach, there were two outcome challenges:
1) Proximity Justice Actors have the necessary knowledge and materials that allows them to deliver high quality justice services in conformity with their mandate and human rights principles. PJA collaborate to allow each other to fulfil their mandates. PJA inform and support the population of their rights and about the functioning of the justice system so citizens, especially women, vulnerable and marginalized groups, are able to exercise these rights&quot;;
2) Audiences are active citizens who share and debate their own experiences, expectations, recommendations and knowledge with Proximity Justice users and service providers. They have knowledge of their basic rights and the administration of proximity justice allowing them to exercise these rights. They are confident that they can defend their rights and do so before appropriate judicial authorities. Audiences take steps in support of more equitable conditions for women and vulnerable or marginalized&#xA0;groups to access justice services to exercise their rights.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RCN Justice et Democratie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RCN Justice et Democratie</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15150" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic participation and civil society</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.7 - Ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.7 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla ett lyh&#xF6;rt, inkluderande, deltagandebaserat och representativt beslutsfattande p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1986793.6656343131</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1579501.5795015793</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">858418.4847647978</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1986793.6656343131</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1579501.5795015795</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">858418.4847647976</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-01">5926945.297948</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-08-28">1423605.7561126072</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-04-28">1344007.4796938</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">642786.185940513</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">1111501.1115011114</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">468000.468000468</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-28">858418.4847647978</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Based on the final narrative report that was submitted on 16th July 2019, the&#xA0;Embassy assesses that in four and a half&#xA0; years, the project made significant contribution to the promotion of positive behaviour change in addressing the two following problems, namely:
 1) Weak capacity of proximity justice actors - particularly the local mediators (&quot;Abunzi&quot;), Executive Secretaries (ES), Maison d&#x2019;Acc&#xE8;s &#xE0; la Justice (MAJ) agents and three Civil Society Organisations (CSOs) HAGURUKA, ARAMA and TUBIBE AMAHORO working in the field of justice or rights &#x2013; hampered their efforts to uphold justice.
2) Lack of public awareness about basic rights, key laws and the functioning of the proximity justice system (particularly the services offered by MAJ and Abunzi), prevented people from claiming their rights.&#xA0;
Specifically, the Embassy assesses that the project contributed to a better quality of justice services offered to the public through a better collaboration between Proximity Justice Actors (PJA). This was a result of the implementation of activities like trainings and coaching for all PJAs and other relevant actors like judges. The Embassy assesses that the ultimate outcome was that the beneficiaries of such activities were shown to be using the new skills and knowledge to improve service delivery and advise citizens of their rights more often, and to be collaborating with each other better than before, especially in respect of each other&#x2019;s mandate and role in the Abunzi system.
In addition, another major result is that the project has increased the quality and supply of justice services to the most vulnerable people, and has consequentially increased citizens&#x2019; access to quality justice services. Women specifically benefited from such services that led to their increased access to land rights.
The project final narrative report also documents that the demand for justice services has increased as a result of the project activities. Citizens have not only taken steps to defend their own rights, but also to advocate for the rights of others, including women and vulnerable and marginalized groups, and have acted as conduits to increase the dissemination of information. This result is assessed by the Embassy as key in behaviour change.
The Embassy concludes that the above summarised results are the aggregated summarised results. The project also achieved many results&#xA0;on the output level but&#xA0;the output results will not be discussed in this memo.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51160110" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
