<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5116007801-RWA-16020</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision CORE Project</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">World Vision CORE Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creating Off-farm Rwandan Enterprise (CORE) project seeks to boost    employment opportunities and living conditions for women and youth in Nyamasheke and Rusizi districts through strengthening households,     local groups, cooperatives, and small enterprises to formalize and    grow their businesses. The project will work with institutional       strengthening, business development, ICT and social responsibility.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Projektet Creating Off-farm Rwandan Enterprise (CORE) syftar till att &#xF6;ka m&#xF6;jligheter till produktiv syssels&#xE4;ttning och &#xF6;kad levnadsstandard f&#xF6;r kvinnor och ungdomar i distrikten Nyamasheke och Rusizi. Projektet arbetar med kapacitetsutveckling av f&#xF6;retag och lokala grupper, fr&#xE4;mjar tillg&#xE5;ng till finansiella tj&#xE4;nster, och anv&#xE4;nder informationsteknik som ett verktyg f&#xF6;r marknadsutveckling. Fattiga kvinnor och unga utg&#xF6;r en s&#xE4;rskild m&#xE5;lgrupp f&#xF6;r projektet. CORE implementeras av World Vision Rwanda som har l&#xE5;ng erfarenhet av liknande utvecklingsprojekt i andra delar av landet. Projektet ska p&#xE5;g&#xE5; under tre &#xE5;r fr&#xE5;n juli 2015 till juni 2018 med en sammanlagd budget p&#xE5; 49 miljoner kronor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Creating Off-farm Rwandan Enterprises (CORE) project seeks to significantly increase the incomes of women and youth by supporting women and youth-run cooperatives and entrepreneurial ventures in Nyamasheke and Rusizi Districts. Additionally, CORE will expand off-farm employment for women and youth through: strengthening the environment for the creation and successful management of women and youth cooperatives; increasing off-farm entrepreneurship among women and youth; increasing access to financial services for women and youth cooperatives and entrepreneurs; improving access to information communication technology for development (ICT4D) services to support marketing and price analysis; and through developing community-based and government implemented monitoring systems that are robust enough to estimate impact and to monitor economic growth for the project&#x2019;s beneficiaries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21502" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21502" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Vision</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="16020" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Employment creation</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="160" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Social Infrastructure &amp; Services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2016774.821159527</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1872001.872001872</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">690417.0118751726</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2016774.8211595272</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.156255478</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1872001.8720018717</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">690417.0118751727</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">-17977.5589843378</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-01">5813056.837459</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-06-28">1186338.1300938395</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">830436.6910656876</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-10-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-28">0</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-28">1053001.053001053</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-28">819000.819000819</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">690417.0118751726</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">-17977.5314882772</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">At the start of the project WVR established a new field office in Rusizi and hired new staff. They signed memorandum of understandings (MoUs) with the local government, as well as with three third implementing partners; Eglise Anglicane du Rwanda (EAR), Faith Victory Association (FVA), and R&#xE9;seau Interdioc&#xE9;sain de Microfinance (RIM).
Below are some key achievements and results for the first phase of the CORE project;
92 youth and women off-farm cooperatives were created. The project assisted beneficiaries with information about registration process, but also worked to strengthen capacity at the local authorities for them to be able to support this specific target group to access information and to establish businesses and cooperatives. In terms of skills development, the project identified early on that in addition to technical and vocational skills there was a need of increased business skills in terms of for example taxation, pricing and marketing, as well as organisational and financial skills. Thus, this has also been provided to the established and supported cooperatives.
15 TVETS supported with a total number of 1070 youth and women (143 women and 927 youth - 510 girls and 417 boys) in both Nyamasheke and Rusizi districts have graduated and benefited from CORE project supported training centres. The CORE project has put emphasis on supporting technical vocational education and training (TVET) to create a favorable learning environment to youth and women in the operating area. The decision to support these specific 15 TVETs were based on a market assessment conducted which has guided the project to choose the options to support.
The project also provided start-up toolkits to TVET graduates in order to start their income generating activities. This has led to 1167 women and youth created off-farm jobs and utilized their start-up toolkits to generate income.
The project also worked to strengthen value chains through training for different value chain actors and through support with required material to properly carry out their activities.
In order to increase access and utilization of financial services for women and youth, the project has worked to support the creation of village saving and loans associations (VSLA), conducted training on financial literacy, and worked to link saving groups with formal financial services. Here RIM has played a central part. The project has facilitated formation of 1518 VSLAs with a total number of 37177 members. Combined, the VSLAs have managed to save approximately 790 000 USD and disbursed loans to members for a total of 560 000 USD.
EAR and FVA have been instrumental in the work to support VSLAs. VSLAs have proven to be a strong entry point to personal savings and lending for the most vulnerable community members, and further some VSLAs have engaged in income generating activities together and graduated to a cooperative or SME. As for the revolving fund established with RIM, the micro business portfolio has been successfully provided financing to 2 325 women and youth from 211 VSLAs, to run off-farm businesses. As mentioned above, financial linkage sessions were conducted to introduce community members and entrepreneurs with formal financial institutions. In total 6330 people attended these linkage sessions, which were conducted in partnership with RIM and other microfinance institutions such as SACCOs.
To improve access and utilization of information and communication technology (ICT) for women and youth, in order to support off-farm businesses, the project has facilitated training on ICT4D modules. The project has also created 13 Community Knowledge Centers (CKC) and strengthened seven existing CKCs. Two trainer of trainers (ToTs) per CKC were trained to facilitate training to community members. This training has reached 2186 women, 8783 boys, 4525 girls and 1450 men. This enables the beneficiaries to access important online services through for example the governments Irembo portal, access market information and market their products and services online. An online market platform was also developed and beneficiaries were trained on how to use the platform for applications and advertising.
Further, the final project report states that despite actions to empower women, women are still highly dependent on their husbands for decisions making, mainly due to cultural barriers. Moreover, the multiple roles of women in economic life, community life and family life, limits the hours they are able to dedicate to their businesses. Due to the districts proximity to the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) and the high frequency of cross-border trade, a risk had been identified that relates to child labor through exposing children to engage in petty trade. Efforts have been made in the project to address this issue as the project promotes cross-border trade. The report also mentions that people with disabilities and special needs still face difficulties to attend some activities both due to that some areas are hard to reach and also due to feelings of inferiority.
When it comes to indirect social impacts, several beneficiaries testified to that strengthening their businesses in terms of increased production, income and profit, has led to many being able to put their children in school (pay school fees), pay health insurance, buy livestock, and build up their assets by investing in a house or property etc. Further, VSLA members testified to that they also used their savings meetings to also discuss other topics relevant to them and to their communities, such as reconciliation and family planning. Cooperatives have for example said that their objectives were to create income generating activities for the young girls in the area, who otherwise are at risk of ending up in prostitution. This illusrates how increased income and economic empowerment are relevant also to social empowerment and social impact.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51160078" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
