<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5116012101-RWA-15220</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education for sustainable peace in Rwanda (ESPR)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Utbildning f&#xF6;r h&#xE5;llbar fred i Rwanda (ESPR)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Organisationen Aegis Trust har ans&#xF6;kt till ambassaden om bidrag f&#xF6;r projektet &apos;Education for Sustainable Peace in Rwanda&apos; (ESPR), under perioden 1 juli 2016 - 30 juni 2019.

ESPR &#xE4;r en forts&#xE4;ttning av den framg&#xE5;ngsrika insatsen &apos;Rwanda Peace Education Programme&apos; (RPEP, insatsnr 51160051), vilken implementerades av Aegis Trust och dess samarbetspartners mellan 1 juli 2013 - 30 juni 2016 och bland annat bidrog till introduktion av fredsutbildning i den nationella l&#xE4;roplanen i Rwanda. 

ESPR:s &#xF6;vergripande syfte &#xE4;r att bidra till &#xF6;kad most&#xE5;ndskraft mot folkmord i Rwanda. Mer specifikt kommer projektet arbeta genom 1) utbildare (l&#xE4;rare och f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ldrar), 2) ungdomar, samt 3) beslutsfattare och forskare att st&#xE4;rka fredsutbildning i skolor och rwandiska samh&#xE4;llen. F&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntade programaktiviteter f&#xF6;rv&#xE4;ntas inkludera utbildningar f&#xF6;r blivande l&#xE4;rare och l&#xE4;rare att kunna l&#xE4;ra ut det nya &#xE4;mnet &apos;Fred och V&#xE4;rderingar&apos; inom alla &#xE4;mnen och niv&#xE5;er; p&#xE5;verka utformandet av undervisningsmaterial och l&#xE4;rarmetod f&#xF6;r &#xE4;mnet &apos;Fred och V&#xE4;rderingar&apos;; n&#xE5; ut till f&#xF6;r&#xE4;ldrar (i egenskap av &apos;icke-formella&apos; utbildare) och utrusta dem med relevant fredsutbildning f&#xF6;r att kunna p&#xE5;verka sina barn positivt; bygga ett n&#xE4;tverk av unga flickor och pojkar i hela landet med kompetens, kunskap och handlingskraft att genomf&#xF6;ra fredsbildande verksamhet i sina samh&#xE4;llen; st&#xE4;rka det rwandiska forskningssamfundet i syfte att genomf&#xF6;ra och kommunicera forskning om f&#xF6;rebyggande av folkmord och fredsbyggande f&#xF6;r att kunna p&#xE5;verka nationella beslutsfattare; och inr&#xE4;tta samh&#xE4;llsbaserade program f&#xF6;r att leverera fredsutbildning till allm&#xE4;nheten.

Den totala budgeten f&#xF6;r projektet &#xE4;r 35 000 000 SEK.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The civil society organization Aegis Trust has applied for a grant from the Embassy for the project &apos;Education for Sustainable Peace in Rwanda &apos; (ESPR), during the period July 1, 2016 - June 30, 2019.

ESPR is a continuation of the successful contribution &apos;Rwanda Peace Education Programme&apos; (RPEP, contribution no 51160051), which was implemented by Aegis Trust and its partners between July 1, 2013 - June 30, 2016 and, inter alia, contributed to the introduction of peace education in the national curriculum in Rwanda.

ESPR&apos;s overall objective is to contribute to strengthened resilience against genocide in Rwanda. More specifically, the project will work through 1) Educators (teachers and parents), 2) Youth, and 3) Decision-Makers and Researchers to strengthen peace education in schools and Rwandan communities. Program activities are expected to include training for pre-service and in-service teachers to teach the new cross-cutting subject &apos;Peace and Values&apos;; influence the design of teaching materials and teaching methodology for the subject &apos;Peace and Values&apos;; reach out to parents (as &apos;non-formal&apos; educators) and equip them with relevant peace education in order to influence their children positively; build a network of young girls and boys across the country with the skills, knowledge and drive to implement peace-building activities in their communities; strengthen the Rwandan research communityto implement and communicate research on the prevention of genocide and peace-building in order to influence national decision-makers; and the establishment of community-based programs to deliver peace education to the public.

The total budget for the project is 35 million SEK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intended outcome of Education for Sustainable Peace in Rwanda (ESPR) is to contribute to sustainable peace in Rwanda through peace education within formal and non-formal education and influence related policies through research.ESPR will achieve this by working with three key change agents (&apos;Boundary Partners&apos;): 1) Educators, 2) Youth and 3) Decision-makers &amp;amp; Researchers. The programme will build a sustained legacy that will promote critical thinking, empathy and personal responsibility among Educators and Youth to improve social cohesion, and will catalyse pluralistic and constructive exchange on genocide and peacebuilding topics to improve policy and practice that will promote social cohesion and sustainable peace in Rwanda.&#xA0;
Update (extension)
Aegis submitted a proposal to amend the agreement for Education for Sustainable Peace in Rwanda (ESPR) programme for three months (July-September 2021 in order to bridge the period between the end of the programme in June until the new programme is designed and appraised by the Embassy.
Rationale of the extension
Under ESPR, Aegis aims to build resilience against identity-based violence through Peace and Values Education (PVE) targeting formal and non-formal education.
As Aegis transitions from ESPR to its next three-year programme, in coordination with Interpeace and Never Again Rwanda, there is a need to develop a coherent approach and implementation framework that will allow better coordination and synergy, Value for Money and additional outcomes.
The addendum period will serve as a bridge between the current programme and the upcoming programme, which is due to start on October 1st, 2021. The extension will allow Aegis to maintain the key human resources and capacities that it has built internally during ESPR,&#xA0;to finalize the proposal for the upcoming programme, cooperate with the Embassy during the appraisal, and to make a number of necessary studies and analyses, some of which would otherwise be done during an inception phase of the new programme.
The addendum will also allow Aegis, Interpeace and Never Again Rwanda to set the ground for their joint implementation framework,&#xA0;which is meant to&#xA0;reduce transaction costs as a result of better coordination. A concept note on the joint programming, developed by the three organisations, is shared with the Embassy in advance of signinig this extension with Aegis.&#xA0;
Outputs
1. An agreed upon implementation framework between the three organizations established;
2. Intervention convergence and divergence between the three organizations identified;
3. The opportunity that comes with the choice to work jointly and/or separately (where there is convergence) assessed;
4. A conflict analysis conducted;
5. Training targeting staff (new content and crosscutting issues) conducted; Review and confirmation of content done;
6. Training sessions for the three organizations (Aegis, Never Again and Interpeace) and Radio La Benevolencija as Aegis downstream partner conducted;
7. A stakeholder review and consultations (including REB and other policy makers) conducted;
8. Feedback from key boundary partners collected (including field work);
9. Behavioural baseline information established; A participatory programme design workshop organized;
10. Proposal will be developed and submitted</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aegis Trust</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="21000" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERNATIONAL NGO</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civilian peace-building, conflict prevention and resolution</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="152" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict, Peace &amp; Security</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="16.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">16.a - Strengthen relevant national institutions, including through international cooperation, for building capacity at all levels, in particular in developing countries, to prevent violence and combat terrorism and crime.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">16.a - St&#xE4;rka ber&#xF6;rda nationella institutioner, bland annat genom internationellt samarbete, i syfte att bygga upp kapacitet p&#xE5; alla niv&#xE5;er, i synnerhet i utvecklingsl&#xE4;nderna, f&#xF6;r att f&#xF6;rebygga v&#xE5;ld och bek&#xE4;mpa terrorism och brottslighet.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">584351.0781277391</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1263601.2636012635</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879313</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2030478.3257014141</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">584351.0781277391</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">1263601.2636012635</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">2030478.3257014141</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">401750.3284580388</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-06-23">5843510.781277</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-07-28">584351.0781277391</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-05-28">631800.6318006318</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">631800.6318006318</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-05-28">1726042.5296879315</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-03-28">444167.1337471843</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-07-28">1586311.1919542297</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/rwanda-and-burundi/51160121-grant-agreement.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/rwanda-and-burundi/decision-on-contribution--signed--51160121-.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Education for sustainable peace in Rwanda(ESPR)</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ingen resultattitel tillg&#xE4;nglig</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since the previous Conclusion on Performance on handover of ESPR between responsible programme managers in January 2019 to 2021 during the second extension, ESPR has achieved a number of the following results: 1. Teachers are now able to discuss and teach&#xA0;difficult issues related to Genocide. In this regard, the project has provided Rwanda Education Board (REB) with teaching materials to be able teach Peace and Values Education (PVE) only that according media reports, it has not been easy for all teachers to implement the curriculum. The next phase or project should strongly focus on this. During Covid-19 related lock down, it was a blessing in disguise&#xA0;for the project because the otherwise very busy teachers&#xA0;were available to attend trainings at Aegis. The programme has trained Educators&#xA0;to&#xA0;participate in Peace Building (PB) &amp;amp; Peace Education (PE) activities in their communities and the former trainees become Peace Ambassadors. 38 (17 female&#xA0;&amp;amp; 21 Males) peace ambassadors in Kigali and Karongi Peace Schools have been reached during the reporting period in 2020. These numbers are measured through surveys and this is how it is established that it is difficult for teachers to teach such sensitive subjects related to Genocide.&#xA0; 2. Programme&#xA0;supported research has influenced policy change. Ministries of of youth,&#xA0;culture and other relevant government agencies have contacted Aegis to review their respective policies to ensure that the policies are in harmony&#xA0;with PVE. This was inspired&#xA0;by the research Aegis conducts within the programme. Another good example is where Rwandan parliamentarians has consulted Aegis to guide the work of legislation of Laws in the area of reconciliation and peace building. For example&#xA0;Ministry&#xA0;of of youth consulted Aegis to help ensure that youth policy and strategies are conflict and peace building&#xA0;sensitive. Same as Ministry of culture expressed need for Aegis to help ensure that the policy and strategies on culture embrace Peace and Values Education. The Embassy assesses that this integration of conflict sensitivity is in line&#xA0;with what Sweden wants. 3. The space between the youth and older generations has been reduced. The programme has achieved this through the use of inter generation dialogue in communities between the youth and older people. The Embassy notes that its important to ensure that what teachers teach students is not negatively affected by what older people might be teaching to the young generation that contradicts PVE.&#xA0; During the reporting period, in terms of numbers reached, 164 parents (86% women and 78 % women) were trained with support from local leaders mainly in Kigali which is a factor in ownership and sustainability. Based on pre-post surveys conducted by Aegis Trust, the workshops objectives were achieved for example: 82.2% of the participants confirmed to have learnt a lot including knowledge about conflicts and how to deal with them. This was the main expectation that participants had expressed at the beginning of the workshop; 79.4% have acquired knowledge on how to develop positive values in their children;70.8% have gained knowledge about the Continuum of Violence and the genocide against the Tutsi increased. When asked about what changed in them, they mentioned the following:74.3% said that they will be humble as a way to prevent conflicts; 78.2% said they will listen more to their children; 76.9% promised to be more patient towards their partners; 79.7% promised to be role model at home; 72.1% committed to work towards complementarity at home. In terms of further impact, when asked what they intend to do with the knowledge and skills they gained from the workshop, participants made it clear that in addition to changing their actions and practices themselves, they will not keep silence. 69.2% revealed that they are going to be active bystanders and will use the existing platforms to influence community members. On another note 81% of the participants said that the knowledge and skills gained will help them manage their families and change their relationships with family members. This is very significant given that these parents come from families that live in conflict.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51160121" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
