<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5116005301-RWA-43010</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Ett FN</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One UN</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Development Assistance Plan (UNDAP I) 2013-2018, also called One UN, was designed to support realization of Rwanda&#x2019;s medium-term national development priorities under the Economic Development Poverty Reduction Strategy 2 (EDPRS2) and Rwanda Vision 2020. Below are listed the outcomes that the Embassy had earmarked its funds to.
Results Area 1: Inclusive Economic TransformationOutcome 3: Rwanda has in Place Improved Systems for: Sustainable Management of the Environment, Natural Resources &amp; Renewable Energy Resources, Energy Access &amp; Energy Security, to Achieve Greater Environmental and Climate Change Resilience in line with Rio+20 Recommendations on Sustainable Development.&#xA0;
Result Area 2: Accountable Governance
Outcome 1: Citizen Participation and Empowerment: Accountability and Citizen Participation in Sustainable Development and Decision-Making Processes at all Levels Improved.
Outcome 2: Human rights, Justice, and Gender Equality Promoted and Implemented at all Levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">St&#xF6;det syftar till att genom FN-systemet bidra till ekonomisk, social , demokratisk och fredlig utveckling i Rwanda och till att st&#xE4;rka     FN-systemet p&#xE5; lokal niv&#xE5;.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The support aims to contribute to economic, social, democratic and    peaceful development in Rwanda through the UN system and to           strengthen the UN system itself at the local level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="41114" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNDP/United Nations Development Programme</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multisector aid</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="430" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Other Multisector</narrative>
  </sector>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B03" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">10747405.269299269</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">10204230.382367091</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2372676.260187679</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">3393003.393003393</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2013-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2013-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-01-01">10747405.269299269</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2014-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-01-01">10204230.382367091</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2015-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-01-01">2372676.260187679</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-01-01">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">3393003.3930033925</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-05-01">30553337.837007</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-07-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-07-28">6141374.439599582</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2013-11-28">4606030.829699687</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-08-28">5830988.789924052</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2014-12-28">4373241.592443039</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2015-12-28">2372676.260187679</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2016-12-28">1168702.1562554783</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-03-28">1053001.053001053</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-08-28">292500.2925002925</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-12-28">2047502.0475020474</value>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Examples of results - Results Area 1: Inclusive Economic Transformation
The capacity of budgeting processes of the central government planners was enhanced, and the UN contributed to the increased number of districts submitting budget proposals on a timely basis: from 80% in 2013 to 100% in 2014. The districts are now also able to identify and include all anticipated resources and expenditures in annual budgets.
Three Rwandan companies received support to negotiate markets with international buyers, resulting in two agreements for exports of fruits and vegetables being signed with European companies.
One UN reached 17,363 farmers (9,625 women, 7,738 men) directly, many of them pertaining to women groups, and indirectly, many thousands of families were reached. Examples worth noting include 1,088 women and 240 men who increased their production capacity, and 125 women who strengthened their skills in kitchen gardening, resulting in improved food and nutrition security.
The UN organized training of trainers for 37 farmer facilitators, who in their turn trained almost 300 farmers. Through participatory methods, about 80% of the farmers in Yanze increased their skills in practicing soil and water conservation.&#xA0;Overall, 13 farmer groups were established with a total of 293 farmers participating in the trainings (171 females and 122 males).
One million women in Rwanda accessed financial services and 4,520 people (3,204 of whom were women) learned to make proposals to financing agencies to get loans to initiate new businesses.
Millions of people in East Africa are on the move, in search of skilled and non-skilled jobs. The UN programme supported the Government of Rwanda in developing a migration policy that aims to: (i) facilitate and encourage tourists to come to Rwanda; (ii) allow the entry of foreign skilled workers in occupations lacking in Rwanda&#x2019;s labor market; (iii) allow and facilitate the entry of investors with substantial funds to invest in Rwanda; and (iv) enable the Rwandan Diaspora to contribute towards nation-building.
Special attention is brought to the results related to Enviroment and Climate Change as the Embassy has put extra focus monitoring that thematic area.
The UN programme contributed to Rwanda having a National Energy Policy in place, as well as to improved technologies and skills for resource efficiency. At national level, there is increased access to electricity, as well as a total of 2,400 hectares of ecosystems that have been rehabilitated nation-wide (the UN contributed to 432 of them)20. Forest coverage also increased, by 0.3% of the total land size; reaching 29.8%, it generated 23,227 jobs.
By strengthening individual and institutional capacities for poverty-environment mainstreaming, both vertical and horizontal policy coherence for poverty and environment issues in Rwanda have been enhanced. These policy and budgetary changes led to an increase in Government expenditure on environment, natural resources and climate change: from 0.4% of Rwanda&#x2019;s total budget in 2009/10 to 6% in 2015/16. This is a significant increase, showing great goal fulfilment.&#xA0;
One UN contribution also included providing technical and financial support to operationalize Rwanda&#x2019;s Fund for Environmental and Climate Change (FONERWA), created in 2014 and now the largest of its kind in Africa. This fund aims to mobilize and channel domestic and international financing to public and private environmental and climate change projects. Since its establishment, FONERWA has mobilized approximately USD 130 million for strategic climate resilience investments in Rwanda. In 2018, FONERWA received global recognition for its work to address climate change through receiving the 2018 UN Climate Action Award from UNFCCC. The UN has continued to provide support under UNDAP II in the work to establish FONERWA as a Green Bank that will potentially serve the East Africa region. The Swedish Embassy har since 2019 a bilateral agreement with FONERWA.
One UN, in collaboration with MINECOFIN, REMA and MoE, mainstreamed environment into priority productive sectors (agriculture, urbanization, energy and industries). The number of sector policies reflecting environment, climate change, disaster risk reduction and gender increased from 2 to 15. At district level, the number of districts with environment, climate change, disaster risk reduction and gender mainstreamed in the development plans and budgets increased from 7 in 2013 to 30 districts (which is all) in 2017.
One UN also supported the design and launch of the Green Village Toolkit, assisting district developers to incorporate green technologies, such as biogas or other renewable energies and measures for the sustainable management of natural resources. These were complemented by conducting the training on the Green Village Toolkit for Rwanda for local government officials from seven. Following this training, local officials were able to draw green village layout plans for their districts. Through the National Human Settlement Policy and Strategy (also supported by One UN) the Government of Rwanda proposed to support a roll-out of additional model Integrated Development Programme (IDP) villages, which will include most elements of the green village demonstrations.
A number of enterprises participated in demonstration programs to highlight the benefits of the preventive approach of applying resource efficiency. It is estimated that in 2018, 40% SMEs now use alternative technologies, a large increase compared to 2013 (baseline 15% of SMEs). That effort, among others, are beneficial towards sustainable industrialization. The work will continue during UNDAP II.
Example of results in results area: Accountable Governance
The UN contributed support to the two election processes taking place during the UNDAP period, by increasing the capacity of the institutions (National Election Committees, NEC, and others), as well as by capacity building and awareness raising of both political candidates and the public. Citizens&#x2019; satisfaction, measured as citizens expressing confidence in the operations of the NEC, increased significantly from 69% (in 2013/2014) to 87% (in 2018).
87.61%, of the adult population claims to have confidence in the respect for human rights &#x2013; a more than 10% increase since the start of the UNDAP. This data is based on Rwanda Governance Score Card annual report. The UN contributed to the country&#xB4;s achievements around human rights and gender mainstreaming through strengthening national and local institutions, support to research generation and to the elaboration of publications.
By the end of the UNDAP I, 27.81% of the district budgets were allocated to gender priorities &#x2013; a great achievement compared to only 15% in the UNDAP baseline. The One UN support to sector and district authorities, technical staff of the MIGEPROF enhanced their knowledge in formulating, implementing, monitoring and evaluating policies from a gender perspective which contributed to the increased number funds being allocted to gender priorities.
One UN supported the Rwandan government in producing the 2014-15 Rwanda Demographic and Health Survey (RDHS), a nationally representative survey of 12,699 households. The primary purpose of the RDHS is to provide policymakers and planners with detailed information on: fertility and family planning; infant, child, adult, and maternal mortality; maternal and child health; nutrition; malaria; knowledge of HIV/AIDS and other sexually transmitted infections; and domestic violence, among others.
Community dialogues that brought together more than 55,000 women, men and youth across Rwanda ensured a wide dissemination of gender equality and women empowerment (GEWE) messages across all spheres of society.
More than 200 journalists, correspondents and other radio personnel were trained on enhancing the quality of programming, interviewing, broadcasting and sustaining radio stations, through the use of public data and other means.
In partnership with the Rwanda Media Commission, trainings and dialogue sessions were provided to officers from Rwanda National Police (RNP) and the media fraternity. Dialogue sessions brought together a total of 460 persons, including media personnel, RNP officers and representatives from district administration support organs. Interactions between them led to closer collaboration between the RNP and the media fraternity on freedom of expression and safety of journalists. To sustain this trust, modules on freedom of expression, based on UNESCO&#x2019;s Freedom of Expression and Public Order Training Manual, were developed to be incorporated in RNP&#x2019;s training curriculum at all levels.
One UN supported the establishment of the innovation award winning Electronic Case Management System in all courts and prosecution offices. Citizens can now file their cases and track feedback easily as well as access courts, prosecution, lawyers and police services. The system, in combination with the judiciary reforms, led to a drastic decrease in the number of backlog cases, by more than 40% from 2011 to 2018.
With One UN support, the Children Policy was developed and approved, and led to updating of the law on competence and functioning of abunzi mediators in order to expand their competence on most offences involving children.
The last UPR was submitted in 2015, and the UN provided technical support to enhance the development and finalization of the UPR. With support from One UN, the Government, civil society and the National Commission for Human Rights were trained on the UPR process. As a result, a coalition of more than 25 civil society organizations was formed. With support from the UN, the coalition developed a report for the upcoming second round of UPR in 2015. The CSO coalition elaborated a roadmap for the monitoring of the implementation of the 2015 UPR recommendations, conducted a comprehensive mid-term assessment to assess the progress made in implementing the UPR recommendations, and shared the findings with stakeholders &#x2013; including recommendations made to relevant government ministries.
One UN also assisted Rwanda in implementing and reporting on the Committee of the Elimination of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW) recommendations.
The UN contributed to sustainable peace in Rwanda by strengthening local capacities to implement peace and reconciliation, rebuilding trust between genocide survivors, perpetrators and their families. With UN support, 250 facilitators acquired skills in conducting community dialogues focusing on repentance, forgiveness, and social healing. As a result of training and dialogues on social healing, families of the incarcerated and ex-perpetrators resolved to participate in the genocide commemoration period, comforting families of the victims and sharing the information they may know in line with the genocide, what they could not do before. In addition, 10,000 prisoners benefited from dialogue on healing and 595 of them became facilitators in seven prisons. Through the support, the country is preparing thousands of prisoners who will be released in the coming years to integrate into their communities.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51160053" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
