<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>SE-0-SE-6-5103008101-RWA-15170</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="SE-0" secondary-reporter="0" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET phase II</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">FEMNET phase II</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening African women&apos;s rights with focus on the right to safe and legal abortion, abandonment of child marriages and abandonment of Femal Genital Mutilation (FGM/C). This will be done through strategic policy incluence in collaboration with the African women&apos;s rights network FEMNET and through capacity building of its&apos; members of women&apos;s rights organisations on the African continent.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">Syftet med insatsen &#xE4;r att st&#xE4;rka afrikanska kvinnors r&#xE4;ttigheter med fokus p&#xE5; r&#xE4;tten till s&#xE4;ker och laglig abort, avskaffande av barn&#xE4;ktenskap och avskaffande av kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning. Detta genom strategiskt p&#xE5;verkansarbete och policyutveckling i samarbete med det afrikanska kvinnor&#xE4;ttsn&#xE4;tverket FEMNET, samt genom kapacitetsuppbyggnad av dess medlemmar av kvinnor&#xE4;ttsorganisationer p&#xE5; den afrikanska kontinenten med fokus p&#xE5; sex l&#xE4;nder (Zambia, Mozambique, Rwanda, Guinea Conakry, Liberia och Tanzania).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the programme are:
1. Enhance capacity and knowledge of Womens Rights Organizations and Young Women led Organizations to understand and advocate for safe and legal abortion, ending FGM and eradicating child marriage using human rights-based approaches .
2. Strengthen accountability and delivery by African States on SRHR commitments enshrined in the Maputo Protocol and Plan of Action, the ICPD Programme of Action, 2030 Agenda on Sustainable Development and the Beijing Platform for Action (BPfA)
3. Advance effective and meaningful participation of African Womens Rights Organizations at key regional and global policy platforms (the African Union and UN levels)
4. Increase awareness and visibility among key stakeholders in the region and enhance media capacity on SRHR issues, specifically the ACHPR Campaign on Decriminalization of Abortion in Africa, AU Campaign to abolish child marriages and FGM in Africa.
5. Strengthen institutional capacity and functioning of FEMNETs Secretariat in achieving and sustaining programme results</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET/The African Women&#x2019;s Development and Communication Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="32000" role="4" type="30">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FEMNET/The African Women&#x2019;s Development and Communication Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-0" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sweden</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="SE-6" role="3" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+46 8 698 50 00</telephone>
   <email>sida@sida.se</email>
   <website>www.sida.se</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valhallav&#xE4;gen 199, 105 25 Stockholm, Sweden</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="151" percentage="100" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Government &amp; Civil Society-general</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="15170" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&#x2019;s rights organisations and movements, and government institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="3.7" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">3.7 - By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">3.7 - Senast 2030 s&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla att alla har tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsov&#xE5;rd, inklusive familjeplanering, information och utbildning, och att reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa integreras i nationella strategier och program.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.3 - Avskaffa alla skadliga sedv&#xE4;njor, s&#xE5;som barn&#xE4;ktenskap, tidiga &#xE4;ktenskap och tv&#xE5;ngs&#xE4;ktenskap samt kvinnlig k&#xF6;nsstympning.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.3 - Eliminate all harmful practices, such as child, early and forced marriage and female genital mutilation.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.6" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5.6 - Ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights as agreed in accordance with the Programme of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the outcome documents of their review conferences.</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="SV">5.6 - S&#xE4;kerst&#xE4;lla allm&#xE4;n tillg&#xE5;ng till sexuell och reproduktiv h&#xE4;lsa och reproduktiva r&#xE4;ttigheter i enlighet med &#xF6;verenskommelserna i handlingsprogrammet fr&#xE5;n den internationella konferensen om befolkning och utveckling, Pekingplattformen samt slutdokumenten fr&#xE5;n respektive &#xF6;versynskonferenser.</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction(DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="3"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="B01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.117000117</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">57534.7509895977</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">179781.935088146</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">65148.7019121144</value>
  </budget>
  <budget>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">93273.7935617764</value>
  </budget>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-01-01">117000.1170001169</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-01-01">57534.7509895977</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">179781.935088146</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">65148.7019121144</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">93273.7935617764</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <planned-disbursement>
   <period-start iso-date="2022-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-12-28"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2022-01-01">0</value>
  </planned-disbursement>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-01">538200.5382</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-28">117000.117000117</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-12-28">57534.7509895977</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-08-28">95178.6715172538</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-28">84603.2635708922</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-28">65148.7019121144</value>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-05-28">93273.7935617764</value>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51030081_51030081_51030081-GrantAgreement-FEMNETPhaseII.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Grant Agreement</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A09"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://documents.iati.openaid.se/document/zambia/51030081_51030081_51030081-DecisiononContribution-FEMNETPhaseII.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Decision on Contribution</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A11"></category>
  </document-link>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Results achieved</narrative>
    <narrative xml:lang="SV">Uppn&#xE5;dda resultat</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome 1: Enhanced capacity of Womens Rights and Young Women led Organizations to influence domestication, implementation, and reporting on existing regional and global SRHR policies and commitments in 6 target countries

During the reporting period, FEMNET mobilized womens rights activists and advocates to amplify calls for the postponement of the cancelled CSW64 due to COVID-19; to participate in the Africa CDC discussion at regional level where they have been able to identify SRHR to be listed as an essential service; engaged the AU gender directorate and managed to influence the AU gender guideline, though the SRHR language was not adopted and there are plans on continuous discussion to further engage on influencing SRHR language within the guidelines. 

In Guinea Conakry, FEMNET was able to subgrant the Make Every Woman Count (MEWC) organization. MEWC trained 25 NGO representatives, prompting dialogues and conversations between trained CSOs and MEWC to make various recommendations to the Guinean government, to develop a national report on the Maputo Protocol implementation in Guinea as required by the AU. MEWC is currently working with the Centre for Human Rights in Pretoria, who will facilitate the development of the report. The Women Rights organizations trained on the Maputo Protocol are now working closely in collaboration with the Gender Ministry, to ensure that they implement the recommendations made by CSOs on the roadmap to reporting the Maputo protocol for Guinea. The trained journalists are now reporting and documenting online, through AfricaGuinee and GuineeNews. Guinea has not yet reported on the protocol since its ratification in 2012. With the awareness creation and training on Maputo Protocol in Guinea and the enhanced collaboration and partnership with WROs and The Centre for Human Rights in Pretoria, FEMNET hopes Guinea will be able to accelerate the development of the CSO shadow reporting on Maputo Protocol for Guinea.

Outcome 2: Improved domestication of regional and global womens rights instruments and budgetary allocation to realize SRHR policy commitments by government in the 6 target countries

In accelerating the ending of FGM by 2030, in 2020 FEMNET collaborated with IWHC (International Womens Health Coalition) and other actors to contribute to the omnibus declaration on COVID-19. The resolution was finally passed on the 11th, ahead of the UN General Assembly. Among other recommendations, FEMNET pushed for explicit mention of harmful practices and influenced the language on SRHR, Girls, VAW (Violence Against Women), Health, Vaccine, etc.

In Zambia through the Zambia National Mens Network, men and boys have been capacitated on SRHR and they are now championing change within their communities. FEMNET has also linked them to the regional trained journalists on SRHR and they are now working with the media professionals to create advocacy awareness on SRHR issues affecting men and boys in Zambia. This has also enabled them to work with the media professionals to cover cases of child marriage, teenage pregnancies, defilement of girls and the push for establishment of courts in parts of Zambia for legal redress to sexual violations among others, which directly contributes to the implementation of Maputo protocol through existing national laws and policies. Some of the key achievements for men -to-men work in Zambia has been the men in Rufunsa presenting a petition to the government through the Minister of Gender to establish a magistrate court as there is none. The only Magistrate Court is K160 KM metres away in another town making it difficult for victims of SGBV to receive justice. The Men and boys who have benefitted from FEMNET trainings are now advocates in their communities, and they are speaking out and taking actions against violation of women and girls rights.  In addition, the men who used to be perpetrators have now become community mobilisers reaching out to other men and parents on the implications of Child, Early and Forced Marriage. More local health workers have been mobilised by Zambia National Mens Network (ZNMNGD) through the District Health Office to influence access to SRHR for adolescents girls.

In Tanzania, in working towards increased advocacy to accelerate Tanzanias commitments to FP 2020 commitments and promotion of Family Planning work, FEMNET through her sub grantee Young and Alive Initiative (YAAI) in the United Republic of Tanzania has been able to participate in the Tanzania National Family Planning Working Group (NFP WG) where they have been working in collaboration with other stakeholders and coalitions like Tanzania Youth and Adolescents Reproductive Health (TAYARH) to review the National Family Planning Costed Implementation Plan (NCFP CIP II) and contributing to the drafting of the third upcoming version. Their contributions to the reviews of the NCFP CIP II and participation in the drafting of the 3rd upcoming version will ensure that their key advocacy ASKs on allocation of budget on Youth Friendly Family Planning services are addressed. YAAI has been able to actively push for scaling up of Family Planning uptake among young women as a means of preventing unsafe abortion. They have successfully done this through their close collaborative work with the Department of Reproductive and Child
Health of Ministry of Health and their active engagement in the Family Planning Technical working group. 

Outcome 3: Increased strategic communication incorporating mass media targeting policy makers, opinion shapers and influencers (religious &amp; cultural leaders, media) creating a conducive environment on progressive SRHR policy implementation in the 6 target countries

Following the SRHR and Media training in 2019, the team of 38 journalists and media professionals, who were trained by FEMNET, leveraged on digital platforms and produced different media and knowledge products throughout 2020. Some of the media pieces were used to influence policies at national level. A good example is a radio journalist in Rwanda who popularized the ministerial order legalizing abortion in Rwanda. This generated a lot of discussions over a period of time.

To build on the already existing media coverage around SRHR in Liberia, a journalist designed a gender sensitive program titled SRHR HOUR which will be aired on both radio and television, the program is intended to bring the discourse to the public for their understanding and subsequent decision making. The program starts effective first week in March 2021 and will be aired on Spoon FM Radio/Television.

In Zambia, stories published in 2020 by the journalist shed more light on SRHR, the lived realities and the need for policy shifts for example for girls to access safe and legal abortion as well as the need for more coordinated approach in comprehensive sexuality education programs.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Not applicable</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">No indicator available - only a description of the activity results is published</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <crs-add>
   <other-flags code="2" significance="1"></other-flags>
  </crs-add>
  <sida:contribution contributionid="51030081" xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/contribution#"></sida:contribution>
  <sida:strategies xmlns:sida="http://sida.se/ns/strategies#">
   <sida:strategy code="1061702" currency="SEK" strategy-amount="3700000000" strategy-end-date="2022-12-31" strategy-start-date="2015-01-01">
    <sida:title>Regional SRHR 2015-2022</sida:title>
    <sida:titleSV>Regionalt SRHR 2015-2022</sida:titleSV>
   </sida:strategy>
  </sida:strategies>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
