<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>US-EIN-56-2460366-XM-DAC-7-PPR-29436</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="US-EIN-56-2460366" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict Dynamics International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Political accommodation and reconciliation in Somalia (CDI-SOYDEN-Forum ARC)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict Dynamics International (Conflict Dynamics) leads the implementing consortium in partnership with the Somali Youth Development Network (SOYDEN) and the Forum of Federations (FoF). The program of work described below aims to deliver significant impact towards the following ARC sub-goals: - 1.2 Formal and informal authorities responsible to maintain security perform their tasks more effectively, more accountably and in better coordination, responding to the needs and rights of the population - 1.3 Communities and civil society lead efforts to improved human security independently and in coordination with responsible authorities By contributing to a lessening of conflict at the local level, and supporting governance structures that effectively prevent and mitigate conflict the program of work is also expected, though the creation of an enabling environment, to make a contribution towards other ARC goals, in particular: - 3.1 National and international actors take responsibility for effective and inclusive mechanisms for peacebuilding and prevention of conflict, with an active role for women - 3.2 Government institutions at all levels implement laws and policies and have functioning mechanisms in place for internal and external accountability The program of work comprises two complimentary approaches to lessening of conflict at the local level and supporting governance structures that effectively mitigate conflict: - Program Outcome A focuses on addressing local level human security challenges faced by communities across Somalia as a result of an incomplete reconciliation process by creating and supporting inclusive local level peace architecture. - Program Outcome B focuses on supporting the Federal Government and Federal Member States in reaching consensus on, and beginning to implement, an accommodating distribution of powers as part of the process of creating a federal Somalia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="PPR-29436" ref="US-EIN-56-2460366" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict Dynamics International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Forum of Federations</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-7" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Youth Development Network</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Somali Program</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>infosomali@cdint.org</email>
   <website>http://www.cdint.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">1035 Cambridge Street Suite 10A Cambridge MA 02143 USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="15112" percentage="40" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15130" percentage="30" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15152" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15154" percentage="5" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15185" percentage="5" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <sector code="15220" percentage="10" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-11-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-10-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-01">1480777.42</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-11-29">1480777.42</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29436" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="PPR-29436" ref="US-EIN-56-2460366" type="21">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict Dynamics International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="0">
   <transaction-type code="11"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-03-14">6750000</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-DAC-7-PPR-29436" ref="XM-DAC-7" type="10">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Netherlands Ministry of Foreign Affairs</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org receiver-activity-id="PPR-29436" ref="US-EIN-56-2460366">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict Dynamics International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="3">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA Conflict &amp; Stability</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overarching measures for conflict and stability in Somalia</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.1 Number of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people who directly benefit from the programme activities. The exact definition depends on the local context and the rationale behind the indicator and is to be defined by the grantee(s). &#x2018;Safer/more secure future&#x2019; refers to the perceptions and hopes of beneficiaries concerning their prospects/opportunities with regard to their safety and security. This includes security in the sense of physical safety or security in socio-political terms (e.g.. human rights, freedom of movement and association, participation in civic and political life - including conflict resolution processes) and reflects the extent to which they believe they have a chance to live a life free from fear in the area where they currently live, while also feeling more in control of their lives. &#x2018;Future&#x2019;: The time-frame for this indicator is at minimum the duration of the programme (3-5 years), but will most likely be longer considering benefits of certain programme activities might only be reaped after the programme ends. For example, a person who has received skills-training during years 1-3 may have only gotten a job in the last year of the programme. The benefits of this increase in income and improved social status may only become clear in the eyes of the beneficiary during the following years. Thus, grantees must translate the concept of &#x2018;future&#x2019; according to the period which they anticipate is necessary for the long-term impact of the programme to bear &#x2018;visible&#x2019; results. This indicator is used to gain insight into how the ARC programmes have contributed to the &#x2018;stability&#x2019; of the area where beneficiaries live and can be triangulated with data generated through the related life stories indicators (OA.2 &amp; OA.3) which will be collected by the end of the programme. By &#x2018;stability&#x2019; we specifically mean &#x2018;legitimate stability&#x2019;, which indicates that stability is not a goal in itself. We aim towards the form of stability that arises from social cohesion between population groups, and from citizens&#x2019; acknowledgement of the legitimacy of existing structures and institutions, both formal and informal and their ability to engage with them. Stability of this nature, giving people a sense of security in both physical and socio-political terms, is a precondition for sustainable development. Rationale: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund, we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future. The ARC Fund aims to have a positive influence on beneficiaries&#x2019; future perspective of the opportunities they have regarding their security, safety, human rights, political influence and other socio-political freedoms. The outcome envisaged at overarching level is therefore to ensure that the root cause underlying trends of conflict, instability and irregular migration have been addressed in such a way that programme beneficiaries, as a result, believe they have a likely chance to build a sustainable life in the place where they currently live and become less vulnerable to forces that threaten their existence (i.e. physical insecurity, political instability). This indicator, specifically, concentrates on the conflict and physical and socio-political stability related aspects of addressing root causes. Disaggregated by: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). For countries which officially use a different definition of youth (e.g. South Sudan/Burundi), consortia of grantees can agree to use such a country-specific definition instead. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report they see a safer/more secure future [&#x2026;]. The number is not cumulative. Time schedule for data collection: Data collection for this indicator will be collected at the start of the programme, after two years and at the end of the programme (depending on the duration period of the programme). However, grantees are welcome to measure this indicator on an annual basis if they feel such information is useful to collect more regularly.</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.1 Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report that they see a safer/more secure future for themselves in the area where they currently live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people who directly benefit from the programme activities. The exact definition depends on the local context and the rationale behind the indicator and is to be defined by the grantee(s). &#x2018;Safer/more secure future&#x2019; refers to the perceptions and hopes of beneficiaries concerning their prospects/opportunities with regard to their safety and security. This includes security in the sense of physical safety or security in socio-political terms (e.g.. human rights, freedom of movement and association, participation in civic and political life - including conflict resolution processes) and reflects the extent to which they believe they have a chance to live a life free from fear in the area where they currently live, while also feeling more in control of their lives. &#x2018;Future&#x2019;: The time-frame for this indicator is at minimum the duration of the programme (3-5 years), but will most likely be longer considering benefits of certain programme activities might only be reaped after the programme ends. For example, a person who has received skills-training during years 1-3 may have only gotten a job in the last year of the programme. The benefits of this increase in income and improved social status may only become clear in the eyes of the beneficiary during the following years. Thus, grantees must translate the concept of &#x2018;future&#x2019; according to the period which they anticipate is necessary for the long-term impact of the programme to bear &#x2018;visible&#x2019; results. This indicator is used to gain insight into how the ARC programmes have contributed to the &#x2018;stability&#x2019; of the area where beneficiaries live and can be triangulated with data generated through the related life stories indicators (OA.2 &amp; OA.3) which will be collected by the end of the programme. By &#x2018;stability&#x2019; we specifically mean &#x2018;legitimate stability&#x2019;, which indicates that stability is not a goal in itself. We aim towards the form of stability that arises from social cohesion between population groups, and from citizens&#x2019; acknowledgement of the legitimacy of existing structures and institutions, both formal and informal and their ability to engage with them. Stability of this nature, giving people a sense of security in both physical and socio-political terms, is a precondition for sustainable development. Rationale: In order to understand and learn more about the impact of the ARC Fund, we must measure the extent to which the ARC programmes have had an influence (positive/negative) on beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions and hopes regarding their future. The ARC Fund aims to have a positive influence on beneficiaries&#x2019; future perspective of the opportunities they have regarding their security, safety, human rights, political influence and other socio-political freedoms. The outcome envisaged at overarching level is therefore to ensure that the root cause underlying trends of conflict, instability and irregular migration have been addressed in such a way that programme beneficiaries, as a result, believe they have a likely chance to build a sustainable life in the place where they currently live and become less vulnerable to forces that threaten their existence (i.e. physical insecurity, political instability). This indicator, specifically, concentrates on the conflict and physical and socio-political stability related aspects of addressing root causes. Disaggregated by: - Male/ Female - Youth*/Not youth *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). For countries which officially use a different definition of youth (e.g. South Sudan/Burundi), consortia of grantees can agree to use such a country-specific definition instead. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Pecentage of programme beneficiaries who report they see a safer/more secure future [&#x2026;], in relation to the total number of respondents/beneficiaries. Time schedule for data collection: Data collection for this indicator will be collected at the start of the programme, after two years and at the end of the programme (depending on the duration period of the programme). However, grantees are welcome to measure this indicator on an annual basis if they feel such information is useful to collect more regularly.</narrative>
    </description>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.2 Lifestories of programme beneficiaries who explain whether/how the program has reduced conflict in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="0" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">OA.3 Lifestories of programme beneficiaries who explain whether/how the program has enabled them to better protect, respect and fulfill their rights in the area where they currently live</narrative>
    </title>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LL Outcome A2: Women in targeted District Peace Committees have increased capacity to shape and take a lead in peacemaking and support transformation of gender perspectives of entire District Peace Committees.</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a subset of RA3.SG.2</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.2: Number of women DPC members who feel they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Feel they have the ability&#x2019; refers to perception of the respondent regarding their power or capacity to do or act, in this case, in a manner which serves as a meaningful contribution towards conflict resolution according to programme beneficiaries. &#x2018;Conflict resolution&#x2019; means that a peaceful solution has been found to a disagreement between two or more parties. Rationale: This indicator tells us something about the level of empowerment of a vulnerable group targeted by the programme. The assumption is that the programme will increase the numbers of people who feel that their voice matters, and who feel that their efforts can be considered as a valuable contribution towards conflict resolution. If more people feel this way, the assumption is that more people will actively participate and indeed make a contribution or encourage others to do so. This will increase the inclusiveness of vulnerable groups in the peace process. Disaggregated by: Youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of women DPC members who feel that they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Collection and analysis of women DPC members&#x2019; responses on workshop evaluations Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No data yet. Women DPC members are yet to be trained on gender related topics. As of 28 July 2018, a capacity needs assessment was being conducted to establish priority training needs for women DPC members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.2: Percentage of women DPC members who feel they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Feel they have the ability&#x2019; refers to perception of the respondent regarding their power or capacity to do or act, in this case, in a manner which serves as a meaningful contribution towards conflict resolution according to programme beneficiaries. &#x2018;Conflict resolution&#x2019; means that a peaceful solution has been found to a disagreement between two or more parties. Rationale: This indicator tells us something about the level of empowerment of a vulnerable group targeted by the programme. The assumption is that the programme will increase the numbers of people who feel that their voice matters, and who feel that their efforts can be considered as a valuable contribution towards conflict resolution. If more people feel this way, the assumption is that more people will actively participate and indeed make a contribution or encourage others to do so. This will increase the inclusiveness of vulnerable groups in the peace process. Disaggregated by: Youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of women DPC members who feel that they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution - in relation to the total number of respondents. Data collection method &amp; source: Collection and analysis of women DPC members&#x2019; responses on workshop evaluations Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1 Reduced violence and improved physical security/freedom from fear</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">This long-term outcome falls under ARC result area 1.Human Security and aims to reduce violence and improve physical security / freedom from fear in targeted areas for specific groups of citizens.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.2 (disaggregated) percentage of programme beneficiaries who report they are feeling secure in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are DPC members. Rationale: Result area 1 aims at reducing violence and improving physical security / freedom from fear in targeted areas for specific groups of citizens. The extent to which citizens say they are feeling secure in the area where they live is an indicator for improved freedom from fear. The reduction in violent conflict is not measured by this indicator but by indicator RA1.1. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report they feel secure in the area where they live, in relation to the total number of respondents/beneficiaries. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members Time schedule for data collection: Yearly.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="88" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">105 (88%) of the 120 respondents interviewed reported that they felt secure in the area where they live. They also felt that their families as well as possessions were safe from harm. On the other hand 15 (12%) respondents reported not feeling safe in the areas where they live citing insecurity as&#xA0;a key factor responsible for their fears.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80%"></target>
     <actual value="91">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the 92 respondents interviewed, 84 (91%) reported that they felt safe in the area where they live, felt their families and possessions were safe as compared to 8(9%) who cited not feeling safe in their areas as a result of the threat from Al-Shabaab.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70%"></target>
     <actual value="94">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The respondents were asked if they felt safe, 177 (94%) responded that they felt safe for them selves and property while the remaining 11 (6%) said that they dont feel safe the later citing issues related to clan conflicts and Al-Shabab, during the 2018 data collection 153(92. %) said that they felt secure and that their posessions were also safe. The respondents indicated Al-Shabab and clan conflict as the causes affecting their safety.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="75%"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70%"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80%"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.2 (disaggregated) number of programme beneficiaries who report they are feeling secure in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are DPC members. Rationale: Result area 1 aims at reducing violence and improving physical security / freedom from fear in targeted areas for specific groups of citizens. The extent to which citizens say they are feeling secure in the area where they live is an indicator for improved freedom from fear. The reduction in violent conflict is not measured by this indicator but by indicator RA1.1. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report they feel secure in the area where they live - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members Time schedule for data collection: Yearly.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="105" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">105 (88%) of the 120 respondents interviewed reported that they felt secure in the area where they live. They also felt that their families as well as possessions were safe from harm. On the other hand 15 (12%)respondents reported not feeling safe in the areas where they live citing insecurity as&#xA0;a key factor responsible for their fears.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="84">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the 92 respondents interviewed, 84 reported that they felt safe in the area where they live, felt their families and possessions were safe as compared to 8 who cited not feeling safe in their areas as a result of the threat from AlShabaab.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="177">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The respondents were asked if they felt safe, 177 (94%) responded that they felt safe for them selves and property while the remaining 11 (6%) said that they dont feel safe the later citing issues related to clan conflicts and Al-Shabab, during the 2018 data collection 153(92. %) said that they felt secure and that their posessions were also safe. The respondents indicated Al-Shabab and clan conflict as the causes affecting their safety.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.1 (disaggregated) number of programme beneficiaries who report a reduction in the past year in the level of violent conflict in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are DPC members. &#x2018;In the past year* before&#x2019;. For example, the question will be: &#x201C;Have you experienced a reduction in the amount and/or severity of violent conflicts in this year (2016) compared to last year (2015)?&#x201D; &#x2018;level of violent conflicts&#x2019; refers to the amount and/or the severity of conflicts* in which at least one party uses, to determine the outcome of their conflict, any kind of violent acts against citizens, including sexual violence, and/or other physical security threats, such as landmines. *Conflicts are defined as clashing of opposed interests, such as inter-communal conflicts, a crime, human rights violation, misdemeanour, civil dispute over land, commercial or family interests, personal status, employment, inheritance, etc. Rationale: Result area 1 aims at reducing violence and improving physical security / freedom from fear in targeted areas for specific groups of citizens. The extent to which citizens report a reduction in violent conflict in the area where they live is an indicator for the increase in human security. The improved freedom from fear is not measured by this indicator. This is measured by indicator RA1.2. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report a reduction in the past year - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members Time schedule for data collection: Yearly.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">120 respondents were interviewed to assess the level of violence within their districts. The respondents 20 districts. Of the 120 respondents, 37(31%) reported that there was No Violence, 41 (34%) reported that there was Minimal Violence, 31(26%) reported that the area was Somewhat Violent.&#xA0; 11(9%) people felt that the area was Violent. None (0%) reported that the area was Extremely Violent</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No numerical targets for this indicator set, only percentage</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="68">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">92 respondents were interviewed from 16 districts. 5 (5.5%) reported that there was no violence in their area, 63 (68.5%) reported that there was minimal violence, 21(23%) reported that area was somewhat violent, 2(2%) reported that the area was violent while 1(1%) said that the area was extremely violent The total respondents who reported that there was minimal or no violence was 68.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="126">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the total interviewed 186, 126(68%) responded that there is no violence while 56(30%) said that there was some violence and the rest 4(2%) said that there was a high level of violence. This shows a significant reduction compared to 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.1 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who report a reduction in the past year in the level of violent conflict in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Definitions: &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are DPC members. &#x2018;In the past year* before&#x2019;. For example, the question will be: &#x201C;Have you experienced a reduction in the amount and/or severity of violent conflicts in this year (2016) compared to last year (2015)?&#x201D; &#x2018;level of violent conflicts&#x2019; refers to the amount and/or the severity of conflicts* in which at least one party uses, to determine the outcome of their conflict, any kind of violent acts against citizens, including sexual violence, and/or other physical security threats, such as landmines. *Conflicts are defined as clashing of opposed interests, such as inter-communal conflicts, a crime, human rights violation, misdemeanour, civil dispute over land, commercial or family interests, personal status, employment, inheritance, etc. Rationale: Result area 1 aims at reducing violence and improving physical security / freedom from fear in targeted areas for specific groups of citizens. The extent to which citizens report a reduction in violent conflict in the area where they live is an indicator for the increase in human security. The improved freedom from fear is not measured by this indicator. This is measured by indicator RA1.2. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report a reduction in the past year, in relation to the total number of respondents/beneficiaries. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members Time schedule for data collection: Yearly.</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">120 respondents were interviewed to assess the level of violence within their districts. The respondents 20 districts. Of the 120 respondents, 37(31%) reported that there was No Violence, 41 (34%) reported that there was Minimal Violence, 31(26%) reported that the area was Somewhat Violent.&#xA0; 11(9%) people felt that the area was Violent. None (0%) reported that the area was Extremely Violent</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="74">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">92 respondents were interviewed from 16 districts. 5 (5.5%) reported that there was no violence in their area, 63(68.5%) reported that there was minimal violence, 21(23%) reported that area was somewhat violent, 2(2%) reported that the area was violent while 1(1%) said that the area was extremely violent. The total % of respondents who reported that there was minimal or no violence was 74.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
     <actual value="68">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the total interviewed 186, 126(68%) responded that there is no violence while 56(30%) said that there was some violence and the rest 4(2%) said that there was a high level of violence. This shows a significant reduction compared to 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LL Outcome A3: DPCs improve their ability to work with local authorities in a collaborative manner</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.4: (disaggregated) number of communities and civil society groups that report they have the capacity to influence formal human security authorities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Communities and civil society groups&#x2019; refers to the District Peace Committees. &#x2018;The capacity to influence&#x2019; refers to the perception of respondents, i.e. to what extent they feel they are capable and effective in their efforts towards policy influencing. &#x2018;Formal and informal human security authorities&#x2019; refers to those bodies from the security sector that are targeted through the programme (e.g. the local police and/or a community security mechanisms and/or&#x2026;), NOT the entire security sector. For this programme, they refer to local government. Rationale: One assumption in the theory of change is that when human security authorities respond to citizens&#x2019; needs and rights, they will contribute to the human security situation in the area. Another assumption is that when pressured, informed and/or persuaded by CSOs and communities, human security authorities become more responsive to citizens&#x2019; rights and needs. The programme supports the capacity development of the community and civil society actors to do so. This indicator measures the number and % of actors who report an increase in their capacity to influence formal and informal human security authorities. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of communities and civil society groups which report they have the capacity to influence formal human security authorities - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members and DPC records Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="10" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">84 members of 14 DPC&apos;s interviewed to assess their capacity to influence formal security authorities.10&#xA0;(71%) DPC&apos;s reported that they had the ability to influence formal security authorities while 4 (29%) reported that they did not have the capacity to influence authorities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="25"></target>
     <actual value="118">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">118, 69% 186 members of 17DPCs were interviewed to assess their capacity to influence formal security authorities. 118 (69%) respondents reported that they had the ability to influence formal security authorities 58(31%) stated they did not.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15"></target>
     <actual value="53">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;92 members of the 16 DPCs were interviewed to assess their capacity to influence formal security authorities. 53 of the respondents reported that they had the ability to influence formal security authorities while 39 stated they did not.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="21"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="33"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.4: (disaggregated) percentage of communities and civil society groups that report they have the capacity to influence formal human security authorities</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Communities and civil society groups&#x2019; refers to the District Peace Committees. &#x2018;The capacity to influence&#x2019; refers to the perception of respondents, i.e. to what extent they feel they are capable and effective in their efforts towards policy influencing. &#x2018;Formal and informal human security authorities&#x2019; refers to those bodies from the security sector that are targeted through the programme (e.g. the local police and/or a community security mechanisms and/or&#x2026;), NOT the entire security sector. For this programme, they refer to local government. Rationale: One assumption in the theory of change is that when human security authorities respond to citizens&#x2019; needs and rights, they will contribute to the human security situation in the area. Another assumption is that when pressured, informed and/or persuaded by CSOs and communities, human security authorities become more responsive to citizens&#x2019; rights and needs. The programme supports the capacity development of the community and civil society actors to do so. This indicator measures the number and % of actors who report an increase in their capacity to influence formal and informal human security authorities. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of communities and civil society groups which report they have the capacity to influence formal human security authorities, in relation to the total number of respondents. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members and DPC records Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="71" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">84 members of 14 DPC&apos;s interviewed to assess their capacity to influence formal security authorities.10&#xA0;(71%) DPC&apos;s reported that they had the ability to influence formal security authorities while 4 (29%) reported that they did not have the capacity to influence authorities</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="65"></target>
     <actual value="69">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">118, 69% 186 members of 17DPCs were interviewed to assess their capacity to influence formal security authorities. 118 (69%) respondents reported that they had the ability to influence formal security authorities 58(31%) stated they did not.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="58">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;92 members of the 16 DPCs were interviewed to assess their capacity to influence formal security authorities. 53(58%) of the respondents reported that they had the ability to influence formal security authorities while 39(42%) stated they did not.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3 Increased presence of mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict and of a capable and accountable government</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.3 (disaggregated) number of programme beneficiaries who feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Rationale: Result area 3 aims at increasing the presence of mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict and of a capable and accountable government. The extent to which beneficiaries &#x2018;feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict&#x2019; is an indication of the presence of a capable and efficient government that is establishing mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth/non-youth, clan, district, state, gov&apos;t level, political class *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping with decision makers and wider political thought leaders Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Six out of six (100%) programme beneficiaries interviewed, including two Ministers and four senior advisors at both federal and state levels, reported that DoP/IGR arrangements are crucial for helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict in the future. These DoP/IGR arrangements are not yet in place. Additional data (including from wider political influencers) will be added once more interviews take place.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4, 100% Of programme beneficiaries interviewed, 2 of 4 agreed and 1 of 4 strongly agreed with the statement that governance arrangements are promoting the prevention of conflict and reconciliation of different interests</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="8">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">8, Of programme beneficiaries interviewed, 4 of 8 agreed and 4 of 8 strongly agreed with the statement that governance arrangements are promoting the prevention of conflict and reconciliation of different interests</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.3 (disaggregated) % of programme beneficiaries who feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Rationale: Result area 3 aims at increasing the presence of mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict and of a capable and accountable government. The extent to which beneficiaries &#x2018;feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict&#x2019; is an indication of the presence of a capable and efficient government that is establishing mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth/non-youth, clan, district, state, gov&apos;t level, political class *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report they feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict, in relation to the total number of respondents/beneficiaries. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping with decision makers and wider political thought leaders Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Six out of six (100%) programme beneficiaries interviewed, including two Ministers and four senior advisors at both federal and state levels, reported that DoP/IGR arrangements are crucial for helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict in the future. These DoP/IGR arrangements are not yet in place. Additional data (including from wider political influencers) will be added once more interviews take place.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="100">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">8, 100% Of programme beneficiaries interviewed, 4 of 8 agreed and 4 of 8 strongly agreed with the statement that governance arrangements are promoting the prevention of conflict and reconciliation of different interests</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA 3.2Percentage (%) of programme beneficiaries who report they feel secure in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Rationale: Result area 3 aims at increasing the presence of mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict and of a capable and accountable government. The extent to which beneficiaries &#x2018;feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict&#x2019; is an indication of the presence of a capable and efficient government that is establishing mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth/non-youth, clan, district, state, gov&apos;t level, political class *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping with decision makers and wider political thought leaders Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA.3.1 Number (Disagregated) of programme beneficiaries who report a reduction in the past year in the level of violent conflicts in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Rationale: Result area 3 aims at increasing the presence of mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict and of a capable and accountable government. The extent to which beneficiaries &#x2018;feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict&#x2019; is an indication of the presence of a capable and efficient government that is establishing mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth/non-youth, clan, district, state, gov&apos;t level, political class *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping with decision makers and wider political thought leaders Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA 3.2 Number of programme beneficiaries who report they feel secure in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Rationale: Result area 3 aims at increasing the presence of mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict and of a capable and accountable government. The extent to which beneficiaries &#x2018;feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict&#x2019; is an indication of the presence of a capable and efficient government that is establishing mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth/non-youth, clan, district, state, gov&apos;t level, political class *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping with decision makers and wider political thought leaders Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA.3.1 Percentage (%) of programme beneficiaries who report a reduction in the past year in the level of violent conflicts in the area where they live</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Rationale: Result area 3 aims at increasing the presence of mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict and of a capable and accountable government. The extent to which beneficiaries &#x2018;feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict&#x2019; is an indication of the presence of a capable and efficient government that is establishing mechanisms to peacefully resolve conflict. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth/non-youth, clan, district, state, gov&apos;t level, political class *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who feel that DOP/IGR arrangements are helping to prevent and/or resolve conflict - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping with decision makers and wider political thought leaders Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A3.1: District Peace Committees share information on their roles with local government</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A3.1(1): Number of local/state government actors who receive information on the role of district peace committees</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: District, level of government Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of local/state government actors who receive information on the role of DPCs - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of data from meeting records of DPCs Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6"></target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">10 DPCs from Banadir interact with their respective local administrations on a monthly basis. Between March and December 2017, DPC members in Mogadishu have met and shared information with: -Bondheere District Commissioner -Banadir Governor -Banadir Deputy Governor -Regional Health director - Officer at the Chief Justice&apos;s office -Sec General BRA -Security Director BRA -Police chief</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A3.2: Publications analyzing the work of district peace committees have been developed and disseminated for wider stakeholder use</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A3.2(1) Number of publications disseminated to various stakeholders</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: District/other location Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of publications disseminated - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of data from publications log Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="200"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="400"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.2: Training manuals on gender related topics have been developed and disseminated in a user friendly manner</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.2(1): Number of training manuals disseminated</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: District/other location Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of training manuals disseminated - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of data from publications log Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">The training manuals are planned to be developed in the year 2020</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training Manuals have not been developed yet. Currently, assessments have been conducted in Banadir (16 districts), Jubbaland (2 districts), Southwest (5 districts) and Hirshabelle (1 district). Findings from the assessment will inform the development of a gender training manual tailored to the needs of the women DPC members. Male members of the DPCs will benefit from the training that will be conducted once the manual is in place. Through assessments conducted in 2018 , it was established that women focus mostly on the private sphere solving issues of gender based violence and not on issues considered to be male domains. .</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1.2: Senior office holders, advisors/ influencers have participated in facilitated dialogues and developed options for the DOP and IGR</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1.2(1): Number of senior decision makers, advisors/influencers who participate in facilitated dialogues</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, government level, position, clan, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of dialogue attendees - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Attendee lists from workshop/dialogue reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="13">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed within the first quarter. 13 attendees were senior decision makers/advisors/influencers, of which 3 were women and 10 were men. There were also 18 political thought leaders at the workshop, of which 5 were women and 13 were men. Q2 Update: Discussions with Ministries of Health and of Constitutional Affairs have occurred re future workshops</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1.1: Participants are trained to develop appropriate options for DOP and supportive IGR systems</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1.1(1) Number of senior decision makers, advisors/influencers who report that the trainings have provided them with a deeper knowledge of distribution of powers and intergovernmental relations</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, government level, position, clan, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of training attendees who report the trainings have provided them with a deeper knowledge of DOP/IGR - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop/training evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop/training reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="29">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the interviewed 32 participants, 29 responded that the trainings provided them with a deeper knowledge of distribution of powers and intergovernmental relations while 3 said that the trainings did not help them understand DOP/IGR.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed within the first quarter. 18 out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot; with 5 being the most positive.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1.1(1) Percentage of senior decision makers, advisors/influencers who report that the trainings have provided them with a deeper knowledge of distribution of powers and intergovernmental relations</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, government level, position, clan, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of training attendees who report the trainings have provided them with a deeper knowledge of DOP/IGR - in relation to the total number of attendees, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop/training evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop/training reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="91">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the interviewed 32 participants, 29 (91%) responded that the trainings provided them with a deeper knowledge of distribution of powers and intergovernmental relations while 3 (9%) said that the trainings did not help them understand DOP/IGR.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="95">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed within the first quarter. 18 out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot; with 5 being the most positive. Q2 update: Research on gender &amp; federalism started</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3.2: Political decision makers have received technical advice on strengthening legal and administrative systems for effective management of IGR / DOP structures</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3.2(1) Number of decison makers that receive advice on effective legal / administrative systems for management of IGR/DOP structures</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, government level, position, clan, region. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of senior decision makers that receive advice on effective legal/administrative systems for management of DOP/IGR structures - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Meeting records, workshop reports, supplemented by responses to workshop evaluations Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3.1: Political decision makers have received technical advice for effective establishment of IGR / DOP structures</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3.1(1) Number of decision makers that receive advice on establishment of IGR/DOP structures</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, government level, position, clan, region. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of senior decision makers that receive advice on establishment of DOP/IGR structures - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Meeting records, workshop reports, supplemented by responses to workshop evaluations Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Q2: But various exchanges with Minister of Constitutional Affairs including advice on how to make his consultations more accommodating. Offer for support on federal elements of his work. Also several discussions with DG of the Ministry. July: Met with Ministry of Health team, who expressed interest in further discussions and discussed practical challenges to service delivery due to lack of clarity between roles of FGS and states. August: Met with President Xaaf of Galmudug, discussed inter-state challenges especially with Puntland over Galkayo and internal issues with ASWJ &#x2013; Explained political accommodation approach and how it could be useful. He expressed interest in learning more about IGR issues.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1.3: Senior office holders and advisors/ influencers are supported by the Consortium to bring options to relevant bodies and leaders</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1.3(1): Number of senior decision makers, advisors/influencers supported</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, government level, position, clan, region. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of senior decision makers, advisors/influencers supported - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Meeting records/Outcome Mapping. Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">While the programme contributed to increasing beneficiaries&apos; knowledge and understanding of DOP/IGR, there was no progress on options being taken up in formal dialogue processes because: 1) The federal government was still working out its negotiations with the states and also what role the national leaders&apos; forum (NLF), now renamed the National Security Council (NSC) would take; and 2) Within the states, they were still agreeing their strategy for engaging with the federal government. There was also a false start around the Ministry of Constitution&apos;s role because they did not secure sufficient buy-in initially so had to spend significant time to build relationships. By 2018, these appear to be on a much more on a cooperative footing and likely to progress. The Consortium was cognizant of continuing to try to build relationships and prepare groups at this time, but also did not want to force an issue when the time was not ripe, especially because of DNH considerations.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.2: DPC members have been trained on DOP and IGR</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.2(1): Number of DPC participants who report that the trainings improved their knowledge on DOP and IGR</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, stakeholder type, age, clan, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of training attendees who report the trainings improved their knowledge of DOP/IGR - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop/training evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop/training reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="28"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Training on DoP and IGR for DPCs are planed to be conducted this year depending on the situation of the COVID19</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="28"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="28"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="28"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="28"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.2(1): Percentage of DPC participants who report that the trainings improved their knowledge on DOP and IGR</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, stakeholder type, age, clan, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of training attendees who report the trainings improved their knowledge of DOP/IGR - in relation to the total number of attendees, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop/training evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop/training reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.3: All District Peace Committees are aware of the concept of gender sensitivity and how to use the tools developed under A2.2</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.3(1): Number of peace committee members trained that report an increase in knowledge on gender sensitivity</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of workshop attendees who report an increase in knowledge on gender sensitivity - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="47"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.3(1): Percentage of peace committee members trained that report an increase in knowledge on gender sensitivity</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of workshop attendees who report an increase in knowledge on gender sensitivity - in relation to the total number of attendees, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.2: District peace committee members have developed relevant skills in relation to&#xA0;conflict resolution/management and reconciliation</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.2(1): Number of peace committee members trained who report the workshops increased their knowledge on conflict resolution/ management and reconciliation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of workshop attendees who report the workshops increased their knowledge on [...] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Percentage of workshop attendees who report the workshops increased their knowledge on [...] - in relation to the total number of attendees, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on DPC members&apos; workshop evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">266 members (of which 98 were women) from 12 districts - Yaqshid, Shangani, Boondheere, Hamarweyne, Howlwadhag, Hodan, Dayniile, Dharkenley, Karaan, Heliwa, Wadajir, and Wartanabada - were trained on conflict prevention, mgmt, resolution / peace diaries. Dharkenley DPC members reported they used skills learned in the trainings to ease tensions between a land owner and community members. Increased information sharing across DPCs has also been noted, including between Waberi and Hamarjajab DPCs to resolve a conflict.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="39">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">39 of the total 46 participants in Abdiaziz and Waberi reported that the workshop increased their knowledge and confidence to conflict resolution</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.2(1): Percentage of peace committee members trained who report the workshops increased their knowledge on conflict resolution/ management and reconciliation</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of workshop attendees who report the workshops increased their knowledge on [...] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Percentage of workshop attendees who report the workshops increased their knowledge on [...] - in relation to the total number of attendees, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on DPC members&apos; workshop evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="85">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">85% of respondents in the Waberi and Abdiaziz training told that the training increased their knowledge and confidence to conflict resolution</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No data yet, however peace diaries printed &amp; training started. 108 members from 4 districts - Yaqshid, Shangani, Boondheere, and Hamarweyne - trained on conflict prevention, mgmt, resolution / peace diaries.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.3: Materials on DOP and IGR developed and disseminated for wider stakeholder use, including by local-level actors</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.3(1): Number of materials on DOP and IGR disseminated</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Material type and topic, district/region. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of materials on DOP/IGR disseminated - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of data from publications log. Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3.3: The implementation of select IGR / DOP arrangements have been assessed and recommendation(s) made for their improvement</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3.3(1): Number of recommendations made based on reviews of the implementation of DOP / IGR arrangements</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Type of arrangement, whether recommendations made. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of recommendations made on IGR / DOP arrangements - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of consortium records. Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3.3(1): Number of reviews of the implementation of DOP / IGR arrangements</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Type of arrangement, whether recommendations made. Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of reviews of the implementation of IGR / DOP arrangements - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of consortium records. Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome B: The Federal Government of Somalia and Federal Member States have increased consensus around, and have begun to implement, practical and politically accommodating distribution of powers (DOP) and supporting intergovernmental relations (IGR) that meet the unique needs of Somalia: at federal to state, within state, and state-state levels, thereby reducing Somali citizens&#x2019; vulnerability to conflict.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B(3): Number of programme beneficiaries who report increased consensus between the federal government and federal member states around DoP and/or IGR issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report increased consensus [&#x2026;] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop evaluations and Outcome Mapping, supplemented by evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Six out of six (100%) programme beneficiaries interviewed, including two Ministers and four senior advisors at both federal and state levels, reported increased consensus on further engagement between the federal government and federal member states around DoP and/or IGR issues. Five out of six respondents reported complete consensus on further engagement, while one respondent reported emerging consensus and the need for more dialogue. As there has been hardly any dialogue around the DoP/IGR issues themselves, respondents focused on consensus on engagement on DoP/IGR instead of the issues themselves. While there was unanimous consensus around the need for further dialogue, there is little understanding of how DoP and IGR arrangements would look like.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 of 8, of respondents, felt there was consensus around DOP (Distribution of Powers). Significantly though 5 of 8, of respondents, felt that there was an emerging consensus around DOP. This data was collected in early 2018 so it might be slightly more positive than had it been collected in December 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="33">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="6">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="36">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshop"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="7">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="39">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="42">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B(3): Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report increased consensus between the federal government and federal member states around DoP and/or IGR issues</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers and political thought leaders. Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report increased consensus [&#x2026;] - in relation to the total number of respondents. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop evaluations and Outcome Mapping, supplemented by evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Six out of six (100%) programme beneficiaries interviewed, including two Ministers and four senior advisors at both federal and state levels, reported increased consensus on further engagement between the federal government and federal member states around DoP and/or IGR issues. Five out of six respondents reported complete consensus on further engagement, while one respondent reported emerging consensus and the need for more dialogue. As there has been hardly any dialogue around the DoP/IGR issues themselves, respondents focused on consensus on engagement on DoP/IGR instead of the issues themselves. While there was unanimous consensus around the need for further dialogue, there is little understanding of how DoP and IGR arrangements would look like.</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="37.5">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">3 of 8, or 37.5% of respondents, felt there was consensus around DOP (Distribution of Powers). Significantly though 5 of 8, or 62.5% of respondents, felt that there was an emerging consensus around DOP. This data was collected in early 2018 so it might be slightly more positive than had it been collected in December 2017</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-31"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="65">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="65">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Outcome Mapping"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70">
      <dimension name="Data source" value="Workshops"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.5: Number of options developed in workshops for politically accommodating DOP/IGR that would increase opportunities for decision making by citizens, including vulnerable groups, that are taken up for consideration by a formal government body</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): Modified from original indicator: &#x201C;(disaggregated) total number of laws and policies - (#) drafted, (#) reviewed or (#) adopted - that empower or enhance decision-making by citizens, including vulnerable groups, that were advocated for within the programme.&#x201D; Where &apos;options taken up for consideration by a formal government body&apos; are considered draft policies &#x2018;Increase decision-making&#x2019; refers to giving power or authority to citizen groups. &#x2018;Vulnerable groups&#x2019; is to be defined by the grantee and depends on the programme context. Rationale: The assumption is that inclusive policies and laws that empower or enhance decision-making by citizens, including men, women and vulnerable groups, will enhance their voice in the type of decisions taken by authorities that have an impact on their lives. It is assumed that an increased voice will enhance a shift towards policies, laws and practices in favour of citizens&#x2019; rights and local needs, contributing to more sustainable peace and the prevention of the (re)occurrence of conflict. The indicator counts the number of options that are in favour of decision-making by citizens. Disaggregated by: DOP/IGR topic, drafted/reviewed/adopted Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Total number of different options developed in workshops that are taken up for consideration by a formal body - (#) drafted, (#) reviewed or (#) adopted - [...], compared to the start of the programme. The number is not cumulative. *It is important to ensure laws/policies are not counted double, i.e. a policy drafted in year 1 that has been adopted in year 2 must not be counted twice. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop reports for options developed and Outcome Mapping to track which options are taken up by a formal body. Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.6: Number of options developed in workshops for politically accommodating DOP/IGR that are representative of the diversity within the community, that are taken up for consideration by a formal government body</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): Modified from original indicator: &#x201C;(disaggregated) total number of laws and policies - (#) drafted, (#) reviewed or (#) adopted - which are now more representative for the diversity within the community, that were advocated for within the programme.&#x201D; Where &apos;options taken up for consideration by a formal government body&apos; are considered draft policies &#x2018;representative for the diversity within the community&#x2019; means that options take into account the diverse characteristics of the individuals living in the community, e.g. origin, ethnicity, religion, socioeconomic stratum, sexual orientation, etc. Rationale: The assumption is that laws and policies that take the diversity of communities into consideration, hence representing the diverse range of local needs, will contribute to a more sustainable peace and helps to prevent the (re)occurrence of conflict. Disaggregated by: DOP/IGR topic, drafted/reviewed/adopted Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Total number of different options developed in workshops that are taken up for consideration by a formal body - (#) drafted, (#) reviewed or (#) adopted - [...], compared to the start of the programme. The number is not cumulative. *It is important to ensure laws/policies are not counted double, i.e. a policy drafted in year 1 that has been adopted in year 2 must not be counted twice. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop reports for options developed and Outcome Mapping to track which options are taken up by a formal body. Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">While the programme contributed to increasing beneficiaries&apos; knowledge and understanding of DOP/IGR, there was no progress on options being taken up in formal dialogue processes because: 1) The federal govt was still working out its negotiations with the states and also what role the national leaders&apos; forum (NLF), now renamed the National Security Council (NSC) would take; and 2) Within the states, they were still agreeing their strategy for engaging with the federal government. There was also a false start around the Ministry of Constitution&apos;s role because they did not secure sufficient buy-in initially so had to spend significant time to build relationships. By 2018, these appear to be on a much more on a cooperative footing and likely to progress. The Consortium was cognizant of continuing to try to build relationships and prepare groups at this time, but also did not want to force an issue when the time was not ripe, especially because of DNH considerations. With thought leaders, work was done on a range of options on DOP that illuminated possible ways of solving issues and other challenges, which will help inform our work with political decision makers in 2018.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.1: Women members of the District Peace Committees learn and gain experience from one another.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.1(2): Number of women who report the workshops increased their knowledge on ways to confront challenges they face within the DPCs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of [women] attendees who report the workshops increased their knowledge on [...] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No workshops on this yet, but we have contracted a gender specialist at CDI, developed a detailed action plan for the stream of work with women, and are actively recruiting a TOR for a Somali gender consultant</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="106">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">a total 106 of reported that the workshops increased their knowledge on ways to confront challenges they face within the DPCs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A2.1(2): Percentage of women who report the workshops increased their knowledge on ways to confront challenges they face within the DPCs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaggregated by: Youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of [women] attendees who report the workshops increased their knowledge on [...] - in relation to the total number of attendees, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="86">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">86% of the workshop participants reported that the workshops increased their knowledge on ways to confront challenges they face within the DPCs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No workshops on this yet, but we have contracted a gender specialist at CDI, developed a detailed action plan for the stream of work with women, and are actively recruiting a TOR for a Somali gender consultant</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.3: (disaggregated) number of female Programme beneficiaries who actively participate in and/or lead local peace processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Female programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refers to the women to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are women DPC members. &#x2018;Who participate&#x2019; refers to the women who are taking part in activities related to promoting peace and reducing local divides, mainly participating in District Peace Committees. &#x2018;Local peace processes&#x2019; refers to processes that aim to promote peace and reduce local divides. As defined by the program, they are District Peace Committee activities. Rationale: The assumption is that women&#x2019;s participation, e.g. an active role for women in and/or leadership of peace processes will ensure a more fair representation in local dialogue and therefore contribute to sustainable peace building. This indicator gives an idea of the (direct) effects of encouraging participation of women in conflict resolution mechanisms that is done in different forms in programmes. Disaggregated by: Youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of female programme beneficiaries who participate [...] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of numbers of DPC members, from DPC records and consortium activity reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10"></target>
     <actual value="111">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">111-This is counting all women DPC members in Bardaale, ElBerde, Yaqshid, Shangani, Boondheere, Hamarweyne, Howlwadhag, Hodan, Dayniile, Dharkenley, Karaan, Heliwa, Wadajir, and Wartanabada districts. The majority women members have been involved in dealing with domestic violence cases and engaging in community sensitization and awareness creation forums at the village level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12"></target>
     <actual value="123">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is the total number of women who participated in the experience sharing workshop for women in Benadir region participated by Women DPC members, Women parliamentarians and others from the civil society</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="13"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="14"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.3: (disaggregated) percentage of female programme beneficiaries who actively participate in and/or lead local peace processes</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Female programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refers to the women to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are women DPC members. &#x2018;Who participate&#x2019; refers to the women who are taking part in activities related to promoting peace and reducing local divides, mainly participating in District Peace Committees. &#x2018;Local peace processes&#x2019; refers to processes that aim to promote peace and reduce local divides. As defined by the program, they are District Peace Committee activities. Rationale: The assumption is that women&#x2019;s participation, e.g. an active role for women in and/or leadership of peace processes will ensure a more fair representation in local dialogue and therefore contribute to sustainable peace building. This indicator gives an idea of the (direct) effects of encouraging participation of women in conflict resolution mechanisms that is done in different forms in programmes. Disaggregated by: Youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of female programme beneficiaries who participate [...] - in relation to the total number of beneficiaries. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of numbers of DPC members, from DPC records and consortium activity reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40"></target>
     <actual value="53">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">111, 53% This is counting all women DPC members in Bardaale, ElBerde, Yaqshid, Shangani, Boondheere, Hamarweyne, Howlwadhag, Hodan, Dayniile, Dharkenley, Karaan, Heliwa, Wadajir, and Wartanabada districts. The majority women members have been involved in dealing with domestic violence cases and engaging in community sensitization and awareness creation forums at the village level.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome A: Local communities in targeted districts in Jubbaland, South West, Galmudug, Hiraan / Middle Shebelle and Banadir, through DPCs, help to contribute to: enhanced human security, reconciliation, building a culture of peace, gender equity, and improved confidence between communities and local government and the federal system.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.3: Percentage of programme beneficiaries in targeted districts who report trust and cooperation within the community. (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are DPC members. Rationale: One important step towards improving human security is increasing trust, understanding, tolerance and cooperation between groups with diverse backgrounds within the community and civil society. The assumption is that increased social cohesion as a result of trust-building and cooperation will contribute to improved human security. This indicator measures to what extent beneficiaries experience trust and cooperation within the community. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of DPC members who report trust and cooperation within the community, in relation to the total number of respondents. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop evaluations and phone survey of DPC members Schedule of data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="37" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value above shows VHT and HT combined. Very high trust: 13% High trust: 24% 120 respondents representing 20 districts were interviewed to assess the level of&#xA0;trust and cooperation&#xA0;within their districts. Of the respondents, 1 (1%) reported that there was No Trust, within the community,&#xA0;13 (11%) reported that there was a Low Level of&#xA0;trust within the community, 61 (51%) respondents felt that there was Trust within the community, 29 (24%) reported that there was a High Level of trust within the community while 16 (13%) reported that there was a Very High level of trust amongst themselves</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="24">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="49">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">92 respondents were interviewed to assess the level of trust and cooperation within the community. 2 (2%) reported that there was no trust within the community, 7(8%) reported that there was low level of trust, 25(27%) acknowledged that there was trust within the community, 45(49%) felt that there was a high level of trust while 13(14%) reported a very high level of trust within the community</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="13">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="14">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">92 respondents were interviewed to assess the level of trust and cooperation within the community. 2 (2%) reported that there was no trust within the community, 7(8%) reported that there was low level of trust, 25(27%) acknowledged that there was trust within the community, 45(49%) felt that there was a high level of trust while 13(14%) reported a very high level of trust within the community</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="17">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="85">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">VHT: 21, 11% HT: 60, 31% 186 respondents from 17 districts were interviewed to assess the level of trust and cooperation within the community. 1(0.5%) reported No Trust 5(5%) reported a low level of trust 99(54%) reported trust within the community 60 (31%) reported a high level of trust 21(11%) reported a very high level of trust</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="26">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="29">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="32">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="28">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="High"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="19">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="21">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Level of trust" value="Very high"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.3: Number of programme beneficiaries in targeted districts who report trust and cooperation within the community. (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are DPC members. Rationale: One important step towards improving human security is increasing trust, understanding, tolerance and cooperation between groups with diverse backgrounds within the community and civil society. The assumption is that increased social cohesion as a result of trust-building and cooperation will contribute to improved human security. This indicator measures to what extent beneficiaries experience trust and cooperation within the community. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of DPC members who report trust and cooperation within the community - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop evaluations and phone survey of DPC members Schedule of data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="45" year="2017">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">Value above shows VHT and HT combined. Very high trust: 16 High trust: 29 120 respondents representing 20 districts were interviewed to assess the level of&#xA0;trust and cooperation&#xA0;within their districts. Of the respondents, 1 (1%) reported that there was No Trust, within the community,&#xA0;13 (11%) reported that there was a Low Level of&#xA0;trust within the community, 61 (51%) respondents felt that there was Trust within the community, 29 (24%) reported that there was a High Level of trust within the community while 16 (13%) reported that there was a Very High level of trust amongst themselves</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="58">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">92 respondents were interviewed to assess the level of trust and cooperation within the community. 2 (2%) reported that there was no trust within the community, 7(8%) reported that there was low level of trust, 25(27%) acknowledged that there was trust within the community, 45(49%) felt that there was a high level of trust while 13(14%) reported a very high level of trust within the community. The above figure in the actual is the combination of High and Very high trust.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <actual value="159">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">VHT: 21, 11% HT: 60, 31% 186 respondents from 17 districts were interviewed to assess the level of trust and cooperation within the community. 1(0.5%) reported No Trust 5(5%) reported a low level of trust 99(54%) reported trust within the community 60 (31%) reported a high level of trust 21(11%) reported a very high level of trust</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.2: Number of conflicts that are addressed and resolved by community structures that are supported by the programme (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Conflicts&#x2019; refers to clashing of opposed interests, such as a crime, human rights violation, misdemeanour, civil dispute over land, commercial or family interests, personal status, employment, inheritance, etc. &#x2018;Addressed and resolved&#x2019; refers to a situation in which a community structure has dealt with or discussed a conflict* and has subsequently settled that conflict according to the parties involved in the conflict. &#x2018;Community structures&#x2019; refers to the District Peace Committees Rationale: The number of conflicts that are addressed and resolved is an indication of the ability of communities and civil society with diverse backgrounds to apply mechanisms for managing and preventing conflicts and promoting cooperation. Disaggregated by: Issue of conflict, status of case, within or between districts Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of unique conflicts that are both addressed and resolved by DPCs that received training on peace diaries - per calendar year. This number is not cumulative. Percentage (%) of conflicts that are both addressed and resolved by DPCs - compared to the total number of conflicts addressed by DPCs that received training on peace diaries. Data collection method &amp; source: Collection of information from DPC records (mainly peace diaries) and regular communication between SOYDEN and DPCs Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This data is still being gathered, as Peace Diary training was ongoing in Fall 2017. However, 99 respondents (97%) reported that DPCs were effectively resolving conflict.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="213"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.2: Percentage of conflicts that are addressed and resolved by community structures that are supported by the program (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Conflicts&#x2019; refers to clashing of opposed interests, such as a crime, human rights violation, misdemeanour, civil dispute over land, commercial or family interests, personal status, employment, inheritance, etc. &#x2018;Addressed and resolved&#x2019; refers to a situation in which a community structure has dealt with or discussed a conflict* and has subsequently settled that conflict according to the parties involved in the conflict. &#x2018;Community structures&#x2019; refers to the District Peace Committees Rationale: The number of conflicts that are addressed and resolved is an indication of the ability of communities and civil society with diverse backgrounds to apply mechanisms for managing and preventing conflicts and promoting cooperation. Disaggregated by: Issue of conflict, status of case, within or between districts Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of conflicts that are both addressed and resolved by DPCs - compared to the total number of conflicts addressed by DPCs that received training on peace diaries. Data collection method &amp; source: Collection of information from DPC records (mainly peace diaries) and regular communication between SOYDEN and DPCs Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="76"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.1 Number of programme beneficiaries who report that informal human security authorities targeted through the programme are responsive to the needs and rights of the population (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Informal human security authorities&#x2019; refers to District Peace Committees &#x2018;Responsive to the needs and rights&#x2019; for this programme means effectively resolving conflicts. More broadly, it refers to the extent to which programme beneficiaries feel that security authorities take action to address needs and rights of the population, especially towards the disadvantaged / underprivileged groups. The actions may include: invite programme beneficiaries to participate in (consultation) meetings, putting specific rights and needs on the (political) agenda, develop new policies or laws, take policy measures, adjust existing policies or laws, start implementing laws and policies, etc. [See also Data collection method]. &#x2018;The population&#x2019; refers to the group of programme beneficiaries as defined by the grantee. Rationale: The assumption in the theory of change is that when formal and informal human security authorities adequately respond to citizens&#x2019; needs and rights &#x2013; &#x2018;adequately&#x2019; in the eyes of key informants - , they will positively contribute to the human security situation in the area. Increasing the responsiveness of these authorities is an important element of the programme which has to be monitored by this indicator. The indicator measures the development of responsiveness of the authorities. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who report that targeted (in)formal human security authorities are responsive - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative, i.e. you do not add this year&#x2019;s number to last year&#x2019;s number when you report. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="96">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;DPC: 96, 94% Local Govt: 6, 100% Respondents reported that DPCs were actively supporting reconciliation and responsive local governance structures. According to interviewees, the Peace Committees have been able to prevent the escalation of conflicts, are respected, and the communities have seen the benefits of peace and co-existence in the society. Their intervention has resulted in increased trust, community interaction, and mutual respect. Six out of six district administrators (including district commissioners, deputy district commissioners, and a deputy governor) reported that DPCs were resolving conflict and restoring trust between communities. This change has been attributed to the district administrators having more knowledge on work being done by the committees as well as an increase in interactions. District administrators have participated in joint trainings with DPCs and have held joint monthly meetings. Due to difficulty in accessing community members, it was not possible to hold focus groups with community members for year 1, however it is planned for year 2. &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="10">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="186">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="11">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="75">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">DPC members</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="85">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA1.SG.1 Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report that informal human security authorities targeted through the programme are responsive to the needs and rights of the population (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Informal human security authorities&#x2019; refers to District Peace Committees &#x2018;Responsive to the needs and rights&#x2019; for this programme means effectively resolving conflicts. More broadly, it refers to the extent to which programme beneficiaries feel that security authorities take action to address needs and rights of the population, especially towards the disadvantaged / underprivileged groups. The actions may include: invite programme beneficiaries to participate in (consultation) meetings, putting specific rights and needs on the (political) agenda, develop new policies or laws, take policy measures, adjust existing policies or laws, start implementing laws and policies, etc. [See also Data collection method]. &#x2018;The population&#x2019; refers to the group of programme beneficiaries as defined by the grantee. Rationale: The assumption in the theory of change is that when formal and informal human security authorities adequately respond to citizens&#x2019; needs and rights &#x2013; &#x2018;adequately&#x2019; in the eyes of key informants - , they will positively contribute to the human security situation in the area. Increasing the responsiveness of these authorities is an important element of the programme which has to be monitored by this indicator. The indicator measures the development of responsiveness of the authorities. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who report that targeted (in)formal human security authorities are responsive in relation to the total number of respondents/beneficiaries. Data collection method &amp; source: Phone survey of DPC members Time schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="94">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">DPC: 96, 94% Comm: 0, 0% Local Govt: 6, 100% Respondents reported that DPCs were actively supporting reconciliation and responsive local governance structures. According to interviewees, the Peace Committees have been able to prevent the escalation of conflicts, are respected, and the communities have seen the benefits of peace and co-existence in the society. Their intervention has resulted in increased trust, community interaction, and mutual respect. Six out of six district administrators (including district commissioners, deputy district commissioners, and a deputy governor) reported that DPCs were resolving conflict and restoring trust between communities. This change has been attributed to the district administrators having more knowledge on work being done by the committees as well as an increase in interactions. District administrators have participated in joint trainings with DPCs and have held joint monthly meetings. Due to difficulty in accessing community members, it was not possible to hold focus groups with community members for year 1, however it is planned for year 2. &quot;</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="40">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="45">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="Community Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="75">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="97%">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="85">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="90">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="N/A">
      <dimension name="Beneficiary type" value="DPC Members"></dimension>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.1: Different influential groups, including women, have participated in facilitated dialogue and understand their own and others&apos; perspectives on DOP and IGR options</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.1(1): Number of political thought leader participants who report that the dialogues have increased their understanding of perspectives on DOP and IGR</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Political thought leader&#x2019; refers to influential and politically active individuals who are not directly connected to people in government, such as members of civil society, women&#x2019;s, and youth groups. Rationale: Disaggregated by: Gender, stakeholder type, age, clan, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of dialogue attendees who report the dialogues increased their understanding of perspectives on DOP/IGR - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop/dialogue evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop/dialogue reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 18 (2 female) participated a conversation on supporting DoP and IGR in Somalia, the participants included member of parliament, of the 12 respondents who filled the post workshop assessment 9(75%) of them said that the conversation increased their understanding in DOP and IGR</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">January to August 2018: four workshops were held with the Federal Negotiation Technical Committee (FNTC) on DOP/IGR, fiscal federalism and the justice model to enhance their knowledge on federalism as well as equip them with the technical expertise in negotiating constitutional arrangements for Somalia. The FNTC is a committee tasked to drive forward negotiations on federalism including the elections model, resource sharing and allocation of powers, to support political agreements at the leadership level. The workshops have contributed to increasing beneficiaries&apos; knowledge and understanding of Distribution of Powers/Inter governmental relations As per the Post workshop data collected after the January workshop,15 said that the workshop increased their understanding and provided them with a deeper knowledge on IGR and DOP while only 1 respondent said it did not improve his understanding. Similarly the data collected after the workshop conducted in March,15 of the interviewed respondents said that the training had improved their understanding while the remaining 1 said that the workshop did not improve their knowledge.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed within the first quarter. 18 out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot; with 5 being the most positive. Q2 Update: Research on gender &amp; federalism started</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="48"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2.1(1): Percentage of political thought leader participants who report that the dialogues have increased their understanding of perspectives on DOP and IGR</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Political thought leader&#x2019; refers to influential and politically active individuals who are not directly connected to people in government, such as members of civil society, women&#x2019;s, and youth groups. Rationale: Disaggregated by: Gender, stakeholder type, age, clan, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of dialogue attendees who report the dialogues increased their understanding of perspectives on DOP/IGR - in relation to the total number of attendees, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Answers on workshop/dialogue evaluations, supplemented by anecdotal evidence from workshop/dialogue reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="94">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">January to August 2018: four workshops were held with the Federal Negotiation Technical Committee (FNTC) on DOP/IGR, fiscal federalism and the justice model to enhance their knowledge on federalism as well as equip them with the technical expertise in negotiating constitutional arrangements for Somalia. The FNTC is a committee tasked to drive forward negotiations on federalism including the elections model, resource sharing and allocation of powers, to support political agreements at the leadership level. The workshops have contributed to increasing beneficiaries&apos; knowledge and understanding of Distribution of Powers/Inter governmental relations As per the Post workshop data collected after the January workshop,15 (94%) said that the workshop increased their understanding and provided them with a deeper knowledge on IGR and DOP while only 1 respondent (6%) said it did not improve his understanding. Similarly the data collected after the workshop conducted in March,15 (94%) of the interviewed respondents said that the training had improved their understanding while the remianing 1 (6%) said that the workshop did not improve their knowledge.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="95">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed within the first quarter. 18 out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot; with 5 being the most positive. Q2 Update: Research on gender &amp; federalism started</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LL Outcome B1: Targeted federal and state senior decision makers, their advisors and influencers representing key interest groups including women, develop increased consensus, and have increased knowledge, to design and support the implementation of politically accommodating DOP and IGR at all levels, including their relevance to gender transformation and minority rights.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1(1): Number of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding of DOP and/or IGR issues and options, and of the different effects of DOP and/or IGR decisions on marginalized and minority groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers, and their advisors and influencers. Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR, state Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding [&#x2026;] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop reports, workshop evaluations, Outcome Mapping of decision makers, their advisors, and their influencers Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18-This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed in the first quarter. 18 out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;&quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot;&quot; with 5 being the most positive.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="36"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="39"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="33"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="42"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B1(1): Percentage of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding of DOP and/or IGR issues and options, and of the different effects of DOP and/or IGR decisions on marginalized and minority groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are decision makers, and their advisors and influencers. Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR, state Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding [&#x2026;] - in relation to the total number of workshop attendees. Data collection method &amp; source: Workshop reports, workshop evaluations, Outcome Mapping of decision makers, their advisors, and their influencers Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="95">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18, 95% This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed in the first quarter. 18 out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;&quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot;&quot; with 5 being the most positive.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="65"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LL Outcome B2: Somalia&#x2019;s wider political influencers, including civil society and thought leaders, gain a deeper understanding of and consensus on politically accommodating distribution of powers and intergovernmental relations at all levels, including their relevance to gender transformation and minority rights, leading to greater trust in Somalia&#x2019;s nascent social contract.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2(1): Number of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding of DOP and/or IGR issues and options, and of the different effects of DOP and/or IGR decisions on marginalized and minority groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are political thought leaders. Rationale: Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR, state/region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding [&#x2026;] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Training/dialogue reports, training evaluations, Outcome Mapping of political thought leaders Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="33"></target>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From January to August 2018, four workshops were held with the Federal Negotiation Technical Committee (FNTC) on DOP/IGR, fiscal federalism and the justice model to enhance their knowledge on federalism as well as equip them with the technical expertise in negotiating constitutional arrangements for Somalia. 1st Workshop (15-16 Jan 2018)-18 participants attended the Workshop. Of the 18, 16 responded to the training evaluations with 15 (94%) demonstrating an understanding of DOP/IGR issues and options. 2nd Workshop (7-8 March 2018)- of the 18 attendees, 16 responded to the evaluations with 15 (94%) demonstrating an understanding of DOP/IGR issues and options 30 (94%) of the total 32 respondents demonstrated an understanding of DOP/IGR issues and options</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="30"></target>
     <actual value="18">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;18 This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed in the first quarter. 18(2 female) out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;&quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot;&quot; with 5 being the most positive.&quot; The workshop was done 16 to 17 May 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="36"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="39"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="42"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B2(1): Percentage of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding of DOP and/or IGR issues and options, and of the different effects of DOP and/or IGR decisions on marginalized and minority groups</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are political thought leaders. Rationale: Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR, state/region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who demonstrate increased understanding [&#x2026;] - in relation to the total number of workshop attendees. Data collection method &amp; source: Training/dialogue reports, training evaluations, Outcome Mapping of political thought leaders Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="95">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">18, 95% This is based on the first DOP/IGR workshop, completed in the first quarter. 18(2 female) out of 19 respondents rated the workshop a 4 or a 5 when asked the question, &quot;&quot;Did the workshop increase your understanding of perspectives on DoP and IGR? (1-5),&quot;&quot; with 5 being the most positive.&quot; The workshop was done 16 to 17 May 2017.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="55"></target>
     <actual value="94">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">From January to August 2018, four workshops were held with the Federal Negotiation Technical Committee (FNTC) on DOP/IGR, fiscal federalism and the justice model to enhance their knowledge on federalism as well as equip them with the technical expertise in negotiating constitutional arrangements for Somalia. 1st Workshop (15-16 Jan 2018)-18 participants attended the Workshop. Of the 18, 16 responded to the training evaluations with 15 (94%) demonstrating an understanding of DOP/IGR issues and options. 2nd Workshop (7-8 March 2018)- of the 18 attendees, 16 responded to the evaluations with 15 (94%) demonstrating an understanding of DOP/IGR issues and options 30 (94%) of the total 32 respondents demonstrated an understanding of DOP/IGR issues and options</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="60"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="65"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="70"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LL Outcome A1: DPCs in targeted areas have increased capacity to sustainably manage and resolve local conflicts and build trust within and between communities.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.2: Number of programme beneficiaries who feel they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are trained DPC members. &#x2018;Feel they have the ability&#x2019; refers to perception of the respondent regarding their power or capacity to do or act, in this case, in a manner which serves as a meaningful contribution towards conflict resolution according to programme beneficiaries. &#x2018;Conflict resolution&#x2019; means that a peaceful solution has been found to a disagreement between two or more parties. Rationale: This indicator tells us something about the level of empowerment of the vulnerable groups that are targeted by the programme. The assumption is that the programme will increase the numbers of people who feel that their voice matters, and who feel that their efforts can be considered as a valuable contribution towards conflict resolution. If more people feel this way, the assumption is that more people will actively participate and indeed make a contribution or encourage others to do so. This will increase the inclusiveness of vulnerable groups in the peace process. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of DPC members who feel that they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Collection and analysis of DPC members&#x2019; responses on workshop evaluations Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="131">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 134 DPC members were interviewed to gauge their ability to contribute to conflict resolution. Of the 134 members, 85 were male and 49 were female. 98% (131) of the respondents stated that they had the ability to contribute to conflict resolution while 2% (3) of the respondents were not confident enough.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="85">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 46(14 Female) people have been trained on conflict resolution in Abdiaziz and Waberi Districts of Mogdishu. The training was participated by 32 DPC members 14 other participants from the Police and security officials and the district adminstration. 85% of respondents told that the training improved their capacity to resolve conflict.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-12-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">RA3.SG.2: Percentage of programme beneficiaries who feel they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution (disaggregated)</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Programme beneficiaries&#x2019; refer to the people to whom the intervention is directed. As defined by the programme, they are trained DPC members. &#x2018;Feel they have the ability&#x2019; refers to perception of the respondent regarding their power or capacity to do or act, in this case, in a manner which serves as a meaningful contribution towards conflict resolution according to programme beneficiaries. &#x2018;Conflict resolution&#x2019; means that a peaceful solution has been found to a disagreement between two or more parties. Rationale: This indicator tells us something about the level of empowerment of the vulnerable groups that are targeted by the programme. The assumption is that the programme will increase the numbers of people who feel that their voice matters, and who feel that their efforts can be considered as a valuable contribution towards conflict resolution. If more people feel this way, the assumption is that more people will actively participate and indeed make a contribution or encourage others to do so. This will increase the inclusiveness of vulnerable groups in the peace process. Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district, state *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of DPC members who feel that they have the ability to contribute to conflict resolution - in relation to the total number of respondents. Data collection method &amp; source: Collection and analysis of DPC members&#x2019; responses on workshop evaluations Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
     <actual value="98">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A total of 134 DPC members were interviewed to gauge their ability to contribute to conflict resolution. Of the 134 members, 85 were male and 49 were female. 98% (131) of the respondents stated that they had the ability to contribute to conflict resolution while 2% (3) of the respondents were not confident enough.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="80"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.1: New district peace committees that include women and minority groups&#xA0;have been established and/or reconstituted in targeted districts</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.1(2): Number of women, youth, and members of minority clans participating in targeted DPCs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): Where &apos;minority clan&apos; = clans that are a minority in the district Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of women, youth, and members of minority clans participating in targeted DPCs - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of numbers of DPC members, from DPC records and consortium activity reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="6">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">14 of the new DPC members are female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">6 women members from Kaxda, 4 from Wajid and 5 from Hudur</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">7 DPC members were youth. Berdale (4) and ElBerde (3)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 (3 from Kaxda, 3 from Wajid and 3 from Hudur).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">9 of the total DPC members in Bardere and Dinsor were female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="13">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">There were 13 female members combined in both Berdale (7 females) and ElBerde (6 females) DPCs</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">of the 15 members of the DPC 4 of them were youth including 2 female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">of the 15 members of the DPC 7 were female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="5">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.1(2): Percentage of women, youth, and members of minority clans participating in targeted DPCs</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): Where &apos;minority clan&apos; = clans that are a minority in the district Disaggregated by: Gender, youth*/non-youth, clan, district *Youth is defined as persons of the ages between 15 and 24 (established UN definition). Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of women, youth, and members of minority clans participating in targeted DPCs - in relation to the total number of DPC members. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of numbers of DPC members, from DPC records and consortium activity reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="31">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">13 (31%) out of the total number of DPC members in Berdale and Elberde are women</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="17%">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">17% of the total number of DPC members in Dinsor and Bardere were youth</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="30">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">24% of the total number of DPC members in the two DPCs established were female</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="17">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">7 (17%) of the total number of DPC members in Berdale and Elberde are youth</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Minority clan"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="20">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Women"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="8">
      <dimension name="Member type" value="Youth"></dimension>
     </target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.1(1): Number of DPCs established or reconstituted</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Reconstituted&#x2019; refers to where a DPC once existed but has disappeared Disaggregated by: District Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of district peace committees established or reconstituted. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of numbers of DPCs, from DPC records and consortium activity reports Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <dimension name="A1.1: New district peace committees that include women and minority groups have been established and/or reconstituted in targeted districts"></dimension>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">4 ( Dinsor, Barawe and Bardere in South West State, Burtinle in Puntland of Somalia)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bardaale DPC was established between 9th to 11th September 2017 with a total of 23 (7 female ) members. ElBerde DPC was established between 5th to 7th October 2017 with a total of 19 ( 6 female) members.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.1: New district peace committees that include women and minority groups have been established and/or reconstituted in targeted districts</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kaxda District Peace Commitee in Banadir region was established on the 15th of May 2018 with a total of 17 members (6 female). Wajid District Peace Committee in South West State was established on the 27th of June 2018 with 15 members (4 female). Hudur DPC in South West State was established in August 2018 with a total 15 ( 5 female) members.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 (Dhuusamareeb DPC was established)</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="1"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-11-30"></period-end>
     <target value="4"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.3: District peace committees&#xA0;are working to resolve conflicts and are promoting peace through reconciliation within their districts and working with their counterparts in neighboring districts.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">A1.3(1): Percentage of cases brought to peace committees where the parties reach agreement</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;Resolution&#x2019; of a case refers to settling the case Disaggregated by: District, type of case, gender of parties Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of cases brought to district peace committees that result in a resolution &#x2013; in relation to the total number of cases brought, per calendar year. Data collection method &amp; source: Review of numbers of cases brought and resolved, from DPC records Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="76">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">213 of the 282 cases were resolved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">No data yet because peace diary training only recently occurred, so there are no records yet of cases resolved.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
     <actual value="91">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">Of the total  126 cases received in the first and second quarter of this year 114 (91%) were resolved</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
     <target value="50"></target>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LL Outcome B3: Select practical administrative and/or institutional arrangements for distribution of powers and intergovernmental relations are functioning in a way that supports movement toward sustainable political accommodation, gender transformation and minority rights.</narrative>
   </title>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3(1): Number of interlocutors who report a strengthening of key administrative and/or institutional arrangements that underpin agreed DOP and/or IGR as compared to the previous year</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;key administrative and/or institutional arrangements&#x2019; are on topics that are identified as priorities Rationale: Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Number of interlocutors who report a strengthening [&#x2026;] - per calendar year. The number is not cumulative. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping of decision makers, interviews (including of key experts) Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="2">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">B3(1): Percentage of interlocutors who report a strengthening of key administrative and/or institutional arrangements that underpin agreed DOP and/or IGR as compared to the previous year</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precise Definition(s): &#x2018;key administrative and/or institutional arrangements&#x2019; are on topics that are identified as priorities Rationale: Disaggregated by: Gender, interlocutor type, gov&apos;t level, DOP/IGR, region Calculation/Unit of Measurement: Percentage of interlocutors who report a strengthening [&#x2026;] - in relation to the total number of respondents. Data collection method &amp; source: Outcome Mapping of decision makers, interviews (including of key experts) Schedule for data collection: Yearly</narrative>
    </description>
    <baseline value="0" year="2017"></baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2021-10-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
