<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity budget-not-provided="3" default-currency="USD" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:cerf="http://cerf-gms.unocha.org/CERF01" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CERF-20-RR-WFP-008</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CERF" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNOCHA - Central Emergency Response Fund (CERF)</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency food support for those affected by conflict in North West Syria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WFP through its network of eight cooperating partners operating inside North West Syria will provide emergency food assistance targeted at IDPs that have either displaced once or multiple times. With CERF funds WFP anticipates being able to procure and replenish, enough RTEs to cover four rounds of distribution for some 420,000 people and forms the basis for the table below. Worth noting is that WFP has planned to provide up to four rounds of RTEs for those that have displaced especially depending on how the conflict develops as outlined in the released North West Syria Preparedness and Response Plan, meaning less people could be reached depending on the situation on the ground. 

Unlike WFP&#x2019;s general food assistance (GFA) programme in North West Syria that targets about 1.1 million people a month with dry food rations that provide 2,100 kcals. Under the GFA programme beneficiaries are assessed through the beneficiary selection tool the same assessment protocols cannot hold in the current displacement context.  WFP instead has decided to implement a &#x2018;no regrets policy&#x2019; for the distribution of RTEs. This means that whoever is fleeing and on the move is entitled to emergency food assistance without having to go through a rapid food security assessment of their level of food insecurity. Instead, Cooperating Partners conduct a rapid interview on the ground to establish needs. By adopting this approach, WFP can provide emergency assistance at scale and help ensure that no one falls through the cracks in receiving life-saving assistance. This &#x2018;no regrets&#x2019; blanket distribution of emergency food assistance approach supports protection by ensuring that all those impacted by the intense conflict have access to urgent humanitarian assistance and that civilians do not risk being excluded when others are receiving, helping to mitigate tensions among the affected population. The approach of WFP&#x2019;s cooperating partners to go where the people are moving also offers mitigation against protection risks often identified in accessing humanitarian assistance, such as movement restriction due to reasons such as security or an inability to access assistance due to a lack of transport or no income to pay for transport.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CERF" crs-channel-code="41147" ref="XM-OCHA-CERF" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OCHA Central Emergency Response Fund (CERF)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41140" role="2" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations World Food Programme (WFP)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="20-RR-WFP-008" type="A1">
   <owner-org ref="XM-OCHA-CERF">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN OCHA Central Emergency Response Fund (CERF)</narrative>
   </owner-org>
  </other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020-01-15</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-14" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020-07-14</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020-12-31</narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA)</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Central Emergency Response Fund (CERF) secretariat</narrative>
   </department>
   <email>cerf@un.org</email>
   <website>http://www.unocha.org/cerf/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA), Central Emergency Response Fund (CERF), 2 United Nations Plaza (DC2), East 44th street (13th floor), United Nations, New York, USA</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <humanitarian-scope code="16" type="1" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://cerf.un.org">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SYRIAN ARAB REPUBLIC&#xA0;(SYRIA)        DISPLACEMENT        2020</narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="XM-OCHA-CERF-20-RR-WFP-008">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-02-20">6000000</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disbursement to CERF Project Emergency food support for those affected by conflict in North West Syria</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-OCHA-CERF" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">OCHA Central Emergency Response Fund (CERF)</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="XM-DAC-41140">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations World Food Programme (WFP)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="2"></disbursement-channel>
   <sector code="72040" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.unocha.org/cerf/sites/default/files/CERF/HCRCReports/20-RR-SYR-40986-NR01_Syrian Arab Republic_RCHC.Report.pdf">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">RESIDENT / HUMANITARIAN COORDINATOR REPORT ON THE USE OF CERF FUNDS SYRIAN ARAB REPUBLIC&#xA0;(SYRIA)        RAPID RESPONSE        DISPLACEMENT        2020</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A07"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1">
   <condition type="2">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CERF funding is based on an agreed proposal, including specific planned outcomes and outputs.</narrative>
   </condition>
  </conditions>
  <result aggregation-status="0" type="1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Output 1</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of emergency food assistance through ready to eat rations</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator aggregation-status="0" ascending="1" measure="5">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicator 1.1</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Number of IDPs reached with emergency food assistance (Ready to Eat Food Ration)</narrative>
    </description>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-15"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
