<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>NL-KVK-40535338-FGG-TOC2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="NL-KVK-40535338" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Friends of the Earth International</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FGG FoEI ToC 2: Improved Trade and Investment</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A. Enabling environment. The rights and (legal) space of people, communities and civil society actors in Low- and Lower-Middle Income Countries (LLMICs) active on trade and investment are protected. B. Capacities strengthened. Increased capacity of civil society actors to research, network and advocate on trade and investment. C. Alternatives developed. Alternative approaches to the current trade and investment regime&#x2014;which are people-driven, gender inclusive and sustainable policies and practices that improve policy coherence for development, such as the Alternative Trade Mandate&#x2014;have been developed, piloted and promoted by FGG and civil society actors. D. Agendas set. Decision makers prioritise improvement measures due to support from influential civil society actors, critical media attention, increased public awareness and effective scrutiny of trade and investment policies. E. Policies changed. Policies related to trade and investment have been improved, so that they advance policy coherence for development. F. Practice changed. Improved trade and investment policies and processes are implemented and enforced.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Civil society; Governments; International institutions; Private sector actors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FGG&#x2019;s goal is to ensure that trade and investment advances socially just, inclusive and environmentally sustainable development. Like Minister Ploumen, we believe that trade and investment can contribute significantly to economic opportunity and equality. But the current global trade and investment regime has helped create and exacerbate governance gaps that adversely affect society, expanding the rights of corporations while diminishing the policy options available to governments. Policies promoting trade and investment have overlooked the potentiality of negative impacts, putting them at odds with commitments on policy coherence for development (PCD). There is an urgent need to close these governance gaps and to increase policy coherence in general. We believe that this will redress the imbalance between the rights and obligations of corporations and the regulatory space available to governments to fulfil environmental and social objectives, including increased gender equality and respect for human rights. Redressing this imbalance is essential in achieving socially just, inclusive, and environmentally sustainable societies. As the Minister has stated in her policy agenda, the market is not perfect. We believe that governments must be able to regulate in society&#x2019;s interest. Governments have an obligation to assess the impacts of their policies and take action or refrain from introducing a policy when there is significant risk or evidence of negative impacts. However over the course of the last two decades there has been a trend for governments to sign up to bilateral and multilateral trade and investment agreements that restrict their ability to implement policies that stimulate inclusive and sustainable growth, and create incentives for them to cast aside their obligations to citizens. In addition, existing policies on energy sourcing and financing constrain the space within which more socially just, inclusive and environmentally sustainable energy systems could emerge. This dynamic is aggravated by the inclusion of investor-state dispute settlement (ISDS) mechanisms in many agreements. These enable companies to sue governments for pursuing policies that may adversely affect future profits. Fierce competition for investment between countries further aggravates these problems, exerting downward pressure on wages and the price of natural resources. There is increasing interest, including in the Netherlands and the EU, in new approaches to trade and investment where benefits are shared more equally. The Netherlands is a key actor in the global debates on trade and investment and Policy Coherence for Development, and has set a trend that has been followed by many donor countries and international institutions. We believe that the government&#x2019;s willingness to tolerate dissent and sustain dialogue with representatives of civil society around the world can lead to transformative change. Besides specific trade and investment policies, also policies related to agriculture and food security, energy and climate, raw materials use, transport and infrastructure, biodiversity and other areas, can have a significant impact on trade and investment flows and therefore on inclusive and sustainable development and on people in Low- and Lower-Middle Income Countries (LLMICs). Oftentimes, these links are overlooked. In order to achieve policy coherence for development, FGG will carry out joint analyses with partners looking at how key public policies drive investment towards or away from sustainable and inclusive food and energy systems, and a respectful relationship with the environment. Based on these analyses, which will include descriptions of new or existing alternative models, FGG and its Southern partners will develop a joint strategy to influence relevant policies. Satisfying global energy needs through fossil fuel extraction, including fracking, large-scale hydropower projects, nuclear energy, and industrial agriculture (such as flex crops and industrial tree plantations), constitutes one of the main sources of greenhouse gas emissions. It also generates unsustainable solutions that promote exclusion and increase people&#x2019;s vulnerabilities. FGG focuses on demonstrating how existing policies on energy sourcing and financing (in both the North and the South) prevent more socially just, inclusive and environmentally sustainable energy systems emerging. At the same time they facilitate resource grabbing and extend corporate control over energy production. Our work creates options for the pursuit of models that represent real solutions to climate change, and that move forward, in a socially just way, toward the phasing out of fossil fuels. This dossier includes policies that are directly or indirectly related to climate and energy policies, such as policies on public energy provision and subsidies, financing and foreign direct investment, transport, infrastructure and growth corridors, extractives, agriculture, biodiversity, mining and raw materials production and use. FGG will strive to improve existing policies regulating activity around climate and energy, by strengthening community driven innovations aimed at providing for local energy needs and bringing lessons learned into policy discussions and interventions in key decision making spaces including UN Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) and within EU institutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="NL-KVK-40535338-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-40535338" role="1" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Friends of the Earth International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-40535338" role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Friends of the Earth International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="NL-KVK-40535338" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Friends of the Earth International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Friends of the Earth International</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+31 (0)20 6221369</telephone>
   <website>http://www.foei.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Friends of the Earth International Secretariat P.O.Box 19199 1000 GD Amsterdam The Netherlands</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="0.1"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CM" percentage="0.3"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="0.1"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GT" percentage="0.6"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="HN" percentage="2"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="0.9"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="1.7"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="0.4"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PG" percentage="0.4"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="1.3"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="1.7"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="SV" percentage="3"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="TG" percentage="2"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="0.1"></recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="0.1" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="6.4" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="679" percentage="5" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="0.1" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="73.8" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="92030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="2" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="1" vocabulary="1"></policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="30"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-01-01">411244</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-01-01">411244</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-01-01">411244</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-01-01">411244</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-01-01">411244</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">408082</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC 2 2017</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-40535338-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-40535338" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2017-12-31">408082</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC 2 2017</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">447378</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC2 2018</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-40535338-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-40535338" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2018-12-31">447378</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC2 2018</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">477007</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC2 2019</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-40535338-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-40535338" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2019-12-31">477007</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC2 2019</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">475216</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC2 2020</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-40535338-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-40535338" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2020-12-31">475216</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure TOC2 2020</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="1"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">405018</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditures TOC 2 2016</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="NL-KVK-40535338-FGG" ref="NL-KVK-40535338" type="21"></provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2016-12-31">405018</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditures TOC 2 2016</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="NL-KVK-40535338-FGG" type="1"></related-activity>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome C: Alternatives Developed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Alternative approaches to the current trade and investment regime&#x2014;which are people-driven, gender inclusive and sustainable policies and practices that improve policy coherence for development, such as the Alternative Trade Mandate&#x2014;have been developed, piloted and promoted by FGG and civil society actors.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.C</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># alternative approaches to the current trade and investment regime developed with CSOs in LLMICs that have been developed, piloted and/or promoted.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.C" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1: In addition to argumentation that had been developed in earlier years, based on developments in the context, in 2016 FoEE and FoEI have issued several new publications on the risks of ISDS. E.g. FoEI&apos;s and TNI&apos;s report &apos;The Hidden costs of RCEP and corporate trade deals&apos; (http://www.foei.org/resources/publications/hidden-costs-rcep-corporate-trade-deals-asia). These argumentations have been used e.g. in the organisation of regional ISDS argumentation trainings. FoEI2: In order to put the topic of the need to transition away from fossil fuels at the Marrakesh UNFCCC COP (November 2016), FoEI produced the factsheet &quot;Dirty Energy in Africa&quot;, in collaboration with FoE South Africa, FoE Uganda, FoE Mozambique and FoE Nigeria, and included input from allies in the Maghreb region (where the COP22 was taking place). The factsheet included information on dirty energy exploration and impacts in Africa as well as case studies from FoE member groups, and urges African governments to introduce new policies ensuring a transition to a clean, community-controlled renewable energy infrastructure. It was produced in English, French, Spanish and Arabic and disseminated at COP22 during events and at our stall in the civil society space of the COP venue and electronically through the poken system at the COP. It was also distributed via the FoEI website and via email lists to FoE member groups. FoEI produced 200 English and 50 each of French, Arabic and Spanish. Ahead of the UNFCCC COP, FoEI produced an animation video to illustrate how the current energy system impacts people&#x2019;s lives and how this will worsen if there is no energy transformation. The video was released in English, French, Spanish, Arabic (forthcoming versions in Portuguese, Norwegian and Korean). It was viewed at least 12,000 times on Facebook.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">* Clear argumentation is developed against the inclusion of ISDS mechanisms in current trade negotiations and future trade agreements. * One study produced, which outlines a model for a socially and environmentally just transition toward the phasing out of fossil fuels.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1(1): Further development of approach to socially and environmentally just transition to a fossil free energy future. FoEI2(1): Proposals developed which promote agroecology (local markets, inclusive policy development, investment) presented to High Level Panel of Experts of the World Committee on Food Security and to the UN FAO and its member governments.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: As part of further developing work on just transition, FoEI finalized, published and promoted the People Power Now! Energy Manifesto. It contains 10 demands and each demand sets out a positive measure that will accelerate the transition towards a climate just world. It also highlights the initiatives of indigenous peoples and frontline communities that are already putting these values into practice. The PPN Manifesto was launched at the UNFCCC COP24 in Bonn, in December, at a well-attended side event with speakers from across FoE and from key allies. The Manifesto has been promoted towards policymakers and widely distributed among CSO networks. [FoEI2(1)]: A pilot project on agroecology in urban agriculture in San Salvador was set up by a CSO in El Salvador and a curriculum developed for 10 training workshops, which were implemented by 28 CSO actors. FoEI provided financial and planning support to the CSO from El Salvador to develop the project.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: FoEI will promote among CSOs participating in the Transforming Economies World Social Forum its Scaling up Economic Justice Solutions theory, which was developed in collaboration with CSOs, including from LLMICs. The theory is about the way in which economic justice solutions (developed by social movements, including feminists, indigenous people and peasant movements around the world) like cooperatives and public services that reduce inequality, contribute to equitable power relations including between women and men and expand the role of cooperation, community management and sustainable planning in all aspects of life, can be scaled up from separate local and regional efforts to initiatives with a national and global significance.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: FoEI presented its Scaling up Economic Justice Solutions strategy at the online Transforming Economies World Social Forum (June 2020). FoEI&apos;s publication: &apos;Transforming our Economy. Scaling up the Solutions&apos;, developed by CSOs from a.o. Cameroon, Uruguay and Argentina, based on inputs from multiple LLMIC CSOs collaborating in FoE International&apos;s Economic Justice Programme, pleads for new economic strategies to be distributive and regenerative by design and focused on the primary goal of achieving sustainable societies, being in harmony with nature and based on environmental, social, economic and gender justice, and peoples&#x2019; sovereignty. FoEI proposes five economic justice solutions to transform the global economy: Providing public services for all through tax justice; Scaling up economies based on social ownership and cooperativism; Supporting local markets and fair trade; Valuing and measuring the wellbeing of people and planet; and Ensuring binding rules to dismantle the power of big business. These economic justice solutions are all based on FoE member groups&#x2019; existing local and national struggles across the globe. The publication argues that to be transformative, scale is important. Thousands of solutions for a more just and sustainable world already exist. Their impact must be increased, and local initiatives must be scaled up to become national or international policies. Solutions should be replicable in a just and inclusive way that respects the diversity of culture, social and political context and promotes gender, class and racial justice.
[FoEI2(1)]: FoEI&#x2019;s analysis on the climate crisis linked to the Covid-19 pandemic resulted in a set of principles on Covid-19 and Climate Justice, and demands for a Just Recovery from Covid-19, such as that responding to the Covid-19 and climate crises should occur simultaneously, applying the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities to move away from fossil fuel dependency to 100% community-owned, renewable energy for all. The principles were developed with FoE groups from LLMICs and other countries, and promoted among FoE groups globally, including in LLMICs, who used it to advocate towards their national governments on the national Covid-19 policies.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: LLMIC CSOs in cooperation with other CSOs cooperating in FoEI&apos;s Climate Justice Programme will develop and promote an alternative 1.5 degree pathway (as related to the Paris Climate Agreement) without &apos;bio-energy with carbon capture and storage&apos; (BECCS) or geoengineering. [FoEI2(1)]: In 2019 CSOs from LLMIC, together with FoEI, will develop or promote at least one other alternative approach to the current trade and investment regime. It will either be an alternative approach to the current climate finance that will accelerate a just energy transition which will be developed through research that will support FoE member groups in LLMICs to better understand the landscape of international climate finance. Or a CSO from an LLMIC in the Middle East will together with FoEI produce, release and promote a 100% renewable energy report for this LLMIC that will make the case for system change towards energy sovereignty. This report will be promoted through the media and likely a broader campaign.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="7">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: Together with FoE groups (a.o. from LLMICs El Salvador, Nigeria, Uganda) FoEI has advanced the discussion on proposals for natural climate solutions and proposals to stop false solutions to climate change such as bio-energy with carbon capture and storage (BECCS), geoengineering and carbon markets. The groups&apos; proposals have been successfully promoted and used in Madrid at the UNFCCC COP25 mobilization to mobilize civil society and campaigning to put pressure on the negotiations to block an agreement on a global carbon market. [FoEI2(2)]: Civil society concerns about the negative impacts of industrial monoculture plantations, including land grabbing, soil and water pollution, sexual violence towards women, the destruction of food sovereignty, and that certification of industrial plantations is a false solution to climate change were put forward at a September 17 UN Committee on World Food Security (CFS) event on plantations in Rome in a civil society intervention drafted by FoEI and La Via Campesina (&apos;Impacts of plantations on Food Security and Nutrition &#x2013; CFS workshop 17 Sept 2019&apos;), which also promoted community forest management. FoEI also made an intervention on why certification is a false solution to address the negative impacts of plantations, which was discussed by governments, intergovernmental and research institutions. [FoEI3(1)]: Six CSOs from Asia-Pacific (from PNG, Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines, Sri Lanka, Palestine) with the financial, strategizing and communications support of FoEI in December released a research report &apos;The laws of Land Grabs in Asia Pacific&apos; as an alternative approach for land rights and land grabbing issues, with recommendations for transformative political and legislative measures which would ensure greater protection of community land rights, the prevention of land grabs and human rights violations, and the sustainable management of natural resources. The report was launched at an event in PNG attended by a state representative from the Conservation and Environment Protection Authority, as well as representatives of CBOs, and other stakeholders. Currently the national government is reviewing legislation on land, and forestry, conservation and environmental protection. The CSO is making use of the publication in their ongoing work, including in community legal education workshops (for customary land owners and CBOs). At the national level the CSO uses the report to call for the government and decision makers to amend and include provisions within their natural resource and land laws that facilitate/promote rights of indigenous and local people. The CSO demands the total removal of specific legal provisions for corporations which are seen to be the driver of land grab in the country. With the removal of these provisions people are able to access and farm their lands freely, their rights are recognized by the government and their environment stays intact and viable for future generations. [FoEI4(1)]: A CSO from an Asian LLMIC (Indonesia) with the financial support of FoEI and building on positions co-developed with CSOs globally within FoEI&apos;s Food Sovereignty Programme developed a policy paper &apos;Community Management of Coastal and Small Islands - A Policy Paper for Food Sovereignty in Coastal Area&apos;, which was delivered to the Provincial Government, media, and other CSOs. The CSO in their advocacy work, is striving to correct the land bias in food policy, pushing for fisherfolk communities to be recognized as food producers. [FoEI5(1)]: A CSO from a Latin American LLMIC (El Salvador) developed and proposed a national law for the promotion of agroecology. With the financial and communications support of FoEI, it received national media attention for their advocacy in favour of this alternative approach to unsustainable agribusiness and its negative impact on nature and people, following the implementation of a communications strategy that included two press conferences in October. The proposed law was presented to the Agriculture Commission of the Legislative Assembly on 22 October by 16 CSOs accompanied by a mobilization of 350 peasants [See also 2.B FoEI9 and 2.D FoEI10]. [FoEI6(1)]: As an outcome of the first national Peasant Social Forum, held in November in Togo, attended by a representative of the Minister of Agriculture, Animal Production and Fisheries, co-organized and facilitated by a CSO from an African LLMIC (Togo) together with a national CSO network, a joint declaration promoting agroecology and the key role of women in family farming was adopted by the forum (Forum Social des Paysans) on 27 November: &apos;SOUVERAINETE ALIMENTAIRE ET BIODIVERSITE&apos;. This declaration, which includes clear demands from civil society to the government for this alternative approach to unsustainable agribusiness and its negative impact on nature and people, will be delivered and discussed at the Ministry of Agriculture, Animal Production and Fisheries in 2020. FoEI contributed to the forum financially, logistically , with knowledge development and communication work.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1:] In 2017 FoEI further developed its approach to a socially and environmentally just transition away from fossil fuels, including through promoting exchange of ideas amongst FoE national groups across regions, in dialogue and joint events with representatives of the labor movement from all regions and working with a feminist organization on this issue. One Nigerian CSO, one Sri Lankan CSO, one Haitian CSO and one Togolese CSO took part in efforts coordinated by FoEI to develop cross-regional joint analysis and strategizing in relation to the transition to a just energy system. This included participation in the development of an internal FoEI discussion paper on Just Transition, which was an input to discussions within the federation and to a discussion with the trade union movement. FoEI provided financial support for representatives from Nigeria, Sri Lanka and Togo to take part in a roundtable strategy discussion (Bonn, November) with representatives of the international trade union movement (ITUC and affiliates from around the world); representatives from Nigeria and Sri Lanka were speakers at a public event co-hosted by FoEI and ITUC (Bonn, November) on Just Transition to an audience of more than 100 people. A representative from the Women&#x2019;s Environment and Development Organization (WEDO) was also a featured speaker at the public event, with input on the gendered concerns relating to the transition. FoEI worked with national groups across its federation to organize two coordinated days of action (Oct 13-14) to draw attention to the negative impacts of dirty energy, the urgency to demand climate justice in addressing the climate crisis and to transition to a new environmentally and socially just energy system. FoEI support included providing international strategic and communications coordination, regional workshops, Real World Radio coverage and materials. 26 national FoE groups held physical actions and 4 others did online actions, which supported their local and national demands. One CSO in Togo reported that being part of a global day showed them to be strong in the national context and gave them profile to be able to advocate. One CSO in Indonesia&#x2019;s actions across the country demonstrated people power against coal, and there have seen subsequent court victories (see 1.E). One CSO in Mozambique established their work on gas while also showing a global connection, one CSO in El Salvador held a manifestation against agro-fuels and connected to their peers across the world. Later in the year FoEI coordinated a 20-country delegation at the UNFCCC COP23 (Bonn, November) engaging in a range of awareness raising events, actions (including on climate finance, against fossil fuels, carbon markets, just transition), networking and alliance building meetings, press conferences and actions to promote justice and equity approach in relation to the climate crisis. FoEI focused efforts in supporting member groups from Asia-Pacific (host of the COP) in highlighting key messages against dirty energy and in relation to climate-impacted peoples, distributing a report and videos on this issue. FoEI organized two well-attended workshops on dirty energy and climate-impacted peoples at the People&#x2019;s Climate Summit. [FoEI2:] In 2017 FoEI worked with member groups across all regions (including CSOs in Mozambique, Indonesia and Philippines) to develop a joint proposal to transform the economy. This set of demands is: public services for all through tax justice, grow the cooperative and solidarity economy, support fair trade and local markets, creating economies of purpose not profit and enacting binding rules for big business. The proposal was presented in an 18-page report called &#x2018;Transforming Our Economy: Scaling up the Solutions&#x2019; in 4 languages (English, Spanish, French, Portuguese; designed version launched 2018 but in use in 2017). This framework of FoEI&#x2019;s economic transformation vision is based on local and national examples and 25 ideas of how to scale up solutions. The report has been used with allies at social movement events, including at the Continental Convergence for Democracy and Against Neoliberalism (Montevideo, Nov. 16-18), a massive gathering of social movements in Latin America, also supported by FoEI financially and with coordination staff and Real World Radio coverage. FoEI also produced 10 social media info-graphics on solutions and local case studies and produced one two-minute video highlighting one element of the proposal (cooperativism), which had over 250,000 views.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome D: Agendas Set</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decision makers prioritise improvement measures due to support from influential civil society actors, critical media attention, increased public awareness and effective scrutiny of trade and investment policies.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.D</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># proposals for improvement to policies related to trade and investment discussed by national, regional and international government bodies and/or by private policy makers, in academia, public agenda, media and social movements.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.D" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1(i): Thanks to the work done on trade and investment in the Asia Pacific region WALHI/FoE Indonesia was able to bring up the controversial aspects of ISDS in the public and political debate in Indonesia. WALHI took part in an ISDS argumentation training organised by FoEI and TNI in November 2016, which it re-used in its advocacy around the RCEP round of negotiations taking place in December 2016. WALHI was also co-organiser of the civil society summit happening in parallel of the talks (December 2-10) that highlighted the civil society concerns around the inclusion of ISDS in future trade deals (outlined in the open letter to the 16 RCEP governments signed by 316 CSOs, http://igj.or.id/civil-society-open-letter-to-governments-in-the-16-rcep-countries/). Activities included a day of informational sessions, one protest action, one NGO breakfast with Indonesia&apos;s head negotiator, and one CSO stakeholder meeting with trade negotiators, and one media conference (which resulted in coverage of the issues, for example, http://www.thejakartapost.com/news/2016/12/07/rcep-talks-speed-up-amid-tpp-failure.html). FoEI1(ii): FoEI&apos;s support to CESTA/FoE El Salvador allowed it to highlight in the El Salvadoran media the links between the lack of binding rules on transnational corporations and foreign investor privileges through the ISDS case Oceano Gold/Pacific Rim. FoE El Salvador held 2 press conferences on the case, which created visibility on the case and allowed CESTA to connect with other movements in opposing it. FoEI2(i): As a result of the level of community resistance organised by ERA/FoE Nigeria against tar sands development plans of the Nigerian government, the Nigerian government did not take any further step in relation to the exploitation of tar sands in Nigeria in 2016 and the projects have been delayed. FoEI2(ii): Honduras-based CSO is exposing the damaging effects of planned mega hydro-projects for the environment and communities. This has resulted in higher awareness of these dangers within communities, and the emergence of public debates around these in Honduras. April 13-15, 2016 approximately 1500 people from grassroots CSOs in Honduras came together for the event &quot;Berta Caceres Lives International Peoples&apos; Summit&quot; in Tegucigalpa and Rio Branco, Honduras, to commemorate the legacy of Berta Caceres&apos;s work in defense of Lenca traditional territories.&#xA0;The occasion was also used by Honduran CSOs to analyze and share common challenges faced by CSOs and communities in defending their lives and livelihoods, particularly in relation to corporate and state impunity following the 2009 coup d&apos;etat. As a result, there is broader national level understanding of the different experiences and strategies of Honduran CSOs, and increased, common political analysis and national-level debate: http://encuentrobertacaceresvive.blogspot.nl/.&#xA0;In addition, key Honduran CSOs took forward social media campaigns to raise visibility across Honduras of impunity and to strengthen and engage community-level voices in national-level political debates: https://www.facebook.com/madretierrahonduras/?hc_ref=PAGES_TIMELINE</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">* Critique of ISDS becomes part of the public and political discourse in several countries (but at least one) in Africa, Latin America and Asia-Pacific (with specific focus on the following LLMICs countries: Indonesia, Nigeria, Uganda, Colombia, El Salvador and Malaysia) * The need to transition away from fossil fuels is put higher on the political agenda because of exposure of two cases of dirty energy projects and how they negatively impact the potential for sustainable development (including the respect of human rights and gender-related aspects).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="32">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: CSOs and social movements participating in CSO fora around the UNFCCC COP25 will discuss FoEI research on the alternative 1.5 degrees pathway, and position papers prepared by FoEI and LLMIC FoE groups on geoengineering and &apos;bio-energy with carbon capture and storage&apos; (BECCS). This will strengthen civil society in its efforts to oppose false solutions to climate change and to promote alternatives to the current policies and frameworks amongst decision-makers during the COP25 and thereafter. [FoEI2(2)]: Policy makers in at least 2 international/regional level advocacy forums will discuss FoEI proposals for improved investments policies related to dirty energy projects developed together with LLMIC CSOs. [FoEI3(10)]: 10 FoE groups will forge alliances with trade unions around proposals prepared by these groups for improved climate and energy policies, and together with these unions develop and take forward a just transition strategy at their national level. [FoEI4(6)]: Demands and critique from LLMIC CSOs and FoEI are part of public and political discourse in the context of national (Togo, El Salvador, Sri Lanka, Indonesia) and regional trade and investment agreement discussions (including on African Free Trade Area, RCEP and ISDS). FoEI supports and strengthens these agenda-setting efforts through the facilitation of strategy development, organization of workshops and/or webinars, and development of communications strategies and materials. [FoEI5(1)]: Critique from LLMIC CSOs and FoEI of ISDS is part of the discourse at United Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) session. [FoEI6(6)]: Proposals (developed by working groups where FoEI facilitates and/or participates and CSOs from LLMICs participate) that promote agroecology, including the promotion of permanent structures on agroecology within the FAO, have been presented to and are being discussed by the World Committee on Food Security (CFS) and to the UN FAO and its member governments [5 member countries are counted]. [FoEI7(4)]: At the national level in at least 3 LLMICs, and at the UN/FAO Committee on Food Security and Nutrition (CFS) level, upon advocacy of CSOs in these LLMICs against industrial plantations and the related deforestation and human rights violations and landgrabbing, policies promoted by these groups that are in favor of community forest management and agroecology will be discussed. Proposals for these policies have been developed within the FoE network and in other CSO fora with the participation of LLMIC FoE groups and FoEI. FoEI will facilitate the development of a joint advocacy strategy and the participation of representatives from 2 CSOs from LLMICs at the FAO/CFS. [FoEI8(1)]: A World Committee on Food Security (CFS) policy roundtable process on agroecology is agreed and underway. Materials prepared by 7 LLMIC CSOs and FoEI will be discussed in this roundtable process. [FoEI9(1)]: An analysis of LLMIC CSOs and FoEI of the trade in waste issue, with a focus on the impact of the Chinese import ban on plastics, and the link between the need for trade justice and zero waste/plastic is discussed in social movement and receives attention in the media.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: Proposals from a CSO from a Latin American UMIC (Uruguay) on chapters of the EU-MERCOSUR FTA that are problematic for domestic and regional policies such as ISDS (and that were developed in collaboration with LLMIC CSOs, FoE International and FoE Europe in the framework of FoEI&apos;s Economic Justice Programma) has reached the governmental agenda in the country after multiple meetings between the CSO and the government. [FoEI2(5)]: FoEI strengthened the alliance between FoE groups in Latin America (from Colombia, Brazil, Argentina and Uruguay) and trade unions in Latin America on a Just Transition and Gender Justice, which resulted in discussions within the alliance on what a feminist just transition would look like and building relationships between the women&#x2019;s movements, climate movement and unions. FoEI provided financial and coordination support that contributed to the participation and representation of CSOs and movements in the Latin American region in a regional event (November) where they shared their positions on social and political issues including trade and investment, which contributed to shaping the resulting common agenda for social movements in the Latin American region. Furthermore, FoEI strengthened the collaboration between FoE groups (from South Africa, Mozambique, Nigeria and Togo) and trade unions in Africa on a transition away from coal. Also, FoEI (i.e. the FoE groups including from LLMICs as collaborating in FoEI&apos;s Climate Justice &amp; Energy Programme) as part of a wider climate alliance was able to put Just Transition elements on the agenda of youth movements to ensure Southern voices, equity perspectives, current climate impacts in the global South (not only future focused) were a part of the narrative and programme of these youth movements. Further, a FoE group in an Asian LLMIC (Palestine) with the financial support from FoEI ensured that proposals for renewable energy, empowerment of women in this sector and gender sensitive renewable energy laws were put on the agenda of two ministries who conveyed the CSO&apos;s messages on how to empower women through mainstreaming gender in clean energy programs. This also resulted in the Ministry of Economy including criteria for women to participate in clean energy projects in their annual plans. [FoEI3(1)]: FoEI and FoE groups (a.o. from Sri Lanka, Malaysia) were part of a strong movement that campaigned for the inclusion of plastic waste under the scope of the Basel Convention to end the free trade of plastic waste. National level advocacy contributed to the result of one government of an Asian UMIC speaking out against the free trade of plastic waste and actively sending back plastic waste to origin countries. [As the country in question is a UMIC, this outcome is counted not as an F-outcome (practice change) but a D-outcome (support)]. [FoEI4(2)]: In July the FAO launched the Global Knowledge Product (GKP) on Agroecology following the involvement of the International Planning Committee (IPC) of the Food Sovereignty movement (advocating a global food system based on agroecology and food sovereignty) in a process to develop an FAO Global Analytical Framework for the multi-dimensional assessment of Agroecology and guidelines for its application. This is part of the FAO approach to scaling up agroecology. According to the FAO &#x201C;this tool will consolidate information on the impact of agroecological approaches in order to facilitate informed decision making. It will provide a guidance framework in reviewing policy options for agroecology and thus assist policy makers in assessing the multi-dimensional impacts of agroecological production systems.&#x201D; FoEI and FoE groups participating in FoEI&apos;s Food Sovereignty Programme (including groups from LLMICs such as Togo and El Salvador) contributed to this step, which implements concrete advances in the FAO&#x2019;s work on agroecology, by representing the IPC in the technical working group that drafted the analytical framework. In addition to contributing to shaping the GKP civil society, through the IPC, continues to be involved in shaping the agenda of the ongoing implementation of GKP, including during a follow up regional workshop to the GKP launch that took place in Mexico City in November. Furthermore, FAO will contribute to the development of the UNCBD&apos;s Global Biodiversity Framework (GBF) with this proposal (see below). Agroecology constitutes a sustainable alternative approach to unsustainable agribusiness and its negative impact on nature and people, see e.g. the statement from the Forum Social des Paysans from 27 November 2019 co-organised by a CSO from Togo with the support of FoEI, &apos;SOUVERAINETE ALIMENTAIRE ET&#xA0;BIODIVERSITE&apos;. [FoEI5(1)]: The UN Committee on World Food Security (UN CFS) launched a policy convergence process on agroecology, which FoEI, as part of the global food sovereignty movement and member of the Civil Society Mechanism (CSM) of the CFS, has been advocating for years. The CSM further contributed to agenda-setting within this policy convergence process with a December 6 submission to the rapporteur for the policy convergence process, as part of the open consultation process with the CSM to gather input on priority issues to be addressed during the process and to feed into the zero draft of a the process. Agroecology constitutes a sustainable alternative approach to unsustainable agribusiness and its negative impact on nature and people, see e.g. the &apos;CSM Inputs for the CFS policy convergence process on &#x201C;Agroecological and other innovative approaches for sustainable agriculture and food systems that enhance food security and nutrition&#x201D; to which FoEI, represented in the CSM has contributed with the FoE groups participating in FoE International&apos;s Food Sovereignty Programme, such as from LLMICs Togo and El Salvador. [FoEI6(1)]: Joint campaigning to resist financialization of nature is now on the agenda of the International Planning Committee of the Food Sovereignty movement (IPC) following a May 2019 training on financialization of nature conducted by FoEI for the IPC&#x2019;s land and territories working group. This training resulted in a joint strategy and campaign proposal in relation to resisting financialization of nature being developed with social movements. From an ecological justice perspective, financialization of nature must be rejected as a false solution to climate change. [FoEI7(1)]: FoEI&apos;s and the food sovereignty movement&apos;s position on the need for a right to land was presented to the UN Committee on Economic Cultural and Social Rights (CESCR) and discussed on October 14, when FoEI was part of an expert panel at the CESCR event on &#x201C;Land under changing environmental conditions and climate change&#x201D; and is being considered in the context of the CESCR&#x2019;s process to develop a General Comment on Land (as a Human Right). FoEI positions are developed in the framework of FoE International&apos;s Food Sovereignty Programme, in which CSOs from LLMICs such as Togo and El Salvador participate. [FoEI8(1)]: CSOs including FoEI participating in the UNCBD&apos;s SBSTTA 23 (Convention on Biological Diversity, Subsidiary Body on Scientific, Technical and Technological Advice) have had discussions for the first time on why financialization of nature policies and carbon offsetting mechanisms (such as those included in the Paris Agreement for the UNFCCC) should not be included in the CBD Global Biodiversity Framework (GBF) which is currently being developed for the 2020-2030 decade. Financialization of Nature (FoN) is considered a topic which is difficult to communicate, but is extremely relevant and important to discuss because of its harm to environment and social justice. FoEI published a study explaining this: &apos;Regulated destruction. How biodiversity offsetting enables environmental destruction&apos; that is used in these processes. FoEI positions are developed in the framework of FoE International&apos;s Food Sovereignty Programme, in which CSOs from LLMICs such as Togo and El Salvador participate. [FoEI9(1)]: FoEI&#x2019;s joint analysis on rights inherent to Community Forest Management, developed with CSOs from LLMICs El Salvador, Honduras, Indonesia, Philippines, Togo, Ghana, Nigeria, Mozambique, and Sri Lanka, and submitted to and presented at meetings of and around the UNCBD, has contributed to the discussions in the UNCBD Alliance and at the UNCBD Thematic Consultation on Effective Area-Based Conservation Measures for the post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework and has been adopted by the CBD Alliance. The analysis is about the essential role that communities have in area-based conservation and the need that these rights are recognized and implemented. [FoEI10(1)]: A CSO from a Latin American LLMIC (El Salvador) who had developed a national law for the promotion of agroecology was invited to a hearing on 22 October in the national parliament to present technical arguments on the proposed law, in which deputies from the Agriculture Commission of the Legislative Assembly were present. The CSO presented the law together with 16 CSOs accompanied by a mobilization of 350 peasants [See also 2.B FoEI9 and 2.C FoEI5].</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1(1): CSO demands and critique are part of public and political discourse in context of regional trade agreement discussions. FoEI2(1): Cross-regional climate justice mobilization and exposure of 2 cases of dirty energy projects and their negative impact on the potential for sustainable development (including respect of human rights and gender-related aspects), puts the need to transition away from fossil fuels even higher on the political agenda. FoEI3(1): Proposals related to agroecology (local markets, inclusive policy development, investment) receive increased support from LLMIC governments pushing them higher on the agenda in international processes lead by the UN Committee on World Food Security (CFS), and the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(4)]: FoEI worked with Milieudefensie and a CSO from Uganda to produce materials to stop ISDS and the impacts of oil drilling in Uganda. The materials supported Milieudefensie advocacy work in the Dutch BIT reform process and the Ugandan CSO&apos;s oil campaign. The petition was presented by Milieudefensie to the Dutch government. FoEI also supported CSOs from Korea, Australia and Uruguay to provide a submission to the Dutch BIT reform process. Their inputs were sent to and reviewed by the Dutch government [1]. FoEI also supported an Australian CSO to produce an ISDS briefing paper &#x2018;The case for banning Investor State Dispute Settlement in Australia&#x2019;, which was used in advocacy work around the TPP trade deal and for submission to the Australian senate. It resulted in a political party [1] adopting two recommendations from this paper. Furthermore, FoEI supported a South Korean CSO to undertake lobby and advocacy work at the UNCITRAL Asia ISDS reform meeting. FoEI supported the CSO to develop key anti-ISDS arguments and responses to pro-ISDS messages. The representative of FoE South Korea spoke with government officials at the UNCITRAL meeting and on a panel at one CSO side-event [1]. FoEI published the report &#x2018;RCEP, A secret deal. Trade talks fail the transparency and public participation test&#x2019; in cooperation with TNI and other allies. The report provides an analysis on the secrecy around the RCEP negotiations in nine countries and gives recommendations on how to democratize this process to improve transparency and public participation. This report was covered by the media [1]. [FoEI2(1)]: FoEI published a &#x2018;Transforming our Economies: Scaling up the Solutions&#x2019; report in three languages. The solutions in this report were brought in discussion by a CSO from Argentina at the G20 in an event with allies. [FoEI3(5)]: The People&#x2019;s Demands (shaped by people&#x2019;s movements including FoEI and its member groups) were submitted by a Togolese CSO to the UNFCCC secretariat [1] at COP24 in December and discussed during a press conference by media and CSOs. Press coverage was also achieved for an action co-organised by FoEI on the impunity of oil companies. The FoEI&#x2019;s People Power Now! Energy Manifesto was launched at the UNFCCC COP 24 during a public event where it was discussed by unions [1], CSOs and indigenous people [1], media [1], and state representatives [1]. [FoEI4(1)]: The High Level Panel of Experts of the Committee on Food Security (HLPE, a science-policy interface of the UN Committee on World Food Security (CFS)) [1] made substantial changes to five areas of the Zero draft on agroecology, following the five substantive comments made by civil society. The civil society input was organized by the drafting team of the working group on agroecology of the Civil Society Mechanism to the CFS, which is facilitated by FoEI. [FoEI5(1)]: FoEI participated in a delegation of the International Planning Committee to the Committee on Agriculture (COAG, a platform linked in partnership with the FAO, representing 800 CSOs and 300 million small scale food producers) with the result, after FoEI&apos;s input to the FAO analytical framework for agroecology had been discussed at the FAO Expert workshop on multi-dimensional assessment of agroecology, that the COAG [1] included two civil society demands in its final report to the FAO council for adoption. One demand is on agroecology as an approach towards a sustainable food system and the other on mainstreaming of biodiversity across agricultural sectors. [FoEI6(2)]: As a result of lobby by FoEI and five other organisations, the UN Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) [1] removed &#x201C;voluntary commitments&#x201D; from the draft text about the process to develop post-2020 objectives for the CBD. The organisations also successfully advocated including civil society participation in the first regional meeting in this process. Furthermore, FoEI organized four actions to claim space and visibility through joint actions at COP 14 of the CBD for civil society positions on gene drives, Indigenous Peoples rights, the need for a holistic approach to biodiversity and exposed the vested interest of corporations in the negotiations of the COP. FoEI representatives were interviewed, and civil society positions on key issues were better reflected in media [1] than in previous years, as a result of FoEI communication support for civil society at the CBD COP 14 in Egypt in November. [FoEI7(1)]: FoEI position on food sovereignty was shared and experiences were discussed with 200 civil society organizations from 12 LLMICs (Burkina Faso, Niger, Nigeria, Uganda, Senegal, Benin, Mali, Guinee, Ivory Coast, Ghana and Togo) in November in Togo during the West African Caravan on the Convergence of Land, Water and Seed.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1:] FoE groups continued to make the critique of ISDS a part of public and political discourse. FoEI supported a CSO in South Korea to co-organise Civil Society Forum&apos;s and official stakeholder engagement at the 20th round of RCEP negotiations (South Korea, November) on the issue of ISDS, including speaking on panels and media articles. FoEI provided financial support for staff at a CSO in the Philippines to discuss the issue of ISDS at the IP Summit, a large indigenous community gathering (Manila, October) and to participate in ISDS fora in Nueva Vizcaya and Quezon City (July). [FoEI2:] FoEI was invited by the Civil Society Mechanism (CSM) of the UN Committee on World Food Security and Nutrition (CFS) to facilitate the working group on Sustainable Forestry for Food Security and Nutrition. This working group collected input, made joint analysis and prepared the statements, both in the negotiations with the High Level Panel of Experts (HLPE) and at the forum of the CFS44 (October 9-13, Rome). The High Level Panel of Experts (HLPE) presented draft recommendations that were negotiated at the policy round table with government delegates at the CFS44 on sustainable forestry for food security and nutrition, to which Civil Society Organizations made at least 10 statements to improve the content of the recommendations to strengthen the rights of forest dependent people. The improved recommendations were approved by the CFS44. At the CFS44 forum meeting (government delegates, food related UN institutions), Civil Society Organisations made 5 proposals to advance food sovereignty and agroecology that were supported by government delegates. These are: 1. Recognition that forests are not just trees but also encompass people especially forest dependent people who are small-scale producers and feeding the majority of the world. 2. Recognition that the recommendations are particularly important to address the needs of indigenous peoples and local communities and smallholders especially forest-dependent people who have a spiritual, cultural, social, political and economic relationship with forests. 3. Recognition that gender equality and women&#x2019;s and girls&#x2019; empowerment, respecting their rights, and access to forest and land tenure, agriculture and forestry support services, capacity building, and fostering women&#x2019;s equal participation in decision making is essential to achieving food security and nutrition and should be mainstreamed across all policy recommendations. 4. Recognition of the traditional practices and the key contribution of indigenous peoples and local communities and smallholders when managing sustainably and in an integrated manner land, forests and trees while achieving food security. 5. Agreement by the CFS to further discuss the negative impact of plantations on food security and nutrition [FoEI3:] In Palestine in meetings with the Ministry of Women&#x2019;s Affairs and the Energy Quality Authority concerns about gender equity and women&#x2019;s empowerment in relation to energy management raised by a Palestinian CSO, receiving financial support from FoEI, were favorably received and a recommendation to develop a guidance document on mechanisms for gender mainstreaming in energy management and energy policies will be developed. [FoEI4:] FoEI coordinated a delegation of 7 people (representatives of CSOs from Germany, Uruguay, Argentina, Brazil, and FoEI&#x2019;s Real World Radio) to participate in the World Trade Organization (WTO) ministerial conference in Buenos Aires (Dec 10-13) and Peoples Summit, including direct advocacy to negotiators as part of OWINFS coalition, signing on to two civil society statements, organising one event on economic justice solutions, many speakers on panels, responding to banning of civil society (including FoE regional representative), mobilizing/organising protest and communication support to Fuera OMC coalition. FoEI carried out communications work to support the delegation. FoEI&#x2019;s key messages were: People must be included in trade policy discussion; Do not expand the WTO into dangerous new areas of investment, e-commerce and domestic services regulation; Reform public stock-holding for food sovereignty. These were advocated directly to country delegations inside the WTO and in the media. This was one the biggest civil society and social movement WTO mobilisations in a decade with thousands of people on the streets, good media coverage and coordinated advocacy on the inside of the negotiations. This contributed to ensuring no new harmful issues were agreed at the WTO.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: FoEI&#x2019;s positions developed on planetary emergency, false solutions and pathways towards climate justice will be discussed at the COP26 by social movements and are expected to be covered by the media. [FoEI2(1)]: FoEI&#x2019;s positions on the current trade and investment system (a system that transfers enormous powers to multinational corporations whilst undermining the fundamental rights of women and men to work, food and a clean environment) in relation to the WTO and large-scale infrastructure projects will be covered by the media. FoEI advocates people powered economic justice solutions like cooperatives and public services that reduce inequality, contribute to equitable power relations including between women and men and expand the role of cooperation, community management and sustainable planning in all aspects of life. [FoEI3(1)]: FoEI&#x2019;s proposals on agroecology, specifically concerning: (i) the implementation of the FAO Global Knowledge Product on Agroecology; and (ii) the FAO Committee on Agriculture (COAG) work on agroecology will be discussed at the upcoming FAO regional conferences. FoEI will contribute to this outcome by engaging in advocacy for the proposal at the FAO and by coordinating the participation of CSO representatives from Asia, Africa and Latin America to promote agroecology in regional FAO civil society consultations, and by supporting the engagement of civil society in similar advocacy by facilitating the International Planning Committee for Food Sovereignty (IPC) of the food sovereignty movement&#x2019;s working group on agroecology. [FoEI4(1)]: FoEI positions in relation to biodiversity, community forest management, financialization of nature and food sovereignty are discussed in the Committee on Biological Diversity (CBD) process to develop a post-2020 framework on biodiversity, including at the CBD COP15 in China and receive media coverage. FoEI will contribute through advocacy, delegation preparation and coordination, communications activities and engagement with the International Planning Committee of the Food Sovereignty movement&#x2019;s working group on agrobiodiversity. FoEI&#x2019;s critique of financialization of nature mechanisms and its vision on biodiversity receives media attention as a result of FoEI communications work.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="10">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1a(1)]: FoEI&apos;s analysis on the climate crisis linked to the Covid-19 pandemic, which resulted in a set of climate justice principles on Covid-19 and climate and which were taken up in FoEI&#x2019;s Just Recovery principles (see 1.C FoEI2), were discussed and integrated into the statements of one African, and one global climate justice movement CSO network.
[FoEI1b(1)]: FoEI, an African LLMIC CSO and a European national CSO (France) co-released a report on a gas development project in the African country exposing how a foreign state and companies fuel violence and devastation through their involvement in the development of gas mega-projects in LLMICs. The outcomes of the report received widespread coverage in the media.
[FoEI1c(1)]: One African LLMIC CSO received media coverage of their proposal to move away from fossil fuels to sustainable, renewable energy in their country. FoEI provided financial, strategic and communication support.
[FoEI2(3)]: FoEI&#x2019;s positions on the current trade and investment system in relation to financial relief bailouts from Covid-19, and to stop trade and investment treaty negotiations during the Covid-19 outbreak, aiming to prevent corporations from profiting from the pandemic at the cost of the public interest (see 1.C FoEI2) were covered by the media. FoEI&apos;s advocacy on a large-scale international infrastructure project may have contributed to critique being picked up by a governmental think tank, and led to this think tank presenting a policy proposal for increasing environmental and human rights regulation of investments overseas.  
Furthermore, FoEI together with FoE groups and allies (also from LLMICs outside the Mercosur region) campaigned against the EU-Mercosur trade agreement, a.o. by publishing the research report &apos;Burning Amazonia. A Global Corporate Crime. A Warning to Stop the MercoSur-European Union Free Trade Agreement. This may have contributed to the agreement being further delayed, via the use of the research findings and positions documented in the report, in advocacy in the EU (see 2020 report Milieudefensie and FoE Europe, 2.A.a MD2, 2.B FoEE2, 2.D FoEE1, 2.D MD2). 
[FoEI3a(2)]: The FAO civil society consultation in Latin America and Caribbean, with FoEI input, led to a final declaration that was read at the 36th FAO regional conference (October 2020), urging governments to implement public policies for agroecology in partnership with social movements; denouncing the attempts of corporate capture of agroecology; and proposing how FAO should support the implementation the civil society vision on agroecology. The International Planning Committee (IPC) of the Latin American and Caribbean Peoples Food Sovereignty Alliance had organized together with other CSOs in the region and the FAO Regional office the Regional CSO Consultation of the 36th FAO Conference. FoEI participated in the IPC and the civil society consultation with three delegates from FoE groups in the region, including one from a Central American LLMIC. Furthermore, the IPC of the (global) Food Sovereignty movement promoted their vision and demands for agroecology and made visible different initiatives of corporate capture of agroecology, resulting in agroecology being put on the agenda of the Committee on Agriculture of the FAO (COAG), during its 27th meeting in September 2020. FoEI is a facilitator of the (global) IPC working group on agroecolgy
[FoEI3b(1)]: FoEI cooperated in formulating recommendations from the Civil Society Mechanism (CSM) of the Committee on World Food Security (CFS) in a report on the radical transformation of food systems needed in response to the Covid-19 pandemic, &apos;Voices from the Ground. From Covid-19 to Radical Transformation of our Food Systems&apos; (October 2020), in which data collected from all regions and CSM constituencies on Covid-19 and food systems are analysed. Furthermore, FoEI collaborated in presenting this report during a panel addressing government delegates and the CFS Chair at the CFS High Level Special Event on Global Governance of Food Security and Nutrition (October 2020). 
[FoEI4(1)]: Proposals from CSOs in relation to the Convention on Biological Diversity&#x2019;s (CBD) post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework (GBF) were discussed during the 2nd session of the Open-ended Working Group (February 2020) and at the CBD&#x2019;s Subsidiary Body on Implementation (April 202). The CSOs were successful in achieving that proposals on mainstreaming, decision making, conservation and restoration of ecosystems and financial mechanisms were included in the negotiation text. The proposals are important to avoid offsetting measures in the GBF and to strengthen the nature-based approaches and to strengthen the governance of Indigenous Peoples and Local Communities, as well as of small farmers. FoEI played a leading role in formulating the proposals and in developing the CSO advocacy strategy.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome F: Practice Changed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improved trade and investment policies and processes are implemented and enforced.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.F</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># mechanisms, policies and regulations implemented and enforced by national, regional and international government bodies to ensure policies related to trade and investment advance policy coherence for development in LLMICs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.F" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome B: Capacities Strengthened</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Increased capacity of civil society actors to research, network and advocate on trade and investment.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.B</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># CSOs in LLMICs that lobby and advocate for improved policies related to trade and investment, based on increased skills, knowledge or network contacts.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.B" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1-4(ia): WALHI/FoE Indonesia applied improved skills and knowledge regarding trade and investment in its participation in the RCEP (the proposed FTA of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations) round of negotiations taking place in December 2016. WALHI&apos;s representative was able to confidently engage on ISDS with trade officials and speak to the media on the issue, and WALHI co-organised the civil society summit happening in parallel of the trade negotiation talks and that highlighted the public concerns around the inclusion of ISDS in future trade deals. FoEI contributed to WALHI&apos;s capacity through: - financial support provided to the group to campaign on RCEP in Indonesia; - the organisation together with TNI of a three-day ISDS argumentation training for CSOs in the Asia-Pacific region in November 2016 the Philippines (with 40 participants); - the organisation of a cross-regional skillshare on trade and investment in Indonesia in November 2016. FoEI1-4(ib): In Africa, FoEI supported ERA/FoE Nigeria&apos;s trade campaigner to write a report on the impact of EPAs trade deal on the country (http://tinyurl.com/h6xuwtl) by assisting with the research, editing and funding the printing of the report. The report will be used by FoE Nigeria in 2017, including at a conference on EPA to be organised by several NGOs. FoEI1-4(iia): The ability of three LLMIC CSOs to call for a just energy transition has improved through the funding of specific projects of these organisations: - A project of PENGON/FoE Palestine on energy promoting their call for a transition to renewable energy. PENGON/FoE Palestine ran two series of trainings aimed at strengthening the ability of its members to lobby and advocate for the promotion of renewable energies in Palestine and at increasing the technical capacities of isolated communities to run and maintain solar projects. The lobby trainings targeted 17 environmental organisations (70% of the participants were women). Participants took part in lobby meetings organised by PENGON with the ministry of energy as well as in the preparation of PENGON&apos;s lobby materials. Meanwhile technical trainings were delivered in five different communities (30% of the participants were women), who improved their ability to deal with solar-powered facilities autonomously. PENGON built up from the problems encountered to anticipate in its lobby work on potential future problems for other projects. The rationale was to build up the skills and knowledge amongst the PENGON member organizations in order to build up their ability to contribute to (joint) campaign work in the future. - A project of ERA/FoE Nigeria to prevent the exploitation of polluting and energy-intensive bitumens (tar sands) in which ERA could build on experience and knowledge of FoEE with tar sands exploitation in Canada and tar sands exploitation plans in Madagascar and elsewhere in Africa. ERA works closely with communities impacted by oil and gas extraction projects in Nigeria. In 2016, one of the main focuses of ERA&#x2019;s work was to stop the development of tar sands exploitation in the country. This is crucial from an environmental and human rights perspective because the bitumen belt in Nigeria is very big, spreading across tens of thousands of square kilometers and exploitation could potentially impact thousands of communities and millions of people. As a result of local visits, the organisation of educational sessions about tar sands and the threats related to their exploitation, townhall meetings to get communities and local authorities organised in response to the government and companies approaching them with plans for exploitation, the communities&#x2019; knowledge of tar sands and their impacts on the environment and communities has greatly expanded. Townhall meetings and other focus group discussions organised by ERA have united communities that are normally very isolated and allowed them to speak together with one voice on the bitumen issue. Reaching out to communities through visits and meetings on location has allowed women to participate and learn, and to start taking part in the decision processes. - A project of (un-named) Honduras-based CSO to stop funding of hydroprojects detrimental to the environment. In Honduras, communities trying to resist developments that go against the interests of those in power face severe repression and violence, sometimes killings. This is the case in the two zones where the Honduras-based CSO is working &#x2013; Zona Lenca and Marcala La Paz, where most of the hydro concessions of the country are located. The Agua Zarca and Corral de Piedra hydro projects, which are both located in that zone and both present important threats for people and nature, are part of the organisation&#x2019;s priorities at the moment. The FGG-funded project as a whole allowed the Honduras-based CSO to increase its presence in affected areas and to develop its concrete help to communities who have no knowledge and capacities to question and oppose environmentally harmful projects; projects which also contribute to human rights&#x2019; abuses. By implementing the activities and providing capacity-building to more communities, the Honduras-based CSO developed its own capacities (getting organised internally to better reach out to isolated communities, adapting their capacity-building modules to the needs of communities on the ground, and integrating the safety and security aspects linked to the current context in Honduras). The Honduras-based CSO organised several modules of legal capacity-building for communities all throughout the projects. Staff members, volunteers and three lawyers visited local communities and trained them about their community rights and human rights. FoEI1-4(iib): FoEI coordinated FoE member group attendance at the International Coal Network&#x2019;s global meeting in the Philippines (October 2016), including CEJ/FoE Sri Lanka, WALHI/FoE Indonesia, Groundwork/FoE South Africa, JA/FoE Mozambique, Les Amis de la Terre France and CENSAT/Colombia, which was important for member groups in North and South to share knowledge and strategies in their campaigns against coal and advocate the need for a transition towards renewables. FoEI5: FoEI, a Honduras-based CSO, Latin American FoE groups, FoEE and Milieudefensie have contributed to raising international attention through lobby and advocacy including solidarity actions and petitions about the controversial aspects of the Agua Zarca hydro-electricity generation scheme in Honduras and the violation of EHRD civil rights following the murder on Berta Caceres, coordinator of a Honduras-based CSO. This has notably resulted in a commitment from the Dutch FMO to stop funding the project. At the national level however the government appears keen on going ahead with this project. The lack of full transparency around the murder of Berta Caceres is further complicating the situation on the ground, with threat of violence remaining very high. Considering the dangerous situation faced by Honduras-based CSOs in Honduras, their advocacy and public outreach is much more focused towards governments outside their territories and international public and media rather than their own authority. FoEI6: 11 environmental CSOs from Asia are more sustainable as a result of developing improved strategies for engaging and retaining youth in CSO related work. In Indonesia, 26-30 November 2016, WALHI/FoE Indonesia, hosted the event &quot;Building Second Generation Leadership&quot;. 14 youth participants from 11 environmental CSOs from 11 countries (RSEU/FoE Russia, BELA/FoE Bangladesh, FoE Japan, ProPublic/FoE Nepal, CEJ/FoE Sri Lanka, CELCOR/FoE PNG, SAM/FoE Malaysia, PENGON/FoE Palestine, KFEM/FoE South Korea, WALHI/FoE Indonesia, FoE Australia) took part in this regional-level event focused on building capacities of younger environmental activists to analyze key environmental issues in the region, e.g. Forest Fires and Haze; Trade and Investments in Asia; and to develop strategies for mobilizing, engaging and retaining younger generations in the work of environmental CSOs across the region. Participants were also trained on building effective lobby and advocacy campaigns, as well as practical skill development for social media campaigning in Asia.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="4">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">* For at least four member groups in LLMICs in Asia, Latin America and Africa: (i) trade and investment knowledge as well as lobby and advocacy skills on the topic have increased through the organisation of webinars, trainings and workshops, and (ii) their network contacts to advocate for a just energy transition have improved through the joint organisation and participation in a broad civil society mobilisation moment.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="19">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI 1:] With FoEI financial support one Palestinian CSO continued advocacy and lobby activities to promote renewable energy in Palestine. They successfully lobbied for modifications to bylaws in relation to incentives for investment in the clean energy sector and for gender to be mainstreamed into energy management. Additionally, they organized a national clean energy competition to promote research relating to and visibility of community clean energy initiatives; they created a clean energy map of projects implemented in the past five years or under construction in Palestine, which was adopted by the ministry of energy and natural resources as a national reference. They continued to build capacity with 15 communities and engineering staff at 13 municipalities to manage and maintain solar units. [FoEI2:] With financial support from FoEI one Latin American CSO used increased technical, knowledge and advocacy skills to build engagement of communities and their organizations, including indigenous peoples&#x2019; councils, in participatory processes to resist water privatization and energy projects that threatened rights and livelihoods, with the result that one municipal process to move towards water privatization was reversed and five communities issued statements of their intention to be free from mining and hydroelectric dams. [FoEI3:] Building on raised internal capacity one CSO in Togo, with financial support from FoEI, worked to empower communities and increase support among civil society organizations to advocate against the threats to rights and livelihoods posed by offshore oil exploration. Through community workshops, development of materials and outreach to journalists, awareness was raised and groundwork was laid for lobby work to begin, which was delayed in 2017 due to the political crisis in Togo. FoEI also supported this work with a solidarity and fact-finding visit, developing materials related to the case and communications work to make it visible to a larger audience. [FoEI4:] In Togo, FoEI provided input to the trade campaigner at one CSO to contribute to the organization of a workshop for Togolese civil society on the impact of EPAs on the country and the advocacy that followed. [FoEI5:] In 2017 FoEI provided international and regional coordination and financial support to FoE Asia Pacific to carry out research and produce a report &#x201C;Asian Development Bank: Stop Financing Coal&#x201D; for use by Sri Lankan and Philippines CSO partners in advocating against coal and fossil fuels in official meetings and civil society activities related to ADB and AIIB in order to pressure for change in the banks&apos; investment policies; in Indonesia where an Indonesian CSO advocated against investment in coal, as well as during FoEI&#x2019;s international day of action (October), during activities at UNFCCC COP23 in Bonn (November) with a Japanese CSO in relation to the Japanese government and banks investment in two coal power plant expansion projects in West Java, Indonesia. FoEI gave visibility to the Indonesian campaign by helping to produce and distribute materials (case study, video and photos) about the cases and the negative impacts of coal. [FoEI6:] 17 CSOs from LLMICs (El Salvador, Guatemala, Haiti, Cameroon, Ghana, Liberia, Mali, Mozambique, Nigeria, Tanzania, Togo, Uganda, Nepal, Palestine, Philippines, PNG, Sri Lanka) participated in regional workshops coordinated by FoEI to increase their skills and knowledge in lobby and advocacy for agroecology and each region decided to collaborate to produce lobby materials that can be used at the national, regional and international levels. 13 of these started to connect at the regional level to network on agroecology and have been involved in joint work to produce advocacy materials, used at the national level in the ongoing campaigns of the CSOs in the respective countries and where relevant also at the regional (FAO regional symposia) and international levels (CFS, FAO, CBD). Building on their participation in FoEI capacity building workshops and joint strategy development on food sovereignty and community forest management, one Indonesian CSO lobbied at the 44th session of the Committee on World Food Security and Nutrition (CFS) 9-13 October in Rome for improved policies related to trade and investment to advance food sovereignty and agroecology. [FoEI7:] With FoEI funding one Mozambican CSO supported community representatives to take part in the 2nd Southern Africa Permanent People&#x2019;s Tribunal (PPT) August 17-18 in Johannesburg, South Africa, and present cases of threats to rights and livelihoods caused by a large agribusiness initiative and a dam project, advocating for the right to say no to destructive development pathways. [FoEI8:] FoEI financially supported one CSO in El Salvador to work with allies to demand a ban on incineration of agricultural products and solid waste, ban on agrotoxics and called for the creation of a Vice Ministry of Water in El Salvador to respond to the threat of water privatization. [FoEI9:] In 2017 FoEI continued to work with civil society to increase understanding of the critique of ISDS and to build capacity to advocate and lobby against the inclusion of this mechanism in trade negotiations. Last year&#x2019;s &#x201C;Hidden costs of RCEP and corporate trade deals&#x201D; produced with TNI was translated and adapted for use in lobby and advocacy activities in 2017 (in India, South Korea and Indonesia). A 40-page ISDS lobby guide for activists was produced (with TNI and CEO) and distributed to over 500 people and used during training workshops. In June a webinar training on trade and investment was organized for 17 FOE member groups (including CSOs in Togo, El Salvador and Philippines).</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="12">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1(1): With advocacy support from FoEI, an Southern FoE member group will work on one environment-related ISDS case including advocacy for reform directly to the Southern government and international institutions and raise awareness of the negative impacts of investment protection. FoEI2(2): FoEI will contribute and increase the impact of one regional campaign for trade justice in which 2 Southern member groups are involved, and support 2 Southern member groups in other regions to campaign more effectively for a just trade and investment system. FoEI3(5): With communication, strategizing and advocacy support from FoEI, 5 LLMIC CSOs lobby and advocate to stop harmful energy projects (coal, gas, hydro) and influence wider government policy/laws on energy. FoEI4(1): With communication and advocacy support from FoEI, FoE Palestine will continue its ongoing lobby and advocacy to promote solar energy in Palestine. FoEI5(3): With communication and strategizing support from FoEI, 3 LLMIC CSOs engage in lobby and advocacy of their governments to advance policy recommendations on agroecology in the FAO regional symposia and UN CFS.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="36">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: FoEI together with Milieudefensie worked with a CSO in Uganda to produce a video and an international petition to stop ISDS and the impacts of oil drilling in Uganda. The video was used as a tool by FoE Uganda in their oil campaign to raise awareness amongst the general public. The materials also supported Milieudefensie advocacy work in the Dutch BIT reform process. A petition was presented by Milieudefensie to the Dutch government. [FoEI2(1)]: FoEI provided financial and strategic support to a CSO in Indonesia to attend and advocate at the EU-Indonesia trade negotiations meeting and civil society forum. FoEI provided communication support for a call to audit World Bank funded projects during the IMF/World bank summit. [FoEI3(+1)]: FoEI supported advocacy on key dirty energy cases across the world. FoEI gave strategic and content support to CSOs in Japan and in Indonesia for advocacy towards banks to stop funding Indonesian coal plants. The FoE demands, which included proposals to change funding policies and practices, were discussed between one bank and the Japanese CSO. FoEI also supported a Mozambican CSO&apos;s gas campaign in developing and advocating demands to private banks to stop the funding of gas exploration and projects and to link them to UNESCO to request their support. [FoEI4(+1)]: FoEI organised and supported a Climate Justice and Energy Week of Action across the FoE federation with strategic support, campaigning materials and content. Results of the Week of Action support to groups in LLMICs: a CSO in Togo highlighted the impacts and risks of offshore oil exploitation with a press event and launched a video on offshore oil in Togo. A CSO in Mozambique organised public actions opposing a mega-dam and monoculture plantations. Content development included establishing FoE positions and materials on BECCS (bio-energy with carbon capture and storage) and 1.5 degrees and the IPCC report. CSOs used the findings in their national contexts to push for policy change around fossil fuel phase out or scale up of renewables. The Mozambican CSO used the materials to build the knowledge of other CSOs in their network on the current situation of climate science and advocated on FoE positions established in the federation in a meeting at a Climate Change platform. The CSO from Togo used the materials to advocate towards the national government to emphasize the negative impacts of the extractives industry and in particular offshore oil exploitation in Togo. [FoEI5(14)]: FoEI supported a CSO in Palestine to share their experiences with solar power and gender mainstreaming of energy policies with the FoE federation and allies by organising two &#x2018;Women &amp; Energy&#x2019; webinars. Furthermore, the Palestinian CSO built knowledge on the clean energy sector and clean energy policies of 13 women CSOs and CBOs which they used in advocacy towards the several Palistinian ministries. [FoEI6(+3)]: An LLMIC CSO delegation from Mozambique, Sri Lanka [1], Indonesia, Togo, Uganda, Nigeria [1], El Salvador [1] and Palestine attended the UNFCCC COP24 in Bonn in December. Pre-COP24 preparation and collaboration with FoEI and other FoE member groups ensured FoE members could strongly advocacy for climate just policies in COP24 actions. [FoEI7(+0)]: FoEI as facilitator of the working group on agroecology of the International Planning Committee facilitated the civil society participation in the FAO 2nd &apos;International Symposium on Agroecology on Scaling up agroecology, to achieve Sustainable Development Goals&apos; that took place on 3-5 April 2018 and coordinated the civil society input into this symposium, leading to the adoption of at least four civil society demands that were included in the Summary of the Chair. [CSOs in Nigeria and El Salvador applied the capacity built, and have already been counted above]. [FoEI8(+4)]: After having contributed to a FoE video on agroecology and community forest management in 2017, a CSO from Togo took the initiative to organize a workshop to develop a joint strategy in the region, including CSOs from Togo, Liberia [1], Uganda, Nigeria and Cameroon [1], to promote agreoecology and community forest management. FoEI supported this workshop financially and with facilitation of the sessions. It was the first time that a joint analysis was made specifically for the region and a first attempt to coordinate and work together on the issue. A draft action plan that includes lobby and advocacy objectives was made and will be implemented in 2019 and 2020. Furthermore, the Food Sovereignty, and Forests &amp; Biodiversity programs of FoEI, in collaboration with other programs, organized a 5 day strategic workshop in Cameroon to develop a strategic framework for FoEI on agrocommodities. There were 24 participants from 18 countries, of which 8 from LLMICs (Indonesia, Papua New Guinea [1], Sri Lanka, Honduras [1], Nigeria, Liberia, Mozambique, Cameroon), sharing experiences, strengthening networking around these issues, building knowledge including via a field visit to a community negatively impacted by agribusiness operations, and developing a joint multi-year strategy in relation to agrocommodities. With this framework for strategies, the lobby and advocacy work is clearly focusing on promoting alternatives to the current agribusiness model, including agrocommodities plantations. FoEI contributed with logistics, coordination and facilitation support for this meeting. [FoEI9(+0)]: FoEI supported a CSO in Papua New Guinea to coordinate joint research on land rights security of local and indigenous communities in Asia Pacific. Land related laws in six Asian countries were analyzed that can be used in lobby &amp; advocacy activities to fight landgrabbing and to strengthen the rights of people to land. CSOs from the Philippines, Palestine, Indonesia, Malaysia, Sri Lanka and Papua New Guinea reviewed the laws and contributed to a publication, which will be translated into local languages for lobby and advocacy purposes. Capacities of the mentioned groups to do research, make joint analysis and working together have been strengthened. Joint advocacy activities will be implemented in 2019. [FoEI10(+6)]: A CSO from El Salvador with the financial and content support of FoEI coordinated a research with a CSO from Guatemala [1] and 7 CSOs from other Latin American countries of which 2 LLMICs (Honduras and El Salvador) on agrocommodities and their impacts on people and environment. The findings will be used by a network of NGOs and CBOs in El Salvador working on agriculture and land related issues to do advocacy in the territories where they work, and nationally in a campaign to the Legislative Assembly to prohibit the use of agrochemicals. A series of sensitizing meetings was organized in four communities in El Salvador [4], with 52, 35, 81 and 31 people and with 25 organisations participating in a Salvadoran agroecology network [1]. The findings were published in December and the meetings took place late in the year. Networking and increased awareness among CSOs in El Salvador is taking place to prepare for L&amp;A on protection of food sovereignty and land. [FoEI11(+4)]: As a result of ongoing FoEI-funded regional facilitation of thirteen national member groups in Asia Pacific (of which 8 from LLMICs Bangladesh [1], East Timor [1], Indonesia, Nepal [1], Palestine, Papua New Guinea, the Philippines [1] and Sri Lanka) and the organization of a regional strategizing meeting in June in Nepal the design of a regional level campaign on trade and investment is being prepared by the groups, and joint work to scope out options for future joint work on issues of Chinese investments, including the Belt Road Initiative took place. [FoEI12(+1)]: FoEI provided financial and facilitation support for the School of Sustainability convened by the ATALC region in Cuba in November, resulting in the strengthened capacity of 12 regional member groups (3 from LLMICs: El Salvador, Guatemala and Haiti [1]) to engage in political processes in their countries an regions, and together with allied organisations and social movements, through their representatives that participated in the event. Based on an evaluation of previous pedagogical processes in the region, and the analysis of the current national and regional contexts, strategic plans were made for future capacity building and learning spaces and processes in the region. We expect to link these efforts to future lobby and advocacy outcomes.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="9">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(3)]: At least 3 CSOs from LLMICs (and CSOs in other countries) have their capacity strengthened to influence the dominant narrative as well as policies in their national context relating to Climate Justice including promoting equity and denouncing false solutions to climate change. This increased capacity is the result of FoEI&#x2019;s networking, strategizing and communication support. [FoEI2(3)]: At least 3 CSOs from LLMICs (and CSOs in other countries) have facilitated LLMIC citizens to advocate during the UNFCCC COP26 in the UK under a common narrative of planetary emergency and climate justice. This is the result of FoEI&#x2019;s networking, coordination, strategic and communication support aimed at making space for the presence of CSOs at the COP26 for southern voices. FoEI will ensure gender inclusive participation at the COP26 as well as the inclusion of feminist messages in FoEI COP mobilization messages. [FoEI3(+1)]: At least 2 CSOs from LLMICs (and CSOs in other countries) will increase their capacity to advocate for halting specific dirty energy projects and financial flows towards these projects. FoEI will support these CSOs&#x2019; advocacy actions with strategizing, highlighting their cases at the international level, and international mobilization, partly by using information gathered in previous years around dirty energy cases. [One CSO already counted above]. [FoEI4(1)]: 1 CSO from an African LLMIC has increased its capacity to develop the campaigning and advocacy capacity of communities potentially affected by offshore oil projects to advocate against the development of such projects. This is the result of FoEI&#x2019;s support in campaigning and financial support. [FoEI5(+0)]: Through strategic and financial support from FoEI, a CSO from an Asian LLMIC will increase its capacity to support the enhancement of women&#x2019;s participation and leadership in clean energy projects and advocacy towards the government to invest in and support women-led clean energy projects. [CSO already counted above]. [FoEI6(1)]: At least 1 CSO from an LLMIC will, in collaboration with multiple Asia Pacific CSOs and FoEI, increase its capacity to develop positions on a large-scale infrastructure initiative, to be used to address at international meetings of this infrastructure initiative environmental problems and human rights violations related to this initiative. [FoEI7(+0)]: Civil society representatives from at least two LLMICs participate in the Civil Society Mechanism (CSM) preparatory forum and annual UN Committee on Food Security (CFS) meeting and/or the CSM preparatory meetings and CFS negotiations about policy recommendations on agroecology, bringing their experiences and knowledge into the CSM efforts to influence CFS and FAO policies in favor of agroecology and community forest management as well as directly into the CFS space. Working with the food sovereignty movement and FoEI these CSOs will continue advocacy work calling for a CFS policy convergence process on agroecology. FoEI will support their participation through coordination and strategic capacity development. [CSOs already counted above]. [FoEI8(+0)]: FoEI will provide financial support for one LLMIC CSO in Latin America that will increase the capacity of a grassroots movement in the country (developing and promoting proposals, networking, strategizing, communication) to advocate for policies that support agroecology at the municipal level and advocate at the national level for a ban on the use of chemicals in food production and carry out an advocacy campaign on the link between agroecology and just energy transition. [CSO already counted above]. [FoEI9(+0)]: FoEI will provide financial support for one LLMIC group in Africa to advocate at the national level for chemical-free agriculture and a change in the national family law to better enable equal access to land for women farmers; at the local level they will advocate for agroecology and women&#x2019;s role in family farming. The CSO participates in FoEI cross-regional mutual capacity developing activities related to LLMIC CSOs&#x2019; strategies to promote food sovereignty (in which the advocacy capacity of this group is developed as well as, by this group, the advocacy capacity of the other participating LLMIC groups). [CSO already counted above].</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(2)]: FoEI further developed its narrative on climate justice by developing publications and demands in relation to carbon markets and net zero, finalizing research and analysis on sustainable and just pathways to keep global temperature rise below 1.5 degrees, producing an analysis on the climate crisis linked to Covid-19, and developing demands for a just recovery to the Covid crisis. These publications and analyses were used in national advocacy on fossil fuel development by CSOs from at least one African and one Latin American LLMIC.
[FoEI2(+0)]: With the UNFCCC COP26 postponed, FoEI focussed on preparing for the COP in 2021 by strengthening the network&apos;s analysis and develop clear demands on carbon markets, net zero, and 1.5 degree pathways, and building the knowledge of FoE groups and other CSOs on these issues through calls and webinars. FoEI organised several events during the online COP26 civil society gathering, including one where one FoE group from an African LLMIC spoke on financing of gas projects. FoEI co-organised four COP26 civil society online events with 8,000 participants globally. [CSO already counted above].
[FoEI3(+0)]: FoEI supported (strategizing, highlighting their cases at the international level, and international mobilization of CSOs and citizens) a CSO from an African LLMIC to map the companies and governments financing gas projects in their country and to release a report exposing the devastating impacts of foreign investments in gas projects. This information was used by the CSO in advocacy towards the national government to try to stop the gas projects. FoEI supported a non-LLMIC Asian CSO to lobby their government bank to not finance gas projects in this African country. [CSO already counted above].
[FoEI4(1)]: FoEI supported (strategy development) a CSO from an African LLMIC to work with communities whose territory and fishing waters are threatened by plans to develop offshore oil projects and support them to speak out about the impacts of the offshore projects online. The CSO developed a database of potential foreign financiers of the projects and campaigned towards the government to move away from dirty energy. 
[FoEI5(1)]: FoEI supported (financially and with strategizing) a CSO from an Asian LLMIC to strengthen the role of women&#x2019;s community-based organizations (WCBOs) in clean energy projects. The WCBOs were trained on mainstreaming gender in policies, lobby and advocacy, the clean energy sector and technical skills for operating clean energy projects. The WCBOs with support of the CSO organized lobby meetings with decision makers to strengthen women&#x2019;s participation in the energy sector, and to minimize the impacts of energy scarcity on women. Additionally, they held meetings with business incubators and social enterprises to promote women clean energy interventions and supported the creation of a women&#x2019;s council, made up of WCBOs and individuals that will actively promote women&#x2019;s engagement in the clean energy sector and lobbying for policy changes in the future.
[FoEI6(+7)]: FoEI supported multiple Asian Pacific, African and Latin American CSOs of which eight from an LLMIC to develop positions on a large-scale infrastructure initiative. Based on these positions, the groups advocated towards the national government leading this initiative (writing letters, media work). FoEI built the knowledge of CSOs from countries affected by this initiative. One Asian-Pacific LLMIC CSO (included in the aforementioned group) supported an indigenous community to defend their ancestral land from the negative impacts of a project connected with this large-scale infrastructure initiative. [One CSO already counted above].
[FoEI7a(1)]: FoEI contributed strategic input and helped to coordinate the development of a letter (November) from the International Planning Committee for Food Sovereignty (IPC), a platform of over 6000 organizations including LLMIC CSOs, to the FAO to demand they end a new partnership between the FAO and CropLife, the international trade association of agrochemical companies, which would undermine support for agroecology. (See also 2.D FoEI 3a).  
[FoEI7b(+1)]: The Civil Society Mechanism (CSM), including LLMIC CSOs supported by FoEI (coordination, strategizing, communication), to the Committee on World Food Security (CFS) provided critical feedback (February 2020) on the zero draft on Policy Recommendations on Agroecology and other Innovative Approaches, which was reflected in the CFS summary of feedback. FoEI supported, financially and with facilitation, the development of a positioning and capacity building document with input from eight CSOs in the Latin American and Caribbean region (including two LLMICs) called &apos;ATALC and the Construction of People&#x2019;s Emancipatory Agendas and Initiatives&apos; (February 2020), with information on food sovereignty and CFM and biodiversity to be used in lobby and advocacy at the CSF and CBD in 2021. (See also 2.D FoEI 3b). [One CSO already counted above].
[FoEI7c(+1)]: Five CSOs from LLMICs took part in a five-day Food Sovereignty Asia-Pacific School of Sustainability regional workshop in February 2020 organized and facilitated by FoEI and one of the CSOs. The training focused on food sovereignty and links to campaigns in the region, international and regional food sovereignty movements and FoEI interaction with them, and communications and digital media skills for food sovereignty. The trainings were connected to community visits and interviews with community people, from which participants created media materials for a local campaign, and a regional media strategy. [Four CSOs already counted above].
[FoEI8(+0)]: One Latin American LLMIC CSO supported financially by FoEI organized consultations and a meeting between peasants and policy makers on the development of a law in support of agroecology. This law is now awaiting approval in the Legislative Assembly. Additionally the CSO supported one municipality in its declaration as a territory free of pesticides and continued efforts to establish a national school on agroecology. [CSO already counted above].
[FoEI9(+0)]: One African LLMIC CSO supported financially and strategically by FoEI, in collaboration with other organizations, took part in ongoing campaigning and advocacy to promote agroecology at the local and the national level in the country, including women&#x2019;s role, by organizing several meetings and webinars in which CSOs, farmers and government officials took part, and preparing a magazine and a lobby document. [CSO already counted above].
[FoEI10(+1)]: FoEI provided strategic support to four civil society representatives, one from an African LLMIC CSO, and one from an Asian-Pacific LLMIC CSO, to participate in the Open-Ended Working Group of the UN CBD in February 2020 where the Post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework was discussed. [One CSO already counted above].</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="15">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(10)]: In 2019, FoEI will strengthen and mobilize 10 civil society groups and social movements in LLMICs to advocate under a common narrative of planetary emergency and climate justice by strengthening their network and knowledge. FoEI will do this by developing communication and campaigning materials and supporting joint advocacy actions. [FoEI2(+0)]: Five CSO partners from LLMICs will be supported by FoEI to block specific dirty energy projects and to influence wider government policy/laws to prevent investment in and development of dirty energy projects. The advocacy capacity of these CSOs will be strengthened through the support of FoEI in developing communication materials and through the support of FoEI in advocating to halt investments in dirty energy projects at national level and at international level advocacy forums. The CSOs will use the FoEI&#x2019;s People Power Now (PPN) Good Energy Manifesto and principles, which was jointly developed with Friends of the Earth groups in LLMICs, in the demands they put forward in their lobby and advocacy work in 2019. In 2019 FoEI will develop materials to make the PPN manifesto useful for the CSOs&#x2019; regional and national level advocacy. Further, FoEI will likely strengthen the CSOs&apos; advocacy capacity by bring together allies which will strengthen the PPN network. [FoEI3(+2)]: Training and awareness raising sessions at regional strategising meetings and / or FoEI&apos;s Schools of Sustainability in the Latin America and Asia Pacific regions will strengthen the capacity of 4 CSOs in LLMICs to engage in advocacy on trade and investment agreements and especially ISDS, including denouncing the differentiated impacts of trade and protectionism and injustice on women. The CSOs will use the strengthened capacities to advocate at their governments and at the international level for gender just, climate just and economic just trade and investment policies. [FoEI4(+0)]: 5 CSOs in LLMICs lobby and advocate at the national level to stop financialization of nature policies and practices, based on increased knowledge on the UN REDD Programme (Reducing Emissions from Deforestation en forest Degradation) and BECCS (bio-energy with carbon capture and storage) gathered in CSO meetings on the topic organised by FoEI and based on the positions developed in these meetings. [FoEI5(+3)]: At least 3 CSOs in LLMICs will engage in advocacy towards their governments to gain support for a round table process at the UN Committee on Food Security and Nutrition (CFS) to develop policies on agroecology. The groups do so with advocacy capacities strengthened together with other CSOs within FoEI&apos;s Food Sovereignty Programme.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="51">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1/2(24)]: FoEI supported (coordinating, strategizing, communications) 24 FoE and other groups, movements, and women CBOs in African (Ghana, Tanzania, Togo, Nigeria, Uganda, Mozambique, Liberia), Asian (Sri Lanka, East Timor, Philippines, Bangladesh, Indonesia, Palestine (6 organisations), India) and Latin American (El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Paraguay, Cuba) LLMICs to campaign, lobby and advocate for climate and environmental justice, against the adoption of carbon markets in the UNFCCC Paris Rulebook, and for gender sensitive and gender inclusive renewable energy laws and projects, both at the national level in LLMICs and at UNFCCC COPs and other international climate meetings. FoEI and FoE groups supported this advocacy through strategic coordination and preparation, providing materials and climate justice advocacy messages, and strengthening networks and connections with allied CSOs. [FoEI3(+0)]: Through strategic coordination, knowledge building and financial contributions, FoEI supported 7 CSOs from LLMICs in Asia (Sri Lanka, Malaysia), Africa (Togo, Ghana, Uganda, Mozambique) and Latin America (El Salvador) to lobby and advocate at national and international government bodies for reform on ISDS, the economic, environmental and social impacts of Free Trade Agreements, and for the inclusion of plastic waste under the scope of the Basel Convention to stop the free trade in plastic waste. [CSOs already counted above]. [FoEI4(+1)]: Increased capacity to lobby and advocate of 29 CSOs of which 6 from LLMICs (Cameroon, Nigeria, El Salvador, Guatemala, Philippines, Indonesia) for a transformative approach in the development of the 2020-2030 UNCBD&apos;s (Convention on Biodiversity) Global Biodiversity Framework (GBF) has led to a better zero draft of the GBF under discussion in 2020. The GBF will be guiding governments on how to prevent further loss of biodiversity, restore and strengthen biodiversity. One of the demands of CSOs and FoEI is to mainstream biodiversity in all sectors. A joint analysis on the rights inherent to Community Forest Management developed with input from 9 CSOs from LLMICs (El Salvador, Honduras, Indonesia, Philippines, Togo, Ghana, Nigeria, Mozambique, Sri Lanka) was used in discussions at UNCBD working groups Subsidiary Body on Scientific, Technical and Technological Advice (SBSTTA) 23 and 8jWG (Working Group on Article 8j) and at the CBD organized thematic consultation on effective area-based conservation measures for the post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework. [1 CSO not yet counted above, see also 2.D FoEI8 and FoEI9]. [FoEI5(1)]: With financial and communications support from FoEI 1 CSO from a Asia-Pacific LLMIC (Papua New Guinea) launched a report &#x2018;The Laws of Land Grabs in Asia Pacific&#x2019; on joint research they carried out with five other LLMIC CSOs (from Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines, Sri Lanka, Palestine) in the region on land rights security in Asia Pacific at an event with CSOs, a PNG state representative and the media. This supported their ongoing dialogue with the PNG government, including in the context of ongoing review processes of legislation on land, forestry, conservation and environmental protection. [See also 2.C FoEI3]. [FoEI6(+0)]: 1 CSO from an Asia Pacific LLMIC (Indonesia), with financial and strategic support from FoEI, strengthened their ongoing lobby and advocacy work in support of a coastal community resisting land/sea grab by the tourist industry with campaign training and meetings with the community and the development of a policy paper, which was delivered to the provincial government, media and other CSOs, and will be used as a tool in future lobby meetings. [CSO already counted above, see also 2.C FoEI4]. [FoEI7(+1)]: Following a FoEI-funded and facilitated regional capacity development and strategizing meeting on the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI, July, Bangladesh) 13 CSOs in the region, including from 8 LLMICs (Bangladesh, Indonesia, Nepal, Papua New Guinea, Philippines, Sri Lanka, East Timor, India) developed a joint strategy and communications plan for their work related to the BRI. In the mentioned meeting the organisations also developed a joint strategy, including a plan for a digital campaigning and food sovereignty training, which will take place in 2020. [1 CSO not yet counted above]. [FoEI8(+9)] An African LLMIC (Togo) CSO, with financial support and strategic input from FoEI, coordinated and facilitated a regional workshop for 16 CSOs from 7 LLMICs (Nigeria, Cameroon, Ghana, Uganda, Liberia, Mozambique and Togo, including 10 CSOs from the mentioned LLMIC (Togo) where the workshop was held), including representatives of feminist and peasant movements from the region, to strengthen capacities to advocate and lobby for community-based forest management and agroecology, build understanding on gender justice issues in relation to agroecology, and on policy processes at the Committee on World Food Security. As a result of the workshop (December 4-5) CSOs from across the region developed a joint strategy to mainstream gender justice in food sovereignty and system change forestry programmes into regional activities. [9 national CSOs from the LLMIC (Togo) counted; other CSOs already counted above]. [FoEI9(+15)] With FoEI financial support 16 CSOs in a Latin American LLMIC (El Salvador) took part in lobby and advocacy activities in support of a national law on agroecology developed and promoted by these organisations; the proposed law was presented to the Agriculture Commission of the Legislative Assembly on 22 October accompanied by a mobilization of 350 peasants. Furthermore, with the financial support of FoEI the CSO developed a National Agroecology School (a three-year training program on agroecology) for eight communities, which focuses on strengthening technical and political capacities of representatives of 14 CSOs in relation to practicing and advocating for agroecology as an alternative to the industrial agricultural model. Furthermore, with financial support from FoEI, the CSO strengthened the movement for food sovereignty by coordinating and facilitating two workshops (one on agroecology as a path to food sovereignty, November 12 and the second on the impacts of the industrialized agricultural production model, December 5) to build knowledge, lobby and advocacy capacities of CSOs from national eight regions. The workshops were part of an ongoing process to include civil society in the development and promotion of a national Law for the Promotion of Agroecology. Additionally, the CSO spoke at an event (October, 100 participants including a representative of the ministry of agriculture) about linking agroecology to the solutions to the climate crisis and contributed to raised capacities on the issue of gender and agroecology through the organization of an event for the exchange of experiences on agroecological knowledge, native seeds and rural women in the framework of the Day of Rural Women, October 15 with 150 participants (60 women) including farmers, grassroots groups and feminist organizations from five regions. [See also 2.C FoEI5 and 2.D FoEI10. One of the CSOs already counted above, 15 national CSOs counted].</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome E: Policies Changed</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Policies related to trade and investment are improved, so that they advance policy coherence for development.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.E</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># mechanisms, policies and regulations improved or introduced by national, regional and international government bodies to ensure policies related to trade and investment advance policy coherence for development in LLMICs.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.E" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1: The Palestinian authorities have responded positively to PENGON/FoE Palestine&#x2019;s initiatives on sustainable energy, and the government is keen on scaling up renewable energies to change the energy mix. PENGON&#x2019;s advocacy work has focused on the improvement of a Palestinian law adopted in 2015, leading to changes in the government conditions for private actors keen on investing in the sector that were adopted in 2016. Moreover PENGON cooperated closely with environmental specialists and the ministry of energy in order to devise a Pre-Master Plan on Solar Energy in Production in Palestine. It was discussed with other ministries, private sector (such as electricity companies), NGOs and donors through several meetings and workshops (during which additional recommendations were brought in) and finally adopted by the government in 2016. However challenges to meaningful impacts on the ground remain the political conditions in the region.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">FoEI1(1): One government in Asia Pacific adopts a &#x2018;redline&#x2019; policy to not negotiate trade and investment deals that weaken/undermine environmental protection or the right to regulate, following advocacy of CSOs in the region.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(0)]: Outcome not (yet) achieved in 2018. Advocacy work continues in 2019.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="3">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: A FoE group from Asia in various meetings with the national Ministry of Energy conveyed the challenges for women to be active in the clean energy sector. In 2019 this resulted in the Ministry of Energy including criteria for women to participate in clean energy projects in their annual plans. They also included encouragements for women to be able to invest in this sector. [FoEI2(1)]: FoEI successfully advocated for the removal of ISDS from the RCEP FTA. Such was decided for at the 26th RCEP negotiation round. Advocacy included meeting with various country delegations, co-organising a civil society conference on RCEP and a protest at the conference, and supporting media work, in coalition with other CSOs. [FoEI3(1)]: FoEI and FoE groups&#x2019; contribution to the campaign for the inclusion of plastic waste under the scope of the Basel Convention on the Control of Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal has had influence on the agreement by over 180 countries in the 14th COP in April and May on amendments to the convention resulting in increased transparency in the trade in plastics, the right for countries to know and refuse plastic waste imports through strengthened prior and informed consent measures. In 2019 FoEI and FoE groups were part of a strong movement that campaigned for the inclusion of plastic waste under the scope of the Basel Convention. This campaign contributed to pressure on governments which resulted in them speaking out against the free trade of plastic waste.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: National government legislation was passed in a non-LLMIC Asia Pacific country (Australia) banning the export of unprocessed waste from this rich country overseas to other countries including LLMICs. In the framework of its global campaign on plastic waste export and the Basel Convention on the Control of Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal, FoEI had advocated for such legislation in plastic waste exporting countries together with CSOs from LLMICs and non-LLMICs in the region.
[FoEI2(1)]: A municipality in a Central American LLMIC officially declared itself free of pesticides in October 2020. This happened after a meeting with 60 participants, and preceding communications work including press conferences and radio spots as part of the efforts to promote agroecology by a CSO supported by FoEI. The creation of a public policy of rejection of pesticides is a sign that agroecology is gaining ground in the country. This was also demonstrated with the creation of the law for the promotion of urban and peri-urban agroecological family gardens, which was presented to the legislative assembly by a CSO network in which the CSO supported by FoEI plays an active role in promoting agroecology, and jointly organizing consultations between peasants, government and the private sector on the law for agroecology. This agroecological gardens law is now waiting to be approved by the Legislative Assembly.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="2">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1:] In Palestine the Energy Quality Authority agreed to adopt regulations to encourage more investment in clean energy projects. New regulations were approved in relation to investment incentives for solar units. An agreement between the Ministry of Education and the Palestinian Investment Fund was signed to convert all governmental schools in Palestine to solar energy (more than 2000 schools). A CSO supported by FoEI has been advocating such measures for the past years. [FoEI2:] The Bandung Administrative Court in West Java, Indonesia revoked the environmental permit for a coal power plant, following a lawsuit and opposition from villagers and civil society organizations to the planned project. A CSO supported by FoEI had contributed to this.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
  <result aggregation-status="1" type="2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outcome A: Enabling Environment</narrative>
   </title>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The rights and (legal) space of people, communities and civil society actors in Low- and Lower-Middle Income Countries (LLMICs) active on trade and investment are protected.</narrative>
   </description>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.A.b</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># effective legal and other grievance mechanisms adopted or improved by governments via which CSOs and communities can resolve grievances with governments and companies related to trade and investment and claim their environmental, human and worker rights.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.A.b" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
   <indicator ascending="1" measure="1">
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">2.A.a</narrative>
    </title>
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"># mechanisms put in place or improved by governments that guarantee access for civil society to democratic decision making processes related to trade and investment, including the right to resist developments.</narrative>
    </description>
    <reference code="2.A.a" indicator-uri="https://fairgreenandglobal.org/" vocabulary="99"></reference>
    <baseline value="0" year="2016">
     <comment>
      <narrative xml:lang="EN">All baselines are set at 0</narrative>
     </comment>
    </baseline>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="1">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">[FoEI1(1)]: FoEI and CEO worked together during the UN Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) COP 14 in Egypt in November to successfully change the procedure to hire expert advice in the CBD process to avoid or manage conflict of interest. The organisations had conducted research into the consultants that are hired by the CBD to give expert advice about public goods. The secretariat took the matter up and has forwarded a draft text to the scientific advisory committee, stating that actors with a vested interest should not be hired for matters of the common good. This draft text has been approved by the COP. See decision 14/33 on the &#x201C;Procedure for avoiding or managing conflicts of interest in expert groups&#x201D;. With this procedure in place, CBD has adopted a different way of working that is contributing to more independent expert advice, which improves the democratic character of the CBD, which sets a framework for agricultural policy making by national governments.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2016-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2016-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2017-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0">
      <comment>
       <narrative xml:lang="EN">N/A. Targets set for the combined periods 2016 and 2017 are included in &#x201C;Period 2016-2017&#x201D;. Results achieved in the period 2016-2017 are reported under &#x201C;Period 2016&#x201D; and &#x201C;Period 2017&#x201D;.</narrative>
      </comment>
     </target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
    <period>
     <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
     <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
     <target value="0"></target>
     <actual value="0"></actual>
    </period>
   </indicator>
  </result>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
