<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR-17/DDA-3560/J-CfPAug17/BN/INGO/6912</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening winterization response in support of vulnerable Syrian and Jordanian households living in urban and rural areas in Irbid, Amman, Madaba, Karak, Tafileh and Ma&apos;an Governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The action aims to provide, in a targeted and equitable manner, most vulnerable Syrian and Jordanian families in urban and rural areas (including ITSs), with adequate resources to mitigate the impact of winter harsh conditions, thus protecting their life, health and dignity.
INTERSOS has developed significant expertise in the winterization response in Jordan, through projects and activities implemented since 2013 cash and material assistance has been guaranteed mainly in partnership with UNICEF, OCHA, and DG-ECHO. INTERSOS Jordan mission has thus acquired substantial capacities and expertise in identifying winterization needs and gaps, and in adequately and timely responding through cash assistance, NFIs distribution and emergency intervention during harsh weather conditions. As active member of the Basic Needs WG, of the Winterization, Harsh Weather Contingency, and ITSs Task Forces, INTERSOS guarantees: solid coordination with relevant actors deep knowledge of needs and gaps in the targeted areas capacity to operate in hosting communities and in mobile settings (ITSs) respect of nationally agreed standards operating procedures (SOPs). As in the past, the action guarantees extended geographical coverage from the North (Irbid) to the centre (Amman and Madaba) and the South (Karak, Tafileh and Ma&#x2019;an). 
The identification of the beneficiaries will be guided by the criteria established by the Vulnerability Assessment Framework (VAF), refined through INTERSOS assessment tool, while the assistance is in line with the guidelines approved by the Winterization Task Force, led by UNHCR. 
Cash assistance represents the core component, while the emergency response distributions INTERSOS normally provides in responding to harsh weather conditions, will be guaranteed through already secured funding from DG- ECHO. 

826 vulnerable HHs in six (6) governorates will receive winterization unconditional cash (approximately 4,129 individuals) hawallas (transactions) from specialized financial institutions, cash in-hand will be implemented when dealing with beneficiaries unable to use or reach ATM cash points. Beneficiaries will also be provided with informative leaflets on the process of the distribution, and on how to access complaint mechanism. 
50% of the total beneficiaries (approximately 413 HHs) will be in Irbid, 40% in Amman (with a 5% in Madaba) and 10% in the South (90% in Karak and 10% between Tafileh and Ma&#x2019;an). 
70% of the total beneficiaries (578 HHs) will be selected among Syrian refugees and 30% (248 HHs) among vulnerable Jordanian population

The action will build upon the following programs currently implemented by INTERSOS in the same governorates targeted by the present proposal: a DG ECHO action providing cash assistance, NFIs and emergency distributions in support of the most vulnerable individuals and families living in urban and rural areas (including ITSs). A Cash for rent program implemented in the same areas through a JHF funded action
The action will benefit from INTERSOS office in Amman, and its existing field offices in Irbid and Karak.
INTERSOS is committed to apply its cost sharing policy between the present intervention and its ongoing programs and to guarantee additional synergies in terms of logistical support, human resources and other direct costs, identification and the referral of extremely vulnerable cases.

Disabilities, minorities, age and gender is mainstreamed in INTERSOS overall program and in all the implemented activities, and will be taken into consideration throughout this proposed intervention. Mitigation measures, including internal tools, for potential protection concerns are already in place, while INTERSOS always guarantees full accountability of the Organization itself, of the action and of the staff involved.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-10" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marcello Rossoni</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962(0)796614738</telephone>
   <email>jordan@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="31">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Karak</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.02243739 35.69031941</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amman</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.91905968 35.92902353</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Irbid</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.55798676 35.84675724</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-11-10"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-31">112706.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-31">287292.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1">
   <transaction-type code="7"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-11-06">0.01</value>
   <provider-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="JOR73-6912">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-10-31">399999.02</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302980762">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-11-06">319999.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303461830">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-07-27">79999.8</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
