<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR-17/DDA-3560/J-CfPMar17/WASH/INGO/5771</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving access to WASH infrastructure and knowledge of hygiene best practices in Informal Tented Settlements (ITSs) in Irbid, Amman, and the southern governorates</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS is implementing its program in Informal Tented Settlements (ITSs) since 2014, providing different range of services, mapping needs and gaps, including access to safe water and to adequate sanitation facilities. With the proposed project, INTERSOS intends to respond to some of the above most critical needs refugees living in ITS are suffering from when accessing WASH services. It is important to stress that the present action will complement INTERSOS ongoing program, funded by UNICEF, and will allow INTERSOS to fill concerning gaps in the already implemented and/or scheduled WASH assistance. Specifically, the present intervention will improve access to safe water and adequate sanitation facilities for extremely vulnerable individuals and families living in those ITSs INTERSOS and UNICEF are not able to serve, or where the planned response is not sufficient to address all the needs. The planned action will also allow INTERSOS to timely respond to sudden increase in the population size of given ITSs, a common phenomenon in mobile settings. 

The action is to be implemented over a period of six (6) months: in the first month, INTERSOS will finalize the list of ITSs to be prioritized with distributions and installation of mobile latrines water tanks and handwashing stands, and procure the needed material procurement will be in line with INTERSOS regulations. SPHERE standards will be respected, while capitalization of the experience gained in the WASH intervention in ITSs with UNICEF will be ensured in the ongoing program, standard WASH mobile infrastructure for ITSs have been already designed and tested and will be used in the present action. In the first month INTERSOS will also prepare an initial WASH baseline in the ITSs. From the second to the fifth month (4 months), set up of WASH infrastructures, provision of water filters and latrines cleaning kits, establishment of gender balanced WASH committees, and hygiene awareness sessions will be implemented. The proposal provides the needed flexibility to address additional needs emerging during the implementation, if needed. Hygiene Promotion will use the &#x201C;Hygiene promotion in ITSs Manual&#x201D;, developed by INTERSOS and endorsed by UNICEF in 2016. WASH baseline and Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) exercise will be finalized during the last month. The hygiene promotion awareness sessions will be complemented with a distribution of hygiene and dignity kits. 
300 Syrian vulnerable families (approximately 1.500 individuals) in the four (4) governorates of Irbid, Amman, Karak and Ma&#x2019;an will be assisted with WASH infrastructure. 70% of the families this project will support &#x2013; approx. 210 families &#x2013; will be from Irbid governorate 20% from Amman &#x2013; approx. 60 families - 5% from Karak and 5% from Ma&#x2019;an &#x2013; around 15 families respectively. Considering the mobile nature of ITSs, often linked to the agricultural seasons, these are estimation that may change during the implementation. To improve tracking capacity and timely response, INTERSOS will be following the ITSs in their new location, thanks to the &#x201C;focal point&#x201D; system already applied in the INTERSOS/UNICEF intervention. 70% of the total beneficiaries will be selected among Syrian refugees and 30% among vulnerable Jordanian households most of the Jordanian beneficiaries, 130 HHs, will benefit from hygiene awareness sessions, and distributions of hygiene and dignity kits. Overall target of the intervention will be 430 families (approx.2150 individuals).
Synergies with INTERSOS ongoing program will be established to guarantee cost effectiveness, comprehensive assistance to beneficiaries, and internal referrals, when needed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marcello Rossoni</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>0796614738</telephone>
   <email>jordan@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="31">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Karak</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.02243739 35.69031941</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="11">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Amman</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.91905968 35.92902353</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Irbid</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.55798676 35.84675724</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="33">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ma&apos;an</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.18802033 35.72991609</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="11" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Water Sanitation Hygiene</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-06-15"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-22">371960.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-22">28037.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="JOR73-5771">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-22">399997.71</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302762569">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-11">319998.17</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303389441">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-12">47964.96</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
