<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <iati-identifier>XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR-17/DDA-3560/J-CfPMar17/Sh./INGO/5800</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF" secondary-reporter="0" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cash for rent assistance to vulnerable Syrian and Jordanian households living in urban and rural areas in Irbid, Karak and Ma&apos;an Governorates.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims at timely providing equitable, transparent and accountable support to vulnerable Syrian and Jordanian households (HHs) living in urban and rural areas through an Emergency Cash for Rent intervention with the purpose of avoiding severe risks of eviction and of supporting access to basic shelter and basic facilities and services. The proposal also aims at mitigating disproportionate rental increases and further forms of exploitation. In turn, the proposal aims at tackling protection and security concerns among the most vulnerable segments of the targeted population through legal protection and referrals. Unregistered refugees and/or refugees without a valid MoI card will be among those supported, being particularly subjected to protection and eviction risks.

The proposed project will be implemented over a period of seven months: one (1) month is needed for authorities&apos; approvals and recruitment, two (2) months will be dedicated to final identification of eligible beneficiaries, verification of documentation and signing of contracts (between landlords and tenants) and agreements (between landlords and INTERSOS). Core of the action will be the four (4) months of distribution of conditional cash for rent assistance, paid directly to the landlords, and awareness sessions on HLP rights for both tenants and landlords the last month will cover simultaneously the last tranche of payment and final Post Activity Monitoring (PAM).

A total of 410 vulnerable HHs (with an average of 5 family members) in the three (3) governorates of Irbid, Karak and Ma&#x2019;an will be assisted. Given the high influx of Syrian refugees in the North, 80% of the households this project will support &#x2013; approx. 328 households &#x2013; will be from Irbid 10% from Karak and 10% from Ma&#x2019;an &#x2013; around 82 families respectively. According to the national standards, 70% of the total beneficiaries will be selected among refugees and the other 30% among vulnerable Jordanian households &#x2013; totally 287 Syrian families and 123 Jordanian households will be assisted. It is anticipated that a slight majority of women will be directly supported with the proposed project as from our internal database single women are more exposed to challenges related to payment of rent. Identification of beneficiaries will be guided by the criteria established within the VAF, with additional protection-focused tools INTERSOS has developed and already tested. The assistance provided will be in line with the final Guidelines on Cash for rent, and on Increased Awareness about HLP Rights approved by the Shelter Working Group (2016), led by UNHCR, of which this organization is an active member. Lesson learned from the recently ended action have also been integrated in the current proposal.

INTERSOS has recently completed a Cash for Rent program in the same areas of the proposed project. The experience gained allowed INTERSOS to tailor the present project proposal in order to maximize its impact on the target population. This project will allow INTERSOS to continue supporting the most vulnerable HHs among those already targeted with the present action, and to include HHs previously identified but not supported due to funds availability.

INTERSOS has also a deep knowledge of needs and gaps in the target areas, where several projects in other sectors are implemented. Synergies with these projects will be established in order to guarantee both financial effectiveness and a comprehensive assistance to beneficiaries, who will be internally referred to increase their access to assistance.

Disabilities, minorities, age and gender are mainstreamed in all programs and activities and will be constantly taken into consideration throughout this proposed intervention. Mitigation measures, including internal tools, for potential protection concerns are already in place, while the organization will guarantee full accountability of the whole action and of the staff involved.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="2" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" role="1" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info>
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Marcello Rossoni</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <job-title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Head of Mission</narrative>
   </job-title>
   <telephone>+962(0)796614738</telephone>
   <email>jordan@intersos.org</email>
  </contact-info>
  <activity-scope code="4"></activity-scope>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location ref="31">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Al Karak</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>31.02243739 35.69031941</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="21">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Irbid</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>32.55798676 35.84675724</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <location ref="33">
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ma&apos;an</narrative>
   </name>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>30.18802033 35.72991609</pos>
   </point>
  </location>
  <sector code="4" percentage="100" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://www.humanitarianresponse.info/en/coordination/clusters">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Shelter and NFI</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="43010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-07-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">301924.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">97341.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="JOR73-5800">
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-06-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-06-21">399266.9</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3302755012">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2017-07-06">319413.52</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction humanitarian="1" ref="3303395846">
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2018-06-18">74827.22</value>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73" type="40">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan Humanitarian Fund</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTERSOS</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://pfbi.unocha.org">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan BI 2017</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="B17"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <related-activity ref="XM-OCHA-CBPF-JOR73-2017" type="1"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
