<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-4</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Scienze infermieristiche al Comboni College: didattica inclusiva  per le minoranze cristiane emarginate</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">La presente proposta, di durata biennale, ambisce a ridurre le disuguaglianze in Sudan, potenziando e 
promuovendo l&apos;inclusione. Nello specifico, intende supportare l&#x2019;accesso all&#x2019;istruzione universitaria nelle 
professioni sanitarie degli studenti appartenenti ai gruppi pi&#xF9; vulnerabili, in particolare i rifugiati e, tra questi,
le minoranze cristiane esposte a discriminazioni3
. 
Attraverso la partnership con Il Comboni College of Science and Technology (CCST), si costruir&#xE0; e attrezzer&#xE0; un 
immobile, sede del nuovo corso di laurea in Scienze infermieristiche con specializzazione in Cure palliative &#x2013;
oncologia e Ostetricia &#x2013; Unit&#xE0; di cure intensive. Le aule includeranno dei laboratori di simulazione per integrare 
il corso teorico con attivit&#xE0; pratiche al fine di garantire un apprendimento di qualit&#xE0; agli studenti, futuri 
professionisti del settore sanitario sudanese e ridurre i rischi di errore sui pazienti all&#x2019;inizio della carriera. Grazie 
alla collaborazione con il CCST, da anni impegnato nell&#x2019;offerta didattica,si aspira alla costruzione di un ambiente
sano, rispettoso, inclusivo ed accessibile.
Il contesto attuale rende particolarmente difficile ai rifugiati l&#x2019;accesso all&#x2019;universit&#xE0; pubblica, dove il voto 
dell&#x2019;esame di maturit&#xE0; ne filtra l&#x2019;accesso. I giovani rifugiati normalmente abitano nelle periferie dell&#x2019;area 
metropolitana di Khartoum, dove mancano servizi pubblici basilari come l&#x2019;acqua o l&#x2019;elettricit&#xE0;4
. A causa di questi 
problemi economico-sociali, di barriere linguistiche, culturali e religiose5 e delle discriminazioni subite, i rifugiati 
sono i pi&#xF9; svantaggiati in et&#xE0; scolare e faticano a raggiungere i voti minimi fissati per accedere a rette ridotte 
per le Universit&#xE0; pubbliche, restando cos&#xEC; esclusi dall&#x2019;educazione terziaria. Questo ha un impatto negativo sulla
loro mobilit&#xE0; sociale, creando una forte marginalizzazione. 
Le carenze del sistema sanitario sudanese sono dovute sia alla scarsa offerta di servizi, sia alla limitata 
competenza del personale6
, dovuta ad una inadeguata preparazione accademica. Quest&#x2019;iniziativa interverr&#xE0;
contemporaneamente sul settore sanitario e su quello educativo, prioritari per la cooperazione in Sudan, 
focalizzandosi sul bisogno di formare personale sanitario qualificato in uno spazio sicuro per le minoranze 
cristiane. Il CCST propone infatti rette accessibili a tutti e il 46% dei suoi 786 studenti universitari proviene da 
famiglie rifugiate7
. Il nuovo corso, cos&#xEC; come l&#x2019;intera struttura del CCST, sar&#xE0; aperto a tutti, per favorire la 
convivenza pacifica e ridurre il rischio di esposizione alla violenza dei beneficiari della minoranza cristiana. 
All&#x2019;interno del corso si imposter&#xE0; altres&#xEC; un programma di mentorship e tutorship, per rafforzare il collegamento 
tra percorso di studio e inserimento lavorativo. I beneficiari saranno gli studenti, che usufruiranno di un 
accompagnamento nel passaggio dall&#x2019;Universit&#xE0; ai servizi sanitari e i docenti, che vedranno rafforzate le proprie 
competenze didattiche. Si alimenter&#xE0; cos&#xEC; un circolo virtuoso di un&#x2019;istruzione migliorata e maggiormente 
integrata con il lavoro, consentendo prestazioni pi&#xF9; elevate da parte degli operatori sanitari, cos&#xEC; da migliorare 
i servizi per la popolazione. Inoltre, il nuovo edificio sar&#xE0; la sede del gruppo di volontari in cure palliative avviato 
al College dal 2018, che include studenti musulmani e cristiani dei diversi programmi accademici guidati dal 
personale del corso di cure palliative. I nuovi laboratori saranno usati per migliorare anche le competenze dei 
volontari attivi con i bambini del centro oncologico di Khartoum, contribuendo all&#x2019;inclusione di un gruppo di 
pazienti particolarmente fragile. Il gruppo sar&#xE0; anche coinvolto nella creazione di un centro comunitario di cure 
palliative nel quartiere di Haj Yousif, dove la chiesa ha un piccolo centro medico che serve gli abitanti di questo 
quartiere della periferia di Bahri, con una grande presenza di rifugiati sudsudanesi</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This two-year proposal aims to reduce inequalities in Sudan by strengthening and promoting inclusion. 
Specifically, it intends to support access to university education in the health professions of students belonging 
to the most vulnerable groups, in particular refugees and, among them, Christian minorities exposed to 
discrimination. 
Through the partnership with Comboni College of Science and Technology (CCST), a property will be built and 
equipped, home to the new degree course in Nursing Sciences with specialization in Palliative Care &#x2013; Oncology 
and Obstetrics &#x2013; Intensive Care Unit. The classrooms will include simulation laboratories to integrate the 
theoretical course with practical activities in order to ensure quality learning for students, future professionals 
in the Sudanese health sector and reduce the risk of error on patients at the beginning of their career. Thanks 
to the collaboration with the CCST, for years engaged in the teaching offer, we aspire to the construction of a 
healthy, respectful, inclusive and accessible environment.
The current context makes it particularly difficult for refugees to access public university, where the grade of 
the baccalaureate exam filters access. Young refugees normally live on the outskirts of the Khartoum 
metropolitan area, where basic public services such as water or electricity are lacking. Because of these 
economic and social problems, linguistic, cultural and religious barriers, the discrimination suffered, refugees 
are the most disadvantaged of school age and struggle to reach the minimum marks set for access to reduced 
fees for public universities, thus remaining excluded from tertiary education. This has a negative impact on 
their social mobility, creating a strong marginalization.
The shortcomings of the Sudanese health system are due both to the lack of provision of services and to the 
limited competence of staff, due to inadequate academic preparation. This initiative will simultaneously focus 
on the health and educational sectors, which are priorities for cooperation in Sudan, focusing on the need to 
train qualified health personnel in a safe space for Christian minorities. The CCST offers fees accessible to all 
and 46% of its 786 university students come from refugee families. The new course, as well as the entire 
structure of the CCST, will be open to all, to promote peaceful coexistence and reduce the risk of exposure to 
violence of the beneficiaries of the Christian minority. Within the course, a mentorship and tutorship program 
will also be established, to strengthen the link between study path and job insertion. The beneficiaries will be 
students, who will benefit from an accompaniment in the transition from the University to health services and 
teachers, who will see their teaching skills strengthened. This will fuel a virtuous circle of improved education 
that is more integrated with work, enabling higher performance by health professionals, to improve services 
for the population. In addition, the new building will be home to the group of palliative care volunteers 
launched at the College from 2018, which includes Muslim and Christian students from different academic 
programs led by palliative care course staff. The new laboratories will also be used to improve the skills of 
volunteers active with children at the Khartoum cancer center, contributing to the inclusion of a particularly 
fragile group of patients. The group will also be involved in the creation of a community palliative care center 
in the Haj Yousif district, where the church has a small medical center serving the inhabitants of this 
neighborhood on the outskirts of Bahri, with a large presence of South Sudanese refugees and Nuba displaced 
persons. Finally, the volunteer activity may concern the cycling club for girls and girls already hosted within the 
Comboni campus, which through sport deals with women&apos;s empowerment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="22000" role="4" type="22">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AISPO - ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; TRA I POPOLI ONG/ON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012590/05/4" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="11420" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Higher education</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="4.A" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Build and upgrade education facilities that are child, disability and gender sensitive and provide safe, non-violent, inclusive and effective learning environments for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, empower and promote the social, economic and political inclusion of all, irrespective of age, sex, disability, race, ethnicity, origin, religion or economic or other status</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="10" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reduce inequality within and among countries</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="5" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention on Biological Diversity</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="8" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Convention to Combat Desertification</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="7" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Adaptation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="6" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid Targeting the Objectives of the Framework Convention on Climate Change - Mitigation</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="2" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aid to Environment</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="11" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="10" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="12" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nutrition</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="3" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Participatory Development/Good Governance</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="4" significance="0" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trade Development</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="4"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-01-01">319727.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-10">799317.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AISPO - ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; TRA I POPOLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-17">479590.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="22">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AISPO - ASSOCIAZIONE ITALIANA PER LA SOLIDARIET&#xC0; TRA I POPOLI ONG/ON</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-01-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-02-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-03-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-3" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-4" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-5" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-6" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-7" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-8" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-04-9" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-0" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-1" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-2" type="3"></related-activity>
  <related-activity ref="XM-DAC-6-4-012590-05-3" type="3"></related-activity>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
