<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EUR" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-6-4-012355-01-0</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">Sinergie cliniche, formative e organizzative per le cure chirurgiche dell&#x2019;infanzia negli stati di Gezira e Kassala</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="IT">L&#x2019;iniziativa mira a rafforzare negli stati di Gezira e Kassala i servizi di chirurgia pediatrica di terzo livello e il sistema di precoce identificazione delle patologie malformative attraverso una rete di centri periferici e di medici di famiglia in modo di ridurre la mortalit&#xE0; neonatale e infantile, morbilit&#xE0;&#x2019; e disabilit&#xE0; da queste determinate. A tal fine verr&#xE0; sostenuto il centro di chirurgia pediatrica dell&#x2019;ospedale di Madani, polo didattico per la formazione specialistica post laurea; creato un centro specialistico di riferimento nel polo sanitario di Kassala (Kassala Health Citadel) in fase di sviluppo grazie a finanziamenti bilaterali, multilaterali e contributi EU assicurati da AICS; sviluppate delle reti di diagnosi precoce e prima terapia (sistema cos&#xEC; detto di Hub&amp;Spoke) e avviati partenariati formativo scientifici tra l&#x2019;UdA (centro d&#x2019;eccellenza italiano per la chirurgia pediatrica con gi&#xE0; attive collaborazioni in Sudan nell&#x2019;ospedale di Madani) e i poli universitari di Al Gezira e Kassala. L&#x2019;intervento prevede principalmente lo sviluppo delle capacit&#xE0; tecniche di chirurgia pediatrica e di gestione del malato e dei servizi ambulatoriali per i medici specializzandi e il personale medico e infermieristico ospedaliero, con particolare attenzione ad assicurare opportunit&#xE0; di partecipazione ai corsi e crescita professionale alle donne. La formazione verr&#xE0; assicurata da missioni di specialisti Italiani e da corsi del personale universitario e ospedaliero Sudanese preventivamente formato e aggiornato da UdA. L&#x2019;iniziativa inoltre garantir&#xE0; l&#x2019;accesso universale ai servizi di cura terziaria, come previsto dal sistema sanitario sudanese, promuovendo la lotta alla discriminazione per le patologie femminili e per i portatori di patologie malformative che inducono alla segregazione e discriminazione. L&#x2019;introduzione di screening delle malformazioni neonatali e la loro cura permetter&#xE0; anche la prevenzione di gravi disabilit&#xE0; che inficiano l&#x2019;integrazione sociale e l&#x2019;inserimento nel mondo del lavoro.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The initiative aims to strengthen the third-level paediatric surgery services in the states of Gezira and Kassala and the system for early detection of malformations through a network of peripheral centres and family doctors in order to reduce neonatal and under 5 mortality and morbidity and disabilities created by them. To this end, the paediatric surgery centre of the Madani hospital will be supported as national centre for post-graduate specialist training; a reference surgical centre will be created in Kassala Health Citadel, the health pole under development thanks to bilateral, multilateral funding and 
EU contributions insured by AICS; an early detection and first therapy networks created (so-called Hub &amp; Spoke system) and initiated scientific/training partnerships between the UdA (Italian centre of excellence for paediatric surgery with already active collaborations in Sudan in Madani hospital) and the university of Al Gezira and Kassala. The intervention mainly involves the development of technical skills in surgery and patient care and management of outpatient services for medical specialists and hospital medical and nursing staff, with particular attention to ensuring opportunities for participation in courses and professional growth for women. Training will be conducted by missions of Italian consultants and sessions by Sudanese university and hospital staff previously trained and updated by the UdA. The initiative will also guarantee universal access to tertiary care services, as provided for by the Sudanese health system, promoting the fight against discrimination for female and for those with malformations that lead to segregation and discrimination. The introduction of screening for newborn malformations and their treatment will also allow the prevention of serious disabilities that affect social integration and fully productive life.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11004" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11004" ref="XM-DAC-6-4" role="2" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org crs-channel-code="11004" role="4" type="15">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSIT&#xC0; DEGLI STUDI G. D&apos;ANNUNZIO DI CHIETI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <other-identifier ref="012355/01/0" type="A1"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SD" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <location>
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
  </location>
  <sector code="12110" percentage="20" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health policy and administrative management</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12181" percentage="70" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical education/training</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="12191" percentage="10" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Medical services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="5" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.5" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, eliminate gender disparities in education and ensure equal access to all levels of education and vocational training for the vulnerable, including persons with disabilities, indigenous peoples and children in vulnerable situations</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.2" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, end preventable deaths of newborns and children under 5&#xA0;years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.3" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, ensure equal access for all women and men to affordable and quality technical, vocational and tertiary education, including university</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, reduce by one third premature mortality from non-communicable diseases through prevention and treatment and promote mental health and well-being</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4.4" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2030, substantially increase the number of youth and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and vocational skills, for employment, decent jobs and entrepreneurship</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="5.1" vocabulary="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="3" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</narrative>
  </tag>
  <tag code="4" vocabulary="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all</narrative>
  </tag>
  <policy-marker code="1" significance="1" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender Equality</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <policy-marker code="9" significance="2" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn and Child Health (RMNCH)</narrative>
  </policy-marker>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2023-01-01">574525.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="2">
   <period-start iso-date="2024-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2024-01-01">574525.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-24">1788398</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commitment - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSIT&#xC0; DEGLI STUDI G. D&apos;ANNUNZIO DI CHIETI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2022-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="EUR" value-date="2022-06-30">639346.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disboursement - Financial Year 2022</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org ref="XM-DAC-6-4">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AICS - Italian Agency for Cooperation and Development</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org type="15">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSIT&#xC0; DEGLI STUDI G. D&apos;ANNUNZIO DI CHIETI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
