<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2021EASyr-5-CA001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 Syria Regional Appeal - Jordan - Cash Assistance for Essential Needs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2021, UNRWA will continue to provide cash assistance to PRS through a targeted approach prioritizing the most vulnerable with a higher cash transfer. PRS households where the head of family does not hold a Jordanian document receive US$ 40 per person per month, while PRS belonging to families where the head of household holds Jordanian documents, and who are hence more likely to have access to public services and other entitlements for Jordanian citizens, receive US$ 25 per person per month. Some 460 PRS and 152 Syrian refugees in King Abdullah Park (KAP), who are considered extremely vulnerable, will also continue to receive regular cash assistance. In 2021, to further support the resilience of PRS families, UNRWA will continue to provide a one-off emergency cash assistance with an average value of US$ 200. This support will be provided to an estimated 700 PRS families who experience a major shock or a crisis with distressing consequences on their economic situation. In 2021, UNRWA expects that more families will need this assistance due to the additional shocks created by COVID-19 and has increased the planned caseload from 2020 (passing from 450 families in 2020 to 700 in 2021). During the last quarter of 2021, winterization assistance will also be provided to all PRS. This assistance is provided based on family size, with families receiving between US$ 277 and US$ 453 depending on the number of members. This methodology is in line with the winterization assistance provided by the international community to non-PRS in Jordan. According to the 2019 Winterization Post Distribution Monitoring (PDM) conducted in the first quarter of 2020, 82 per cent of respondents reported that winterization assistance helped them to cope with the harsh winter season. To mitigate the additional socioeconomic hardship created by COVID-19, UNRWA will complement the regular assistance provided to PRS with two rounds of COVID-19 top-up cash assistance of US$ 100 per person per round for all PRS in Jordan, including those in KAP. According to the PDM conducted in September 2020, 30 per cent of respondents confirmed that the COVID-19 cash assistance provided by UNRWA was enough to cover their basic food and NFI needs. 56.7 per cent stated that the cash assistance had moderately helped to improve their living conditions post COVID-19 lockdown; and 59.2 per cent confirmed that the cash assistance had moderately reduced their financial burden. In 2021, UNRWA will also distribute cash assistance to the most vulnerable ex-Gazans and PRI who are struggling with the socioeconomic consequences of COVID-19 and who do not have access to the social safety net services provided by the government. Through this intervention, UNRWA plans to assist 27,635 households, comprising SSN and non-SSN ex-Gazans and PRI, with US$ 282.5 per household, disbursed in two rounds of US$ 141.5 per household per round. This includes 138,184 ex-Gazans (27,600 households) and 156 Palestine refugees from Iraq (35 households). UNRWA foresees an increase in the number of ex-Gazans applying for UNRWA COVID-19 assistance. Upon the availability of funds, and after verifying the eligibility of the applicants, UNRWA may need to adjust this intervention based on the number of beneficiaries. In 2021, should funding become available, UNRWA plans to join an inter-agency assessment of refugees in Jordan. The outcome will guide Jordan Field Office towards a comprehensive and context-related understanding of the vulnerabilities of Palestine refugees in Jordan, including PRS, to better inform planning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org/resources/emergency-appeals</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response/Emergency food assistance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/global-coordination-groups-beta">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SHL Emergency Shelter and NFIs</narrative>
  </sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="RSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1" vocabulary-uri="https://fts.unocha.org/plan-code-list-iati">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Refugee Response and Resilience Plan (3RP) 2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">22155124</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2021EASyr-5-CA001-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-09-30">8000126.18</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
