<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2020EAoPt-2-PI001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 oPt Emergency Appeal - Gaza - Protection</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Poverty, the consequences of recurrent hostilities, displacement, political instability, weak protection systems, sub-standard housing and overcrowding continue to increase protection vulnerabilities in Gaza, especially for women, children and persons with disabilities. The GMR demonstrations and the response thereto, including the excessive use of force contrary to applicable standards under international law, have also had a significant impact in terms of the protection risks of Palestine refugees. 

To mitigate and respond to the mounting protection risks and impacts, UNRWA will maintain its protection capacity and processes within programmes and services and will strengthen inter-programme coordination and cooperation and referral systems. Particular attention will be placed on responding to GBV and on promoting child protection, including addressing issues related to child labour, child marriage, reintegrating children who dropped out back into the classroom, assisting children with disabilities and respond to needs related to the impact of the GMR demonstrations on children. 

The training of front-line staff will continue across all UNRWA programmes, focusing on protection principles, referral systems, and GBV in emergency situations. UNRWA will also raise awareness about the protracted humanitarian crisis in Gaza and in particular the impact of the GMR on the rights of Palestine refugees, through active engagement in interagency coordination systems. The Agency will brief foreign delegations visiting Gaza on the humanitarian and protection environment and will advocate for efforts to ensure greater respect for Palestine refugee rights. 

In 2020, UNRWA will support special protection interventions, including through selected Community-Based Organizations (CBOs) and other non-governmental organizations (NGOs), for approximately 1,000 refugee children with disabilities. UNRWA is currently reviewing its support modalities to CBOs, including the provision of cash subsidies,  beneficiary vouchers, capacity-building advice and assistance to local organizations, initiatives supporting greater inclusion in current UNRWA programming, and/or deployment of temporary staff through UNRWA CfW Programme. 

In order to assist vulnerable women in need of legal aid services, including survivors of GBV, UNRWA will support the provision of legal counselling and legal representation, as well as other social interventions to approximately 5,000 Palestine refugee women in partnership with community based Women Programme Centres (WPCs). In addition, WPCs will be supported to raise awareness and involve Palestine refugee communities in the protection of women against GBV, to enhance both response and prevention. Support by UNRWA will be provided through cash subsidies or grants to selected WPCs and experts and/or deployment of temporary professional staff through the UNRWA CfW programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org/resources/emergency-appeals</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material Relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/global-coordination-groups-beta">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HPSE20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1" vocabulary-uri="https://fts.unocha.org/plan-code-list-iati">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">occupied Palestinian territory 2020 (part of 2018-2020 HRP)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">1200000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2020EAoPt-2-PI001-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">15649.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
