<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2020EASyr-0-CM001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 Syria Regional Appeal - HQ - Capacity and Management Support</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Within UNRWA, the Department of Planning is responsible for the planning and coordination of emergency response activities, including the regional component of the Agency&#x2019;s Syria Regional Crisis Response. This includes coordination with the humanitarian system at the regional level in Amman on programming, advocacy and fundraising, and the production of key documents and appeals and reporting and monitoring against these appeals. UNRWA participates actively in the Humanitarian Response Plan (HRP) for the whole of Syria and in the Regional Refugee and Resilience Plan  (3RP) and related technical and senior-level working groups.  When PRS are reported outside of the Agency&#x2019;s fields of operations, the Agency liaises with and refers cases to relevant partners for their follow up, in accordance with their relevant mandates and the status of PRS under international law. In 2020, through its liaison office in Egypt, UNRWA will continue its efforts to coordinate support to some 3,000 PRS in the country through the provision of health and food assistance, access to education and advocacy. 

Under this appeal, a senior emergency officer  maintains day to-day oversight of the Agency&#x2019;s response to the crisis and to ensure that dedicated capacity is available for political advice, emergency preparedness and response.  A statistician will be retained, to ensure the appropriate level of technical capacity for data monitoring analysis.  In addition, a regional cash assistance and poverty specialist will reinforce the Agency&#x2019;s technical capacity on cash transfers, including advice on levels of assistance and alignment with services provided by other humanitarian actors. This will improve both the effectiveness and efficiency of the Agency&#x2019;s cash based interventions.

The Department of Planning will maintain oversight of monitoring and reporting on emergency activities using an Agency-wide results-based monitoring (RBM) framework. The three field offices covered under this appeal continue to collect data on a daily basis and report to the RBM system on a quarterly basis. Progress on anticipated results will be reviewed at the field and Agency levels on a quarterly and semi-annual basis, respectively. External reporting will be provided twice a year through semi-annual and annual reporting. UNRWA will also maintain other headquarter functions in support of emergency operations, including engagement with international human rights mechanisms led by the Department of Legal Affairs. 

UNRWA continues to require additional capacity to reinforce the planning, management, monitoring and evaluation of emergency interventions and the safety and security of staff and refugees. This is vital for the efficient and effective delivery of activities and to maintain and build capacity to respond effectively to rapid-onset emergencies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org/resources/emergency-appeals</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="72050" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response/Relief coordination and support services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="10"></sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="RSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1" vocabulary-uri="https://fts.unocha.org/plan-code-list-iati">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Refugee Response and Resilience Plan (3RP) 2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">351359</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2020EASyr-0-CM001-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">39768.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
