<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2020EASyr-3-CA001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2020 Syria Regional Appeal - Lebanon - Cash Assistance for Essential Needs</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PRS in Lebanon continue to face significant humanitarian and protection needs. Protracted displacement, lack of livelihood opportunities and limited access to public services have disrupted the lives of PRS in Lebanon and severely undermined their coping mechanisms. Many PRS in Lebanon face a precarious and marginalized existence due to their uncertain legal status and limited social protection mechanisms, making them heavily reliant on UNRWA for their basic needs. Over 89 per cent of PRS in Lebanon are in critical need of sustained humanitarian assistance.  

Within this complex and challenging operating environment, UNRWA will continue to provide emergency assistance to meet the essential needs of PRS affected by the protracted crisis. 

In 2020, cash assistance to PRS will remain a priority for UNRWA emergency interventions in Lebanon. Given the high levels of vulnerability and dependency across PRS, UNRWA will continue to support all 27,700 PRS (8,450 families) with cash assistance, representing the total estimated PRS population in Lebanon in 2020, based on the results of the verification exercise conducted in August and September 2019. Targeted PRS will receive cash-for-food assistance of US$ 27 per person per month, in addition to multipurpose cash assistance of US$ 100 per month per family to cover a range of basic needs, including shelter and NFIs. 

In order to better assess the living conditions and the vulnerability of PRS in Lebanon, in 2020 UNRWA is planning to conduct a socio-economic survey of PRS in Lebanon. Depending on the outcome of the survey, the Agency will review its approach to cash assistance and adapt its interventions as appropriate to continue to provide a meaningful response to the most pressing needs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org/resources/emergency-appeals</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72040" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Emergency Response/Emergency food assistance</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="6" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/global-coordination-groups-beta">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SHL Emergency Shelter and NFIs</narrative>
  </sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="RSYR20" type="2" vocabulary="2-1" vocabulary-uri="https://fts.unocha.org/plan-code-list-iati">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Refugee Response and Resilience Plan (3RP) 2020</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-01-01">26228122</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2020EASyr-3-CA001-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2020-12-31">20777427.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
