<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2019EASyr-4-FS003</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Syria Regional Appeal - Syria -Livelihoods</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, the Technical and Vocational Education Training Programme (TVET) will maintain its long and short-term courses in Damascus, Dera&#x2019;a, Homs and Aleppo depending on the availability of funds. As demand for TVET services grows, the Agency will continue its efforts to better link students with the job market and increase employability rates of graduates. Reconstruction/rehabilitation-focused courses, such as electricity, plumbing or masonry, will continue to be an area of focus. Despite significant challenges, the microfinance programme continues to provide a growing number of loans to Syrians and Palestine refugees within Syria. In 2019, the microfinance team will continue to provide inclusive financial services to Palestine refugees and Syrians requiring additional capital through the direct disbursement of loans to meet the growing demand for financial products. The majority of the loans requested are consumer loans, which enable a household to cover unforeseen expenditures, such as the purchase of assets. Entrepreneur loans are less in demand, reflecting the ongoing constraints of the socioeconomic context in Syria.  UNRWA is also exploring the feasibility of conducting small scale cash-for-work initiatives in 2019. Work opportunities would be provided to support the provision of current UNRWA services (health, and education), or to support the restoration of Agency services in newly accessible areas.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="10"></sector>
  <sector code="73010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="1"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">20354281</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2019EASyr-4-FS003-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">21563.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
