<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2019EASyr-4-HI001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2019 Syria Regional Appeal - Syria -Emergency Health</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2019, UNRWA will continue to sustain the delivery of quality primary health services through 17 health centres offering the full range of Agency services, five health points (HPs) operating in areas of displacement of Palestine refugees and two mobile health clinics which are able to deploy according to needs. UNRWA health facilities provide a range of primary medical services, including out-patient consultations, vaccinations, growth monitoring, provision of medicine, gynaecology consultations, laboratory services, non-communicable disease care, maternal and child health care and dental services. Furthermore, the Agency provides support to Palestine refugees seeking secondary and tertiary health care through a system of referrals to public hospitals. UNRWA subsidizes the costs of treatment of referred patients by 75-95 per cent, depending on the socioeconomic status of the patient. UNRWA will continue to ensure that patients have adequate access to essential medical supplies and drugs. The Agency will also strive to maintain contingency stocks of medical supplies and drugs to address any emerging situation. Finally, UNRWA will focus its efforts on the resumption of health-care services in newly accessible areas and the rehabilitation and maintenance of damaged facilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="10"></sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="1"></sector>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-01-01">16132603</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2019EASyr-4-HI001-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2019-12-31">2535402.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
