<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2021EAoPt-6-PI001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 oPt Emergency Appeal - West Bank - Protection</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA protection interventions seek to address the direct humanitarian consequences of abuses, and the exposure to protection threats that arise from the IHL and IHRL violations. This will be undertaken through the Crisis Intervention Model (CIM) established by UNRWA, which consists of the identification of protection needs, the provision of psychosocial support, referrals to relevant specialized services (both internal and external to UNRWA) and the provision of cash assistance to families affected by protection concerns, following the completion of an eligibility assessment, carried out by a dedicated team of protection social workers. Advocacy and civil-military interventions are conducted in relation to the activities of the Israeli authorities and/or other duty-bearers, with a view to both promoting accountability for IHL and IHRL violations and advocating for policies and practices which uphold IHL and IHRL, improving the protection situation of Palestine refugees. UNRWA has also adjusted these interventions due to the COVID-19 emergency by developing guidelines on remote investigations of serious human rights violations. In 2021, UNRWA will also take active steps to strengthen its work in community-based protection models for advocacy, fostering conditions in which affected populations are able to advocate for their own needs. Specifically, UNRWA will establish dialogue platforms within the targeted communities; and will interact with targeted communities to promote improved information sharing, analysis and participation to build capacity for community-driven protection, including advocacy, access to services and coordination. Where appropriate and feasible, UNRWA will provide platforms for refugees to advocate on their own behalf during briefings, and will support refugees&#x2019; access to global forums and audiences, and international human rights mechanisms. 

Safeguarding neutrality remains critical for the continued operational effectiveness and safety of staff, beneficiaries and UNRWA facilities. In accordance with the Agency&#x2019;s regulatory framework, including the Neutrality Framework, and standard operating procedures, UNRWA will conduct semi-annual inspections of all its installations (over 200) in the West Bank. UNRWA Protection and Neutrality staff, together with senior UNRWA field staff, will conduct the inspections on UNRWA installations, documenting any neutrality breaches and reviewing them to take the necessary corrective actions. The majority of breaches identified generally entail resource issues such as the absence of a UN flag and/or sign. Protection and Neutrality staff along with senior field staff will discuss and take action to resolve other incidents that may entail more substantive neutrality violations. Staff understanding of neutrality, particularly Senior Area Staff and Installation Managers, will also be strengthened by providing technical advice (including in response to issues and breaches).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org/resources/emergency-appeals</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material Relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="10" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/global-coordination-groups-beta">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protection</narrative>
  </sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HPSE21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1" vocabulary-uri="https://fts.unocha.org/plan-code-list-iati">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">occupied Palestinian territory 2021 (part of 2021-2022 HRP)</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">3060181</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2021EAoPt-6-PI001-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-03-31">316627.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
