<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="USD" hierarchy="2" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-41130-2021EASyr-4-HI001</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2021 Syria Regional Appeal - Syria - Emergency Health</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The provision of health care inside Syria remains hindered by the widespread damage and destruction of health facilities, insufficient human resources and access constraints in some areas. While the general cost of living, including of health services, has dramatically increased since 2011, the ability of public and private hospitals and clinics to respond to the needs of the population has decreased. As a result, the vast majority of Palestine refugees in Syria have become increasingly dependent on UNRWA for the delivery of health-care services. 

In 2020, UNRWA will continue to deliver quality primary health services through 17 health clinics, six health points operating in areas of displacement of Palestine refugees and two mobile clinics which are deployed according to needs. UNRWA health facilities provide a range of primary medical services, including out-patient consultations, immunization services, growth monitoring, provision of medicine, gynaecology consultations, laboratory services, non-communicable disease care, maternal and child health care, dental and MHPSS services.  

Furthermore, the Agency provides support to Palestine refugees seeking secondary and tertiary health care through a system of referrals to public, private and NGO hospitals. UNRWA subsidizes 75-95 per cent of the total cost of treatment for referred patients, depending on the socio-economic status of the patient. UNRWA will continue to ensure that patients have adequate access to essential medical supplies and drugs and will strive to maintain contingency stocks of medical supplies and drugs to address any emerging situation. 

Finally, the Agency will focus its efforts on the resumption of health-care services in newly accessible areas and in areas of spontaneous return. Those areas will include the South (Dera&#x2019;a camp, Muzeirib, Jillin) and the South Damascus area, where accessible (Yarmouk/Yalda), as well as main gatherings, depending on access and based on needs. Should funding become available, UNRWA will also reconstruct its health facilities that have been completely destroyed by the hostilities in selected locations to ensure that Palestine refugees have access to services. The Agency will continue to deploy its mobile clinics to sustain the provision of medical and dental services to refugees in areas where facilities are not fully operational. UNRWA will also equip rehabilitated health centres with confidential spaces for patients facing protection concerns, including cases of gender-based violence (GBV) and violence against children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="XM-DAC-41130" role="4" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">unrwa</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNRWA</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <email>iati@unrwa.org</email>
   <website>https://www.unrwa.org/resources/emergency-appeals</website>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SY" percentage="100"></recipient-country>
  <sector code="7" percentage="100" vocabulary="10" vocabulary-uri="https://data.humdata.org/dataset/global-coordination-groups-beta">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health</narrative>
  </sector>
  <sector code="72010" percentage="100" vocabulary="1" vocabulary-uri="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/codelists/Sector/">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Material Relief assistance and services</narrative>
  </sector>
  <humanitarian-scope code="HSYR21" type="2" vocabulary="2-1" vocabulary-uri="https://fts.unocha.org/plan-code-list-iati">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syria Humanitarian Response Plan 2021</narrative>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </humanitarian-scope>
  <budget status="1" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-01-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-01-01">4779376</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction ref="2021EASyr-4-HI001-Expenditure">
   <transaction-type code="4"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-12-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2021-12-31">3291283.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Expenditure</narrative>
   </description>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
