<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="0" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-CHC-1137523-PF-FGMC-21-23</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-CHC-1137523" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Proforest Initiative</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using deforestation-free commodity supply chains to support national initiatives to combat forest loss</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Companies at all stages in palm oil, rubber, cocoa and timber/fibre supply chains are disconnected from national and subnational policy and governance processes to reduce deforestation. The project will provide guidance for companies on how to support specific, nationally-led processes to reduce deforestation in Indonesia, Ghana, Liberia and Cameroon, and how to implement social safeguards around land use governance at landscape scale. It will provide tools for Chinese companies to adopt more responsible sourcing practices and Chinese institutions to take more leadership in global sustainability processes. Lessons and case studies will inform COP 26 and offer models for scaling up.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org activity-id="pi-uk" ref="GB-CHC-1137523" role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Proforest Initiative</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="20">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CCCMC and other initiatives signed MoU to strengthen their collaboration 

Final implementation tools developed and incorporated into SNR Guidance 

Three workshops or webinars conducted for the palm oil downstream players in China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="20">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guidance for companies on engagement with respective policy process finalised 

Guidance on minimum human right safeguards at landscape level piloted at district level   

Case study to address deforestation outside concessions added to Guidance for Private sector to engage in landscape initiative.</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="20">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Guidance on engagement incorporates lessons on HRIA and stakeholder engagement in landscape 

Key Lessons from the development and operations of the Asunafo-Asutifi Landscape programme documented 

The capacity of companies, state actors and local community enhanced for effective engagement at the landscape level</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="CM" percentage="20">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National strategy and action plan/road map validated and disseminated 

REDD+ process revitalised with the involvement of the private sector 

HCV identified (further investigate HCV presence) in priority area in Mabangassina in the framework of land use planning process</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-country code="LR" percentage="20">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Private sector engaged with the national oil palm strategy 

Guidance for FPIC in the context of the 2018 Land Rights Law available for the private sector 

Government initiate action to harmonise policies on deforestation, gender and conservation</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <sector code="2" percentage="100" vocabulary="7"></sector>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-12-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">1200000</value>
  </budget>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
