<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>IM-CR-024714B-GG13-004</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="IM-CR-024714B" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">openmindedly</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines Typhoon Appeal</narrative>
  </title>
  <description>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Typhoon Haiyan was 300 miles across when it struck the Philippines on 8th November 2013. It
was one of the most intense tropical storms to ever make landfall anywhere in the world and
was accompanied by torrential rain, sustained winds of over 195mph and a storm surge of up
to 30 feet that devastated coastal areas.

Within the first month, the donations received through the DEC appeal enabled DEC member
agencies and their partners to provide aid to more than 1.6 million people in the Philippines.

The aid provided included:
(i)   ActionAid has reached 28,000 people on Bantayan Island off north Cebu, and on Leyte
and in East Samar. This has included food, shelter and hygiene kits.
(ii)  Age International has helped 39,500 people on Leyte Island. They&#x2019;ve delivered food
packages, psychosocial support and shelter materials.
(iii) British Red Cross working across 15 provinces via partners has given help to 725,696.
Aid has included food packages, hot meals in evacuation centres and counselling.
(iv) CAFOD working through partners have reached 361,790 in 13 regions, including
delivering shelter kits and food.
(v)  Care International is working in Ormoc, Albuera, Tolosa and Tacloban and has reached
over 43,750 people. Items delivered include kitchen kits, food and shelter kits.
(vi) Christian Aid through partners has given assistance to over 61,500 in areas including in
Ormoc on Leyte, in East Samar. Items distributed include water, food, sleeping mats,
and hygiene materials.
(vii) Concern reached 3,538 in Malangabang and Baliguian. Items distributed include
shelter materials and kitchen sets.
(viii) Islamic Relief has helped 115,000 in Bantayan, Leyte and the Camotes Islands.
Priorities have included providing food, water and shelter.
(ix) Oxfam working on Cebu, Leyte and Samar has reached 218,375 people with much
needed aid. This has included hygiene kits, sanitation projects, water and farming
assistance for those who have lost crops.
(x)  Plan working with partners has helped 24,000 in East Samar. This work has included
delivering shelter kits, water, and hygiene kits. Child friendly spaces have also been
created for children affected by Typhoon Haiyan.
(xi) Save the Children (including Merlin) have provided assistance to 20,433 in Leyte,
Visayas and Panay. This has been a mix of medial support with mobile clinics and
distributing emergency shelter materials, household items and hygiene kits. 
(xii) Tearfund has helped 28,377 people in Basey, Malabu and Dulag. Items distributed
include household items, water and sanitation items.
(xiii) World Vision has reached 106,260 people in across a number of areas including Capiz,
Aklan and Cebu. Food, hygiene kits, shelter kits have all been distributed. Child friendly
spaces have been set up for children affected by the storm</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="21">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Disasters Emergency Committee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GG-OAC" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-01-01" type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2013-12-31" type="3">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </activity-date>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2013-11-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2013-01-01">50000</value>
   <provider-org ref="GG-OAC">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-1062638">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <disbursement-channel code="1"></disbursement-channel>
   <flow-type code="10"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="110"></finance-type>
   <aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></aid-type>
   <tied-status code="5"></tied-status>
  </transaction>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
