<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-28882</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Piaggio Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The projects will have a number of important development impacts as follows:
(i) Improved access to economic life and mobility for individuals as well as micro/small enterprises in two IDA countries: In India, Piaggio&apos;s LCVs are sold to self-employed or micro/small business owners active in transportation of cargo and passengers and provide highly cost-effective solutions for distribution systems/logistics. In Vietnam, the project will increase competition and improve the quality of two-wheelers available to the consumers.
(ii) Enhancing competitiveness of the manufacturing sector in both countries and technology transfer: Through the projects, Piaggio will transfer technological know-how and help develop technical and management skills in the automotive sector.
(iii) Employment generation: The projects will benefit the local population by generating new employment, approximately 500 in Vietnam and 300 in India. In addition, significant number of indirect jobs are expected to be created along the value chain from suppliers to distribution and after sales services.
(iv) Demonstration effect: Successful completion of Piaggio&apos;s projects will boost confidence in both economies and provide a demonstration effect to other foreign investors.
 (v) Improved energy consumption in product manufacturing and product usage: Piaggio&apos;s technology is expected to be highly efficient in terms of energy consumption in the manufacturing. In addition, the vehicles manufactured will offer better fuel-efficiency and lower green house gas emissions as compared with the competition.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed investment includes support to Piaggio &amp; C. S.p.A. (Piaggio, or the Sponsor), for its two separate projects in Vietnam and India. The project in Vietnam comprises establishment and start-up of operations of approximately 100,000 units per annum (p.a.) capacity, green-field, two-wheeler manufacturing facility in Vinh Phuc, Vietnam, targeting domestic market and regional exports. The project is being implemented by Piaggio Vietnam Company Ltd. (PV), which was established in 2007. The project in India includes establishment of a plant to manufacture compact and more fuel-efficient 1000cc and 1200cc diesel and turbo diesel engines for light commercial vehicles (LCVs) and two-wheelers, with an installed capacity of 150,000 engines p.a. The project is being implemented by Piaggio Vehicles Private Ltd. (PVPL) in its existing LCV plant in Baramati, Maharastra, India. PVPL was established in 1998 and the planned engine investment targets exports and the domestic market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIAGGIO VIETNAM CO., LTD</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-28882" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2010-07-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2011-12-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mr. Mauro Prignoli, Senior Vice President, Finance
Viale Rinaldo Piaggio,
25 -56025 Pentedera Italy
Tel: +39 0587 272589
Fax: +39 0587 276274
mauro.prignoli@piaggio.com</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN-Vietnam">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The green-field plant in Vietnam is located in Vinh Phuc province industrial zone, 45 kms north of Hanoi. The plant in India will be an expansion of PVPLs existing location in Baramati, 160 kms southeast of Mumbai, in the state of Maharashtra.</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.1666700000 107.8333300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CD - Automotive and Light Vehicle</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $55.32 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2010-07-23"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2011-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-07-23">55320000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2010-07-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2010-07-23">55320000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">PIAGGIO VIETNAM CO., LTD</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/28882/piaggio-project">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
