<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-4867</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nghi Son Cement Corp.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Vietnam-Nghi Son Cement Corporation              Region    Asia        Sector       Project No004867   Projected Board DateJune 19, 1997   Company NameNghi Son Cement Corporation   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	The foreign sponsor, NM Cement Company Ltd. (NMCC), has a 65% ownership share in the Project.  NMCC is a consortium of the fourth and third largest Japanese cement producers, Nihon Cement Company Ltd. (70%) and Mitsubishi Materials Corporation (30%).  The local sponsor, Vietnam National Cement Corporation (VNCC), has a 35% ownership share in the Project.  VNCC is the state-owned company with responsibility for the production and distribution of cement in Vietnam.      Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	Project Cost is estimated at US$ 373 million.  The proposed IFC investment consists of an A Loan of US$ 30 million, and a B Loan of US$ 26.5 million.    Location of project and Description of site    	The Project involves the use of 103 ha in Thanh Hoa Province, 155 ha in Nghe An Province (for quarry operations) and 9 ha in Nha Be District, Ho Chi Minh City (for a distribution terminal).  The plant site will be located in Thanh Hoa Province, approximately 210 km south of Hanoi.  The distribution terminal near Ho Chi Minh City is located about 25 km south of the center of the city.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The Project is a joint venture to construct and operate a new 2.14 million tons p.a. cement plant at Nghi Son in northern Vietnam.  The Project expects to sell most of its cement in the domestic market and export the balance to other Asian countries.  At present, demand for cement in Vietnam exceeds domestic supply by over 1.5 million tons p.a., and this gap will continue to grow unless additional capacity is added. The Project is one of several new plants and expansions which will help to bring domestic cement supply and demand into balance, hence reducing the countrys dependence on imports.  Moreover, Vietnams natural endowments of limestone, coal and other raw materials provide the basis for developing an internationally competitive cement industry.  Having secured a site for the cement plant which is on the coast and near abundant limestone reserves, the Project will take advantage of these natural endowments while also benefiting from the sponsors strengths.  The foreign sponsors will contribute the technical knowledge and experience to build and operate a state-of-the-art plant with efficient production techniques, and the local sponsor will offer knowledge of the Vietnamese cement market.  This combination of attributes should enable NSCC to compete effectively in Vietnams growing cement industry and provide about 13% of the countrys cement production capacity in the year 2000.    Environmental Category and Issues    	This is a category A project under IFCs environmental review procedures.  Environmental issues associated with the Project include air emissions, liquid effluents, solid wastes, land use and resettlement, protection of marine resources and quarry reclamation.  Occupational health and safety issues include employee exposure to noise and dust.  Electrostatic precipitators will be installed to control dust emissions from the kiln line to less than 30 mg/Nm3, which is well within both the Government of Vietnam standard and World Bank guideline.  NSCC will cover or install dust collectors on coal, raw materials and cement products storage areas, and on the long-distance belt conveyor that will transport limestone, clay and pozzolana from the limestone quarry to the plant.  The plant will not discharge a significant amount of industrial water because the cooling water will be recycled.  Domestic sewage will be collected and treated by a system consisting of a stabilization pond and septic tanks.  NSCC will install secondary containment (e.g. dikes, berms) for the storage for oils, solvents and liquid fuels to prevent spills, and the contamination of soil, groundwater and surface waters.  NSCC will recycle or reclaim solid waste materials where possible.  If recycling or reclaim is not practical, solid waste will be disposed of in an acceptable manner, in compliance with local laws and regulations.   Approximately 140 families are being relocated as a result of the project; 57 in Hai Thuong Commune and 80 in Quynh Loc Commune in northern Vietnam, and several in Nha Be District near Ho Chi Minh City.  The Governments program for ensuring the fair and equitable treatment of the people being relocated includes a formal Resettlement Plan.  Employees at NSCCs operations will be provided with the necessary Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) to protect their health and safety.  The PPE will include, appropriate to the employees tasks and work area, respiratory equipment, hearing protection, and safety glasses, hats and shoes.    The  are  from the Public Information Center.       Host country location of environmental documents    Peoples Committee offices of Thanh Hoa Province, Nghe An Province, and Ho Chi Minh City       Date SPI sent to PIC May 16, 1997   For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 974-4384  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NGHI SON CEMENT CORPORATION - HANOI BRANCH</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-4867" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="1998-08-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="1999-11-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN-Vietnam">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.1666700000 107.8333300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AA - Cement</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $30.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="1998-08-12"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="1999-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-08-12">30000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="1998-08-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="1998-08-12">30000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NGHI SON CEMENT CORPORATION - HANOI BRANCH</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/4867/nghi-son-cement-corp">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
