<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SPI-7852</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nghe An Tate &amp; Lyle Ltd.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary Of Project Information (SPI)       Project Name    Vietnam-Nghe An Tate &amp; Lyle            Region    Asia        Sector       Project No007852   Projected Board DateJuly 1, 1997   Company NameNghe An Tate &amp; Lyle Sugar Company Ltd.   Technical Partner and/or Major Shareholders    	Tate &amp; Lyle PLC, the worlds largest sweetener manufacturer; (42%)   	Mitr Phol, one of Thailands largest sugar producers; (17.5%)   	The Vietnam Fund Ltd. (10.5%);   	Nghe An Sugar Co. (30%)	   	    Project Cost Including proposed IFC investment    	US$85 million of which IFC would provide up to US$20 million in the form of an A Loan and up to US$28 million as a B Loan.    Location of project and Description of site    	Phu Quy District, Nghe An Province    	Construction and operation of greenfield sugar mill in northern Vietnam for the production of high quality mill white and refined sugars.  The mill will be constructed on a 60 ha site in a predominantly agricultural region of the country.  Part of the site was formerly occupied by a small tea plantation.    Description of Company and Purpose of Project    	The Company has been established as a foreign joint venture under Vietnams foreign investment law.  The Sponsors intend to capitalize on the rapid growth in domestic demand for sugar forecast for the country.  Developmental benefits include direct employment of an estimated 700 mill workers; improvements in the domestic sugar industry such as greater processing efficiency (higher sucrose recovery) and improved quality; increased incomes for an estimated 22,000 smallholder farmers and their families who will supply the mills raw material under long-term cane supply contracts; and greater agricultural efficiency through the Sponsors planned introduction of higher yielding cane varieties, modern planting techniques and improved harvesting methods.  Indirect benefits resulting from demand by the Company will include the development of a cane hauling industry and strengthening of rural credit facilities.    Environmental Category and Issues    	The project has been rated environmental category B under IFC&apos;&apos;s environmental review procedure. Environmental and occupational health and safety issues associated with this project include site location, emissions, liquid effluent treatment, solid waste management and recycling and employee training, health and safety. The project is being developed in an agricultural area with a small village nearby.  Air emissions from the mill will consist of flue gases from the steam boilers and will be kept within local requirements and World Bank guidelines through treatment with a wet scrubber. Wastewater from the mill will be collected and treated in a full scale biological wastewater treatment plant established on-site and will comply with local requirements and World Bank effluent guidelines. Solid wastes generated by the plant will include bagasse, cane filter mud, boiler ash and scrubber sludge. Bagasse will be recycled as fuel for the mill&apos;&apos;s boilers. The other solid wastes will be returned to the farmers to spread on their sugarcane fields as a fertilizer supplement. NATL will implement a workplace health and safety policy commensurate with Tate Lyle policies worldwide. IFC will ensure ongoing compliance with World Bank guidelines during the life of the project by evaluating monitoring reports submitted annually to IFC by NATL and by conducting periodic site visits.    The  is  from the Public Information Center.       Date SPI sent to PIC     April 4, 1997      For Additional Information contact:  Corporate Relations Unit -   telephone: (202) 473-7711   facsimile: (202) 676-0365  Environmental documents for this project are available at http://www.ifc.org and from the World Bank InfoShop (http://www.worldbank.org/html/pic/aboutinfo.html).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nghe An Tate &amp; Lyle Ltd.</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SPI-7852" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-01-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2000-03-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN-Vietnam">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.1666700000 107.8333300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AB - Sugar and Confectionery</narrative>
  </sector>
  <country-budget-items vocabulary="1">
   <budget-item code="7.2.1" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
    <description>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN">Total: $20.00 million</narrative>
    </description>
   </budget-item>
  </country-budget-items>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="411"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2000-01-27"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2000-06-30"></period-end>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-01-27">20000000</value>
  </budget>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2000-01-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="USD" value-date="2000-01-27">20000000</value>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nghe An Tate &amp; Lyle Ltd.</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
   <flow-type code="35"></flow-type>
   <finance-type code="411"></finance-type>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/project-detail/SPI/7852/nghe-an-tate-lyle-ltd">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Project Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
