<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.02">
 <iati-activity hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.02" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>XM-DAC-903-SII-45972</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="XM-DAC-903" type="40">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BaF Vietnam Agri</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project has an Anticipated Impact Measurement and Monitoring (AIMM) rating of Good. The Project is assessed as part of the overarching programmatic intervention (ASF Asia Recovery Program) to respond to the impacts of the ASF on the regional pork industry. The most significant, expected Project-level outcome resulting from this expansion is the impact on consumers from the provision of safe pork at the time of severe supply shortage as well as implementation of advanced biosecurity procedures at the new farms. At the market level, the Project, alongside other planned investment, and advisory interventions, is expected to promote market resilience through improvement of biosecurity and disease management, both by supporting industry consolidation and disseminating best practices among smaller players.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed IFC investment consists of (i) a VND600 billion convertible bond and (ii) a VND300 billion senior bond to BaF Vietnam Agriculture Joint Stock Company (BaF or the Company) to support the Companys capacity expansion of its farm and food business across Vietnam (the Project). The Project is expected to provide BaF with a significant platform and presence in a fragmented market. With Vietnams pork sector severely impacted by African Swine Fever (ASF), BaFs expansion is expected to contribute to a recovery of pork supply as well as an improvement in biosecurity across Vietnam.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="70">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BAF VIETNAM AGRICULTURE JOINT STOCK COMPANY</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org activity-id="XM-DAC-903-SII-45972" ref="XM-DAC-903" role="1" type="40"></participating-org>
  <activity-status code="1"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Finance Corporation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <telephone>+12024733800</telephone>
   <email>ccspg@ifc.org</email>
   <website>www.ifc.org</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">2121 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW Washington DC 20433</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0  0.0000         &#xA0;  44/16 group 16, Dong Quarter, Vinh Phu Ward, Thuan An City, B&#xEC;nh Duong Province,   V  ietnam</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <contact-info type="2">
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BaF Vietnam Agriculture Joint Stock Company  Mr. Phan Ngoc An  Deputy CEO  +84 098 959 7219  anpn@baf.vn  44/16 group 16, Dong Quarter, Vinh Phu Ward, Thuan An City, B&#xEC;nh Duong Province, Vietnam  https://baf.vn/</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <location ref="VN-Vietnam">
   <location-reach code="1"></location-reach>
   <location-id code="1453782" vocabulary="G1"></location-id>
   <name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Project includes the Companys operations involving 13 sow farms, 18 hog farms, 1 slaughter and processing factory, and 2 feed mills at the following identified locations across Vietnam (locations not listed are as yet unidentified):   Sow farms:   Economic Village 2, Eatrol Commune, Song Hinh District, Phu Yen Province  Hoi Thanh Base, Tan Hoi Commune, Tan Chau District, Tay Ninh Province  Base 4, Suoi Day Commune, Tan Chau District, Tay Ninh Province  Suoi Day Commune, Tan Chau District, Tay Ninh Province  Dang Ha Commune, Bu Dang District, Binh Phuoc Province  Po To Commune, Ia Pa District, Gia Lai Province  Giai Xuan Commune, Tan Ky District, Nghe An Province   &#xA0;  Hog farms:   Suoi Day Commune, Tan Chau District, Tay Ninh Province  Hoa Hiep Commune, Tan Bien District, Tay Ninh Province  Thanh Binh Commune, Tan Bien District, Tay Ninh Province  Thung Base, Duc Binh Dong Commune, Song Hinh District, Phu Yen Province   &#xA0;  Slaughter and processing factory:   Block B1 Minh Hung - Sikico Industrial Park, Dong No Commune, Hon Quan District, Binh Phuoc Province   &#xA0;  Feed mills:   Nam Cam Industrial Park, Nghi Xa Commune, Nghi Loc District, Nghe An Province  Nhon Hoa Industrial Park, Binh Dinh Province</narrative>
   </name>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Location description</narrative>
   </description>
   <activity-description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">A description that qualifies the activity taking place at the location.</narrative>
   </activity-description>
   <administrative code="1453782" level="1" vocabulary="G1"></administrative>
   <point srsName="http://www.opengis.net/def/crs/EPSG/0/4326">
    <pos>16.1666700000 107.8333300000</pos>
   </point>
   <exactness code="2"></exactness>
   <location-class code="1"></location-class>
   <feature-designation code="ADMF"></feature-designation>
  </location>
  <sector code="1129" percentage="100" vocabulary="11" vocabulary-uri="http://www.census.gov/cgi-bin/sssd/naics/naicsrch?chart=2012">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A-BD - Other Animal Production</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="6"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="35"></default-flow-type>
  <default-aid-type code="C01" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/45972">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information - Anticipated Impact Measurement &amp; Monitoring (AIMM) Assessment and Main Environmental &amp; Social Risks and Impacts of the Project</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="TEXT/HTML" url="https://disclosures.ifc.org/#/projectDetailSII/45972">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Summary of Investment Information</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A12"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
