<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005594_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Discovering WF16: Building Engagement with Neolithic Archaeology as Pathway to Economic Development in Southern Jordan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As recognized in the UN&apos;s 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda, arts and humanities research can play a significant role in building sustainable tourism and by so doing contribute towards economic development. The DISCOVERING WF16 project will provide an exemplar case study by drawing on the results the AHRC funded 2008-2010 excavation of the early Neolithic settlement of WF16 to build a Neolithic Heritage trail in Wadi Faynan, southern Jordan.  This will help attract Jordanian and international visitors into this impoverished region of southern Jordan, providing employment and income into the local Bedouin community, while enhancing the visitor experience and providing a case study for the use of arts and humanities research in economic development. Following its discovery in 1996 and evaluation between 1997 and 2003, WF16 was subject to a major excavation between 2008 and 2010 (Figs 7 &amp; 8). The settlement was exposed as having a dense cluster of dwellings, workshops and a large communal structure dating to between 11,800 and 10,200 years ago with considerable significance for understanding the origin of sedentary communities and farming economies in SW Asia. Moreover, WF16 is the earliest of three Neolithic sites within Wadi Faynan, providing a unique Neolithic landscape for the region, and potentially for S.W. Asia as a whole. The Jordanian Ministry of Tourism and Antiquities (MOTA) and Eco Hotels have sought to develop sustainable tourism into Wadi Faynan as a means to both support the local Bedouin communities and for nature conservation. This has primarily been undertaken by promoting the wildlife, landscapes and traditional Bedouin lifestyles within Wadi Faynan and by the provision of an Eco-Lodge (managed by Eco Hotels) designed to provide a &apos;wilderness experience&apos; for visitors (Figs 3 &amp; 4). A local museum has been constructed by MOTA but has yet to be fitted with displays and information (Fig 6). Despite archaeology and cultural heritage being a major attraction for tourists visiting the World Heritage site of Petra, located a mere 50 Km from Wadi Faynan, the Neolithic settlements of Wadi Faynan have not been made accessible and marketed to potential visitors. By so doing, the DISCOVERING WF16 project aims to increase the number of tourists coming to Wadi Faynan, partly by attracting some of those who currently only visit Petra, and extend their length of stay in the Wadi. This will generate increased expenditure into the local economy while also enhancing the educative and recreational experience of both the visitors and the resident community. To achieve these aims, DISCOVERING WF16 will work with the MOTA, Eco Hotels and other relevant bodies to establish a Neolithic trail in Wadi Faynan. This will involve a Neolithic Heritage film to be shown at the Eco-Lodge and local museum, display boards for those venues, information boards at the Neolithic sites, a trail guide, and archaeological training for Bedouin guides. These outputs will also provide resources for utilisation by Jordanian bodies in their own initiatives relating to developing sustainable tourism into the region.  The Wadi Faynan Neolithic trail will provide an anchor for the South Jordan Neolithic Trail that will extend from Wadi Faynan to the Neolithic site of Beidha in the vicinity of Petra. This 50 Km walking/cycling/driving trail has been designed to provide access for tourists to a Neolithic sites in the region, drawing on the local communities for services such as food, guides and accommodation, and thereby supporting their development while enhancing knowledge and appreciation of the Neolithic archaeology and its significance for cultural developments in SW Asia. The Wadi Faynan Neolithic trail will provide a key component of this larger and long-term project, which will be promoted within the Neolithic Heritage Film and hence enabling the DISCOVERING WF16 to have impact beyond Wadi Faynan itself.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The DISCOVERING WF16 project will use the outcomes of the AHRC-funded project &apos;Excavation of WF16, an early Neolithic site in southern Jordan (2008-2010, AH/E006205/1)&apos; to build economic and cultural development within the economically depressed region of Wadi Faynan in southern Jordan by supporting sustainable tourism. This application is submitted under the highlight notice for international development. Wadi Faynan is located to the south of the Dead Sea on the eastern side of Wadi Araba in southern Jordan, at the eastern margin of the Dana Nature Reserve (Figures 1 &amp; 2).  This is a desert landscape, relatively isolated from the rest of Jordan. It is an economically depressed area into which eco-tourism is being encouraged as a means of sustainable development. In 2005 the Wadi Faynan Eco-Lodge, a small hotel constructed and run on sustainable principles, was opened to support eco-tourism into the wadi (Figures 3 &amp; 4). Although rich in archaeological remains, the heritage of Wadi Faynan has been insufficiently drawn upon to support such eco-tourism, despite thousands visiting Petra every year, located just 50Km south of Wadi Faynan. In recognition of this, the Jordanian Ministry of Tourism and Antiquities (MOTA) has begun to construct a museum within the wadi (Figure 6). The shell of the museum has now been completed and the MOTA has requested support from archaeologists who have worked within Wadi Faynan to support the development of its displays and activities.   The project will provide support to the new museum, the Eco-Lodge and the resident Bedouin community by contributing to the development of sustainable tourism into Wadi Faynan. The AHRC (AH/E006205/1) funded research project discovered an early Neolithic site, named as WF16 (c. 11.8-10.3 Ka BP), of exceptional quality and importance for understanding the transition from mobile hunter-gatherer to settled farming communities within Wadi Faynan. It is located in the vicinity of two later Neolithic sites, Ghuwayr 1 (c. 10.5-8.3 Ka BP, Figure 5) and Tell Wadi Feinan (c. 8.3-6.5 Ka BP), providing a unique heritage asset for the promotion of eco-tourism. This asset will be realized by constructing a Neolithic Trail to link the Eco Lodge, three Neolithic sites and the museum with associated display boards, trail guides and a Neolithic heritage film. In this regard, the project will contribute to the UN&apos;s 2030 Sustainable Development agenda of &quot;understanding the value of local cultural and heritage assets and their potential wider contribution to wellbeing and development&quot; and to use &quot;arts and humanities research contributions to the development of ...sustainable tourism&quot;.  It has four main objectives: 1. Enhancing the information about and accessibility to the Neolithic archaeology of Wadi Faynan to encourage sustainable tourism involving more and longer visits by tourists from outside and within Jordan and resulting in greater expenditure into the local Bedouin economy; 2. Enhancing the quality and extending the content of Jordanian and international visitor experience to Wadi Faynan by providing access to the Neolithic heritage, increasing their awareness of this cultural period and the role of southern Jordan in the transition to Neolithic farming societies, a development of global significance; 3. Building knowledge about the Neolithic heritage by the resident Bedouin community and by organizations involved with the socio-economic development in the region to build capacity and enhance their own initiatives and activities, notably the Jordanian Ministry for Tourism and Antiquities (MOTA), Eco Hotels and The Jordanian Tourist Board (JTB). 4. Using Wadi Faynan as a case study to draw lessons about how arts and humanities research can contribute towards sustainable tourism and economic development for use by international heritage and developmental organisations, such as International Council on Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS) and World Monuments Fund.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-19">60476.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-19">20158.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-19">80635.616</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to University of Reading</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005594_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FP005594%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
