<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V04348X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF_NF278 Building evidence on households, firms and value chains to support economic policy decisions under COVID-19</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGC has worked with policymakers in the nine named countries to identify key research questions to understand how COVID-19 is impacting their economy, how the economic recovery can be accelerated, which policy interventions should be implemented and how a</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IGC has worked with policymakers in the nine named countries to identify key research questions to understand how COVID-19 is impacting their economy, how the economic recovery can be accelerated, which policy interventions should be implemented and how assistance should be provided to those most in need. Our Co-Investigators, based in the named DAC-list countries, are uniquely positioned to implement a co-generation approach with policymaker partners to design research projects that will inform key policy decisions in the next 18 months and so will maximise impact from the research. Our Principal Investigator, IGC&apos;s Research Director, will leverage IGC&apos;s network of world class researchers to work with Co-Investigators to design high quality and robust research. This proposal will enable us to fund around 30 individual studies, all addressing first order priorities for policymaker partners, and building on the 34 COVID studies we have already launched. Research will combine existing administrative data, which Co-Investigators have good access to and familiarity with, and new data through phone surveys. Data priorities include monitoring value chains, firms and households&apos; economic activity, and measuring the effectiveness of policy interventions on economic agents. We will feed data and research findings back to our existing policymaker contacts, including monitoring dashboards, infographics and appropriate policy options, to facilitate real-time, evidence-based decision making in the participating countries. The two main research activities to be carried out under this project are: - Monitoring and tracking economic activity, focusing on the post-lockdown economic recovery, through descriptive analysis of administrative data and of new survey data generated using carefully designed survey instruments implemented by phone. The analysis carried out will help identify which firms and households are most affected by the economic crisis, the main constraints they are facing and the support they need from governments. Results will be made directly available to policymakers through a series of dashboards and high frequency policy reports. - Testing the effectiveness of policy interventions by building on sample frames from previous randomized control trials to measure the impact of current interventions and, where appropriate and feasible, of new interventions co-generated with policy makers. Comparative analysis undertaken by local and UK-based researchers will use crosscountry and cross-sector variation in policy interventions to assess the effectiveness of these interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-28" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-04-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-18">328357.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-18">659374.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-18">987732.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/V04348X/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">164178.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V04348X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FV04348X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-10-28"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
