<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V006657_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Designing Digital Sustainable Futures: Crafting through COVID-19 crisis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching project objective is to develop an inclusive low-cost sustainable digital ecosystem for craft and to theorise the valuation processes for craft in a digital environment, in order to address and respond to the impact of COVID-19 on the craft sector in Uzbekistan. The sector has been dramatically affected by the COVID-19, as the craft infrastructures of exchange rely extensively on face-to-face contacts, which have been interrupted due to lockdowns. Through GCRF COVID-19 focussed grant, awarded in April, we calculated that 79.1% of Uzbek craftmakers will stop their activities if urgent measures are not taken, causing socio-economic challenges and heritage loss, as craft practices are not codified. We will develop a roadmap to cascade the outcomes in other ODA countries facing similar challenges through a strategic partnership with the British Council.   In particular, the project asks:  1. What are the economic, societal and cultural values of craft? How can these be represented as an intangible heritage? How can these values be mobilised and represented digitally? 2. How can the digital ecosystem create value for craft in local and international markets?  3. How can the craft supply chain, dramatically impacted by Covid-19, be digitally integrated?  4. How can the limitations of the current Uzbek policies on digitalisation be overcome?    The digital ecosystem will consist of a digital library, training courses, a digital salon and mentoring system for female-led craft enterprises, and an e-commerce application.  The specific objectives related to ecosystem development are therefore:  O1) To codesign and develop an e-commerce platform that will increase employment amongst craft communities. This will be launched by November 2020, to promote and support craft makers&apos; sales for the Christmas period. It will be sustainable, inclusive, community based and include an innovative business model for the long term.    O2) To codesign and develop a storytelling virtual salon for mentoring craft women and promoting gender equality. Together with a mentoring system for women, the digital salon will enable inclusive participation, plurality of expression, and promotion of women&apos;s initiatives  O3) To codesign and develop a training toolkit for valuing craft digitally. The training will enhance the capability of Uzbek craft enterprises to sell products during the COVID-19 pandemic, first nationally and then internationally. It will enable craftmakers to improve their skills in managing, valuing and promoting craft as cultural heritage assets, and improve their digital business skills.  O4) To codesign and curate a digital library that will allow craftmakers to share knowledge on craft values and heritage, contributing to open and sustainable societies, as we will feature craft also from under-represented communities  Once developed, the platform will form the basis for discussion with policymakers and will be used to develop a roadmap to support craft in other ODA countries. To achieve this goal the project has two further objectives:  O5) To highlight the digital ecosystem strategy to policymakers and accelerate reforms in the digital economy. The outcomes of the research will be presented to the Uzbek Government to support a policy dialogue and influence legislation on craft as well as on digitalisation processes, which COVID-19 has accelerated. We will make recommendations on valuing craft as heritage, digital skills training, data protection and infrastructures to make the sector survive during the pandemic and create pathways for future recovery.    O6) To develop a roadmap for other ODA countries. We will codesign an innovative business model for community-based profit share and make recommendations to manage the ecosystem&apos;s operations, and will introduce the ecosystem in other ODA countries participating at the Crafting Futures Project and facing similar struggles due to COVID-19.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This challenge-led research project is designed to tackle the effects of COVID-19 crisis on craft communities in Uzbekistan, deeply affected by the lack of the digitalisation of the sector, ensuring the long-term sustainability of the sector which has been systemically compromised by the pandemic, and to create a roadmap for other countries facing similar issues. This project will codesign digital solutions to overcome the impact of the COVID-19 on craft activities and produce a more resilient and inclusive social, cultural and economic community-based ecosystem. In collaboration with local research partners and a specialised IT organisation, we will create an easy-to-use, low cost, digital ecosystem to provide access to markets, socially connect craft communities, share craft masters&apos; knowledge, and value Uzbekistan&apos;s diverse cultural heritage which is at risk of being lost.  The COVID-19 pandemic has forced many governments, including Uzbekistan, to go into lockdown. According to the Uzbek Statistics Office, the pandemic is severely impacting the craft sector, especially in rural areas, where there has been an increase in the number of unemployed and people living in poverty, endangering the future survival of craft enterprises.   Lockdowns and travel bans removed craft communities&apos; main sources of income, disrupted the supply chains and challenged the apprentice system. In our &quot;GCRF Urgency fund: COVID-19 focussed research proposals&quot;, we conducted a survey among 800 craftmakers in Uzbekistan, as there are no official statistics on the craft sector. Two-thirds of respondents are considering closing production, 80% have seen their income decrease during the pandemic and more than 40% do not believe they can survive more than 12 weeks. Thus, Uzbek craft is on the verge of collapsing, with the threat that an entire generation of craftmakers will stop producing and stop sharing craft knowledge, if urgent action is not taken to support, preserve and value its inestimable intangible heritage. Developing a digital ecosystem has been identified by our pilot project as the most promising solution to support craftmakers during the crisis, and create pathways of recovery for the uncertain post-pandemic scenarios. This is urgently required. The project will produce a networked cultural craft-based infrastructure supporting the integration of stakeholders, who are currently disconnected. The digital intervention will consist of a digital library, training courses, a digital salon, mentoring for female-led craft enterprises, and an e-commerce application. The digital ecosystem will fulfill four specific roles providing: 1) access to local and international markets enabling the craft masters to secure an income stream during the COVID-19 crisis; 2) a resource that will ensure the survival of the knowledge and traditions for heritage preservation and valuation; 3) an inclusive and sustainable platform for craftmakers&apos; digital storytelling, including a digital salon for female masters; and 4) a new network to engage with customers, students and other craftmakers.  The project will also produce an innovative business model for the platform to ensure long-term longevity, community involvement, committed management, and a community-based profit-sharing approach after project conclusion. Using digital tools to solve this urgent problem is aligned with the Uzbek Government&apos;s priorities on digitalisation of the economy and on the recovery plans for small enterprises. Uzbekistan only began to develop digital solutions and create the necessary infrastructures in 2016, and to signal the importance of digital economy, the Uzbek President declared 2020 the year of digitalisation.  This project will support the craft sector in Uzbekistan first, and will be cascaded to other ODA countries through a strategic partnership with the British Council programme &quot;Crafting Futures&quot;, through the roadmap that will be produced at the project&apos;s conclusion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uzbekistan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-09">67763</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-09">67762.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">33881.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V006657_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
