<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015074_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">How do human and bacterial behaviour interact in urban and rural African environments to facilitate the stable acquisition of antimicrobial resistance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The development of antibacterials has saved millions of lives; however, the massive global usage of these agents has created huge pressure for bacteria to become resistant to these drugs and to cause infections that are difficult or impossible to treat. This, combined with the flow of drugs slowing profoundly, has made antibiotic resistance a threat to health of global importance. New approaches are necessary to reduce illness caused by resistant bacteria.  In Low and Middle Income countries (LMIC), there is a huge burden of severe illness caused by bacteria, a critical lack of clinics and hospitals to diagnose and appropriately treat bacterial infections and widespread availability of antibiotics without prescription. This situation is responsible for a huge amount of illness and is increasing the pressure on bacteria to become drug resistant. LMIC settings will be the last to benefit from new types of antibiotics and it is therefore of urgent importance to undertake research addressing antibiotic resistance in LMICs that aims to identify which are the most important causes or drivers of the development of drug resistance. This requires scientists from a variety of fields and with a variety skills, from the laboratory to policy implementation to work together.   We will therefore describe both where bacteria live when not causing infections, whether in humans, animals or the environment, and how antimicrobials are used and misused in humans animals and the environment to:    1. Determine ways of using antibiotics make resistance come at a cost rather than as a benefit to bacteria 2. Develop ways of using antibiotics across all sectors that both improves access for people that really need them, but protects medicines of last resort in a manner acceptable to governments, communities and doctors to minimise the local emergence  of resistance; 3. Identify ways in which different parts of government, the health and research sectors can more effectively work together to reduce antibiotic resistance at national and district level, both within and between human and animal health and the environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-02">50391.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The primary and most important objective of the consortium phase application is to describe the spatial and molecular epidemiology of ABR pathogens in the human, animal and environmental context in which antimicrobials are used, in order to build a comprehensive systems model of ABR flow between humans, animals, and the environment in our study settings. This will permit us to proceed with the following objectives of equal importance. 1. Determine treatment strategies that leverage the fitness cost to pathogens of acquiring ABR thus minimising the emergence and persistence of resistance 2. Develop antimicrobial management and usage strategies across all sectors that both improve equity of access and restrict reserve agents in a manner acceptable to governments, communities and end users to minimise the local emergence and persistence of resistance; 3. Identify and addresses barriers to sustainable delivery of collaborative actions to address ABR at national and district level, both within and between human and animal health and environmental systems.  During the development award, we will undertake a number of pilot, collaborative projects, which will enable further interdisciplinary integration and which are designed to inform the consortium phase. We have the following objectives:  1) Evaluation of reservoirs of K. pneumoniae on Chatinkha neonatal unit at QECH, Blantyre, Malawi: Chatinkha is the focus of sustained transmission of extended spectrum drug resistant K. pneumoniae infection, and provides an opportunity to investigate the interaction between human behaviour and ABR of WHO priority pathogen K. pneumoniae between neonates, mothers and staff. We propose to use classical epidemiological methods, underpinned by robust human and environmental microbiology to evaluate reservoirs of the pathogen. We will also determine common evolutionary pathways to resistance in these isolates and associated fitness costs. We will explore human behaviour and its drivers by direct and participant observation of provider, patient and care-givers&apos; hygiene-related behaviour and its contextual drivers within the facility setting and undertake detailed qualitative exploration of their perceptions of infection and ABR. We will integrate this information by statistically fitting a dynamical infectious disease model to our data, which will provide unbiased estimates of transmission risk factors and allow us to predict the impact of candidate control interventions. This will inform development of appropriate and acceptable behaviour-change interventions for improved hospital infection control. 2) Assessment of implementation capacity in sectors responsible for AMR: Key informant interviews with national and district level agencies across relevant sectors will be conducted to understand implementation capacities and opportunities and begin engagement to underpin consortium research uptake.  3) Pilot economic modelling of AMR: Decision-analytic modelling will be performed to compare the cost of ABR to the cost savings from strategies to reduce the burden of ABR.  4) Pilot description of drivers of emergence of ABR in Uganda: We will make a description of antimicrobial usage at HRRH, undertake identification of the spectrum of ABR-pathogens in patients presenting to HRRH and community tracing of 25 patients with confirmed DRI including screening of family, pets, livestock and the environment.  5) AMR workshop in Malawi: Empirical work will be followed by a 3-day workshop in Malawi to present methodological learnings and results from the development award and to summarise ABR research ongoing at MLW and Uganda. The output will be a revised and precisely defined application for the consortium phase."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">50391.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015074_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-222655">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">28950.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015074_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-CHC-222655">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
