<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00833X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate Adaptation, Land Acquisition and Security: the Gendered Politics of Dispossession in Pakistan</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research will investigate the impacts of land acquisition for climate (adaptation) related mega development projects on the security of vulnerable and marginalised citizens and communities. The research will use a gender lens to uncover how citizens face differentiated experiences of dispossession and access to legal mechanisms of accountability and redress.   Two categories of land acquisition that are being developed in response to climate change will be investigated at sites across two of Pakistan&apos;s provinces: (1) rural land sold/leased to foreign investors and/or converted to Corporate Agriculture Farms (CAF); and (2) rural and urban land acquisition by local-foreign investors for the construction of climate-related mega development projects.   The primary concern is to investigate how local security and livelihoods are impacted by these processes. Secondly it focuses on how various actors/institutions use diverse transparency, accountability and litigation mechanisms.   The two provinces - Sindh and Punjab - have diverse histories of conflict, development and land use, offering important analytical and comparative avenues. The case studies reinforce the importance of the rural-urban nexus by bringing to the fore the complex interplay between international investment, governance regimes, land acquisitions, and differentiated forms of land dispossession and indigenous reactions.   Two mechanisms to be investigated are, first, the expectation that climate adaptation developers consult communities and obtain Free, Prior and Informed Consent. Secondly, the role of The Right to Information Ordinance 2013 (RTI) which, supposedly, enables ordinary citizens access to official government documents and approach a court if access is denied concerning any project, scheme or development. Previous research has highlighted that a core driver of local conflicts in Pakistan is the lack of fair legal recourse and grievance mechanisms for ordinary citizens.   This research will provide valuable data on how citizens see the state in climate-related development and if/how they can hold developers accountable. Such data will support appropriate capacity building to foster peaceful legal resolutions and mitigate for security risks of climate adaptation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="PK" type="PAKISTAN"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-09">76387.04</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This primary objective is to provide an evidence base on the impacts of land acquisition for climate (adaptation) related mega development projects on the security of vulnerable and marginalised citizens and communities.   The research will achieve this objective by focussing on two categories of land acquisition that are being developed in response to climate change:  (1) rural land sold or leased to foreign investors and/or converted to Corporate Agriculture Farms (CAF) for the benefit of their future food security; and,  (2) rural and urban land acquisition by local-foreign investors for the construction of climate-related mega development projects.   The research will focus on such land acquisitons at multiple sites in two provinces: Sindh and Punjab. Both provinces have experienced diverse histories of conflict, development and land use, offering important analytical and comparative avenues. The case study approach will reinforce the importance of the rural-urban nexus by bringing to the fore the complex interplay between international investment, governance regimes, land acquisitions, and differentiated forms of land dispossession and indigenous reactions.   There are two core research concerns. Firstly  to investigate how local security and livelihoods are impacted by these processes. Secondly  how do various actors/institutions use diverse transparency, accountability and litigation mechanisms. The research will use a gender lens to uncover how citizens face differentiated experiences of dispossession and access to legal mechanisms of accountability and redress.    The cases will investigate the avenues for transparency and accountability through two existing legal mechanisms: firstly, the expectation that climate adaptation developers consult communities and obtain &apos;Free, Prior and Informed Consent&apos;. Secondly, the role of The Right to Information Ordinance 2013 (RTI) which, supposedly, enables ordinary citizens access to official government documents and approach a court if access is denied concerning any project, scheme or development.   Previous research has highlighted that a core driver of local conflicts in Pakistan is the lack of fair legal recourse and grievance mechanisms for ordinary citizens. This research will provide valuable data on how citizens see the state in climate-related development and if/how they can hold developers accountable. Such data will support appropriate capacity building to foster peaceful legal resolutions and mitigate for security risks of climate adaptation."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">38193.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00833X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">7688.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00833X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
