<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V004867_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ADRELO: Advancing Resilience in Low Income Housing Using Climate-Change Science and Big Data Analytics</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Main Aim: The project will use transdisciplinary knowledge approaches, state-of-the-art green and innovative building and allied services technologies, Big Data and machine learning techniques and critically evaluate improvement needs in housing and Disaster Risk Reduction [DRR] policies, to prototype novel model facilities.   The following project areas will be covered: A. Transdisciplinary Knowledge and Data Management: 1) Assembling and analyzing the transdisciplinary knowledge base to characterize the human- natural system in regions susceptible to climate-related disasters, conceptually model their inter- relationships and linkages to determine critical points of susceptibility and resilience thresholds; 2) Use/ Societal Actor Engagement: Levering Red Cross to identify stakeholders at the local and national levels and empowering them to coordinate the development, implementation, monitoring and review of cross-sector climate-risk-based roadmaps.  B - Climate Science and Socio-Technical Options: 3) Localized and Seasonal Predictions with Machine Learning: Aggregating data from climate models, climate simulation, meteorological, remote sensing, and in situ monitoring for use in analysis. Interpretable ML models will be used to attribute the outputs to the input variables through identifying the contributions of each input variable. 4) Developing a Geographical Information System (GIS)-based application to help in the siting of shared community facilities based on assessment of the social, economic and health implications. Where and how homes are built determines occupants&apos; vulnerability. 5) Design and prototype affordable, sustainable and resilient buildings for the vulnerable, low socio-economic status (SES) populations in appropriate sites. The Brazilian researchers from the S&#xE3;o Paulo State University (UNESP) and University of S&#xE3;o Paulo (USP) are also recognized for the development of accelerated aging techniques, extrusion production, mechanical characterization and microstructural evaluation techniques of cement-based composites reinforced with lignocellulosic fibers and synthetic fibers (polyvinyl alcohol and polypropylene), pines and eucalypt cellulose pulps. The performance targets will be high toughness, modular construction, durability, thermal comfort and affordability. 6) Design and prototype multipurpose community facility that can be used as an infirmary for infectious diseases like cholera with solar operated refrigeration for the required drugs. Approaches to be used: (i) Cement-based materials and particleboards for prefabricated elements for cladding, siding, ceiling and roofing, and; (ii) Structural elements made of bamboo based on prefabrication concept, modular construction and non-permanent construction for housing - performance targets similar to 5. 7) Investigate and validate the feasibility and viability of securing food security resilience during disaster through a food bank facility that is stocked using solar-powered preservation processes. Design and fabrication methods from 6 will be applied.  C - Policy options: 8) Evaluate the policy and governance framework for DRR in climate susceptible and fragile human-natural systems using agent-based models, Big Data analytics, and socio-economic techniques. 9) Design and Develop a Decision Support System for Disaster Management Policy: The team will employ socio-economic-health models, model attributions, and multi-objective optimization approaches to create a tool for decision support in policy development and evaluation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims at enhancing the resilience of low-income communities living in disaster prone areas. The focus is on low-lying coastal zones that have a high risks of droughts and floods in selected parts of East Africa, Brazil and North America. It develops the geographic and socio-economic knowledge of persons living in slum and riverbed areas by gathering georeferenced data on infrastructures and information on the natural heritage of project sites. The project team will also investigate technology adoption barriers and diffusion drivers through designing and prototyping an affordable, disaster-resilient, low-income housing system that use sustainable locally-resourced materials. The development of urban spaces is a function of geographic location, economic history, urban development pattern, and therefore governance will have a bearing on resilience. Still, given that development (or lack thereof) of an urban center is an outcome of existing social, economic, and political inequities political inequities; policy packages for disaster preparedness that do not consider the unique circumstances of vulnerable populations can inadvertently cause harm to low- income households. Furthermore, policy packages will include environmental sustainability and public health considerations. The research will also contribute to accurate modelling of climate and extreme weather events at spatiotemporal level to increase the understanding of climate scientists while empowering policy makers in disaster related decision-making. Machine Learning and Big Data Analytics will be used for climate modelling and to identify optimal disaster resilient-housing urban design and planning policy packages considering projected climate change- related extreme weather scenarios between the current time and 2050. Whilst Big Climate Data is amenable to long-term climate prediction, data for localized and seasonal predictions is still uncertain and sparse. Machine Learning has potential to handle this uncertainty and data sparsity as other applications have demonstrated that it can work with either big data or sparse data.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-17">207062.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-17">166991.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-17">252178.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">51765.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V004867_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">De Montfort University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">51765.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V004867_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">De Montfort University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">51765.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V004867_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">De Montfort University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
