<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P002455_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton RCUK-TUBITAK Integration and Well-Being of Syrian Youth in Turkey</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to assess the needs of Syrian refugee youth in Turkey and to provide concrete policy recommendations for their integration. All recent studies of the Syrian population in Turkey indicate that their status is gradually shifting from refugee to immigrant as a result of the prolonged conflict. While the Turkish government has maintained an &apos;open door&apos; policy regarding refugees from their neighbouring country, they also were not prepared for the scale of the exodus or the length of the war. As a result, the Turkish government is currently struggling to formulate effective policies to deal with a crisis that threatens to impact both Turkey&apos;s future development and regional stability.   Our project focuses on one of the most vulnerable groups within the refugee population: youth whose futures are being put on hold. Youth between 15 and 30 years of age would have attended university or entered the job market, but many are finding that their plans of education and training, or marrying and building a family, must be deferred. The project will assess their background, including educational level and skills; their educational, work, and health needs; and their visions of the future. We aim to develop concrete organisational and policy suggestions for social and economic integration show how Syrian youth in Turkey may be  viewed not as burdensome &apos;guests&apos; but as human capital that can contribute to the country&apos;s development.   The project will assess delivery and access to services such as education and healthcare, and will employ a comparative and historical approach that takes lessons from other states&apos; and from Turkey&apos;s own past responses to mass refugee emergencies. Moreover, we will map the various local, regional, national and international governmental, voluntary, and humanitarian organisations currently working in Turkey in order to understand how and why refugees use these organisations to access services. This will allow us to evaluate the government response and gaps left by that response. Two of our particular concerns are access to education and transition into the labour market, especially critical for the age group under study. The ability of refugee youth to access education will play a critical role in Turkey&apos;s immediate future, as it will determine whether or not Turkey will be able fully to make use of the human capital represented by this large, young population. Assuming that refugees are likely to remain in Turkey at least in the medium term, then, the project aims to improve access of refugee youth to education, health services, and the labour market in order to insure that this young population will contribute to Turkey&apos;s growth rather than become an impediment to its development.  This research is urgent, because the future of hundreds of thousands of Syrian youth is currently in danger. While a number of studies have attempted to assess integration problems and have warned of the immanent dangers of leaving them unaddressed, no study to date has systematically examined the critical age group that is transitioning from childhood to adulthood and currently making decisions that will shape their futures. This will also be the group that will play a critical role in decisions about return to the home country in future years.   The project responds to a research gap regarding this humanitarian crisis, because the urgency and lack of data has so far dictated quick responses regarding populations that are constantly changing and whose needs are shifting. The thirty-month period of the RCUK-TUBITAK grant will provide research teams from two leading universities the opportunity systematically to collect and analyse data on the crisis and examine how those results may change over time, hence providing a base of reliable research data.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-06-15"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="TR" type="TURKEY"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EUROPE, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">89</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">100824.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">101641.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">25616.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This project aims to assess the well-being and needs of Syrian youth in Turkey and to show how they may be viewed not as burdensome &apos;guests&apos; but as human capital that can contribute to the country&apos;s development. Our approach is both global and historically informed, as we aim both to formulate effective policy recommendations for burden-sharing at the EU and international levels and also to examine successful and unsuccessful practices from Turkey&apos;s own recent past that will help us in thinking about local and culturally specific recommendations for integration practices that would enhance the well-being of Syrian youth.  Outputs of the project will include: 1. A project website where we will post: initial research results; announcements and summaries of workshops and conferences; research reports; policy briefs; and academic publications that result from the research. 2. Four research reports aimed at government agencies, NGOs and civil society practitioners that will address: access and delivery of services; comparative best practices regarding integration; gender well-being; and human capital assessment. 3. Two policy briefs aimed at making available research results on access to service and human capital assessment for an EU and international audience.  4. One LSE workshop discussing the research results with NGO representatives and academics working on refugee reception in neighbouring Arab countries and the EU. 5. One LSE workshop discussing methods for improving access to services and integration with experts and NGO representatives from U.K. and EU migration-receiving countries. 6. Policy-informing workshop in Ankara with government agencies, NGOs, and civil society that will offer the opportunity to present research results to date, as well as conclusions from the first LSE workshop. 7. One LSE-organised policy conference in Brussels that will offer the opportunity to present the first policy brief, with results from both the first LSE workshop and the Ankara policy-informing workshops. 8. One LSE policy conference in London that will present the final results of the project to UK and EU policy audiences. 9. At least three presentations of analysis of research at academic conferences. 10. Publication of at least two academic articles in venues such as Journal of Refugee Studies and International Migration Review.  Methodological: The methodological objectives include triangulation of data through simultaneous use of several research methods, and the collaborative and comparative analysis of data through presentation in workshops before production of policy briefs. Presentation of materials in the first LSE and Ankara policy-informing workshops will inform the first policy brief, to be presented in Brussels. Discussion of that policy brief will also inform the writing of subsequent research reports, which will be addressed primarily to Turkish government bodies, NGOs, and civil society. The methods of assessing and presenting the research results, then, call at every level for feedback and discussion between the LSE/MiReKoc team and experts, practitioners, and policymakers at the national, EU, and international levels.  Empirical: The primary empirical objective is the formation of a body of reliable research data on the needs and well-being of a changing and transient population. Although the most intense research period will end by month 15 of the grant, one important component of the research plan is a second period of semi-structured interviews and fieldwork in which researchers will attempt to follow up with persons interviewed in the first round. This will be an important test of the reliability of the first data set, and it will also allow us to make broad observations about the scope of this population&apos;s mobility."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
