<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N004442_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC-Embrapa Genomics and pathogenomics to improve FHB and brusone resistance in Brazilian wheat</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project team The project team combines research leaders with complementary expertise in both the wheat host and the FHB and brusone fungal pathogens in Brazil and the UK. Pedro Scheeren (Embrapa) and Eduardo Caierao (Embrapa) have unrivalled knowledge of Brazilian wheat production, providing expertise in wheat breeding alongside knowledge of germplasm resistance status that is essential for genome wide association scans to be undertaken to identify genomic regions associated with resistance to FHB and brusone. Cristobal Uauy (JIC) is internationally recognised for his expertise in wheat genetics and gene cloning in cereals. CU collaborates closely with Ksenia Krasileva (TGAC/TSL) who leads the development of functional genomics tools in wheat, including the development of exome-capture platforms that will form one of the pillars of the project. Paul Nicholson (JIC) leads a research group investigating the genetic basis of resistance to FHB in cereals and will contribute to both host and pathogen components in the project in partnership with Fl&#xE1;vio Santana and Maria Imaculada Moreira Lima (Embrapa), who lead research on FHB resistance.  James Cockram (NIAB) has extensive experience in combining molecular genetics and genomics with statistical techniques to investigate complex traits in wheat. These skills will be used in collaboration with Luciano Consoli (Embrapa) who leads the quantitative genetics programme, to undertake association mapping of target traits in Brazilian wheat germplasm. James Cockram will provide training to Embrapa personnel to enable them to undertake additional analyses on FHB and brusone data as these become available. Joao Leodato (Embrapa) is a recognised expert on brusone disease and will work alongside Gisele Torres (Embrapa) who has extensive experience of working with the Brusone pathogen and interactions with the wheat host using functional genomics analysis. Antonio Nhani Jr (Embrapa) employs genomics to investigate virulence and host specificity in the brusone pathogen. The skills and knowledge provided by Embrapa researchers will be complemented those of Nick Talbot (University of Exeter) who is internationally recognised for his expertise in the genetics and virulence of the brusone fungus. Diane Saunders (TGAC/JIC) leads research into pathogen populations and virulence, providing essential insight into the structure of the populations of the FHB and brusone pathogens that will be utilised within studies of the genetics of host resistance.   Resources and Infrastructure In addition to the highly complementary skill sets of the Embrapa and UK participants, the organisations contribute complementary resources and infrastructure. Embrapa has excellent field trials facilities and trained personnel across Brazil in regions where the environment is most conducive to the FHB and brusone diseases enabling them to undertake high quality disease trials. The Embrapa site at Passo Fundo is exceptionally well equipped with laboratory, computing infrastructure, glasshouse and plant growth facilities in an environment that enables the rapid growth of plants to minimise generation time and ensure efficient development of plant populations to the required level of fixation for genotyping and phenotyping purposes. The UK partners within this project (JIC, TGAC, NIAB and Exeter) all have extensive laboratory, computational and plant growth facilities, required for the host and pathogen genetics and genomics components of the project. In addition, TGAC has state of the art genome sequencing and transcriptional profiling facilities and computer hardware and software to undertake the associated data processing and analysis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-25">54472.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Fusarium head blight (FHB) and wheat blast (brusone) are devastating diseases of wheat that cause major yield losses in Brazil. The main aim of this project is to develop durable disease control strategies for both diseases in an integrated manner. Both pathogens affect wheat heads causing severe damage to both quality and yield of grain. Without resistant varieties, current disease control in Brazil has to rely on fungicides that are costly, non-sustainable, and largely ineffective. A joint BBSRC-Embrapa workshop on Wheat Improvement in 2011 led to collaboration between Embrapa and JIC, which was enhanced through a BBSRC International Partnering Award (2012-16). This partnership has led to exchange of wheat materials and visits between Embrapa and JIC scientists to undertake joint characterization of Brazilian wheat germplasm. Similarly, an Embrapa-funded exchange programme led to genome sequence analysis of brusone isolates at the University of Exeter to understand pathogen evolution and population diversity. Through the present application, we seek to broaden our BBSRC-Embrapa collaborations to include outstanding researchers in TGAC and NIAB, with complementary skill sets, to identify new sources of resistance and deployment strategies to counter these devastating diseases.  Brusone is caused by the fungus Magnaporthe oryzae and was first seen in southern Brazil in 1985, but has since spread to Argentina, Bolivia, and Paraguay. The disease can cause total yield loss and is distinct in pathology from rice blast disease caused by the same fungal species, further complicating its disease control. In 2009, brusone led to a 30% loss of Brazilian wheat production and brusone precludes their cultivation in the Cerrado region, a 5 million ha region of huge potential for wheat production. Fusarium head blight, caused primarily by the fungus Fusarium graminearum, is a serious disease in both Brazil and the UK. In addition to significant yield and quality losses, FHB causes contamination of grain with trichothecene mycotoxins, such as deoxynivalenol (DON). Both the European Union and Brazil have imposed maximum permissible levels for DON in cereal products. In Brazil, severe FHB outbreaks have recently increased in frequency and in 2014 FHB was so severe that 60% of the wheat harvest was lost in the State of Rio Grande do Sul, while in 2014 in the west of Brazil some farmers lost more than 80% due to a combination of brusone and FHB. There is an urgent need to identify and characterise sources of resistance to both FHB and brusone and ensure that introduction of genes to control one disease, does not compromise resistance to the other. No wheat varieties are immune to either disease. Very little is known about the population structure of the FHB or brusone pathogens in Brazil. Embrapa researchers have obtained evidence that races may exist within the M. oryzae population that have cultivar-specific virulence. This is consistent with phylogenomic analysis carried out at Exeter. Understanding the pathogen population structure and the distribution of specific virulence forms of the fungus will be necessary to identify broad spectrum resistance genes to exclude the prevailing pathogen population and ensure long term durable disease control. Moderate levels of resistance to brusone have already been identified in Brazilian germplasm as part of the WheatBGIn (Wheat Blast Genes Interaction) project, but the genetic basis of this resistance is unclear. Resistance to FHB meanwhile appears to be controlled by several genes of moderate/weak effect that are defined genetically as quantitative trait loci (QTL).  This project will define the genetic basis of disease resistance to both FHB and brusone and use this knowledge, combined with an understanding of pathogen diversity, to develop the most durable disease control strategy to safeguard Brazilian wheat production."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
