<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N007395_2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Learning from the Utopian City: An international network on alternative histories of India&apos;s urban futures</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project interweaves postcolonial historiography and urban studies to learn from the utopian Indian city in order to shape alternative visions of India&apos;s urban future. It does this by taking the view that utopias are as much of grassroots articulations of socially inclusive cities and citizenship as they are top-down visions of urban planning. Building upon the strong foundations established through existing partnerships between UK and Indian researchers, this project aims to explore how an alternate history of utopian urban planning can inform the future of urbanization and urban citizenship in India. It is led by urban geographer (Datta) from UK and architect and feminist geographer (Sabhlok) from India.  The collaboration will be funded over a six month period and will seek to fulfill the following objectives:  1. Explore the relationship between different historical visions of urban utopia and planning policies in four Indian cities (Chandigarh, Varanasi, Nashik and Navi Mumbai) with contrasting trajectories.  While Chandigarh and Navi Mumbai will be examined for their &apos;top down&apos; utopian visions, Nashik and Varanasi will be examined for their &apos;indigenous modernities&apos; and examples of grassroots social utopias.  We will seek to build histories of planned cities in India from independence to the contemporary period (all four of them are proposed smart cities) through desktop study of masterplans and official documents. The aim is to map and identify common threads and divergences in their blueprints, the relationship between state driven and popular visions, the parameters of creating these cities and their current role in shaping India&apos;s urban future. We will also explore how far urban utopian visions in these cities are conditioned for external audiences through reference to international parallels and to what extent were they conditioned and reproduced within urban society.   2. Through objective #1 above, develop a history of utopian cities as a history of changing embodied and engendered relations with the city. This will involve an analysis of the transformations in state-citizen relations across the blueprints of the utopian cities, examining how marginalised citizens learn from their everyday struggles to interact with the ideology of the blueprint and challenge the structure of the built environment to conceive of alternative social utopias. This will entail further detailed study of grey literature available on the selected cities. 3. Develop and exchange knowledge of alternate histories and utopias through a series of inter-connected city workshops between academics, urban planners and grassroots organisations in India. We will use a range of methods including oral histories, diaries, letters, photographs, music, dance, mental maps and so on in the meetings to elucidate a range of alternate histories and futures. Develop an alternative history of the utopian city through grassroots social utopias.  Here we are basing our project model on the highly successful project &apos;Writing British Asian Cities&apos; (AHRC, 2006-9) in which five city-based meetings produced five very different sets of outcomes and series of research results, which we subsequently published.  The meetings/workshops therefore will not act in the traditional sense as fora for presenting academic papers, but as a way of revealing the dynamics of the changing utopian visions for each city and what their future trajectories might  be. 4. Strengthen links between and build capacity of research partners through a two-day end of project symposium in University of Leeds that will catalyse the development of a research programme on the history and future of utopian urbanism in the global south. We will achieve this by developing the network on Utopian Cities as a longer term interaction between Indian academics working on urban histories and societies and those working in other contexts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project interweaves social history, postcolonial and urban studies to learn from alternative histories of the utopian city in order to shape India&apos;s urban future. It does this by taking the view that utopias are as much of grassroots articulations of socially inclusive cities and citizenship as they are top-down visions of urban planning. Building upon the strong foundations established through existing partnerships between UK and Indian researchers, this project aims to explore how an alternate history of utopian urban planning can inform the trajectories of future cities and urbanization in India. It is led by urban geographer (Datta) from UK and architect and feminist geographer (Sabhlok) from India. This is supported by UK Co-Is - Indian historian (Gould) and Urban History and development scholar (Madgin). The aim of the network is to uncover parallel histories of the utopian city that have so far been changed, dominated or appropriated by top down visions of Indian urban planning. It will examine urban histories as being made up of a variety of interacting and sometimes competing utopian visions.  These visions also define citizenship in differentiated rather than universal ways, strongly linked to context, material conditions and political activism. The network will analyse and share knowledge of these alternate histories through a series of inter-connected city workshops with local academics, urban planners and grassroots organisations in India and an end of project symposium in the UK. The network aims to answer the following key questions: - How are urban utopias historically and culturally conditioned in India?  The aim here will be to map and analyse how utopian visions of a new kind of social and political order have particular associations with regimes of control and containment. This will examine how utopias envisioned in newly independent India (1950s) are connected to utopian visions of the 1960s or post liberalization India (2000s). We will identify common threads and divergences in city blueprints, the parameters of creating these cities and their current contribution to India&apos;s urban future.  We will also explore how far urban utopian visions are conditioned by competitive aspirations and developed for external audiences.   - How can the utopian city take account not just of the diversity of its citizens but also the diversity of their visions of the ideal city? This seeks to address the paradoxical nature of the utopian city - as a rule of order and as a productive space of transformation. In other words, we will seek to question how utopias are embodied and engendered by subaltern citizens to sustain as well as challenge political regulation. Drawing upon oral histories, diaries, photographs, letters and other forms of informal artefacts brought to the workshops, this will seek to unsettle the finality of the urban utopia to suggest the continuous mode of becoming of the utopian Indian city.  - How can a history of the utopian city inform the future of India&apos;s urbanization? This aims to examine a dual utopian visioning whereby it is only possible to imagine a utopian future by learning from the history of urban utopias. In so doing, we approach India&apos;s urban futures as already written through its urban histories and therefore accessible to us only through an understanding of its histories. Moreover, as the future is yet to materialise, we argue that its trajectory can be shifted towards more inclusive outcomes through the inclusion of a history of subaltern utopias. The further purpose of the meetings is to extend the project to a) other South Asian cities;  b) explore the means by which academics working on urban society and culture can interact with planners, third sector organisations and architects; c) explore the possibilities for further projects examining the relationship between urban utopiasin the Global South and global north.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-24">1635.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-24">68683.608</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N007395_2" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FN007395%2F2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
