<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_V005901_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving early detection and diagnosis of breast cancer among multi-ethnic rural communities in Malaysia - implementation of the CENP</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Breast cancer (BC) is the commonest cancer in Malaysia. Women in rural areas present with advanced cancer and experience poor survival due to low awareness about symptoms and low participation in BC screening. This project aims to harness the lessons from our previous successful study in Malaysia and the methods of implementation science to develop and evaluate a community education and navigation programme (CENP) that will improve the early detection and diagnosis of BC among rural women. The study will be conducted in Segamat district, Johor State in consultation with local stakeholders and with the support of the South East Asia Community Observatory (SEACO), an established Health &amp; Demographic Surveillance Site. The immediate beneficiaries will be women and families in local rural communities in Malaysia. Our project will benefit rural communities by increasing public awareness about warning signs and symptoms and, more specifically, by navigating women to breast cancer screening. The CENP will identify and counter emotional barriers, dispel misbeliefs and prompt help-seeking behaviour thereby enhancing cancer prevention and leading, where appropriate, to early diagnosis and treatment. Our project via improved prevention and earlier diagnosis will reduce the burden including the personal, financial and psychosocial burden that is experienced by many women and their families as well as the resource burden to the health care system and the wider societal economic consequences for Malaysia. In addition, our project will collaborate with primary care physicians in order to improve their understanding further about the community in which they serve, embed patient navigation in community and primary care services and expedite referral of suspected cases. Furthermore, the project will capacity build&apos; to the benefit of rural communities, NGOs, public health researchers and academics by enhancing knowledge and educational materials and related skills regarding cancer.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The specific objectives are to:  1) review and synthesise the evidence and experiential learning regarding the implementation of community navigation programmes for breast cancer early detection and diagnosis  2) assess the views and preferences of key stakeholder groups regarding community navigation, specifically the views of women in low-income rural communities  3) co-design a culturally sensitive education and navigation programme and identify evaluation metrics for implementation  4) test the appropriateness, feasibility, and acceptability of the CENP  5) conduct a pilot evaluation of the CENP using an experimental/comparative analytical design  6) develop &apos;joined-up&apos; policy briefs for the Ministry of Rural Development and the Ministry of Health that will inform a national scaled-up programme for cancer prevention and early detection rural communities in Malaysia</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-11">48165.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-11">27422.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-11">75588.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton UKRI Award to Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/V005901/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FV005901%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-06-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
