<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006256_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Can We Rebuild the Kasthamandap? Promoting Post-Disaster Rescue Excavations, Salvage and Subsurface Heritage Protection Protocols in Kathmandu</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 7.8 Magnitude Gorkha Earthquake which struck Nepal on 25/04/2015 made thousands of people homeless and killed over 8,000. Representing a human catastrophe, this natural disaster generated a cultural catastrophe, damaging monuments within UNESCO&apos;s Kathmandu Valley World Heritage Site. Beautifully ornate temples of wood, brick and tile, they also represent majors source of income and economic growth through tourism, a key component of Nepal&apos;s fragile economy and source of foreign currency. They also play a central intangible role in the daily lives of thousands of Nepalis, representing portals where the heavens touch the earth and where it is possible for devotees to reach out and commune with their guiding deities. For these reasons, the collapsed monuments are the part of a major program of ODA reconstruction. Reconstruction approaches are designed and led by architects and engineers and their focus is on reconstructing Kathmandu&apos;s famous skyline of timber and tile superstructures on new and deeper foundations of steel and concrete for greater structural stability as part of the &apos;Build Back Better&apos; approach.   Leading a UNESCO post-disaster pilot mission to Kathmandu in October 2015, however, we noted that &apos;Build Back Better&apos; foundations were destroying archaeological sequences below the surface without any formal recording. Our mission was also able to demonstrate the presence of vulnerable deposits in a portion of the ruins of Kathmandu&apos;s oldest monument, the Kasthamandap, and were able to expose part of its undamaged traditional braced foundations. Following requests from the Government of Nepal (GoN) and ICOMOS (Nepal) and responding to AHRC&apos;s &apos;Notice for International Development&apos;, our aim is to build on the success of the &apos;Outstanding&apos; AHRC-funded research in Sri Lanka to conduct a practical field training workshop with non-academic collaborators as the GofN excavates the rest of the moument to evaluate the foundations of the collapsed Kasthamandap in Kathmandu. Together, these activities will assist post-earthquake reconstruction plans and to offer an exemplar and disseminate post-disaster subsurface heritage protection protocols.   Building on the award of the 2014 UNESCO Chair in Archaeological Ethics and Practice in Cultural Heritage to Durham and Kathmandu-based partnerships established during the Chair&apos;s participation in UNESCO&apos;s 2015 post-disaster pilot mission, this FoF proposal will deliver impact by:  1) Bringing together a team of international and Nepali archaeologists, architects, engineers, Sanskritists, soil scientists, civil servants, heritage and disaster managers and residents to build on the success of AHRC-funded research methodologies to assist the development of post-earthquake reconstruction plans for Kasthamandap in December 2016.  2) Hosting a Practical Field Training Workshop in the ruins of the collapsed Kasthamandap for Nepali GOs, NGOs and residents to establish methodologies for the recording and evaluation of collapsed heritage sites and the salvaging of materials within post-disaster urban contexts and to assist post-earthquake reconstruction plans in December 2016.   3) Raising awareness and disseminate post-disaster monument evaluation, salvaging methodologies and post-disaster subsurface heritage protection protocols amongst IGOs, GOs, INGOs and NGOs and residents through the Nepal-focused publication of one popular magazine paper in Spaces and a special number of Ancient Nepal, journal of the GofN&apos;s Department of Archaeology.  4) Raising awareness and disseminate post-disaster monument evaluation and salvaging methodologies and post-disaster subsurface heritage protection protocols amongst IGOs, GOs, INGOs and NGOs and residents through a Nepal-focused dissemination workshop and exhibition at Kasthamandap in May 2017, whilst the network&apos;s outcomes will be sustained via the Durham UNESCO Chair website and shared through the UNESCO Chairs &amp; UNITWIN Culture network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The earthquakes which struck Nepal in 2015 caused a human catastrophe. Not only did they inflict loss of life and livelihoods, they destroyed substantial parts of  Kathmandu&apos;s unique UNESCO World Heritage site. The monuments of the city were not only ornate structures but were living monuments playing central roles in the daily lives of thousands of Nepalis. Furthermore, their rehabilitation is of economic importance as they represent a major source of foreign currency and employment through tourism. Indeed, the Government of Nepal&apos;s &apos;Cultural Heritage Post-Disaster Needs Assessment 2015&apos; (PDNA) estimates that losses relating to damage and livelihoods amount to over US$23 million.   Whilst there is a strong political, social and economic desire to reconstruct rapidly, it is critical that post-disaster rescue archaeology is combined with reconstruction. Indeed, plans to reconstruct temples on existing ruined platforms must first be preceded by a phase of rescue excavations to evaluate the subsurface stability of foundations with detailed recording and scientific analysis as few architectural studies have considered them. These will provide a greater understanding of how monuments developed and facilitate their enhanced rehabilitation and future protection. There is also an imperative for information and data sharing and capacity building as damage has already been inflicted on monuments within the UNESCO World Heritage site during the post-disaster pre-reconstruction phase led by architects and engineers unaware of the heritage beneath their feet.  Indeed, having discussed challenges and opportunities with stakeholders in Kathmandu, it is clear that the current focus on the rehabilitation of architectural superstructures has resulted in additional damage to Kathmandu&apos;s World Heritage site. This has largely gone unnoticed as it entailed damage to subsurface archaeological heritage, even though this heritage is protected by national legislation. Emergency interventions badly damaged some buildings but, whilst they were driven by recovering the injured and dead, more recent damage relates to non-emergency activities, including engineering contractors cutting exploratory trenches and drilling soil cores, workmen cutting foundations, soldiers deliberately collapsing monuments and engineers dismantling others. All of these events had a common absence of in-situ archaeological recording and the absence of consultation with trained professional archaeologists beforehand.  This absence is paralleled in the PDNA 2015, which fails to note the risk to the vulnerable subsurface archaeological heritage from rehabilitation and reconstruction activities. More recent documents, such as the draft &apos;Conservation Guidelines for Post 2015 Earthquake Rehabilitation: Conservation Guidelines&apos; (CGPERCG2015) recognise this risk but need strengthening. It is worth noting that this situation is common across South Asia and there is a capacity deficit in urban and rescue archaeology, despite being located in a region whose built heritage is prone to risks from both seismic events and rapid urbanisation.    Following requests from the Government of Nepal and ICOMOS (Nepal) and responding to AHRC&apos;s FoF &apos;Notice for International Development&apos;, our aim is to build on the success of the &apos;Outstanding&apos; graded AHRC-funded research in Sri Lanka to conduct a practical field training workshop with non-academic collaborators to focus on learning from the evaluation of the foundations of the collapsed Kasthamandap in Kathmandu and as well as on salvaging material to assist post-earthquake plans for its reconstruction and to offer an exemplar for strengthening and disseminating post-disaster subsurface heritage protocols within post-earthquake Kathmandu.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nepal</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-19">56037.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-19">74716.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to Durham University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/P006256/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">56037.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006256_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">18679.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006256_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FP006256%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
