<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R005974_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BactiVac</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of BactiVac is to establish a bacterial vaccinology network that brings key individuals and organisations together to facilitate end-to-end bacterial vaccine development for low and middle income countries (LMICs) from exploratory research, through clinical trials, to licensure and implementation. No bacterial vaccinology network of this nature presently exists. Therefore, BactiVac will fill a major gap in global vaccinology, providing balance to the current critical mass of vaccinologists converging on outbreak and viral pathogens through the &apos;UK Vaccines Network&apos;, and WHO &apos;Research and Development Blueprint&apos; and &apos;Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI)&apos;. BactiVac will draw together entities from the academic, industry and stakeholder sectors from the UK/high income countries (HICs) and LMICs involved in human and animal vaccine R&amp;D to foster partnership, disseminate relevant information and provide catalyst project support with the aim of accelerating LMIC bacterial vaccine development. A particular focus will be to address knowledge gaps in the area, such as identification of bacterial vaccine priorities for LMICs, and to support the transition of vaccines from preclinical to clinical trials, where so many currently flounder. Specific objectives: 1. To establish an open network that connects key individuals and organisations from academia, industry and LMICs to fulfil unmet needs for bacterial vaccines, providing opportunities for the dissemination of knowledge and ideas, fostering partnerships and progressing bacterial vaccine R&amp;D. 2. To establish a framework to address major gaps in our knowledge of bacterial vaccinology, including the prioritisation of LMIC-focused bacterial diseases for vaccine development, and identifying Clinical Research Organisations (CRO), Contract Manufacturing Organisations (CMO) and manufacturing capacities and capabilities to support bacterial vaccine development. 3. To provide support for small-scale projects that will prime substantive funding applications, with an emphasis on those that directly impact bacterial vaccine progression, and involve partnership between network members, particularly members from LMICs and industry. 4. To establish BactiVac as the advocacy network for bacterial vaccinology that campaigns for the need for bacterial vaccines as a means of reducing the burden of endemic bacterial disease, combatting AMR and improving economic development in LMICs. 5. To support training opportunities and exchanges, prioritising those involving LMIC members and industrial partners, for the transfer of knowledge and skills in bacterial vaccinology. 6. To interface with other groups, including other vaccine networks generated from this call, the Developing Countries Manufacturing Network (DCVMN), Veterinary Vaccinology Network (VVN), stakeholder organisation such as WHO and GAVI and funders such as the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation BMGF) to maximize the reach and use of resources to achieve the network&apos;s objectives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vaccines save millions of lives every year and typically work silently in the background, promoting the body&apos;s ability to kill the pathogen before an infection is established. Despite this, bacteria still cause around six millions deaths/year in humans and many more in animals, with people in low and middle-income countries (LMICs) disproportionately affected. Worryingly, as anti-microbial resistance (AMR) increases, the number of deaths from infection will rise with devastating personal and economic consequences. One reason bacteria can cause so much harm is because there are many different diseases caused by bacteria for which there is either no vaccine or the existing vaccine does not provide complete protection. New vaccines against bacterial infections will help people in all countries, but most prominently in LMICs. Unfortunately, there are many barriers that currently prevent such vaccines from being developed. These barriers can be for scientific reasons, such as what to put in the vaccine, or economic issues, such as neglect due to lack of commercial viability. To help overcome these barriers and deliver new vaccines to where they are needed, a network is needed that enables scientists, clinicians and companies from around the world to come together and share their skills and knowledge. This is what the &apos;BactiVac&apos; bacterial vaccinology network for human and animal vaccines will achieve. The network will be centred in the UK, harnessing the considerable strength already present in the UK in disciplines related to bacterial vaccinology, including immunology, epidemiology, systems biology, clinical trials and support for vaccine licensure. Crucially, the network will build on and foster new partnerships with LMICs, with industry, and manufacturers in developing countries. BactiVac will support bacterial vaccine development from when the idea is conceived to when it is licensed for use in humans or animals, particularly helping at those points where most potential vaccines flounder. The network will achieve these ambitions by combining a number of approaches. 1. The network will identify which diseases in LMICs caused by bacteria should be prioritised and how the broad vaccine community can be helped to make new vaccines that prevent them.  2. We will provide training grants, particularly for members from LMICs, to learn the skills needed to grow the research and industrial base in vaccinology.  3. By interconnecting the diverse experience and skills within the membership, we will facilitate new partnerships and sharing of information, supported by the creation of a member directory, a BactiVac website and regular newsfeeds, along with an annual networking meeting.  4. To encourage these new partnerships, the network will support small scale &apos;catalyst&apos; projects through an open annual competition. These projects will grow new areas and partnerships to encourage larger scale funding, accelerate vaccine development and to help overcome the bottlenecks that prevent vaccines going from an idea to a product. 5. Underpinning all of these focused activities BactiVac will provide an advocacy programme that promotes the importance, need and value of vaccines to bacterial infections. This programme will work with the general public, governments and ministries of health, and non-governmental organisations, including key stake-holders in global health policy, such as the WHO and other funding organisations. Collectively, this will lead to a growth in research and development of new vaccines against bacterial infections and improve lives across the world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-04">377103.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-04">505859.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-04">509956.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-04">256526.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-04">128780.59</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-04">2035787.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R005974_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FR005974%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-08-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
