<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S009086_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inactivation of the PRH/HHEX tumour suppressor and its effects on inflammatory signalling in prostate cancer.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Prostate cancer is the most common cancer in men in the UK and this disease has a particularly high incidence in men of African origin. Around 50,000 new cases are diagnosed each year and this is increasing as men live longer. Most men diagnosed with prostate cancer do not die from this disease. However, for patients with disease that has spread to other sites in the body, surgical castration is the recommended treatment. For patients with less advanced disease radiotherapy and/or drug treatments are effective. However, these treatments can have serious side effects including osteoporosis and bone fracture. In many less advanced cases treatment is probably unnecessary as the cancer is very unlikely to progress and spread. Better ways of identifying patients who need treatment and better treatments would be of immense value to patients and result in major cost savings for the NHS. The incidence of prostate cancer in Kenya and other low- and middle-income countries (LMIC) is also rising and in these countries the cost of treatment and the cost of lives lost to this disease are major barriers to economic development. The aims of this project are to improve our understanding of the causes of prostate cancer progression and to create an archive of prostate cancer samples that will be of value to this study and to future work in this area. Inflammation in the prostate is common and this is known to be an important factor in prostate cancer. Inflammation in the prostate in LMIC and UK patients can have many causes including bacterial and viral infections and autoimmune responses. Cells from the immune system are found in the prostate and in prostate cancers they release signals that increase the replication of cancer cells and increase their ability to spread.  We have discovered that a protein called PRH stops prostate cells from replicating and stops them from invading other tissues. We found that as prostate cancer becomes more advanced the activity of PRH is decreased in three ways: first, the PRH protein is inactivated by a modification known as phosphorylation; second, the gene that normally produces PRH is stopped from making PRH; and third, this gene is deleted altogether in some cancer cells. Our work showed that the PRH protein works by controlling the activity of many genes important in allowing prostate cells to respond to signals from immune cells and in particular we showed that PRH controls the response to a molecule called Transforming Growth Factor beta (TGFb) released from some types of immune cell. In addition we have shown that TGFb itself controls PRH activity by decreasing how much PRH is produced by the PRH gene and by increasing phosphorylation of PRH.  We will investigate the importance of immune cells and immune signals in prostate cancer in Kenya and in the UK and find out how changes in the levels and activity of PRH alter the response of prostate cells to TGFb and other immune signals. To achieve this we will collect blood, urine, and cancer samples from Kenyan patients and document the clinical history associated with prostate cancer in these patients using questionnaires. We will then determine the levels of PRH and phosphorylated PRH in Kenyan and UK prostate cancer samples using a technique called immunohistochemistry (IHC) that allows us to visualise proteins in cancer cells. We will also measure the levels of inflammatory signals and immune cells in the Kenyan blood samples. Finally we will determine how changes in PRH levels and activity influence how prostate cells respond to signals from immune cells and how these signals control PRH levels. These studies will advance our understanding of how immune signals are involved in prostate cancer. They will also tell us whether measuring the levels of immune signals in blood and PRH or phosphorylated PRH in prostate cancer might be a good ways to predict which patients require treatment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="KE" type="KENYA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-27">172200.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-27">43398.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The incidence of prostate cancer in the UK is rising and around 50,000 new cases are diagnosed annually. In many cases treatment is unnecessary but at present we are not able to identify these patients with the required level of certainty. The incidence of prostate cancer in Kenya and other low- and middle-income countries (LMIC) is also rising and here the cost of treatment represents a significant barrier to economic development. The increase in prostate cancer in LMIC is driven by increasing life expectancy and by high levels of inflammation. Inflammation plays an important role in prostate cancer through several mechanisms including the creation of a tissue microenvironment that promotes cell replication. Phagocytosis of tumour cells by macrophages, for example, induces an anti-inflammatory phenotype and triggers the secretion of cytokines including Transforming Growth Factor beta (TGFb). A better understanding of the role of inflammation in this disease will result in improved methods for diagnosis and prognosis, as well as new and effective treatments. This would have an important impact on human health in the UK and mitigate a major barrier to development in Kenya and other LMIC.   Our recently published work showed that the transcription factor PRH/HHEX inhibits the proliferation of prostate epithelial cells as well as inhibiting cell migration and invasion. Significantly, the PRH/HHEX gene is located adjacent to the PTEN tumour suppressor gene and these genes are co-deleted in around 4% of prostate cancers. We showed that in prostate cancer cells the PRH protein is also inactivated by increased Protein Kinase CK2-dependent phosphorylation. Moreover, CpG methylation of the PRH/HHEX gene is increased in prostate cancer and this correlates with decreased PRH mRNA levels. We also demonstrated that PRH controls prostate cell proliferation and migration/invasion through transcriptional regulation of Endoglin, a TGFb co-receptor. Current work shows that PRH regulates the expression of many other genes involved in immune signalling including other members of the TGFb pathway. Moreover, TGFb down-regulates PRH mRNA and protein levels suggesting that there is a complex reciprocal interaction between TGFb signalling and PRH. We hypothesise that PRH expression and activity in prostate cells shapes their response to signals from immune cells. We propose that the inactivation or down-regulation of PRH in prostate cells by the mechanisms described above, and as a consequence of signals from immune cells, results in increased cell proliferation and cell migration/invasion and thereby contributes to prostate cancer progression. Our aims are: (1) To establish a Kenyan archive of tumour sections from patients with prostate disorders and prostate cancers and an archive of corresponding blood and urine samples. To complement this legacy archive we will examine the epidemiologic risk factors and the clinical history associated with prostate cancer in this study.   (2) To measure the levels of PRH and phosphorylated PRH in Kenyan and UK prostate cancer samples using immunohistochemistry (IHC) and compare any differences in expression in the two groups. (3) To identify the inflammatory signals (cytokines and immune cells) that are relevant in the Kenyan population using flow cytometry to measure the levels of inflammatory markers and IHC to examine immune cell infiltration in tumours and to examine their correlation with histological and clinical parameters. (4) To determine how changes in PRH levels and activity alter the response of prostate cells to signals from immune cells and to determine how signalling from immune cells down-regulates PRH expression."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
