<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R007977_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LABYRINTH: Conservation, Analysis and Virtual Reconstruction of the Archaeological Site of Hawara Pyramid and Labyrinth (El Fayoum)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hawara is an ancient cemetery site in the south-eastern Fayum region, about 80km south of Cairo. It is the burial place of Amenemhat III, the last great king of the 12th dynasty (about 1855-1808 BC). To the south of the pyramid the Pharaoh constructed a large cult complex (approximately 120 metres by 300 metres), in which the Pharaoh was worshipped as a god for over 1500 years. The huge mortuary temple that originally stood adjacent to this pyramid is believed to have formed the basis of the complex of buildings with galleries and courtyards called a &quot;labyrinth&quot; by Herodotus. In Late Antiquity, the complex was considered as one of the wonders of the world. Despite its historical significance, there have never been clear drawings or details of the labyrinth layout or structure.   Due to sustained irrigation water flow under the pyramid and labyrinth site, the archaeological site has become abandoned and is exhibiting signs of severe deterioration. This water flow has developed over the past century with the water level now approximately 5 meters below the topographic surface, and about 7 meters above the lower corridor level. There is an international effort to implement a sustainable conservation strategy and dewatering of the site. It is imperative to understand the level of underground water table, using remote sensing to record water levels and thermal conditions of the acquifer material and hydraulic properties within the chambers and in the Pyramid substructure. There is an urgent need to document and diagnose existing condition and use the latest Virtual Heritage Technologies to produce scenario conservation and recovery models, before any conservation or dewatering work can commence.     This 36-months innovative research project offers a breakthrough in the development of state-of-the-art virtual reality interface and repository platform that not only records and documents existing site conditions for interactive visualisation, but more importantly will incorporate structural, thermal and water data within the computerised virtual environment. The outcome of this typological model will feed into the assessement of different scenarios of conservation activities and its potential impact, in advance of implementation. The project team will undertake comprehensive investigative research, and analysis  of the site&apos;s archaeological records using innovative virtual heritage technologies that will: a) conduct accurate 3D Cloud-point to laser scan and digitally survey, record and model existing conditions of the site; b) utilise state-of-the-art geophysics underground surveys to detect, analyse and model the labyrinth&apos;s spatial layout and its water table; c) develop a state-of-the-art interactive virtual platform that integrates remote sending indicators and dataset; d) develop virtual reality experience of the site, as well as mobile app for the site&apos;s history and navigation.    This project is developed in partnership with the UNESCO Chair at the University of Florence and the National Research Institute of Astronomy and Geophysics, Egypt. It focuses on the use of state-of-the-art laser scanners, and virtual heritage modelling techniques to develop an integrated and interactive model of the site (underground, aboveground and airborne).   This comprehensive data set/model will act as a platform for identifying issues, decision making and mapping the dewatering and implementation of the conservation work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to develop and implement an evidence-based strategy and action-plan to inform the sustainable preservation of the endangered archaeological site of Hawara (El Fayoum Governorate) using digital and virtual LiDAR Technologies. The project intends to foster tourism by increasing global awareness of the site and its historical significance. This project will inform and drive a UNESCO-led international effort to limit the impact of increasing hydrogeological threats, underground water table and continuous deterioration of the structural integrity of Pyramid burial chambers and the Labyrinth passages.     The project is designed to answer a key research question;    How effective is the use of digital LiDAR scanning technologies in mapping and synthesising discrete evidence-based findings on the spatial layout and conditions of underground archaeological structures?  Furthermore, how this effectiveness could guide a sustainable preservation strategy for an endangered heritage site?    To achieve this aim, this research programme will:     a) Develop and implement a customised methodology for accurate 3D laser scan and digital survey, record and model existing conditions of the site.   This method will include,  3D laser scanning, 3D sound recording, analysis of atmospherics and environmental conditions, above and underground.    b) Utilise intelligent geophysical underground surveys to detect, analyse and model the labyrinth&apos;s remains, spatial layout and its water table.   The research will aim to produce a credible layout of the Hawara archaeological site and location of underground structural remains. This will be achieved through overlaying archaeological, geomatic, geological and geophysical datasets, with spatial analysis and satellite imaging of the site. The project will collect multi-disciplinary data, and will process, generate and weight the dataset findings. The surveys will be coded and reproduced through visual infographics on the publicly accessible virtual reality modelling interface and website.     c) Develop a prototype of a novel interactive virtual heritage platform. This prototype will integrate remote sensing indicators, satellite imaging analysis, geophysical datasets on the customary developed ArcGIS model of the site.  This novel technique of overlaying different datasets to determine accurate locations of sub-surface structures is a semi-automated digital system with evidence-based predictive scenarios of excavation.    d) Develop a virtual reality experience of the site (Pyramid and Labyrinth) portraying the site&apos;s history and evolution over time and history. This will also include developing associated educational infographics and virtual tours.   This will form a critical part of a sustainable tourism strategy that will increase the awareness of the site and its historic significance through engaging global tourism and pre-university educational programmes. A series of cultural activities both onsite and online will also be developed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-08">43098.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-08">84826.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-08">57595.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-08">15030.11</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-08">3228555.904</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Large Grants Award to Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R007977_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FR007977%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
