<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N013492_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton-Bhabha Virtual Centre on Nitrogen Efficiency of Whole-cropping Systems for improved performance and resilience in agriculture (NEWS India-UK)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The need to optimize agricultural nitrogen (N) use is fast emerging as a key global challenge where international cooperation can play a transformational role. The NEWS India-UK Virtual Joint Centre builds on existing global leadership by UK and Indian N researchers to develop and test innovative approaches to optimize N management that help meeting food security goals while reducing multiple environmental threats.  The NEWS India-UK reflects the need to apply the full array of N management opportunities through bi-lateral cooperation between India and UK. This includes improving both crop biological nitrogen use efficiency (NUE), using improved genetic material to help biochemical processes be more efficient and agronomic NUE, which considers the amount of N reaching harvested products compared with N inputs, which can be improved by better field and fertilizer management practices. &quot;NEWS&quot; stands for Nitrogen Efficiency of Whole cropping Systems, reflecting the need for both these strategies if the full benefits are to be achieved.  However, NEWS India-UK also takes two important further steps. Firstly, it applies the outcomes of biological and agronomic NUE advances at the farm scale. Critical here is the need to recycle all available N sources (such as manures, crop residues, atmospheric inputs and biological nitrogen fixation) and to examine the barriers that limit adoption of available methods at the farm scale. Secondly, it scales up the outcomes to the national scale. By focusing on establishing a full agricultural nitrogen budget for India, the approach will point to the major opportunities for improvement. This will integrate the plant and agronomic NUE strategies, farm scale options and national strategies (including from N policies, spatial optimization etc) that could be used to improve N management at a national level, giving clear estimates of the overall benefits. This will enable forward looks or &apos;scenarios&apos; that explore &apos;what if&apos; situations of how N could be managed better in the future and how it could contribute to food and energy security, improve agricultural resilience to climate change and reduce effects of water, air and soil pollution. Virtual Centre deliberately combines scientific disciplines to cross-fertilize ideas and develop more joined-up solutions.  Analysis of natural genetic variation, together with the opportunity that can be provided by Genetic Modification (GM) techniques, will support process studies on improving plant level NUE.  At the field scale, the project will quantify full nitrogen budgets, measure all major N emissions to the air and water and demonstrate how NUE improvements translate into reduced N pollution and greenhouse gas emission.  The field scale will also bring together the options to see how a combination of genetic and agronomic improvements can maximize net benefits of better nitrogen management for higher productivity and climate resilience.  The experimental datasets will then be applied, with support of case studies, to assess the farm scale, with mathematical models used to bring information together and to consider simple tools that can support small-holder farmers for better decision making. Finally, the national-scale work is also addressed by using models, where available statistical information for Indian agriculture is brought together with the expert understanding to develop country-level estimates and the forward look.  The work of the NEWS India-UK virtual centre is organized around 5 science components:  C1:  Plant strategies, genetics and improving plant NUE;  C2: Agronomic strategies to improving field-level NUE;  C3:  Farm scale nitrogen strategies, maximizing the value of all N sources;  C4:  National scale nitrogen strategies and scientific synthesis; and finally, C5:  Capacity Building, Training and Dissemination, which links across the Virtual Centre to strengthen the research integration and build the basis for durable India-UK cooperation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall Strategic Goal of NEWS India-UK is to promote cooperation that demonstrates innovative ways to improve agricultural N management, allowing increased and more resilient food production while reducing multiple pollution threats. The Centre will strengthen the world-leading position of both countries, including their input to the International Nitrogen Management System (INMS), a global science support process for internatonal N policy being developed by UNEP, INI, the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) and others.  Five Strategic Objectives contribute to this goal: 1. To establish an internationally leading program of NUE research that links the complementary strengths of the Indian and UK partners. 2. To strengthen existing and build new collaboration between UK and Indian partners, including developing synergy with allied N research beyond the immediate focus. 3. To make innovative links between N research domains, e.g., plant biology, biotechnology, agronomy, biogeochemistry, spatial data analysis, environmental modelling and policy analysis. 4. To build a wider scientific basis for durable cooperation in agricultural N beyond the project, supported by use of fellowships, post-doctoral training, joint workshops and seminars. 5. To use the research programme as a platform for stakeholder engagement to foster mutual learning and feedback thereby strengthening India-UK cooperation.  The overall Scientific Goal is to show how a combination of agronomic and biological improvements can contribute to raising NUEfc at field, farm and national scales and to demonstrate by how much these improvements will reduce N losses to the environment (including NH3, NO, N2O, N2, NO3-, etc), thereby contributing to increased resilience of Indian agriculture. To achieve this, the Centre includes a transdisplinary programme linking complementary science areas and scales.  Five Scientific Objectives contribute to this goal: 1. To characterize and explain plant NUE differences, including establishment of a phenotypic ranking of Indian rice varieties for NUE supported by improved functional understanding of traits, comparing this with what can be achieved by a known genetic modification (GM) for improved plant NUE. 2. To compare the effectiveness of agronomic and biological approaches to improving NUE, and to assess by how much combined approaches maximize overall crop performance.  3. To quantify the relationships between NUE improvement and measured reduction in N losses, considering the different N forms and N loss pathways. 4. To test how better use of all available N resources can improve Farm NUE in rice-wheat rotations, including from organic manures, atmospheric N deposition and BNF, and to explore options for overcoming the barriers to better manure recycling. 5. To establish a national N agricultural budget for India to examine scenarios of improved N management and resilience, and the associated environmental benefits.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">94208.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">377597.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">401656.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">191482.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">47870.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
