<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S008608_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">On Page and on Stage: Celebrating Dalit and Adivasi Literatures and Performing Arts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Network &apos;Writing, Translating, Analysing Dalit Literature&apos; was created in 2014 by Dr Nicole Thiara, Centre for Postcolonial Studies at Nottingham Trent University (NTU), UK, and Dr Judith Misrahi-Barak, research centre EMMA at Universit&#xE9; Paul-Val&#xE9;ry Montpellier 3 (UPVM), France, following the award of an AHRC grant. The research conducted during the 2014-16 grant period explored and analysed Dalit literature in international, multi-disciplinary contexts for the first time since Dalit literature, produced by artists formerly labelled &apos;Untouchables&apos;, emerged as the most significant, prolific and controversial literary movement in India in the last 30 years. Despite the quality, vibrancy and experimental nature of this burgeoning literary tradition, it had received scant attention from the general public or in academia. To raise its profile, in Europe and globally, and to stimulate academic research and public interest, Thiara and Misrahi-Barak organised six academic and public-facing events in the UK (at Nottingham Trent University, University of Leicester, University of East Anglia), France (at UPVM) and India (at Savitribai Phule Pune University and Delhi University). They were a resounding success (450 participants in total) and the network produced a website, a digital communications channel and several publications. Follow-on funding will allow a series of festival events to be organised that focus on Dalit and Adivasi literatures and the performing arts in India, France and the UK. During the period of network funding, it became apparent that further collaboration is needed to ensure that work by socially precarious, economically challenged, and culturally marginalized artists becomes visible and is valued in both national and global contexts. It emerged that drama and poetry were among the most marginalised of genres, and received the least attention from scholars, even though these genres are among the most significant in Dalit and Adivasi activist circles and the most prominent in voicing resistance to continued caste discrimination and social exclusion. Even more significant was the insight we gained into the widespread perception amongst Dalit and Adivasi writers and performing artists that their literary and artistic output requires larger and more varied audiences in order to sustain its creative and experimental development. Dalit and Adivasi folk art forms are in danger of disappearing if they do not receive more support from a pan-Indian Dalit and Adivasi audience, and from cultural and state organisations, and can be both supported and enriched by new &apos;mainstream&apos; audiences and international recognition.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The network proposes to co-create and co-organise international public events which, for the first time on this scale, will share Dalit and Adivasi performing arts widely. They will include poetry, music, drama performances and films, and public discussions with practitioners of both folk and contemporary performative art forms with the support and contribution of academic researchers who will introduce performances and conduct workshops and interviews. In partnership with various organisations and institutions&#x2014;India&apos;s Department of Kannada and Culture, the Indian National School of Drama, the international theatre festival IAPAR, the Paris libraries, Nottingham&apos;s New Art Exchange and Nottingham UNESCO City of Literature&#x2014; the network plans to host events to engage as wide a range of audiences and communities as possible, including Dalit and marginalised communities in and outside of India. A consultative document will be created in the form of a manifesto, produced collaboratively to initiate public policy and effect change.  This project will invigorate invaluable folk traditions and sustain the development of a variety of artistic practices, the experience of which will encourage and enrich new audiences and contribute to the development of a world in which caste discrimination will be eroded and equality in the widest sense fostered and advanced. Dalit and Adivasi art&apos;s message that no-one should be left behind will be amplified and celebrated.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-05-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">80350.36</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="1. This project proposes to use festival events as a means to create an international platform to promote and raise the profile of marginalised Dalit and Adivasi performing arts and literatures. Dalits are members of Scheduled Castes, formerly labelled &apos;Untouchables&apos;, and Adivasis are referred to as India&apos;s Scheduled Tribes; the literatures and performances of these groups contribute to India&apos;s heritage and are at the forefront of artistic innovation and experimentation in various modern genres. However, their literatures and cultural practices struggle to find wider audiences because they are frequently perceived in mainstream discourse as either excessively political or no longer relevant; their value is frequently disavowed in India. Outside of India, audiences are rarely aware of these significant cultural practices. This project will raise the esteem and visibility of important cultural traditions and practices, both in and outside of India. For the first time, a series of international festivals will showcase some of the most neglected genres, including Dalit and Adivasi poetry, theatre, folk art, film and dance. Co-hosted festivals will engage a range of external partners in Nottingham, Pune, Bangalore and Paris, most of whom have never included Dalit and Adivasi performances in their programmes.  2. This project will provide platforms for, and facilitate access to, international venues for Dalit and Adivasi artists and folk arts, in danger of disappearing due to lack of funding and esteem. By creating access to highly respected and prestigious venues, including the state-owned theatre Ravindra Kalakshetra in Bangalore, Paris libraries, and established and internationally acclaimed festivals such as IAPAR&apos;s in Pune, and the Mela festival organised by Nottingham&apos;s New Art Exchange to showcase South Asian arts, the project will preserve and nurture at-risk art forms and stimulate wider interest and expertise. 3. In collaboration with the artists, project partners, cultural organisations and the network, a manifesto will be created with cultural policy recommendations. 4. Building on the international network created through the original Research Network Grant, this project will draw on the creative work and research of network members to establish new collaborations between creative practitioners, cultural sector organisations and researchers. This expanded collaborative network will enable knowledge dissemination and exchange between international festival organisers, publishers, marginalised theatre troupes and Dalit and Adivasi writers, poets, playwrights, street performers, folk artists, directors, actors, dancers, visual artists and researchers. These collaborative ventures will open up timely and urgently needed opportunities for the fostering, preservation and development of third-sector and scholarly engagement with these artistic practices.  5. Overall, the project aims to empower Dalit and Adivasi communities by creating festival events dedicated to their art forms. It will encourage Dalit and Adivasi audiences to visit prestigious cultural venues, which they often regard as inaccessible, by creating an atmosphere specifically designed and marketed to welcome marginalised audiences, enabled through targeted publicity by external partners. The network draws on the existing website and email subscription list for effective communication of the project&apos;s initiatives to invite the widest possible participation at all events. Events are designed to encourage the social mixing of audiences to create opportunities to overcome perceived caste boundaries. The network will create a Twitter account to encourage engagement. Dalit and Adivasi participation will be a platform for the co-creation of a cultural policy. 6. Events will be filmed and made accessible to the general public via the network&apos;s YouTube channel to create further awareness of and interest in these neglected art forms beyond the duration of the grant."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">80350.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S008608_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
