<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005942_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(Digital) archives, memory and reconstruction in post-Genocide Rwanda (HN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 1994, Rwanda suffered a Genocide of enormous proportions, and has faced huge challenges in its wake. The Genocide is the pivotal event in the recent history of Rwanda, and much of civic and political life since then has focused on the on-going process of reconstruction. A range of educational and other interventions has been made by the government to further reconciliation between perpetrators and victims and positive relations between communities. The aim is to prevent future conflict, to commemorate the dead and respect the survivors, to construct and preserve a shared memory of the event, and to create a shared identity as Rwandans. Rwanda is now on its way to creating a modern integrated society with a burgeoning economy.   The Aegis Trust, a charity that works towards the prevention of genocide through education and research, has collected testimonies and other documentary material about the Genocide and post-Genocide reconstruction as the Genocide Archive of Rwanda, both as a physical archive but more particularly as a digital archive, transforming access to the material. There is a range of other significant archival holdings that if digitised and integrated would significantly increase understanding of the Genocide, and offer further opportunities for education, research, and public understanding and reconciliation.   Most prominent among these is the archive of the Gacaca Courts, which were based on a traditional method of conflict resolution that was revived to deal with the problem of processing large numbers of accused. The records of these courts form an archive of 60,000,000 pages, and are of unparalleled significance as a record of the process of truth telling, justice, and reconciliation. A project is underway, supervised by a consortium including King&apos;s College London and the Aegis Trust, to digitise the documents and create an online archive, with tools and interpretive materials.   These developments can play a key role in the burgeoning digital economy in Rwanda. The government is fostering a knowledge-based economy including ICT, with the aim of becoming a hub of expertise within east Africa, and digital content and asset industries form an important part in this vision. Currently, the skills and knowledge required for managing digital materials are largely lacking, and one of the aims of the Gacaca project is to build this expertise and capacity locally.   These initiatives do however pose fundamental questions about the role and nature of digital archives in Rwanda. The Network will draw upon two areas of research in the digital humanities. The first will explore the role of (digital) archives in transitional justice, the construction of cultural memory, and the impact and potentially transformative effect of mass digitisation. This will provoke an examination of the implications of creating digital archives of records of the Genocide, and of potential uses of the materials, and enable the establishment of policies and processes specific to the Rwandan context. The second will address the infrastructural aspects of digital archives: what forms of archival structures are appropriate and sustainable in the cultural context of Rwanda, and what might their relationship be to the growing digital economy?   We will explore these two themes in two internationally and interdisciplinary conferences in Rwanda and the UK, and as a result we will make specific recommendations for next steps in which the theoretical, practical and pedagogical aspects of the Network&apos;s research around digital archives can contribute to social, cultural or economic development in Rwanda, and also build new international collaborations that can take these forward. In particular, we will develop a roadmap for capacity building in digital content technologies in Rwanda, in collaboration archive holders, higher education, and tech industries, with the ultimate objective of creating a &quot;centre of excellence&quot; for the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="RW" type="RWANDA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-29">33748.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="In 1994, Rwanda suffered a Genocide of enormous proportions, and much of civic and political life since then has focused on the on-going process of reconciliation and reconstruction. Archives, in particular digital archives, have a key role to play in this process. There are many significant archival holdings in Rwanda that would offer significant opportunities for education, research, &amp; public understanding of the Genocide. Most prominent among these is the archive of the Gacaca Courts, a traditional method of conflict resolution, which comprise 60,000,000 pages related to the trials of alleged perpetrators. King&apos;s is working on a project with the Aegis Trust, a charity that works towards genocide prevention, on the creation of a digital Gacaca archive, with online tools and interpretive materials. Moreover, these digital initiatives have the potential for stimulating the burgeoning digital economy, one of the pillars of the Rwandan government&apos;s economic plan, through building local capacity and expertise in digital content and asset technologies.  The Network draws upon two areas of arts &amp; humanities research, specifically from the digital humanities. The first will explore the role of (digital) archives in transitional justice, the construction of cultural memory and identity, and the impact and potentially transformative effect of mass digitisation for arranging, processing and engaging with archives. This will provoke an examination of the implications of creating digital archives of records of the Genocide, including ethical issues raised by personal testimonies, and of current and future uses of the materials; this will enable the establishment of policies and processes specific to the Rwandan context that can inform future work. What new meanings and layers of understanding may be included and excluded as a result, and how might these be represented in the context of Rwandan identity, memory, culture and society?  Secondly, we will address the infrastructural aspects of digital archives: what forms of archival structures and interfaces are required for solutions that are appropriate for the cultural context in Rwanda? How can a sustainable infrastructure for archival memory be developed in Rwanda and what might its relationship be to the growing digital economy? Here capacity building and education in digital archives are key topics to be explored, with involvement of tech SMEs, educators, and funders. The Network will in particular draw in the various institutions in Rwanda with significant archival holdings relating to the Genocide.   In concrete terms, by the end of the Network we aims to achieve the following:   (i) To explore and debate these two themes in the Rwandan context with a wide range of academic and non-academic stakeholders from Rwanda and international experts, by holding two internationally attended and interdisciplinary conferences, in Rwanda and the UK, and thus to frame the emerging international development agenda in Rwanda in these areas.  (ii) To make specific recommendations for next steps in which the theoretical, practical &amp; pedagogical aspects of the Network&apos;s research can contribute to social, cultural or economic development in Rwanda, and to build new international collaborations that can take these forward. This will include new research questions, practitioner-orientated projects with organisations possessing Genocide-related archives, and educational programmes. The recommendations will be detailed in the conference reports and integrated into the final Network report.  (iii) In particular, to develop a roadmap for capacity building in digital archive/content technologies in Rwanda, building on earlier work with Aegis, and to identify &amp; set up new collaborations with archive holders, higher education, and tech SMEs, in terms of (e.g.) training &amp; HE education programmes, and academic-industry partnerships, with the ultimate aim of creating a regional &quot;centre of excellence&quot;."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">33748.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005942_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">8186.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005942_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
