<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008547_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diet, biomarkers and non-communicable diseases in rural and urban China: federated analysis of population-based studies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diet (i.e. intake of specific foods, nutrients, and overall dietary patterns) plays an important role in the development and progression of NCDs, which is the leading cause of early death and disability. However, the majority of the previous studies were conducted in high-income Western countries, with limited information available from low- and middle-income countries (LMICs), such as China, where nearly three-quarters of NCDs occur. This lack of robust information makes it difficult to formulate evidence-based dietary guidelines for NCD prevention in these countries. More importantly, associations observed only in a specific population (or few similar populations) may not be the true effect of diet, but due to the impact of other factors which are closely related to dietary habits, e.g. socio-demographic factors or other lifestyle factors (e.g. physical activity). Therefore, studying the association between diet and NCDs in LMICs has become very important because populations in these countries, compared to those living in Western countries, have very distinct dietary and disease patterns and the correlations between dietary factors and socio-demographic factors are also very different. Moreover, the exact biological mechanisms through which diet exert its effect on NCD incidence and progression is largely unknown. A better understanding of such mechanisms will greatly enhance our capacity to effectively prevent and treat these diseases.  In this proposal, we plan to bring together several large population based studies which in total involves &gt; 1 million Chinese adults for whom information on dietary habits, biomarkers which are closely related to metabolism status of the body, and incidence of NCDs is available, together with long-term stored bio-samples. Joint analyses of existing as well as newly generated omics (i.e. MS-Metabolomics and Metagenomics) data will be performed in order to have a comprehensive robust assessment of diet and NCD association as well as potential underlying mechanisms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-08-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="CM" type="CAMEROON"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MIDDLE AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1028</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-04">22436.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="To overall objective of this federated data analysis is to achieve a better understanding on the associations of various dietary factors with different types and subtypes of non-communicable diseases (NCDs) in rural and urban China as well as the main metabolic mechanisms underlying these associations. Specific objectives include the following: 1) To establish a web-based infrastructure to enable federated analysis of research databases hosted by different institutions while allowing each study to retain full control over individual-level data. 2) To perform comprehensive analysis using existing data resources on prospective associations of dietary factors with NCD outcomes and cross-sectional associations between diet and various biomarkers as well as subclinical measures of NCDs. 3) To collect new data using emerging omics technologies (e.g. MS-Metabolomics and metagenomics) and to investigate the associations between dietary factors and these novel biomarkers. 4) To perform genome-wide association studies to identify the genetic determinants of dietary factors and biomarkers closely related to dietary intake; to explore gene-diet interaction;  and where possible, to perform Mendelian randomisation (MR) studies of diet (including dietary biomarkers) in relation to risk of NCDs. 5) To carefully review, develop and utilise state-of-the-art casual mediation analysis methods for determining the potential mediating effects of various cardio-metabolic, biochemical and multi-omic markers on the associations of diet with different NCDs."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">22436.78</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008547_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">-12938.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008547_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
