<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T029862_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing effective rodent control strategies to reduce disease risk in ecologically and culturally diverse rural landscapes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diseases transmitted from rodents to humans are a serious threat to health, with the highest risk in low-income countries. The risk from rodent-borne infections (RBI) depends on the abundance of infected rodents, as well as how socio-cultural practices and beliefs influence human-rodent interactions. Many rodent species implicated in disease transmission are also pests that feed on crops and stored food, and consequently management to reduce rodent numbers could have a wide impact on health and well-being.  However, controlling rodent populations effectively is challenging. Breeding and movement from adjacent populations may rapidly cancel out the impact of control. Innovative approaches that exploit ecological understanding of where and when rodents breed have been developed in the agricultural sector, primarily in Asia, with communities working together to target control and significantly reduce crop damage. However, such techniques are poorly developed in Africa, and their potential to reduce the risk from RBI is unknown. In some circumstances, changes to rodent movements following control could increase disease transmission and prevalence in rodent populations, potentially increasing risk to humans.   Ultimately, this project aims to reduce the risk from RBI in Africa by increasing the knowledge and expertise needed to develop holistic rodent management applicable for local conditions and communities. Working with communities in Tanzania and Madagascar, in the first stage of the project we will address specific unanswered questions, whilst in the second phase we will develop and test rodent management strategies.  Two questions we will address are: how do rodent movements change after localised control, and how does control influence the prevalence of RBI in rodent populations? To make sure our approach is widely relevant, we will work with rodent species and diseases that have large impacts and contrasting ecologies. We will focus on the multi-mammate mouse, a key pest species in Africa, and the black rat, a globally important invasive pest, and consider three RBI: plague, leptospirosis and rickettsioses, which differ in key aspects of their epidemiology. We will combine field studies with sophisticated computer models to explore how control in different locations and at different times of the year impacts on rodent movement, abundance and the prevalence of RBI. The results will provide important insights into how ecological and epidemiological factors influence the impact of different control strategies on RBI and rodent damage.  We will also work with local communities using a range of approaches to address three further questions: how do communities perceive the health threat from rodents, how do communities currently interact with and manage rodents, and how feasible are different management strategies? As effective control strategies have to be accepted and sustainable for local communities, we need to understand local perceptions and practices. For example, high labour requirements during specific key periods in the agricultural cycle may mean that some rodent control strategies are not feasible.   The insights from this research during the first phase of the project will be used to inform the development of community-led trials of rodent management strategies. The impact of these trials on rodent abundance and the prevalence of RBI will be monitored, and the results used to refine and test our computer models.   We will use this comparative study to identify common features that determine the effectiveness or uptake of a strategy. To ensure our research informs policies, we will conduct workshops with service providers involved in agriculture, health and the environment. Across these sectors we will explore current attitudes, policies and communication practices, and provide training in adaptive management approaches. Our project will also build research capacity through collaboration and  training.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ultimate aim of the project is to reduce the risk from rodent-borne infections (RBI), and improve health and well-being, by increasing the capacity to develop rodent-control measures that are applicable, sustainable and resilient given local ecological, epidemiological, agricultural and socio-cultural contexts. The project will focus on rural landscapes in Tanzania and Madagascar, using exemplar case-study host-pathogen systems with contrasting ecological and epidemiological characteristics. We will exploit high quality existing data and conduct new experimental studies, integrating these with state-of-the-art statistical and modelling approaches, as well as ethonographic and social science studies, in order to inform the co-development of effective rodent management strategies with communities and stakeholders. Community co-development and engagement will take place from the start of the project, with community representatives involved in decision making processes, in the implementation and collection of data and interpreting impact.   Our project has 7 objectives, listed here in order of priority:   OBJ1: Increase the human-capacity in sub-Saharan Africa to develop long-term management strategies for pest rodents in rural landscapes that pose a threat to human health. Our ambition is that the approaches and capacity developed by this project will lead to improved management of rodent pests across the region.  OBJ2: Identify common or, in contrast, specific, ecological, epidemiological, social and cultural factors that affect disease risk and influence the methods, impact, uptake and sustainability of control strategies. These insights will facilitate scaling-up of project findings to other settings by national and international stakeholders.   In order to achieve these objectives we need to first:   OBJ3: Develop a management modelling tool for exploring how rodent control impacts on rodent abundance and RBI at landscape scales, which can readily be adapted to the many species, diseases and contexts where control could improve health and wellbeing.   OBJ4: Use this tool to test different management options for case-study species and RBI in different landscapes, parameterised by existing and new data. These host-pathogen systems have been chosen to provide contrasting ecological and epidemiological characteristics.  OBJ5: Explore influences of agricultural, household and community practices on exposure to RBI and rodent control.  OBJ6: Work with communities and other stakeholders to co-develop solutions for our case-study species and identify opportunities and constraints for scaling-up effective rodent control.  Our collaborative, multi-country project will also:   OBJ7: Increase local skills in anthropological and social science methodologies, laboratory diagnostics, statistical analysis and modelling, and consolidate strong multi-disciplinary UK-Africa and Africa-Africa partnerships.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Aberdeen</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-27" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-04-26" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Madagascar</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">152776.63</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">612344.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">617303.99</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">465784.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">152776.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FQ1 2021-2022 spend on Developing effective rodent control strategies to reduce disease risk in ecologically and culturally diverse rural landscapes</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T029862_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-31">152776.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FQ2 2021-2022 spend on Developing effective rodent control strategies to reduce disease risk in ecologically and culturally diverse rural landscapes</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T029862_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-30">152776.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FQ2 2021-2022 spend on Developing effective rodent control strategies to reduce disease risk in ecologically and culturally diverse rural landscapes</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T029862_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">1848209.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Aberdeen</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T029862/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Aberdeen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT029862%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
