<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N011538_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DEPICT: DEsigning and Policy Implementation for encouraging Cycling and walking Trips</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Walking and cycling are the most sustainable modes of transport in cities and should be placed at the heart of a transition towards low-carbon urban mobility systems. This is because walking and cycling can improve the life chances and health and wellbeing of each city inhabitant -- irrespective of their socioeconomic status, gender, ethnicity, age -- with hardly any adverse impact on the lives of fellow inhabitants. Research on how walking and cycling in cities can be encouraged is burgeoning and provides many compelling insights. However, insights about the role of infrastructure in stimulating urban walking and cycling are limited because the focus is typically on the &apos;hardware&apos; of cycle lanes, sidewalks, bike sharing schemes, road design, urban design and so forth; the &apos;software&apos; of governance, regulation, information provision, maintenance and repair as well as the embedded knowledge, know-how, meanings, values, aspirations and emotions are not always given the emphasis they deserve. Moreover, the research is often set in cities in the global North and assumes insights and concepts that has emerged from there as universally valid and easily transferable to cities in the global South.   This international research project will adopt a broader understanding of infrastructure and develop original empirical and theoretical insights on the basis of comparative research in the UK, the Netherlands and the state of S&#xE3;o Paulo in Brazil. The activities undertaken by the Oxford team focus on the role of community-led initiatives in London to encourage walking and cycling and in creating infrastructures that are conducive to these practices. The Oxford researchers will make an inventory of the heterogeneity of recent community-led initiatives in both cities, covering such issues as what they consist of, who are involved, what the goals are, and who benefits. The Oxford team will also critically evaluate if and how such initiatives can contribute to a large-scale transition towards low-carbon urban mobility. A mixed-method approach consisting of document analysis, interviews and focus groups will be adopted, and the team will engage with local communities, policymakers, interest groups and other stakeholders in various ways. It can be expected that, apart from creating academic outputs, the project will contribute to: social learning among community-led initiatives through the sharing of experiences and good practices; to greater reflexivity about how policy, governance and regulation affect community-led initiatives; and to the creation of more effective support structures for such initiatives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-07-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">43964.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">88284.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">88999.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">22339.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Profound structural changes in urban mobility systems are urgently required because current systems are profoundly unsustainable: they make a large contribution to local and global environmental problems (air pollution, anthropogenic climate change), intensify social inequality and exclusion within cities, raise troubling questions about energy security, and enhance a range of public health problems (obesity, respiratory disease, traffic injury). Walking and cycling are arguably the most sustainable modes of transport and should be placed at the heart of a &apos;just&apos; transition -- i.e. one in which questions of social justice and equity are explicitly considered -- towards low-carbon, energy efficient urban mobility systems in the global North and South. Urban mobility systems configured around walking and cycling will also be more resilient to the effects of high or volatile oil prices and provide affordable mobility and access to destinations, thereby increasing both capabilities (Sen) and extending rights to the city (Lefebvre) across all socio-economic strata of the population. Furthermore, they also have important health and wellbeing benefits for individuals and societies at large.   Yet, the potential of walking and cycling can only be realised when infrastructures that are in place promote cycling and walking. Research on how infrastructural interventions can promote cycling and walking is now burgeoning across a range of disciplines, but tends to adopt a rather narrow understanding of &apos;infrastructure&apos; that is limited to the &apos;hardware&apos; of urban design, bike lanes, traffic lights, public bike sharing schemes, and the like. This project starts from the premise that the role of infrastructure in walking and cycling can be understood better if a broader definition of infrastructures in line with recent thinking in cultural geography, urban studies and anthropology as architectures of circulation is adopted. This means that analytical attention is broadened to also encompass the &apos;software&apos; of practices of governance, regulation, information provision, maintenance and repair; the codified knowledge, and know-how and rules embedded in the &apos;hardware&apos; and the aforementioned practices; the embedded meanings and values; and the associated affective forces and engagements. This broader understanding of infrastructure draws attention to questions of infrastructure politics, distribution of benefits and citizenship, and also to the important role of community-led initiatives to encourage walking and cycling.  Given these considerations, the project seeks to answer the following overall question: Which features of the urban environment, governance of physical infrastructure and local communities in S&#xE3;o Paulo, The Netherlands, and/or United Kingdom influence walking and cycling and how can they be optimised to achieve sustainable urban mobility for all? This question is addressed through a series of work packages which address the following more specific objectives:  a) To develop an in-depth understanding of the meaning of attributes of e.g. physical infrastructure for walking and cycling, traffic rush, gradients, urbanization degrees, and greenness in stimulating walking and cycling for various population categories (WP2);  b) To develop successful pathways for stimulating cycling on the basis of the analysis of planning strategies in S&#xE3;o Paulo state, The Netherlands and the UK at both &apos;hardware&apos; (pathways, parking) and &apos;software&apos; (policies, practices, governmental support) levels (WP3); c) To examine grassroots innovations in infrastructures for urban walking and cycling and critically evaluate if and how these bottom-up innovations can contribute to &apos;just&apos; transitions in urban mobility (WP4); and d) To deepen understanding of the effects of geographical context on pedestrians&apos; and cyclists&apos; experiences and needs and policy making (WP5)."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
