<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005668_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New Engagements to enhance artists&apos; livelihoods in East Africa: Art; Writing; Work</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This impact and engagement project focusses on practical interventions that will support artists living and working in Kenya, Uganda and Rwanda build sustainable livelihoods and help build capacity in the creative industries in in East Africa, an international development priority. It will do this through engagements that respond to the needs, ambitions and priorities of visual art professionals as stated by themselves, the local organisations that support them and set out in government policy and development reports on the creative economy in East Africa commissioned by the British Council.    The planned engagements and impacts have been developed through the activities of the AHRC-GCRF funded research network &apos;Networking New Opportunities for Artists in East Africa&apos; which draws together visual art professionals from diverse backgrounds in East Africa, including artists and art collectives living and working in deprived areas, to collaboratively scope interventions that will support the sustainable development of their livelihoods. The network&apos;s activities focus on identifying pragmatic approaches to shared problems, practical initiatives that will impact directly on real life experiences and and make definable contributions to building capacity for visual art activity in the creative economy, thus working towards EAC and international development goals.  Extended evidence-gathering has identified that a fundamental constraint to addressing many of the challenges artists face is a deficit in &apos;art writing&apos; skills. This deficit is apparent at all levels in the visual art ecology and impacts in variety of ways, from a lack of confidence in preparing basic written material for self-promotion which can exclude or disadvantage many artists when trying to access professional opportunities, to the absence of a shared body of developed artistic critique. Not only does this inhibit artistic production, but it also constrains the role and capacity of the visual arts within the cultural economy. Balanced against this, new platforms including a new art magazine are struggling to emerge, and the enthusiasm, energy and demand for practical initiatives to assist development of artistic writing is evidence that the emergent generation of artistic writers and critics who are already identifying themselves as key future players in the creative economy, will respond enthusiastically to opportunities offered to assist their professional development and make their voices heard.  The project team: arts organisation 32 Degrees East, the British Council in East Africa, the BIEA, art publications Nairobi Contemporary, Art Monthly, and Newcastle University have worked collaboratively to develop plans for a set of engagements that will support specific types of art writing skills, equipping members of the visual art community with the key skills, knowledge and experience which are currently lacking and which will will assist them in the development of sustainable livelihoods.  The project develops four related strands: the development of a new art writing toolkit for essential promotional material; a pilot project developing entrepreneurial and business skills in artists through reflective writing, and an innovative approach to nurturing emergent critical voices in the visual arts, fostering a new generation of artistic writers and providing them a public platform by supporting, in a sustainable way, a new magazine for art writing. Structured around an activity programme that includes workshops, mentoring and the publication of two editions of the art magazine, the project develops its impacts within a context where the importance of supporting artists and growing the creative economy has been recognised through measures such as the passing of the Creative and Cultural Industries Bill (2015), but where government support remains minimal. The impacts that will derive from this project are therefore urgent and vital.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-20">92289.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This project&apos;s overarching aim is to support the development of sustainable livelihoods within the visual art community, and build capacity in the creative industries in in East Africa. It aims to do this through sustainable and scalable engagements that respond to the needs, ambitions and priorities of visual art stakeholders. The challenges the visual art community have been set out in East African government and British Council reports. To explore these challenges, and scope possible solutions, a new AHRC-GCRF funded network &apos;Networking New Opportunities for Artists in East Africa&apos; (NOFA) was formed in January 2018.   These collaborative activities that NOFA has engaged in, informed in detail by priorities set out in a visual art scoping report commissioned by the British Council (Standing 2014) and by evidence of the development needs of their stakeholders gathered by Project Partners, have involved contributions from over 160 visual art stakeholders from Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda as well as grass roots community arts organisations and artists&apos; collectives. Events have been co-designed by NOFA participants and and led by Project Partners in East Africa.  The aim has been to define and develop objectives for focussed and pragmatic activities that can improve the livelihoods of artists working in East Africa. A significant outcome from NOFA proceedings has been the development of a shared understanding, grounded in the evidence of the Standing Report and that presented by Partners, that a deficit in art writing skills, and capacity for art critique impedes the development of sustainable careers for art professionals, and is a constraint in the development of a sustainable and flourishing visual art ecology. This project aims to address this deficit through a series of collaboratively designed and delivered engagements.   Its objectives are to:  1 Design, develop and disseminate an online toolkit aimed at artists who need assistance in writing basic profiling and promotional material (CVs, artist statements etc.) enabling them to develop their livelihoods by capitalising on opportunities open to freelance artists.   2 Work with a group of artists on a pilot project that aims to develop reflective writing skills, giving them the ability to identify and address issues that might impact on their entrepreneurial practice and business skills.  3 Contribute to the development of a more sophisticated level of art critique, by i) fostering aspiring critical writers acquire new skills, understanding and confidence through an innovative mentoring programme, ii) offer them a platform, an understanding of art publishing and further career opportunities by supporting two special editions of a new art magazine where their work will be published.  4 Use this platform to promote the work of East African art professionals, including those engaged, in the East African context, in innovative practices including making work using non-traditional settings or modes of production such as digital platforms, performance, installation, or engaging with challenging subject matter such as complex identities, bringing this work to a wider audience including potential clients as well as the art consuming public.   5 Working through these activities, expand and strengthen the networks of those engaged in this project so that they can use their newly acquired skills and experience to benefit their peers in the visual art community; engage new audiences and markets, and establish new relationships with new stakeholders, thus contributing to the aims of building capacity for the visual arts in the creative industries in East Africa.   Through these engagements, the project aims to impact positively on the livelihoods of visual art professionals, on arts organisations, and on the public who consume art, contributing to a more professionalised and confident visual art community, and a stronger visual art ecology in East Africa."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">92289.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005668_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">-239.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005668_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
