<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M010554_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Epigenetic mechanisms regulating pluripotency from embryonic to adult neurogeneisis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Neurological diseases are amongst the most devastating since the brain does a very poor job in healing itself. In the large majority of cases, new nerve cells cannot be produced to replace injured tissue. With the increase in the population&apos;s average age, diseases such as Alzheimer&apos;s, Parkinson&apos;s and stroke will take an increasingly burdensome toll on individuals, families and society. Hope for a therapeutic solution has arisen with the discovery of brain stem cells and increased understanding of how they are controlled. Stem cells are found in two specific regions of the brain and continue to generate nerve cells in those restricted areas. Our goal is to understand how to enhance this process and entice it to be of more general relevance throughout the brain. In the past decade, laboratories around the world including ours (Shen in Beijing, Szele in Oxford) have discovered many molecules that stimulate stem cells to grow during normal development and molecules that stimulate them to repair a damaged brain. Use of this knowledge will allow us to develop medicines that mimic these molecules and thereby stimulate the growth of stem cells for brain repair. Since the repair of the adult brain is conceptually similar to the development of the brain, we also seek to understand fundamental molecular mechanisms regulating the generation of nerve cells from human embryonic stem cells (hESC). Amazingly, hESC can be grown in cell culture dishes, allowing us to discover molecules that increase nerve cell production. Similarly, adult brain stem cells can be grown in cell culture to study their generation of nerve cells. In this grant, we will use and compare both approaches in our goal to increase stem cell-derived nerve cell generation.  Most research in the 20th century has uncovered how individual molecules regulate stem cells one at a time. In this century, a shift in emphasis has occurred, and the field is now seeking to understand how molecules work together to coordinate stem cell nerve generation. This is an intelligent shift since dozens to hundreds of molecules usually are required to coordinate stem cell nerve generation. But how are so many molecules regulated in the same space and at the same time in such a coordinated way? The answer is in a fashion analogous to how a conductor organizes an orchestra: she may increase the loudness of the string section whilst repressing the horns. So-called &quot;epigenetic&quot; mechanisms coordinate dozens to hundreds of molecules by causing some to be emphasized and some to be repressed. Epigenetic mechanisms can turn molecules completely on or off, or they can more subtly turn them up or down. Importantly, they do this in stem cells and thereby cause the cells to either proliferate or to turn into nerve cells.  In our laboratories, we study how epigenetic mechanisms increase nerve cell production from embryonic stem cells (Shen, Beijing) and from adult brain stem cells (Szele, Oxford). In this collaborative project, we will seek to understand the extent to which the same molecules govern nerve cell production in the embryo as we as in the adult. We will also use this novel molecular knowledge to increase stem cell-mediated nerve cell production in a model of stroke. Brains of infants have a far higher plasticity than those in the adult and aged population. However, even infant brains do not completely repair themselves in diseases such as cerebral palsy. Thus, we will also seek to understand how epigenetic molecules enhance stem cell-mediated repair of a model of infant cerebral palsy.  Our overarching goal is to eventually use this information to increase nerve cell production from stem cells. This exciting branch of regenerative medicine is one of the best hopes for the future of treating neurological disorders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of this collaboration is to reveal novel mechanisms whereby lncRNAs and PRC2 interact to regulate neurogenesis. We will accomplish this by synergizing the strengths of our labs in ESC, lncRNA and genetic/biochemical analyses (Shen lab) with expertise in adult neurogenesis, in vivo approaches, brain development and models of disease (Szele lab).  The proposed project has the following aims: 1. Determine the effects of RIAN and YSD14/Haunt lncRNA KO on ES and SVZ cell neurogenesis. We will use in vitro ES cells and in vitro SVZ neurospheres to study the unique KO mice generated in the Shen lab. We will also carry out in vivo electroporation to knockdown these lncRNAs in the SVZ via shRNAs. Specifically, we will determine the rates of neurogenesis using well established markers and readouts. We will determine whether the lncRNAs affect aspects of neurodevelopment: proliferation, kinetics of cell cycle, fate choices or survival. We will overexpress lncRNA via electroporation in lncRNA KOs to attempt rescue of phenotpyes in ES cells and the SVZ. Throughout this aim, we will monitor stem cell self-renewal and differentiation with 2-P time-lapse microscopy in vitro (ES cells and neurospheres, Sox-2 GFP) and in slices (electroporated GFP). This aim will elucidate the functional role of selected lncRNAs in neurogenesis in ES cells, postnatal and adult neurogenesis.  2. Determine the functional interaction between RIAN and YSD14/Haunt lncRNA and PRC2 in ES cells and the SVZ. We will knock down PRC2 components with shRNA or by crossing GLAST::CreERT2 x Ezh2fl/fl or Eedfl/fl and determine if overexpressing RIAN, YSD14/Haunt or candidate lncRNAs (from Aim 3 below) rescues the phenotype. We will next ask if PRC2 regulates lncRNA expression in PRC2 conditional KO&apos;s and in knockdown experiments. lncRNA expression in ES cells and in the postnatal and adult SVZ will be determined with quantitative PCR and in situ hybridization.  3. Search for lncRNA/PRC2 biochemical interactions in ES and SVZ cells. We will prepare self-renewing ESC (+LIF) and differentiating ESC (-LIF), FACsort SVZ stem, progenitor and neuroblast cells and carry out PRC2 component (Ezh2, Eed, Suz12, Jarid2) ChIP-PCR for selected lncRNAs, based on genomic loci of lncRNAs near neurogenesis relevant genes. These biochemical interactions will then be tested in functional studies as above.  4. Determine the role of RIAN and YSD14/Haunt lncRNA KO on murine models of disease. We will examine the response of the postnatal SVZ to a model of perinatal hypoxia/ishcemia in the KOs. We will compare this to the response of the adult SVZ to middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO)in KO&apos;s. Electroporation in the adult SVZ is limited to ependymal cells therefore we will use lentiviral delivery of shRNAs to knockdown RIAN and YSD14/Haunt in conditional Ezh2 and Eed knockouts in the adult middle cerebral artery occlusion model of stroke. We will examine calretinin+ neuron production after injury as well as fate shifts in neurogenesis versus gliogenesis.  5. Identify and validate new RNA targets for PRC2 as well as investigate the function of these lncRNAs in neurognesis and neural development. In this forward-looking aim, we will use CRISPR/Cas9 approaches to generate novel lncRNA knockdown constructs and lncRNA KO mice. The knockdown constructs will be functionally tested in preliminary in vitro ES and neurosphere assays. Both sets of tools will be openly shared with the stem cell community.  An additional objective of this project is to increase ties between the stem cell communities in the UK and China via our two group&apos;s collaboration. We have already worked together and showed that PRC2 is necessary for adult neurogenesis in the SVZ. In this next phase of our work, we will expand the collaboration with two postdoctoral fellows exchanging and integrating techniques and data across the two labs through frequent travel and extended visits.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China (People&apos;s Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">31612.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">126704.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">127731.13</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">64252.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
