<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_R008620_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">iNtelligent Urban Model for Built environment Energy Research (iNumber)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable urbanisation requires the provision of secure energy for health and comfort. Key to planning sustainable energy services is an understanding of how energy demand changes over time and space and tools to help plan for its reduction.  iNUMBER is a research programme to develop: 1. A building stock and municipal service energy model to help plan a secure energy supply for urban populations to be thermally comfortable and healthy (via the provision of clean water and sanitation). The model will estimate total and disaggregated (in use, time and space) energy demand. Plus, assess the impacts of different mechanisms (e.g. shading, occupant behaviour and insulation) to reduce energy demand and the capacity to provide locally generated clean energy.  2. Linked new and existing data sets. Developing models is relatively simple, the challenge is acquiring the data to input and test the validity of models. iNUMBER tackles this challenge head on by developing state of the art data collection and analytic methods to overcome this challenge in a range of scenarios with different data availability.  3.Tools to help support the urban energy management process iNUMBER supports Indian municipalities and local partners to develop a data-driven intelligent urban model for built environment energy research and municipal planning.  It supports India&apos;s deep decarbonisation pathway by mapping current and future energy demand reduction opportunities in the built environment. It will diagnose urban energy problems, test solutions, verify progress, and improve policy decisions utilising state of the art monitoring, data science and analytics.  iNUMBER primarily focuses around meeting the India/UK Newton research topic &quot;Integration of information, communication and renewable energy technologies at building, community, and city level interventions.&quot; and will also meet elements of the other two areas of the call &quot;peak demand reduction&quot; by contributing new high resolution data and &quot;city and community technologies&quot; by providing guidance to urban planners iNUMBER will: -Undertake innovative research into: urban data collection (e.g. laser ranging combined with IR and visible images from unmanned vehicles), big data analytics, and innovative modelling.   -Promote the economic development of and welfare of developing countries, as required by Newton funding, by helping India to transition to a smart sustainable energy system which is critical to economic development.   -Engage users of different types. Our initial project partners include urban local bodies, energy software developers, energy meter hardware suppliers, residential construction companies, architectural firms, and user experience experts.  Beyond these immediate partners, we will coordinate and collaborate with other research groups in the field, engage with policymakers, and benefit the public. -Leverage Newton and DST funding by ~&#xA3;1m, with support from host universities and project partners who will provide data, test sites, equipment, and provide sector expertise. -Demonstrate usable solutions: online energy information systems; benchmarking backed up by large data sets; low-tech &quot;smart-er&quot; retrofits for electricity meters and sub-meters; reduction strategies for energy and the energy-water nexus tailored to cities of different shapes and sizes. -Build a collaborative India/UK interdisciplinary research project:  This proposal builds on the strengths of India in Information Technology and the strengths of the UK in energy epidemiology to build a best with the best collaboration. The team includes leading academics from engineering, data science, information technology, energy analysis, architecture, building science, urban science, urban planning, energy management from leading institutions in India and the UK. All work packages will be delivered via teams from both UK and India and many work packages involve interdisciplinary collaboration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">iNUMBER&apos;s main objective is to undertake research to develop a new model of building &amp; municipal energy demand, grounded in appropriate empirical data and applicable to reducing energy demand in a wide range of different contexts and with varying data availability.   This proposal has been prepared in response to the Energy Demand Reduction in the Built Environment Joint India/UK Call for Proposals and it follows the rules of the Newton Bhabha Fund by delivering the primary benefits of the project in India and subsidiary benefits in the UK.  The main (non-academic) impact is focused around the challenges of urban development in India, using urban case studies in India. Built environment energy demand in India is driven by the provision of comfort (thermal and lit) and health through the provision of clean water and sanitation. Better understanding the energy-water nexus will be a feature of iNUMBER. In the UK we will enhance existing models using learning from India in ICT, new data sources and new methods; helping position UK to export enhanced methods and tools to other countries. iNUMBER responds to the call topic &apos;Integration of information, communication and renewable energy technologies at building, community, and city level interventions&apos; and in so doing it will make &apos;Collaborative efforts to establish information and communication technology (ICT) based building energy benchmarking, future stock modelling and energy demand forecasting&apos;.   iNUMBER will provide the tools and analysis to enable key stakeholders to plan and manage the development of cities to provide high quality built environments whilst limiting energy demand, carbon emissions and environmental impact.  To facilitate this several specific objectives are set: 1. The development of a building stock model with a focus on energy demand reduction which will: - Utilise existing administrative data available for urban local bodies (ULB) and other publicly available information - Estimate total and disaggregated (in use, time and space) energy demand and assess the impacts of different mechanisms (e.g. shading, occupant behavior and insulation) to reduce energy demand and integrate locally generated clean energy - Be usable during the project and extensible over time - Accept new and different datasets as these are acquired - Allow the integration of municipal services to recognise the significant use of energy in the built environment from services such as water pumping and street lighting. 2. The development of novel, low cost methods of collecting data to input into building stock and urban energy models.  3. The collection of empirical building/urban data that can be used to test the validity of energy demand models. 4. The participation of stakeholders (see letters of support) who are potential users and beneficiaries of iNUMBER to: - Understand their needs and constraints, and identify opportunities - Identify and access available energy, building and municipal services data - Establish the features and outputs an urban model must have to provide valuable utility - Develop scalable and affordable data collection methods   5. Enhance the current understanding of energy use and related issues in the built environment to: - Improve understanding about the current residential building stock and derive energy demand reduction potential - Investigate linkages between occupant comfort, user behaviour and penetration of fast moving consumer goods such as air-conditioners and home appliances - Improve understanding of municipal energy services and derive energy demand reduction potential - Examine the impact of distributed energy generation by roof-top photovoltaic systems on energy demand in buildings and the existing electricity grid - Identify the technical potential of energy saving measures such as enhanced building envelope, low energy cooling systems and deployment of ICT at the city level</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-05">76839.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-05">258521.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-05">218852.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-05">165246.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-05">55378.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-05">7699480</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_R008620_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FR008620%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
