<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010487_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the measurement and enhancement of African children&apos;s rights and well-being in nutrition, healthcare and education through a gender lens</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The governments of the World have agreed to the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). The first five goals are no poverty, zero hunger, good health and well-being, quality education and gender equality. The African Child Policy Forum (ACPF) is the leading independent, not-for-profit, Pan-African organisation, specialising in helping African governments to improve their policies and practices to meet the SDGs for children. This project builds upon a long-term partnership between the ACPF and the University of Bristol to make better use of available data to provide policymakers with the high-quality evidence they need to help meet the first five SDGs.   Agenda 2063 is Africa&apos;s blueprint and master plan for transforming Africa into the global powerhouse of the future. It is the continent&apos;s strategic framework that aims to deliver on its goal for inclusive and sustainable development. This ambitious goal cannot be achieved without improvements in the lives of African Children. However, approximately 27 million African children suffer from stunting (low height for age), 16 million are underweight (low weight for age) and 8 million suffer from wasting (low weight for height). In 2016, only two-thirds of children in Africa had been vaccinated against diphtheria, tetanus and other serious childhood diseases. Similarly, about 7 million children in Eastern and Southern Africa and 8 million in West and Central Africa are likely to receive no pre-primary education in 2030 given the current slow rates of improvement (UNICEF 2018). The combination of poverty and inadequate nutrition, healthcare and education are amongst the most intractable development challenges faced by most countries in Africa (ACPF 2018).   Gender discrimination is also a significant problem in Africa, and there remain many social, economic and cultural factors contributing to the disempowerment and discriminatory practices that disadvantage women and girls. There is a pressing need for systematic assessments on the nature and extent of gender discrimination in nutrition, healthcare and education in Africa over the past decade (2008-2018).   This project will analyse relevant data about children&apos;s lives and circumstances using state-of-the-art quantitative and qualitative methods to explore &apos;what&apos; changes there have been in child nutrition, healthcare and education during the past ten years in Africa, &apos;when&apos; these changes are related to gender disparities and the availability and quality of child protection policies and services in each country, and &apos;where&apos; children at sub-national level are at the greatest risk of being left behind.   Outputs from this project will be published by ACPF in their forthcoming flagship report -- The African Report on Child Well-being 2020: How Friendly are African Governments towards the Girl Child?</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project contributes to global and regional efforts in measuring and enhancing African children&apos;s rights and well-being in nutrition, healthcare and education, with a focus on gender equality and a coverage of 52 African countries. It is an important extension of the exploratory work funded through the 2018-19 ESRC IAA GCRF International Development NGO Data Scheme. This will be the first large-scale, systematic appraisal on the associations between government child-friendliness and child development outcomes, using high-quality macro- and micro-data owned and accessed by the NGO partner, African Child Policy Forum (ACPF). ACPF is a well-established, leading Pan-African NGO based in Ethiopia, specialising in improving the lives of African children. Working closely with ACPF, this project aims to achieve four primary objectives:   1. Tracking changes between 2008-2018 in nutrition, healthcare and education of children in the 52 African countries with available data. This will be achieved through a) analysing longitudinal data provided by ACPF in conjunction with data from the Demographic and Health Survey, Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys, Performance Monitoring for Action, and Global School-Based Health Survey, on the nature and extent of (mal)nutrition (stunting, wasting, underweight and the Composite Index of Anthropometric Failure), healthcare (availability and accessibility of facilities and the quality of primary and secondary healthcare services), and education (the rates of attending pre-primary, primary and secondary school) over the past decade; and b) testing the reliability and validity of the Child-Friendliness-Index (CFI), developed by ACPF (for monitoring the responsiveness of African governments in meeting child-focused Sustainable Development Goals), in explaining the changes in child nutrition, healthcare and education between 2008 and 2018.  2. Exploring gender disparities in access to nutrition, healthcare and education, in order to provide policymakers with better evidence for the need for gender-responsive laws, policies and practices. This will be achieved through a) identifying significant gender gaps in nutrition, healthcare and education; b) estimating the association between gender gaps and CFI components; and c) analysing qualitative evidence provided by ACPF on how national child protection policies and services shape the lifestyles of girls and their families.  3. Supporting a systematic assessment of African governments&apos; performance in fulfilling their obligations to the rights and well-being of children in nutrition, healthcare and education. This will be achieved by explaining the improvement and/or deterioration in each government&apos;s performance, taking into consideration national geographic, demographic, economic and social characteristics as measured by key variables selected and harmonised by ACPF from the World Bank World Development Indicators, the United Nations Development Program Inequality Adjusted Human Development Index and Gender Inequality Index and so forth.  4. Providing an empirical and evidential basis for conversation and advocacy about child rights, development and well-being between local NGOs, policymakers, stakeholders and national and international development organisations (e.g. UNICEF, WHO, UNDP). This will be achieved through a) providing accurate estimates of distributions and disparities of child nutrition, healthcare and education at a sub-national level using small-area-estimations; and b) publishing the results in ACPF&apos;s flagship report -- The African Report on Child Well-being 2020: How Friendly are African Governments towards the Girl Child?</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">52933.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">108485.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">161418.99</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/T010487/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">26466.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010487_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">26466.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010487_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">26466.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010487_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">26466.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010487_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">26680.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010487_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FT010487%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
