<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004242_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sumak Kawsay and the Sustainable Development Agenda: Critical Debates and Creative Responses from a Latin American Indigenous Perspective</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations Indigenous Peoples Major Group has expressed concerns regarding the ongoing potential for indigenous people&apos;s voices to be overlooked in the Sustainable Development Agenda, despite its aspirations to be inclusive (UNIPMG, 2015). The aim of this research network is to challenge these tendencies through an exploration of indigenous perspectives on sustainability and the use of creative means to express alternatives.  &apos;Sumak kawsay&apos; is a Kichwa word meaning &apos;good living&apos;. It has become hugely prominent in Latin America in recent years, featuring in the Ecuadorean and Bolivian constitutions since 2008 and 2009 respectively. Its basic principles include concern for the environment, peaceful communal living and the reduction of inequalities, both economic and social. While these principles might seem to align well with the discourse of sustainable development as expressed in the Sustainable Development Goals, from the perspective of indigenous communities, sumak kawsay should not be equated with the concept &apos;development&apos;, however sustainable. Instead, it offers a decolonial, post-developmentalist alternative approach to human civilisation and aspirations. As one prominent thinker has put it, &apos;[sumak kawsay] helps us see the limits of current development models and it allows us to dream of alternatives&apos; (Gudnyas).  But sumak kawsay is not a global panacea either. Where it has been mainstreamed in Latin America, indigenous communities tend to feel that it has been usurped and used as a way to foist development upon them by making it sound like their voices are being heard in national fora. It also cannot be assumed that all indigenous communities understand sumak kawsay to mean the same thing, nor that sumak kawsay as understood by indigenous communities will automatically herald a state of perfect harmony and equality.  The research network proposed here will focus on these issues in collaboration with indigenous communities in the Northeast of Brazil and the Southwest of Colombia; communities where there is a manifest appetite to address them. It addresses a gap in extant research on the subject by looking beyond Ecuador and Bolivia&apos;s mainstreaming of the concept and by seeking to dream of alternatives beyond the debates about sumak kawsay versus sustainable development. We intend to do this by networking our research across the academic/non-academic divide to pool critical resources, making this process manifest in the form of a multilingual &apos;affective cartography&apos;. This will consist of a website that is a combination of research with art and activism (artivism) and that seeks to find a more egalitarian, subtle, multi-voiced way for the ideas that come out of the network to be expressed. It is not about fixing, defining or appropriating a given culture or its worldview, but about allowing for the expression of relationships and multiple perspectives, through whatever media seem most appropriate. We will seek to position this digital resource as a point of reference for other indigenous and marginalised communities across Latin America and the Anglophone world.  The activities of the research network are built around on-going in-community events run by project coordinators in Brazil and Colombia, and two main in-community workshops bridging the academic/non-academic research divide. This will be complemented by three international symposia to be held at participating universities in Brazil, Colombia and the UK and open to all network members. The overall emphasis in the proposal on in-community work seeks to ensure that indigenous participants in the network remain the intellectual fulcrum of the project.    The network will also publish its findings in a special issue of a prestigious peer-reviewed journal and keep a log of its activities through a project website.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-04" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-14">36329</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-14">20521.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The network&apos;s aims are:  1. to explore, from a contemporary indigenous perspective, the antagonism between the Sustainable Development Agenda and alternative Latin American indigenous-based understandings of human civilisation typically referred to as Sumak Kawsay in Kichwa, Buen Vivir in Spanish and Bem Viver in Portuguese.   2. to seek to envision ways of moving beyond this impasse that allow indigenous communities to make informed decisions about development issues through enhanced levels of self-knowledge and resilience, and to help to build capacity in the communities for articulating &apos;the future they want&apos; more effectively in local, national, regional and global fora.  3. to promote wider discussion of alternatives to development and alternative SDGs that countenance other approaches, both in Latin America and in the UK.  These aims will be pursued via the following objectives:  1. We will facilitate debate in indigenous communities, and between indigenous communities and academic partners, about the SD/SK antagonism, the potential for selective, critical (re)appropriation of SK and the proposal of ethical, strategic and autonomous alternatives to both, through the creation of spaces for dialogue, both real and virtual, and for communal project work.   This will include the organisation of small-scale in-community events and other outreach activities in Brazil and Colombia by our project coordinators, electronic networking between communities in Brazil and Colombia, and two main workshops in Brazil and Colombia involving as many core network and community members as possible.  2. We will enhance social science-based research on SK by ensuring the on-going involvement of indigenous thinkers and researchers in the co-creation of research outputs, and by applying the knowledge and creative methodologies of Arts and Humanities-based research to the issues under scrutiny, through the creation of fora and outputs that support such multidisciplinary and participatory knowledge exchange and methodological debates.  This will include, for example, the use of the methodologies of oral history, and the use of cultural production, eg. film, as a trigger for thinking through complex development scenarios, which will be implemented by our project coordinators. Wider dialogue between all core network and community members will be facilitated by the workshops and the opportunity for inclusion of community members in events taking place in university settings in Brazil, Colombia and the UK.  3. We will seek to disseminate the results of these debates not only among indigenous and academic communities, but also in mainstream society in both Latin America and the UK in order to encourage more widespread acknowledgement of alternative perspectives on development. Where appropriate, we will also encourage indigenous communities to use the results in their interactions with relevant national and international policy making bodies.  Our outputs for dissemination will include an interactive multilingual project website, a web-based multi-authored artivist output known as an &apos;affective cartography&apos;, and a special issue of an academic, peer-reviewed journal. We will also seek to ensure the wider impact of our work through outreach activities organised by the project coordinators in Brazil and Colombia, and through meetings with relevant local community groups in the UK (in Leeds and Bristol).  One additional aim of the project is to create significant, lasting connections between the academic and non-academic partners involved in the network that will serve both to address the issues under scrutiny but also to offer a conduit for the implementation of future participatory projects around key topics affecting indigenous communities."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">36329</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004242_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">15569.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004242_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">4952</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004242_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">-9.20000000000073</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004242_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
