<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CPAID: The Centre for Public Authority and International Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CPAID will address critical questions that have bedevilled the outside world&apos;s engagement with governance of fragile, conflict affected, marginal and impoverished populations. In these places inclusive growth has proved elusive. We propose a different starting point. Rather than anticipating transitions to accountable and capable Western government familiar to policymakers, CPAID prioritises the everyday lived realities of ordinary people in conflict-affected and fragile situations. In these places, the foundations of such growth are far more widespread and pervasive than state institutions. Through the lens of public authority, CPAID researchers seek to understand how governance actually functions in such circumstances, what forms of growth does this accomplish, and can actually existing forms of inclusive growth be promoted by development practitioners. Only a historically-informed, contextual and interdisciplinary analysis of how political, economic and social factors interact can achieve a full understanding of &apos;real governance&apos; in conflict affected in places. Understanding these dynamics is critical to inform new and improved models of international development which will actually provide or enhance firm foundations for future inclusive growth. CPAID will explore how forms of public authority shape and are shaped by a set of interlocking global challenges that pose both risks and opportunities for international development and inclusive growth: namely, the provision of security and justice; migration, displacement and situations of endemic violence; global health threats; control and allocation of resources; and advances in media and information technologies. CPAID will fill a serious evidence gap about on the ground realities in large areas of Africa which currently affect other regions, including Europe. The CPAID team includes world- leading authorities on, Uganda, Kenya, Sierra Leone, Rwanda, Burundi, Democratic Republic of Congo, South Sudan, Sudan, Somalia, Ethiopia, and Central African Republic.  Our primary focus is on public authority as perceived, understood and experienced by populations in locations of research. Research over the last decade or so has challenged prevailing assumptions embodied in the &apos;failed states&apos; discourse, namely that in the absence of western-style governance institutions, fragile and conflict affected societies collapse or flounder. CPAID will undertake research which can help us understand the various ways in which actual forms of public authority work. This approach is desperately needed in development policy. Conventional conflict and post-conflict state building processes, premised on Weberian notions of the state, are hugely expensive and too often unsuccessful or arguably even counter-productive. Moreover, with the rise of &apos;resilience thinking&apos;, donors are increasingly acknowledging that the world is a place of &apos;radical uncertainty&apos;, and determined, in the words of DFID to &apos;embrace uncertainty as an opportunity to... bounce back better&apos;.  This has underpinned a new, but under-researched agenda to find more cost-effective and culturally &apos;embedded&apos; forms of governance that donors can support.  This research will also take place in the context of massive investments to provide internet connectivity. The next five years will witness unprecedented efforts to connect millions of people who do not currently have internet access in Africa, in remote and borderland areas. Examining the role of new technologies, including social media, in reshaping public authorities and governments will provide crucial entry points to develop policies to achieve new forms of inclusive growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CPAID will be at the forefront of cutting-edge interdisciplinary research designed to strengthen our knowledge about how the governance of societies in impoverished, marginal and/or conflict affected places actually functions. Without a sound knowledge of the dynamics of public authority in these places, development and inclusive growth policies simply cannot succeed.  1)      Produce high-quality, evidence-based research that informs local, national and international policies to promote inclusive growth in our research countries. Inclusive growth in many places in Africa and elsewhere has proved elusive. Formal governance can be remote, development policies persistently fail and humanitarian aid, at best, assists a minority. CPAID will use innovative approaches to research across disciplines and beyond narrow academic concerns. Our research will draw its understandings from ordinary people, and in particular vulnerable, marginalised and excluded groups and populations. CPAID will take public authority as its conceptual starting point, exploring the ways in which governance of people actually occurs. CPAID used the term public authority to refer to all forms of authority beyond the immediate family unit, from clans, religious institutions, aid agencies, civil social organisations, rebel militia and vigilante groups -   to formal and semi-formal mechanisms of government.  2) CPAID&apos;s research will focus on under-researched areas involved in prolonged conflict,  endemic violence and social upheaval across Africa including DRC, CAR, South Sudan, Somalia, and Burundi, and in the now relatively peaceful states of Rwanda, Sierra Leone, Uganda and Ethiopia.  All research locations are ODA recipients and qualify as &apos;least developed countries&apos;. Often there is no data available from which policies to promote inclusive governance can be developed. In these countries populations are impacted by weak, ineffective or exploitative state institutions, but we know very little about the forms of public authority which actually serve populations and the possibilities for inclusive economic growth. CPAID&apos;s experienced researchers will study and draw comparisons about how forms of public authority coalesce to shape patterns of governance and conflict over resources across spaces, and temporal scales.   3) CPAID will foster and enhance already existing local partnerships to understand how public authority and governance is (re)shaped following processes of disruption, displacement and return.  Drawing upon existing local knowledge and experience, the research will be co-designed, co-produced and co-disseminated. Through long-standing collaborations with confirmed local partners, the CPAID will develop richer and more relevant analyses and prescriptions, opening up new perspectives on public authority and inclusive growth in our research countries. The centre will privilege new theoretical frameworks and tools of analysis developed from local wisdom.   4) CPAID will use innovative approaches to research across disciplines and beyond narrow academic concerns.  Public authority is a notion that makes this possible and seeks to free our research from problematic and misleading assumptions and projections about the nature of statehood, formal authority and formal governance. CPAID focuses on the populations governed, and their experience of this, thus allowing for meaningful exploration of possibilities for inclusive growth. CPAID involves world-leading scholars from anthropology, economics, development studies, international relations and political science. The central research team have a deep and long-term engagement with the cultures, politics, histories and security dynamics of many African countries. Crucially, this means that local populations can be fully involved in research, and investigations can be conducted ethically and successfully.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-23">905723.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-23">1052560.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-23">951715.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-23">901128.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-23">544175.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">226430.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">226430.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">226430.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">226430.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">228265.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">228265.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">228265.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">228265.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">369613.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">230114.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">230114.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">261373.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">179934.23</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">179934.23</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">179934.23</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P008038_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London School of Economics &amp; Pol Sci</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
