<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S004815_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the National Action Plan for Antimicrobial Resistance (SNAP-AMR) in Tanzania</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antimicrobial resistance (AMR), the ability of bacteria to resist the effect of drugs, is a threat to human and animal health in resource rich nations like the UK and low and middle income countries like the United Republic of Tanzania. In Tanzania, as in many low and middle income countries, the AMR problem is compounded by the fact that people and livestock often live close together and widespread use of antimicrobials in both. In response to a global call to action from the World Health Organisation, Tanzania has created an ambitious National Action Plan to combat AMR, including improving awareness and understanding of the AMR problem among policy makers, professionals and the public and enhancing surveillance, research, infection prevention and antimicrobial stewardship in people and livestock. Successful implementation of the NAP is challenged by lack of human and financial resources, making prioritisation of activities and interventions an essential component of an effective and efficient campaign to control AMR. Our research will provide new evidence to support this prioritisation and targeting, taking an approach that recognises that individuals are part of a larger system and that behaviour of professionals and the public may depend on policy, regulations or knowledge, but also on cultural background, social norms and access to medical, veterinary or diagnostic infrastructure and drugs. Our team of UK and Tanzania-based researchers and policy experts will take an interdisciplinary approach, working with a wide range of biological and social scientists as well as health professionals and community members, to provide novel insights into cultural, socio-economic and biological drivers of antimicrobial use (AMU) in hospitals and the community and in contextually appropriate methods of communication around those issues. The origin of AMR problems can be described as hospital-, community- or livestock-associated so we will work with doctors and nurses, householders and patients, and veterinarians and livestock keepers as well as (in)formal drug providers and other stakeholders to investigate knowledges, beliefs, attitudes and practices around health and AMU/AMR. We will compare health care settings (health centres, district, regional and referral hospitals) and livestock keeping communities (Chagga, Masaai and Sukuma) to reflect a range of professional and cultural contexts. Using focus group discussions, questionnaires and interviews, we will examine factors that influence prescribing and use of antimicrobials and through choice experiments we will examine how changes in e.g. knowledges, social norms or access might change such behaviour. To complement the socio-economic investigations, we will use DNA-sequencing of hospital -, community - or livestock-associate bacteria in combination with mathematical modelling approaches to establish the relative contribution of different sources and transmission routes to the clinical and economic burden of AMR. The combination of insight into the drivers and relative importance of behaviours that may contribute to the AMR problem provides a unique opportunity to identify and prioritise levers of behavioural change to reduce AMU and limit the risk and impact of AMR. Finally but importantly, we will work with policy makers, professionals and the public to design context-specific messages and methods to communicate AMR awareness and infection prevention and control messages in hospitals and community settings, and evaluate the impact of those communication campaigns using a combination of the social and biological sciences methods described above. The combined outcomes of our research will help priority setting in AMR control by identifying the settings where change is practicable and cost-effective. It will inform implementation of the National Action Plan in Tanzania and serve as a generalisable transdisciplinary model of AMR control in low and middle income country settings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will provide novel insights into socio-economic, cultural and biological drivers of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) to identify and prioritise tractable levers of behaviour change in hospitals and communities that will alleviate the burden of AMR related illness in a low income setting. In doing so, we will support the National Action Plan (NAP) on AMR in Tanzania whilst creating a generalisable whole system approach to implementation of the WHO maxim that AMR is a global problem with local solutions. We will explore (1) what drives the contribution of the hospital system to the AMR problem and how this can be mitigated; (2) what drives the contribution of the community to the AMR problem, considering use of antimicrobials in both humans and animals; (3) the relative magnitude and tractability of those contributions; and (4) how best to promote AMR awareness.    Objectives 1 and 2 address key knowledge gaps surrounding behavioural drivers of antimicrobial use (AMU) in hospitals and communities using a suite of social science and economics tools to provide a rich baseline for understanding the context and constraints on AMU at micro-level (e.g. patients, hospital staff, household), meso-level (e.g. health providers such as drug suppliers) and macro-level (e.g. government policy). Activities will target all tiers of the system and three major livestock keeping communities in Tanzania who are known to have different socio-cultural knowledges, perceptions, attitudes and behaviours around AMU in people and animals and who face different socio-economic constraints. The outcomes will reveal potential interventions such as better information, social norm effects, or improved access that influences choice to prescribe, buy or administer antimicrobials in people and animals and to let us identify individuals or actions that may be targeted to bring about the greatest change in AMU. Objective 3 aims to quantify transmission of AMR within and across tiers of the hospital system as well as introduction into the hospital system from human and animal sources in the community. We will focus on pathogens and resistance mechanisms that are at the top of the WHO priority list and known to be major contributors to clinical disease and childhood mortality in Tanzania, i.e. extended spectrum betalactamase resistant Escherichia coli. Using phylogenetic and diversity analyses of bacterial genomes and plasmids from prospectively collected isolates and an extensive existing archive from human and animal sources in Tanzania, we will quantify the flow of AMR into and within the hospital system and quantify the predicted impact of behaviour change to reduce this flow. This will provide evidence to identify the appropriate setting (hospital or community) and context (human or veterinary) for &quot;best bet&quot; interventions. Objective 4 addresses gaps in understanding of how to best to communicate  and promote AMR awareness. Using a theoretical framework and in collaboration with Objectives 1-3, we will co-construct and evaluate a series of interlinked media and education messages, materials and activities to target health care workers and the public, recognising that drivers and constraints on AMU may differ between different tiers of the hospital system and between different livestock keeping communities in Tanzania.  The desired outcome of these activities is improved knowledge and awareness of AMR and its risk, promotion of responsible AMU in humans and livestock, and capacity strengthening of the policy unit tasked with coordinating implementation of the Tanzanian NAP to help avert the threat posed by AMR to lives and livelihoods in Tanzania and other Low and Middle Income Countries. Ultimately, we will deliver transferable outputs by demonstrating that a whole system approach, matched by interdisciplinary partnership offers a way to successfully identify tractable levers of change to tackle the challenge of AMR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-14">1029211.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-14">1025924.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-14">775675.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-14">3089371.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S004815_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FS004815%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
