<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S001964_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of two community-based interventions targeting inappropriate antibiotic dispensing and use behaviours in rural Vietnam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Between 2000 and 2010, worldwide antibiotic consumption increased by 35%, including large rises in the use of antibiotic drugs used as a last-resort, when other treatments fail. This rise was particularly apparent in middle income countries, with growing populations and increasing access to antibiotics. Rising levels of antibiotic consumption are associated high levels of antibiotic resistance, and increasing numbers of bacterial infections that are difficult or impossible to treat with antibiotics. Reducing inappropriate antibiotic use has been shown to reduce the level of antibiotic resistance at population-level in high income countries, but few population-level interventions aiming to reduce antibiotic use have been evaluated in low and middle income countries with higher burdens of infectious disease and antibiotic resistance.  This development grant will inform the design of two community-based interventions aiming to reduce inappropriate antibiotic use and related antibiotic resistance. One intervention will target the supply of antibiotics through private pharmacies, the major source of treatment for minor illness, and where antibiotics can easily be obtained without a prescription. Introducing a rapid diagnostic test in this setting would help pharmacists to differentiate between people with non-bacterial infections that do not require antibiotics, and those with likely bacterial infections that should be referred to a health professional. The other intervention will tackle the demand for antibiotics in communities by using participatory discussion in groups to improve understanding of the problem of antibiotic resistance, and develop appropriate strategies to address it in their community.   To assist intervention development, we will conduct a review of the literature to learn from other successful approaches using rapid diagnostic tests outside the formal healthcare system, and health behaviour change interventions in communities. We will collect information from providers and consumers of antibiotics in communities, to understand what drives inappropriate use, and we will also explore their views about the introduction of rapid diagnostic tests in pharmacies, and what price would be attractive for both. We will work with community members, using visual media to develop materials and messages that can be used to talk about antibiotic resistance with other communities.  On finalising the design of the interventions, a methodology will be developed to evaluate and understand the effect of these interventions, with input from experts and local partners. Funding sources will be identified to implement the interventions and research the effect of community-based interventions on antibiotic use and resistance in rural Vietnam. We will disseminate our learning from this process through international peer reviewed publications, briefing papers, and discussions with local partners and community participants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of this research is to develop two acceptable, replicable, community-based interventions to tackle inappropriate antibiotic use and misuse. Specific objectives related specifically to the community behaviour change and CRP-RDT interventions, as well as overall intervention design, include:  1. Community behaviour change intervention - To gain deeper understanding of current knowledge and behaviours related to antibiotic dispensing and antibiotic consumption, and their          social, cultural and economic drivers, though a combination of ethnographic and visual media-driven approaches - To develop community behaviour change intervention content and messages through a community-led media project  2. CRP-RDT intervention - To pilot CRP-RDT tests in pharmacies, and explore their acceptability and perceived value - To evaluate the possible market value of CRP-RDT tests, and develop an economically feasible model for CRP-RDT distribution through private pharmacies  3. Overall - To develop theory of change and logic models for both interventions - To identify facilitators and barriers to implementation of both interventions - To model the potential impact of different intervention components, to identify the most cost-effective approaches to reducing the burden of          antibiotic resistance in populations</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Viet Nam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-13">49882.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-13">75025.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">24941.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S001964_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">24941.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S001964_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">24941.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S001964_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">24941.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S001964_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">25143.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S001964_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
