<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_S018948_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Novel delivery of phytochemicals for sustainable crop protection</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New solutions for managing insect pests are urgently needed due to evolution of resistance to current insecticides. Insect pests cause annual losses of US$17.7 billion to the Brazilian economy.  Our project focuses on development and bioactivity testing of nanotech and metallic coordination complexes as novel delivery mechanisms for bioactive phytochemcials, to provide new options for crop protection. By using defensive non-host phytochemicals, outside the metabolome of inbred crops, we can deliver phytochemcials that crop pests have not evolved with. UK-Brazil collaboration provides an ideal opportunity to share expertise and strengthen this new and promising area of research.  The Stage 1 (pump-priming) project has successfully shown that nanoformulation and complexing of phytochemicals can solve low solubility issues, improve longevity of release and alleviate phytotoxicity; three major issues that have impeded the development of botanical insecticides to date. Furthermore, our early (proof of concept) phytochemical treatments have good efficacy, causing &gt; 80% mortality of four major insecticide resistant pest species that are plaguing Brazilian agriculture (whitefly, Bemisia tabaci; fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda; Western flower thrips, Frankliniella occidentalis, and peach-potato aphid, Myzus persicae). Treatments were also shown to strongly and significantly inhibit aphid reproduction (near complete shutdown) and had highly significant repellent activity. Stage 1 established a new collaboration between Biologists at Keele University (UK) and Chemists at the Federal University of S&#xE3;o Carlos (UFSCar, Brazil), which was further strengthened by inclusion of crop protection expertise at S&#xE3;o Paulo State University (UNESP, Brazil). The project has benefited from Keele Nanoceutics expertise, allowing low cost nanotech technologies from medical research to be translated into the agricultural field. Investment in Stage 1 has thus provided a solid foundation for future research.  The Stage 2 project will use the collaboration established in Stage 1 to move towards generating new commercially viable phytochemical treatments. Workshops and exchange visits will be held to allow research groups to share expertise and work together. We have three workshops planned: UNESP (June 2019), Keele (Jan 2020) and UFSCar (Jan 2021). Experimental work will focus on three main areas: 1) Development and optimisation of phytochemical delivery using nanoformulation and complexing techniques. Treatments will be scaled up from leaf discs to whole plants with detailed investigation of two promising routes for application: sprayable formulations and systemic uptake via root drench treatments. 2) Testing bioactivity of formulations against economically important Brazilian crop pest targets. Antibiotic, antifeedant and repellent activity will be tested for using established methods we have developed for the four species. 3) Environmental and target specificity assessment. Most of the phytochemicals and formulations we are testing are already widely used as food ingredients, in medicine or in aromatherapy. However, we will obtain evidence in order to make the case for subsequent commercialisation of treatments. Breakdown of new biodegradable formulations will be measured. Non-target effects will be assessed with mammalian cell lines, an egg parasitoid wasp Trichogramma pretiosum (a beneficial natural enemy), and the honeybee, Apis mellifera.  We have shown cross-fertilisation between the disciplines involved in the project, allowing Agriculture to advance by using approaches already developed in Chemistry and Medicine. Our hypothesis is that our novel formulations could provide a means to &quot;outsource&quot;, for crop protection, defensive phytochemicals from plants that crop pests have not evolved with and therefore are susceptible to. The Stage 2 project has considerable potential to generate much needed new tools for managing crop pests.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective is to create commercially viable phytochemical treatments to provide novel methods for insect pest control, building on our successes from the stage one project. Previously, a major constraint on improving botanical pesticides has been availability of delivery systems for labile, unstable compounds. Our project is using advanced nanotech and complexing techniques to improve the performance of phytochemical treatments. The project will continue developing a long-term collaboration combining the expertise of Keele University (UK), S&#xE3;o Paulo State University (UNESP, Brazil) and Universidade Federal de S&#xE3;o Carlos (UFSCar, Brazil) research groups.  1. To share complementary expertise and share best practice between the research organisations in Brazil and the UK to strengthen the underpinning science for providing novel tools to manage insect pests of crops. This will be facilitated by three workshops, short high-level courses and mutual exchange of researchers between organisations.  2. Development and optimisation of novel phytochemical delivery using nanoformulation and complexing techniques using expertise available at the Keele School of Pharmacy and at UFSCar. This will include both surface spray and systemic drench treatments of experimental plant material, using the most promising phytochemicals from stage 1. Biodegradable nanoformulations will be created.   3. Test bioactivity against economically important Brazilian crop pest targets. These will be thrips and aphids at the Keele School of Life Sciences, whitefly at S&#xE3;o Paulo State University and fall armyworm at UFSCar. Antibiotic, repellent, antifeedant activity and effects on reproduction will be measured in replicated bioassays.  4. Environmental and target specificity assessment. Degradation of biodegradable formulations will be tested. Assessment of non-target effects will be made with mammalian cell lines, bees and parasitoid wasps using standard protocols.  New solutions are urgently needed for managing insect pests of crops as they evolve resistance to currently available insecticides and new environmentally benign products are required for future pest management. The Stage 2 project will allow us to continue making progress and test hypotheses relating to how bioactivity of plant secondary metabolites can be enhanced. The project will integrate chemistry, nanotechnology and entomology to provide new ways of delivering bioactive phytochemicals via nanotech complexes for use against insect pests. If experimental results are as promising as expected, there will be huge potential for providing new treatments that would give farmers new options, reduce selection pressure for resistance and transform crop protection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-20">121774.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-20">92070.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-20">30690.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-20">244535.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to Keele University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/S018948/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FS018948%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
