<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02789X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF establishment of biopharmaceutical and animal vaccine production capacity in Thailand and neighbouring South East Asian countries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective is to bring about a permanent step-change in the ability of Thailand, and eventually other South East Asian countries, to produce a range of advanced medicines and vaccines for the treatment of major human and animal diseases. This will contribute significantly towards achieving a number of Sustainable Development Goals relating to Poverty (SDG1), Hunger (SDG2), Health and Wellbeing (SDG3) and Industry, Innovation &amp; Infrastructure (SDG9).  The initial stages will involve a bilateral collaboration with Thai groups while the later stages will engage neighbouring countries to achieve impact at a regional level. The project aims to achieve these aims through a sustained enhancement of Thailand&apos;s capacity to produce high value recombinant proteins, especially biopharmaceuticals and bespoke animal vaccines.  The project brings together Thai groups at the forefront of the country&apos;s new programme to produce recombinant proteins, UK groups that have developed state of the art E. coli- and Chinese Hamster Ovary (CHO) cell-based expression systems, and Bangkok-based UK specialists in SE Asian healthcare, economic policies and dissemination tools.  The specific objectives are as follows: 1. To produce a range of specific biopharmaceuticals, particularly recombinant antibodies to treat cancers and auto-immune diseases, at high levels in the newly-established National Biopharmaceutical Facility (NBF) in Thailand. The biopharmaceuticals will be produced to CGMP (Current Good Manufacturing Practice) standards required for human use. 2. To produce a range of subunit vaccines against porcine circovirus (PCV) and porcine epidemic diarrhoea virus (PEDV) to prevent major swine diseases, and to produce the key veterinary biotherapeutic porcine interferon (IFN). 3. To develop downstream processing protocols that will enable the expressed proteins to be extracted and purified in an efficient, cost-effective manner, thereby reducing costs and achieving greater patient accessibility.  4. To apply industry-standard analyses in order to characterise biopharmaceuticals at the level of detail required by the Thai Food and Drug Administration (FDA). 5. To work with a range of companies and government ministries in Thailand and ensure that the biopharmaceuticals are produced, marketed and distributed by the most effective means. 6. To work with a range of ministries, farms and veterinary product distributors to ensure that the animal vaccines are correctly designed from the outset and produced rapidly to combat new outbreaks, with the final products reaching the end users. 7. To develop a sustained partnership with Institutions in other SE Asian countries that will inform them of progress in the programme and enable them to initiate similar production programmes. The projected outcomes are: (i). Biopharmaceuticals on the World Health Organisation list of &apos;minimum medicine needs for a basic health-care system&apos;, currently available to under 2% of Thai patients, will be produced in Thailand for the first time at a cost that allows wide access to patients. The net results will be a major reduction in cancer-related deaths, especially in earlier age groups. (ii). A suite of veterinary vaccines against major porcine diseases will be produced, fully tested and made available to farms in Thailand. This will result in a sustained reduction in the livestock and food losses that are routinely incurred in this country. (iii). The Thai groups will possess state of the art technical capacity for recombinant protein production, with a level of capability that will facilitate expansion and consolidation, as part of a long-term partnership that incorporates a properly-resourced &apos;follow on&apos; programme in years 5-7. (iv). Neighbouring SE Asian countries will have full access to the programme&apos;s technology and expertise in order to effectively plan similar ventures.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This programme aims to establish state of the art facilities and technology for the production of recombinant proteins, especially biopharmaceuticals and bespoke animal vaccines.  Biopharmaceuticals are protein drugs that are used to treat an increasingly wide range of serious diseases, to the extent that half of all new drugs are predicted to be biopharmaceuticals by 2020. They are usually produced in bacterial or animal cells, which makes them difficult to make and far too expensive for the vast majority of patients in developing countries. In Thailand, fewer than 2% of patients have access to anti-cancer biopharmaceuticals that are routinely used in the UK, and which are on the World Health Organisation&apos;s list of &apos;minimum medicine needs for a basic health-care system&apos;. Cancer rates in Thailand are high and rising, so there is a profound need for these medicines.  Animal vaccines are required to combat infections in livestock, which is a growing problem in Thailand and other countries due to the increasing demands of growing populations. Many imported vaccines do not work well because they were raised against strains that are simply too different. Thailand and other developing countries suffer massive losses in livestock every year, with some outbreaks leading to 90% loss rates. Countries such as Thailand can only address these problems by producing the biopharmaceuticals themselves, at much lower costs, and by formulating vaccines that are matched to circulating viral strains. Progress in both areas requires large scale facilities for recombinant protein production, usually in E. coli or mammalian cells. This is a highly complex area and most developing countries do not have this capacity - hence they need to import the products. To address this problem the Thai government has established a purpose-built National Biopharmaceutical Facility (NBF), built in 2014 and fully equipped for bacterial/ animal cell systems and product formulation. It has also developed a substantial animal vaccine research group.  The UK has world-class expertise in this area of &apos;bioprocessing&apos; and this project aims to apply this expertise, initially in Thailand and later elsewhere, to develop the NBF into a state of the art facility that can make both biopharmaceuticals and vaccine antigens. The UK team includes experts in every step of the production chain, including design of expression system, expression of proteins at high levels, large scale cultivation, product extraction / purification, and product &apos;analysis&apos;. The latter area is crucially important; any drugs licensed for human use have to pass extremely stringent quality tests that involve detailed analysis of the final protein product. During the project a group of the UK applicants will work closely with the Thai team to transfer their capabilities to the Thai centres and build up production capacity. This will be aided by seconding the UK researchers to Thailand for long periods, and visits by the Thai researchers to the UK to learn new approaches. At the same time, others UK and Thai team members will work with government ministries, companies and farms to ensure that the products will be distributed effectively so that they reach end users. Finally, representatives from a range of neighbouring South East Asian countries will be involved in the network meetings so that they are fully aware of the programme&apos;s progress and outputs and able to use the information and technology to initiate their own production pipelines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-17">279471</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-17">1001334</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-17">1007027</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-17">762177</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-17">529909.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-17">4090772.964</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Kent</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P02789X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FP02789X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
