<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_S011684_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Bhabha Industrial Waste: Integrated biorefinery for converting paper mill waste into chemical wealth (waste-2-wealth)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India is the fastest growing paper market in the world (6% per annum; by 2024-25 Indian demand is projected to increase to 23.50 million MT). However, alongside this trend is the huge amount of industrial waste, especially lignocellulosic material that accumulates as part of this expanding industry. This proposal addresses a number of urgent problems relevant to India, including a) a strengthening of the countries economic position through the emerging bioeconomy, b) the need to tackle major and growing environmental waste management challenges and c) addressing countrywide poverty prevalence through new employment. Our team will develop an innovative biorefinery and commercial strategy to establish a demonstrator platform for the sustainable conversion of paper mill waste into high value chemicals. This platform will be used to drive sustainable expansion through commercial inward investment. This technology will lead to reduction in industrial waste/pollution, and improve value recovery from waste in the paper and pulp industry sector. The proposal will strengthen India&apos;s economic position, address major waste challenges and tackle rural poverty. The biorefinery is built from partner expertise in i) valorisation of waste feedstock (India); ii) use of bioengineered strains for fragrance production at industrial levels, and feedstock utilisation (UK); iii) commercial expertise in this market sector (UK/India). The innovation is found in unifying existing technologies to form the biorefinery concept, enabling distributed, green, scalable and sustainable manufacture of chemicals from major paper mill waste streams. The biorefinery will drive inward investment to strengthen India&apos;s economic position, address major waste challenges and tackle poverty prevalence through job creation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-08-16"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-10">69440.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-10">139443.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-10">140573.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-10">70570.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This project will develop a sustainable, scalable and modularised biorefinery for conversion of waste streams from Indian paper/pulp mills to high value fragrance compounds (linalool) and amino acids (lysine). It is based on world leading strengths of the UK partners who have developed stable microbial production strains for a number of fragrances, including (R)-(-) linalool that produce at g/L scale from laboratory feedstocks (Karuppiah ACS Catal, 2017, 7, 6268; Patent number 1701548.8) and expertise of Indian partners in biomass waste conversion and microbial processing. C3 Biotechnologies Ltd is the UK industry partner responsible for commercialising these production strains in partnership with fragrance manufacturers for the production of linalool and related chemicals. This application is based on production of R-(-)-linalool and lysine for which the global markets are stable and large (28250 MT pa and 1.9 million MT pa, respectively). Manufacture of linalool is distributed across Europe, USA and China; 60% is manufactured synthetically, and 40 % is natural (agricultural). Lysine is manufactured by fermentation, mainly in the USA and China. Synthetic R-(-)-linalool is manufactured from acetylene gas (highly unstable; shipped in acetone). Product purity is important. Synthetic linalool is a mixture of stereoisomers and natural linalool requires purification from complex oils. Microbial linalool production is competitive: it i) yields a single isomer of high product purity, ii) requires mild fermentation conditions, iii) is readily recovered from bioreactors, iv) is compatible with distributed manufacture, v) is classified as &apos;natural&apos;, vi) is produced at high levels (g/L) from inexpensve media. We have demonstrated feasibility of production at pilot scale. The challenge now is to unite  production capabilities and waste feedstock technologies to establish a demonstrator biorefinery and develop commercial opportunities to produce linalool and lysine (and ultimately other valuable products) from paper mill waste. This proposal combines the expertise of Indian partners in thermocatalytic/bioconversion of paper/pulp waste to provide a usable feedstocks for manufacture and the UK team in bioengineering to optimise production strains for paper/pulp feedstocks prevalent in India. This is &apos;industrial research&apos;. It unites existing/mature technologies to develop an innovative and modularised manufacturing biorefinery concept that is also readily adapted for production of other chemical products.   The specific objectives are multiple including integration of technical capabilities involved in fermentation, valorisation and downstream recovery infrastructure to enable conversion of waste materials into pure chemical products. This requires:   1. Pretreatment of feedstocks (thermocatalytic/bioconversion routes);  2. Set up of primary fermentation infrastructure (for lysine and linalool);  3. Development of product recovery infrastructure (e.g. distillation and chromatography).   The team will optimise biodegradation of lignocellulose paper mill waste by introducing known lignocellulosic degradation enzymes into the production strains using established pathway engineering technologies. Set up of the biorefinery will take 3 years; in Y1 we will optimise feedstock pretreatment and bioconversion strategies, and develop product capture technology; in Y2 we will optimise lysine production strains and evaluate performance at scale in the biorefinery; in Y3 we will optimise linalool producing strains with target feedstocks and perform scale up and product recovery analysis as part of the integrated production platform. Commercial development will run in parallel driven by C3 Biotechnologies in partnership with Indian industry/urban government."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
