<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R025630_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UK-Philippines Remote Retinal Evaluation Collaboration in Health: Diabetic Retinopathy (REACH-DR)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is estimated that over 1.2 million eyes will need to be evaluated each month in the Philippines of persons with diabetes (PwDM) by 2040. Current Philippine healthcare infrastructure cannot accommodate this demand given the current population of over 100 million with fewer than 2,000 ophthalmologists and 100 retina-specialists. Telemedicine, using remote retinal image grading, can provide a uniquely suited means to unite these disparate factors and enable the establishment of a national programme for diabetic retinopathy (DR) surveillance.The overall goal of our work is to establish a DR telemedicine screening programme in the Philippines. The following objectives will be pursued as three phases of development. Objective #1: Infrastructure Development for Remote Retinal Imaging for DR Information Technology Evaluation and Selection: The information technology platforms will be evaluated with emphasis on remote data acquisition and continuous data metrics in order to allow a single collated list of PwDM for image acquisition, grading and quality assurance/control purposes.  Retinal Imaging Technology Evaluation: Focus on Adaptability in the Philippine Setting The use of retinal imaging technology is a critical feature of DR telemedicine programmes. Identified retinal imaging devices (standard mydriatic, table-top and handheld nonmydriatic and ultrawide field, macular optical coherence tomography) will be evaluated for suitability in the Philippine setting taking into consideration the minimum requirement suggested by the UK Health Technology Assessment and UK-DR screening Program (DRSP) outcomes.  Standard validation studies will be independently performed using UK and Philippine grading centers and coordinated by the Joslin Diabetes Center to assess the performance of imaging devices within the software platform. Devices will be evaluated for ease-of-use, portability, speed of acquisition, image gradability rate (with/without pupil dilation) and operating cost within recommended sensitivity and specificity guidelines. Agreement between clinical Early Treatment Diabetic Retinopathy Study (ETDRS) levels and standard 7-field ETDRS photographs of DR severity and against macular optical coherence tomography will be assessed. Both DR and Diabetic Macular Edema (DME) severity and presence/extent of individual lesions will be assessed by calculating sensitivity/specificity and positive/negative predictive values.  Cost-effectiveness analysis will be performed by Research Division, Health Policy Development and Planning Bureau at Department of Health Philippines. Objective #2: UK Guided DR Screening with the Target Population Proposed Study Population The proposed study population will be a cohort that has been previously evaluated in a Rapid Assessment of Avoidable Blindness and DR (RAAB+DR). Data from RAAB+DR showed that in population over age 50 years with diabetes, there is a high prevalence of DR (28%). Based on published UK analysis of costs, skills and demand, a minimum programme size of 12,000 PwDM is recommended for it to be cost-effective. Extrapolating to the Philippine setting with an estimated prevalence of diabetes of 6.9%, a minimum population of 175,000 people will be needed. The given RAAB+DR cohort of 177,298 meets the required population size with 12,233 PwDM. RAAB+DR programme has established a network of healthcare facilities for the treatment of sight-threatening disease and those in need of treatment will be referred to these locations.   Objective #3: Transfer to Philippine Stakeholders The ultimate goal is to develop a long-term, sustainable DRSP for remote DR evaluation adapted and scalable in the Philippine healthcare setting. Standardized manuals and protocols will be created and training of the Philippine staff will be performed. Standards and key performance indicators patterned from the UK-DRSP will be adapted to Philippine setting and handover to the Philippines will be performed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the major complications of diabetes is vision loss due to a disease known as diabetic retinopathy (DR) that includes diabetic maculopathy affecting predominantly the centre part of the back of the eye, the place of high acuity vision. One of the greatest success stories in diabetes eye care is the United Kingdom&apos;s National Diabetic Retinopathy Screening Programme (UK-DRSP). In 2014, for the first time in 5 decades, DR was no longer the leading cause of legal blindness in the working-age population in England and Wales, likely due to the early detection of DR by screening, along with improved control of blood sugar levels. Later, similar results have been found in other populations. Therefore, the prevalence of diabetes-related blindness and visual impairment is lowest where continuous retinal evaluations for all persons with diabetes exist. Outside the UK, only 18-60% persons with diabetes undergo annual DR examinations, usually by dilated retinal examination by eye-care professionals. However, in the Philippines, in-person retinal evaluation is not always possible, due to lack of trained personnel and suitable equipment. Telemedicine uses telecommunication and information technology to provide clinical health care from a distance and provides an alternative to in-person examination. In the UK, over 2 million persons with diabetes mellitus are screened using telemedicine annually.  The Philippine telecommunication and health-care infrastructure is being developed to sustain centralized telemedicine programmes. The Philippine government showed significant interest and support for the development of such programmes by passing the National Telehealth Service Act of 2009. In 2012-2013, a hospital-based retinal imaging reading center and a limited scale DR specific tele-ophthalmology programme was established in collaboration with the Joslin Diabetes Center. However, deployment of a population based DRSP, for which the well-established UK-DRSP is the ideal partner, especially at remote locations is still lacking. Current conditions in the Philippine health-care setting are optimal for the development of such a programme and this application aims to fully develop this. The objectives of this proposal will be to first establish a DRSP in the Philippines within a well characterized but underserved target population. This objective will be pursued in three phases: i) In the initial phase we will develop the necessary infrastructure jointly by the UK and the Philippine teams. The UK and Philippine principal investigators will perform analysis and validation of existing telemedicine technology with independent expert review from the Joslin Diabetes Center. ii) The second phase will involve adapting selected technologies into the Philippine setting, with the first DR screening being performed under the direct guidance and supervision of the UK team. iii) In the last phase there will be a complete technology transfer to the Philippine stakeholders. Long-term quality assurance and control (QA/QC) programmes will be based on UK-DRSP but will be carefully adapted to the Philippine environment to ensure standards and key performance indicators will be continually maintained and patients remain safe in the DRSP. The proposed teleophthalmology programme for DRSP will help to identify eyes at high risk for losing sight, and this will have direct benefit for individuals. An additional benefit will be the promotion of awareness for the need for eye evaluations which will significantly improve the overall level of eye care and reduce the risk of DR related visual loss in PwDM. The ultimate aim of this project will be the implementation of a national programme in the Philippines with a country-wide benefit.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">63062.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">138134.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">104299.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">43733.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">7299485.398</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Newton Fund Award to Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R025630_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FR025630%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
