<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_M011569_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Big data media analysis and the representation of urban violence in Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil&apos;s current social and political situation gives rise to a particular breed of urban violence aimed at individuals and characterized by its continual presence. The average Brazilian citizen has to contend with this violence on a daily basis. This creates a general state of fear and insecurity among the population in general, but, at the same time, may promote on the part of more socially aware individuals, a sense of empathy with the less privileged classes in Brazil. The influence of the media contributes to this scenario. Daily news reports highlight violent acts carried out by individuals or groups from all social classes. The impact of violence on people&apos;s everyday lives is thus amplified by the media. This fosters beliefs, attitudes and values related to violence, which may or may not be consistent with the actual incidence, forms and causes of violence. The partners will investigate the linguistic representation of urban violence in Brazil by applying the techniques of Corpus Linguistics to two datasets, or &apos;corpora&apos;: 1. The existing transcripts of two focus groups on living with urban violence conducted in Fortaleza, Brazil in 2010, for a total of approximately 20,000 words (Focus Groups Corpus); 2. A 2-million-word corpus of news reports in the Brazilian press, to be constructed as part of the partnership (News Reports Corpus).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The partnership aims to investigate the linguistic representation of urban violence in Brazil by means of the computer-aided methods developed within Corpus Linguistics. These methods make it possible to conduct systematic analyses of very large collections of language data, and to compare datasets of different sizes. The partners will: - Build a 2-million-word dataset (corpus) of reports on urban violence from the Brazilian press. - Employ the computer-aided methods developed within Corpus Linguistics to conduct a systematic analysis of the News Reports Corpus and of existing transcripts of focus groups on urban violence in Brazil. This analysis will reveal: - What types of violence receive more prominence; - How different types of violence are represented. The analysis will lay the foundations for further work on: the use of visual images in media representations of urban violence; and the relationship between media representations, citizens&apos; perceptions and official statistics on urban violence in Brazil.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-16">24351.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-16">146110.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Non Standard fEC Grant Scheme Award to Lancaster University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_M011569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FM011569%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
