<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V000306_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BioSpace: Using space-enabled remote sensing to deliver long term sustainable growth of biopesticide use</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BioSpace aims to build upon previous work on locust forecasting and promoting biopesticide use by validating the models in the different climatic region of Hainan, Southern China.  We have shown that EO data can be used in Shangdong and now want to confirm what effects a different climatic region has on the models produced.  EO data will be gathered for the Hainan region and the data will be ground-truthed to validate the models. Furthermore, Laos, the new partner to our consortium, is on a similar latitude and hence climatic region to Hainan.  With the addition of Laos, we will have the opportunity to tackle another locust species, the yellow-spined bamboo locust (YSBL).  We will determine how practical it is to adapt our models to other locust species while also giving expert advice in helping Laos to control the YSBL with environmentally friendly biopesticides.  Our UK-China collaboration will continue with RADI and NATESC demonstrating the move to making the outcomes of this project more end-user orientated.  In the last project 30 crop pest and disease monitoring and forecasting reports, produced by RADI, were adopted by MoA.  We aim to increase this number during this 2-year project.  We also aim to work closer with NATESC and hopefully start Beta trials of the BioSuccess app (developed as part of an ECMWF funded project) to aid in when to spray biopesticides.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pests and diseases cause significant losses of crops around the world and is a significant threat to food security.  In China the migratory locust affects over 2 million hectares of agricultural land, while in Laos the yellow spined bamboo locust which is widespread across the 9 districts of Norther Laos and damaged over 5,000 hectares of crops in 2019. A new invasive pest, the Fall Army Worm is becoming prevalent in Southeast Asia and China.  It has been found in 22 provinces in China and affected 35,000 hectares of maize in Laos.  Experience from Africa shows it can cause almost total crop losses.  Managing the damage from pests can be difficult due to lack of detailed information on where risks to crops are greatest, use of inappropriate or ineffective control measures, and build of resistance in pest populations to chemical pesticides. In addition overuse of chemical pesticides causes environmental damage in the form of loss of biodiversity and through chemical residues left in the environment, particularly in waterways. In this project we will use Earth observation and meteorological data to provide information that will help farmers and agricultural authorities manage pest risk more sustainably. Using Earth observation imagery we will prepare risk maps that identify habitats where locusts and fall armyworm are most likely to establish populations.  Using satellite data on surface temperature we will develop and run models that predict i) the growth of insect populations and  ii) the effectiveness of biological control methods.  The models will provide information to help preparedness and to guide the timing of application of biopesticides. The project will build upon work already undertaken in North-East China and apply it in the Southern Chinese province of Hainan, and in Laos.  We will provide risk base maps and information products that help chose the method and timing of interventions.  We will work with agricultural management authorities in China and Laos, providing training in the use of the information.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAB International</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-24" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-23" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">161627.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">189309.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">53326.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">404262.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC Newton Newton Fund Award to CAB International</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST/V000306/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">CAB International</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FV000306%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-13"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
