<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004002_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe, Inclusive Participative Pedagogy: Improving Early Childhood Education in Fragile Contexts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early childhood is a critical period for all children. It has been conclusively recognised by research that this period is significant for young children&apos;s rights in the here and now, for children&apos;s future educational, economic and health outcomes, and ultimately societal flourishing.  As attention to early childhood education increases, and governments across the world are moving to compulsory pre-school and early education, this is a pivotal moment for: a) understanding the challenges/opportunities for such provision in different cultural and political contexts; and b) radically rethinking future directions of early childhood education globally. We have significant questions to ask at this very time about the quality of learning experiences and professional support, how early childhood education can be culturally meaningful and appropriate, and ensuring it is affordable, inclusive and accessible.  This project responds to an urgent research need within four overseas development countries - Brazil, Eswatini, South Africa, and the West Bank and Gaza -- where new provision models are emerging in fragile contexts experiencing violence, inequalities and concentrated poverty. It builds on the innovation of the Brazilian academic partner (the International Centre International Centre for Research and Policy on Childhood at PUC-RIO), who researched how to strengthen and increase safe places of early learning for young children in two low-income communities in Rio de Janeiro (2014-17).  Expanding from this, the academic partners in Brazil, Eswatini, South Africa, the West Bank &amp; Gaza, and the UK will identify and develop safe, inclusive participative pedagogy that is implementable in fragile contexts and sustainable for governments, communities and families. While differing in socio-economic and cultural contexts, all four partner countries are poised for early childhood education development through national policy, are experiencing implementation quandaries and have fragile settings due to extreme and pervasive violence, inequalities and/or poverty.  To do so, the research will address these four questions: 1. In what ways and how do current policies, systems and organisations support inclusive participative pedagogy in fragile contexts?  2. What information, knowledge, expertise can be mobilised to understand fragile contexts and the threats, assets and opportunities for early childhood learning, young children and their families?  3. How can inclusive participative pedagogy become embedded and sustainable in communities, their formal and informal contexts, so as to support children&apos;s early learning? 4. Is there an economic case for inclusive participative pedagogy? If so, what are the relevant components and what are the short- and long-term costs and benefits? Inclusive participative pedagogy is a novel concept, which this project will develop, test and challenge. It draws on the respective fields of early childhood pedagogy, inclusive education and violence prevention, and the combined disciplines of the research team which range from child development to public health to economics. It has the potential to provide the answers to the policy and practice questions about quality, culturally appropriate and accessible early childhood education for young children and their families.  Through this research, and its accompanying strategy to share learning and influence change, the project will substantially contribute to partner countries achieving their Sustainable Development Goals in terms of early and inclusive education and preventing violence against children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will draw on the strong partnerships already established between ODA research teams in Brazil (International Centre for Research and Policy on Childhood at PUC-RIO), Eswatini (University of Eswatini), South Africa (Children&apos;s Institute, University of Cape Town) and the West Bank &amp; Gaza (University of Bethlehem), with the University of Edinburgh.  The ODA research teams have worked with their country stakeholders, to articulate what is needed for the project&apos;s research aim and design.  The project will make fundamental contributions to the achievement of Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) in Brazil, Eswatini, South Africa and the West Bank &amp; Gaza: in early childhood education (target 4.2), as well as assisting with the creation of safe, inclusive learning environments (target 4.a) and preventing violence against children (target 16.2).  In particular, the project aims to: 1. Explore, develop and critically consider the conceptual and application of inclusive participative pedagogy in early childhood education (ECE), particularly in fragile settings 2. Support in-depth engagement of community and national stakeholders, in each ODA partner country, so as to improve ECE in their contexts, in order to promote economic development and welfare within each country 3. To share and develop the learning within and from the project, to support cross-national ECE development and capacity building methodologically and substantively, and thus becoming a focal point for ECE research in this important area of developing sustainable, quality and inclusive ECE  To realise these aims the project will: - For the first time, to bring together the necessary disciplines and associated research skills in early childhood pedagogy, violence prevention, participative methodologies and co-production to explore the potential of inclusive participative pedagogy as a new and challenging concept for ECE - Use advanced and tested mixed methods to provide a sound evidence base within each ODA partner country: for national and community-based policy, system and related statistical analysis; for in-depth community-based work to develop the concept and application of inclusive participative pedagogy in particular fragile contexts of violence, inequality and/or poverty. - To ask whether there is an economic case for inclusive participative pedagogy, and if so what are the relevant components and the short- and long-term costs and benefits.   - Develop participative methodologies and co-design methods for engaging with young children, their families and stakeholders, which take account of different contexts. This will be done both within communities and - ambitiously - once community groups are well established, cross-nationally so as to advise the project as a whole.  - Draw on the skills and experience across the 5 country project team, to ensure capacity-building across the team (e.g. skills training: participative methodologies, quantitative research; mentor early career researchers to develop management and leadership experience) and to expand out to share these more broadly through local training and winter/ summer schools.  - Invest in a substantial strategy of knowledge exchange. Effective knowledge exchange is essential locally in the case study communities and nationally in the ODA partner countries. This includes resource development (e.g. training modules for ECE, skills training in participative methodologies and quantitative analysis of administrative data), targeted briefings and media to stakeholder audiences, and direct engagement with key decision-makers and other stakeholders. The learning will be shared with other ODA contexts, to expand and develop the project&apos;s overall impact</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">114746.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">315728.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">106666.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">107530.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">107530.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">1709654.442</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004002_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT004002%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-01-20"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
