<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R022887_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluating the impact of the Mais M&#xE9;dicos (More Doctors) programme in Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Providing access to comprehensive and high quality healthcare for all is key for Universal Health Coverage (UHC) and for achieving many of the United Nation&apos;s Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). However, the limited and uneven allocation of health professionals is undermining progress towards UHC in many low and middle income countries (LMICs). Understanding whether efforts to address shortages in health professionals are successful in improving access to healthcare in underserved areas and produce improvements in health outcomes is crucial for advancing the design of health policy in this area.   Brazil is a country that has historically suffered large disparities in doctor availability with rural and poor areas having a much lower provision of doctors that wealthier, urban areas. This lack of doctors means that many vulnerable Brazilians are not benefiting from the country&apos;s internationally recognised model of primary health care delivery. In 2013, the Brazilian government launched a major programme called Programa Mais M&#xE9;dicos (PMM) or More Doctors programme to address acute shortages of doctors in the public health system in underserved areas. This was achieved by expanding medical school places, increasing investment in healthcare facilities, and through an &quot;emergency expansion&quot; of doctors in rural and poor areas. The latter has involved the allocation of over 17,000 doctors to 4,004 municipalities, with more than 60% of these doctors coming from Cuba as part of an international agreement. This unprecedented expansion of doctors in under-served areas may have important effects on health outcomes and health inequalities, in addition to wider health system impacts. To date, no robust evaluations of programme impacts have been undertaken, hampering learning from the programme for policymakers in Brazil and internationally.   We will evaluate the &quot;emergency expansion&quot; component of PMM using national databases of hospitalisations and deaths which are routinely collected and by conducting interviews with national policy implementers and health system managers and doctors in two states of Brazil. Specifically, we will examine the reasons why some municipalities adopted the programme and others did not, which factors influenced whether the programme was successful in local settings and how access and use of health care services may have changed in response to the introduction of PMM doctors. We will examine if programme impacts differed by whether municipalities were allocated Brazilian or Cuban doctors. We will also examine whether the programme was associated with a reduction in hospital admissions and deaths, both in children and adults, and whether it reduced inequalities in health outcomes.   The project is a collaboration between researchers based in Brazil (University of Brasilia and the Federal University of Paraiba) and in the UK (Imperial College and the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine) who have extensive experience in evaluating health policy in LMICs using quantitative and qualitative methods. We will disseminate our findings through academic forums and have developed a plan to actively disseminate our work with key health policy makers in Brazil and internationally, through events planned with Federal and State Ministries of Health and the Pan-American Health Organisation (PAHO).   Brazil is an eligible country for UK official development assistance (ODA). Many Brazilians cannot access quality healthcare services. This directly affects their welfare, and health needs continue to go unmet - particularly in the poorest and most vulnerable communities. Over 22% and 5% of the population live in poverty in Paraiba and the Federal District (the focus jurisdictions for our qualitative research) respectively, whilst 20% and 10% are illiterate. This project will evaluate the impact of an internationally important HRH intervention on the health of some of Brazil&apos;s most vulnerable communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To evaluate whether the emergency provision of nearly 18,000 doctors under the programa Mais M&#xE9;dicos (PMM) has affected health outcomes; including hospitalisations from ambulatory-care sensitive conditions and mortality among children and adults from amenable causes;  To understand whether PMM impacts differed across population sub-groups, programmatic factors, and by municipal-level characteristics, including explicitly testing impacts on health inequalities;  To understand what factors influenced allocation of PMM doctors to municipalities and to what extent was allocation consistent with PMM criteria of need;  To determine whether the allocation of PMM doctors to non-priority municipalities influenced programme impacts on health outcomes;  To understand facilitators and barriers to successful implementation of PMM, including broader health system constraints, and how these were addressed by national implementers, local health managers and PMM doctors;  To determine whether different characteristics of PMM doctors, particularly the differences between Brazilian and Cuban doctors, have influenced programme impacts;  To work collaboratively and integrate qualitative and quantitative approaches throughout the project to maximise the cross-learning, steer research approaches, contextualise findings, and deliver the outputs that are appropriate for the Brazilian setting and valuable to policy-makers;  To generate longitudinal aggregate datasets from existing data sources covering all municipalities to facilitate robust analyses, and preserve these datasets for future research;  To build capacity for Brazilian and UK based early career researchers in robust data analysis, impact evaluations, international collaborations, and influencing health policy;  To engage with institutions and civil society such as the Ministry of Health, the council for municipal health secretaries, national health conference, the Brazilian Public Health association (ABRASCO), and the Pan American Health Organisation (PAHO), to maximise the impact of the work alongside traditional dissemination routes such as academic publications and conferences;  To draw generalizable lessons from the PMM for other contexts on factors affecting successful implementation, wider health system effects, and expected impact on health;  To influence policy relating to the primary healthcare and human resources for health (HRH) both in Brazil and internationally;</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-04465125" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">100373.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">101186.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">51003.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">252564.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Newton Fund Award to Imperial College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/R022887/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR022887%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
