<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_R017999_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Towards environmental reconciliation in P&#xE1;ramo land in Boyac&#xE1;: resolving ecosystem trade-offs in post-conflict spaces</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conservation and habitat destruction are some of the most complex environmental problems linked to conflict and peace. Whilst conflicts around the world have contributed to destruction of ecosystems, they have also limited the exploitation of resources such as timber, mining, and agriculture in rural areas, many of which are characterised by high biodiversity.  The high Andean p&#xE1;ramo ecosystems of Colombia comprise globally important biodiversity and habitats, which have high ecological, social and cultural value. Local communities who inhabit these landscapes are very diverse in terms of their culture and institutional capacity based on traditional knowledge and local perceptions that provide some social and institutional resilience. However, p&#xE1;ramo social-ecological systems (SES) are subject to increasing multiple pressures from rapid development and climate change as well as the legacy of the long-standing war between the government, the guerrillas and the paramilitaries. The armed conflict has, without a doubt, left a damaging footprint on Colombian landscapes and ecosystems, creating forced displacement and expanding the agricultural frontier into sensitive environments, such as the p&#xE1;ramos.  P&#xE1;ramo landscapes provide crucial ecosystem services, with beneficiaries beyond their boundaries, such as water regulation (groundwater storage and supply to urban centres) and food and energy security through crop production, livestock grazing and fuelwood use.   In 2016 the Colombian Government finalised a peace accord thus marking an end to 52 years of conflict and creating an opportunity to restore the environmental damage and revise the country&apos;s pathways to development. With this in mind, the overall objective of this project is to undertake a quantitative spatio-temporal analysis of p&#xE1;ramo lands - to understand and manage the natural, social and economic drivers affecting water resources and land-use/land-cover change, and the impacts on biodiversity, ecosystems services and livelihoods. The overall objective will be achieved through five specific aims:   RO1: To explore historico-cultural p&#xE1;ramo geographies mapping the imprint of multiple conflicts on the landscape and social and environmental identities developed to resist them  RO2: To enable community and stakeholder analysis of the hydrological resource and ecosystem services provided by p&#xE1;ramos in the greatest detail so far achieved  RO3: To map historic p&#xE1;ramo land cover and livestock dynamics, investigate their drivers, and identify implications of past and future dynamics for ecosystem services, livelihood strategies, and opportunities for sustainable development.  RO4: To economically value ecosystem services provided by p&#xE1;ramo and explore potential Payments for Ecosystem Services  RO5: To facilitate mutual understanding across diverse stakeholders and co-develop pathways to conflict resolution.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Land was at the heart of Colombia&apos;s long-running armed conflict and is now the pillar on which the success of the peace agreement rests. The war changed the country&apos;s social landscapes as much as its natural ones and efforts to address the ecological balance are doomed to fail unless they confront that legacy of conflict. Decades of conflict displaced millions of people from their land and traditional livelihoods, disrupting the social fabric as much as the ecological. The p&#xE1;ramo regions in Boyac&#xE1; illustrate these socio-ecological conflicts. For the last 50 years Boyac&#xE1; has experienced substantial conflict over resources, manifested through land-grabs, dispossession and displacement of local communities. The situation has deteriorated in the last decade associated with the mining boom that has pushed traditional campesinos into p&#xE1;ramo land, further complicated by the fracking concessions currently being awarded in the region. In the wake of the peace agreement Boyac&#xE1; faces substantial environmental problems, particularly with regards to the p&#xE1;ramos, which the local authorities will have to delimit for ecosystem preservation and biodiversity conservation. In doing so, they risk potential new conflicts between contested land usages. Their decision-making needs to balance conservation priorities with concerns for the social and economic future of the displaced traditional campesinos, potato and onion growers, commercial and artesanal miners and small farmers. At the same time, the loss of these livelihoods imposes risks to local and regional food security and rural development programmes.   This project integrates a group of multi-disciplinary scholars from environmental and veterinary sciences, cultural and historical geography, anthropology, economics and design, working with an understanding of the social and ecological nature of these challenges. At the heart of the project is our conviction that peace and reconciliation between the different users of p&#xE1;ramo land in order to facilitate and legitimise decision-making is not an add-on to conservation efforts but a sine qua non condition to the effective conservation of p&#xE1;ramo land.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-25">273922.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-25">370739.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-25">355429.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-25">86879.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
