<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P010377_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social Network Analysis of Innovation Cluster in Creative and Cultural Value Chain: Case of George Town World Heritage Site</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the proposed research project are: 1. To develop a relational model of innovation and entrepreneurship ecosystem for creative and cultural district.  This research aims to build a novel business ecosystem model focusing on how innovation and entrepreneurship could be understood and fostered, specifically, in a newly developed creative and cultural district. This research will identify how small and medium businesses (or individuals in a micro business setting) in this sector build relations and networks that enable them to create and obtain innovative ideas and knowledge, as well as transform it into real business opportunities. In this context, civil society can play an important role and shall be incorporated in the model.   2. To provide social network insights for the development of creative economy and conservation of cultural heritage in George Town, Malaysia. Social Network methodology will be applied to interpret how actors collaborate across different institutional realms (government, business, academic and civil society), different cultural groups and subsectors of the creative economy. The sociograms created will provide insights on the metrics of the networks such as the types of connections, extent of distributions, and clustering and cohesion of groups. 3. To produce a policy brief on strategies for developing creative and cultural districts in George Town.  This will target policy makers and local community organisations with the aim to develop policies and strategies for promoting innovation and entrepreneurship of local residents, and supporting fruitful collaboration among cultural actors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research addresses the phenomenon of creative and cultural cluster in a site with a rich cultural heritage. The project will explore questions regarding the role of different actors in developing businesses in cultural districts while preserving and disseminating their cultural heritage. Hence, the research is positioned in a wider debate regarding the links between cultural preservation, urban regeneration and tourism. The selected site is George Town, a post-British colonial town in Malaysian. The town has experienced gentrification since 1997 after the repeal of Rent Control Act. The pace gentrification exacerbated with the growth of tourism and influx of external capital investment after its have been inscribed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 2008. Gentrification induces displacement of long-term residents and causes erosion of local culture and heritage - a global phenomenon in many World Heritage Sites. Nonetheless, a creative and cultural value chain has been developed with involvement of various local and external actors. The development of cultural district is becoming an important tool for urban planning in fostering the development of urban centres and revitalising neighbourhoods in decline. Reviewing the existing models of innovation and entrepreneurship ecosystem, there is a gap in the scope of these models in capturing civil society actors and insufficiently explaining the phenomena of cultural clusters. Thereby, they are inadequate in informing urban planning policy makers, the innovation community, cultural organisations and small businesses. The main objectives of this project are: 1) To develop a relational model of innovation and entrepreneurship ecosystem for creative and cultural districts 2) To provide social network insights for the development of creative economy and conservation of cultural heritage in George Town 3) To produce a policy brief on strategies for developing creative and cultural districts in George Town  This research intends to deploy a novel approach using Social Network Analysis to identify actors and their networks. Understanding these networks and roles will enable the conceptual development of a novel relational model of entrepreneurship and innovation ecosystem, specifically for cultural districts. This research will collect, via face-to-face administrated questionnaires, approx. 1000 network relations of actors in the creative and cultural value chain in George Town. We will use UCINET to analyse and map this network and identify its strengths and weaknesses. Based on these findings, we will conduct six in-depth case studies of core actors in the networks to gain rich qualitative insights on how they build innovative and entrepreneurial networks. This method is a novel approach to develop and conceptualise a model of innovation and entrepreneurship for creative and cultural district. The model is applicable more generally to other small towns and cities, particularly world heritage sites, where there is a potential to build a creative and cultural district empowering local residents with opportunities. For greater impact, we plan to produce a policy brief on cultural districts for George Town. This brief will be built on the findings of the Social Network Analysis and a review of existing policies in the UK and Penang. We will organise a study visit for Malaysian delegates to creative districts in London, NESTA, and the Department of Culture. The researchers are multi-disciplinary experts from the UK and Malaysia. Two project partners based in Penang are invited to contribute to the research process as well as take the findings forward in policy-making process and in innovation and entrepreneurial activities among the local community. We will organise knowledge sharing and transfer workshops for local researchers. There will be a feedback and dissemination workshop targeting local policy makers, NGOs, and local creative businesses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Greenwich</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-17">12894.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-17">51682.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-17">38996.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-17">2382198.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Greenwich</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P010377_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Greenwich</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP010377%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-02-06"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
