<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N006135_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Dose Reduction Immunobridging Study of two HPV vaccines in Tanzanian girls</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cervical cancer is the commonest cancer among women aged between 15 and 44 years in Tanzania. Mortality from the disease is extremely high because screening programmes are frequently absent or limited in scale and women usually present late, leaving palliative care as the only option. HPV vaccines are most effective if provided to girls who have not yet acquired HPV infection. In Tanzania we have shown that HPV vaccine is safe, is very acceptable and can be delivered with high coverage (around 80%) but setting up and sustaining an HPV vaccination programme for young girls requires considerable investment in human and financial resources.  Despite high acceptability of the vaccine in East Africa, a number of studies have estimated that the cost of delivering HPV vaccine is considerably higher than costs for delivering traditional infant/child vaccinations, even if vaccine is subsidized by the GAVI Alliance. This is primarily because of start-up costs to establish outreach programmes and associated personnel costs with involvement of teachers and nurses who must spend significant time away from their health posts to deliver vaccine, especially if multiple doses are needed. There is global interest in simplifying delivery by reducing the number of doses of HPV vaccine. The cost savings of offering fewer doses of HPV vaccine would be substantial and would also result in less time that health personnel are away from their stations and simplification of vaccine delivery. If a single dose could be given, this could halve the costs of vaccine delivery, making HPV vaccine more accessible to the populations that need it most. Recently, the WHO recommended that 2 doses of HPV vaccine could be given to girls aged less than15 years, based on studies in high and upper middle income countries. However in Africa there are high rates of infections like malaria and worms that can affect immune responses to vaccines. We need be sure that a reduction in the number of vaccine doses does not reduce the protective immune response of these vaccines. We are planning a randomised trial in healthy Tanzanian females aged 9-14 years to establish whether a single dose of HPV vaccine produces immune responses that are likely to be effective in preventing cervical cancer in Africa. We will compare two different HPV vaccines, the bivalent (2-v) vaccine that protects against HPV 16/18 (the cause of 70% of cancers) and a new 9-valent (9-v) vaccine that protects against 9 HPV types. Our trial will enrol and randomise 900 girls aged 9-14 years into 6 groups. They will receive either the 2-v or the 9-v HPV vaccine, as 1, 2 or 3 doses. Girls will be followed up for 36 months after the first dose so we can measure the quality and sustainability of immune responses. We will compare the girls receiving 1 or 2 doses with those receiving 3 doses of the same vaccine, to ensure that the reduced dose regimen produces an immune response that is not inferior to the standard 3 doses. We will also compare the immune responses in our study with results from other countries without a high prevalence of malaria and worm infections, and where the vaccine has been shown to be protective. This will give us information about whether a reduction in the number of doses is likely to be protective in Africa.   This trial will address fundamental questions about HPV vaccine dose reduction in a setting where the potential impact is greatest, and will be extremely important in informing future HPV vaccination policy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human papillomavirus (HPV) infection is the primary cause of cervical cancer. There are 3 licensed HPV vaccines: a bivalent (2-v) vaccine that targets HPV 16/18, the genotypes associated with 70% of cervical cancer cases; a quadrivalent (4-v) vaccine that targets HPV 16/18 and HPV 6/11; and a new 9-valent (9-v) vaccine that protects against 9 HPV genotypes.  Recently the World Health Organization (WHO) recommended moving from a 3 dose to 2 dose regimen in girls aged &lt;15 years based on immunogenicity data from high and upper middle income countries. However, there is increasing evidence that the vaccines are so immunogenic that it may be possible to give them as a single dose, but no randomised trial evidence is available to support this. A single dose vaccine would be hugely cost-saving for Africa and countries where the costs to implement an HPV vaccination programme are much higher than for traditional EPI vaccines. This is primarily because of costs of outreach programmes to schools and associated personnel costs. These costs prevented Tanzania, for example, from taking up a large HPV vaccine donation in 2012.  Malaria, endemic in many parts of Africa, is known to induce a polyclonal immune response which could affect the immune response to HPV vaccines. We therefore need to determine whether the quality of HPV vaccine immune response in malaria-endemic countries is the same as in other countries, especially for reduced dose schedules.  We will bridge our immunogenicity results to those in adult women in whom efficacy has been demonstrated; such immunobridging studies have been used by a number of HPV vaccine trials to infer efficacy in young girls, and are recommended by WHO. Our goal is to determine if we can simplify and reduce costs of HPV vaccine delivery by giving a single dose without adversely impacting vaccine immune responses. The potential impact of a single dose vaccine would be substantial, with significant cost savings, reductions in time health personnel are away from their posts and simplification of vaccine delivery. We are evaluating the 2-v and 9-v vaccine, because of differences in their adjuvants which may affect immunogenicity and thus their suitability for dose reduction. Primary objective: To demonstrate non-inferiority of immune responses of 1 dose of HPV vaccine compared with 3 doses of the same vaccine by evaluating HPV 16/18 seropositivity, antibody avidity and memory B cell responses at M36 Secondary objectives: To demonstrate: 1) Non-inferiority of HPV 16/18 seropositivity after 1 dose of HPV vaccine compared with 3 doses of the same vaccine at M12 and M24.  2) Non-inferiority of HPV 16/18 seropositivity and antibody geometric mean titre (GMT) at all time points when comparing 2 doses with 3 doses within the same vaccine.  3) Equivalence of HPV 16/18 seropositivity and GMT at all time points when comparing the same dose regimen between the two vaccines (e.g. 1 dose of 2-v compared to 1 dose of 9-v). 4) Non-inferiority of HPV 16/18 antibody avidity and memory B cell responses at M36, when comparing 2 doses with 3 doses within the same vaccine, or the same dose regimen between the two vaccines. 5) To evaluate stability of HPV 16/18-specific antibody responses when comparing antibody GMT at M24 with those at M36 within the same arm. To demonstrate: 6) Non-inferiority of HPV 16/18 seropositivity when comparing 1 dose of either vaccine with 3 doses of 2-v vaccine in historical controls, and of antibody GMT when comparing with historical controls who received only one dose, both groups in which efficacy has been demonstrated. 7) Non-inferiority of HPV 16/18 seropositivity and antibody GMT when comparing 2 doses of either vaccine with 3 doses in historical controls.  To evaluate: 8) Cost-effectiveness of 1 dose compared with 2 and 3 doses, and of the 9-v vaccine compared with the 2-v vaccine. 9) Acceptability of 1 and 2 doses compared with 3 doses. 10) Safety and tolerability</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">604468.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">603769.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">608607.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">613485.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">463801.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-15">3048732.759</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N006135_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FN006135%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-03-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
