<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecology of insecticide resistant vectors: consequences for the effectiveness of malaria control strategies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Insecticides impregnated into bednets is the most widespread strategy to control and eliminate malaria worldwide. Insecticides work by killing mosquitoes that can transmit malaria and have been extremely successful in reducing malaria cases throughout sub-Saharan Africa. However, mosquitos are increasingly resistant to insecticides, threatening to reduce their effectiveness. Despite the gravity of this impending threat, the extent of insecticide resistance (IR) and its consequences for public health remain poorly understood. A fundamental assumption is that resistant mosquitoes are identical to susceptible ones in all aspects other than their response to insecticides. However, there are several reasons why this may not be the case. For example, malaria transmission is known to be more sensitive to variation in the long-term survival and behaviour of mosquitoes than to their overall abundance. These features, in addition to other mosquito life-history traits such as their reproductive success, may be altered in resistant mosquitoes. Together this could result in insecticide-based control methods retaining a higher than expected degree of efficacy, even in areas where IR levels are high, which would suggest the possibility of developing control methods to mitigate the consequences of resistance i.e. &quot;resistance busting strategies&quot;.  Thus understanding the ecology and behaviour of IR mosquitoes and how their life history is affected in the short and long-term by control measures is crucial for prediction of the consequences of resistance. Unfortunately, these parameters are difficult to directly measure under natural field conditions, and may be poorly reflected in laboratory bioassays. However, recent developments in ecological modelling have delivered breakthrough, but as yet rarely applied, methods for deriving such hidden (latent) information from the multiple types of data that are routinely collected in mosquito surveillance. I propose to use these new methods to investigate the population dynamics and ecology of malaria mosquitoes in an area of high IR, and to quantify the impacts of both traditional and novel control methods on mosquito life history under field operational conditions. I will focus on the Banfora district of Burkina Faso, a region of high IR, and will make use of mosquito surveillance data, including mosquito abundance, infectiousness, IR status and behaviour, being collected by my collaborators in the AvecNet programme. This data collection is part of a 2-year 90-villages large-scale intervention trial of two alternative malaria control methods for which laboratory assays predict will reduce mosquito populations through two different routes: 1) traditional bednets (LLIN) that are coated with the insecticide pyrethroid, which works by killing adult female mosquitos; and 2) new Olyset DUO nets that are coated with a pyrethroid to reduce adult mosquito survival but also with pyriproxifen, an insect juvenile hormone that affects fecundity and longevity. However, it is unclear how reliably these expected demographic impacts occur when applied within natural populations.   To address these issues I will apply novel analytical tools that integrate the various types of data generated from widely-used surveillance techniques with clinical incidence data, in order to reconstruct the hidden population dynamics and life history-traits of IR mosquito vectors, and use it to 1) determine how the ecology of IR mosquitoes modulates their malaria transmission potential, 2) quantify the impacts of current and novel control methods on these mosquitoes and 3) design optimal deployment of future intervention methods in areas of high IR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This fellowship is driven by one of the most prominent challenges in the fight against malaria: increasing levels of insecticide resistance (IR) in malaria mosquitoes across sub-Saharan Africa. IR has the potential to threaten the effectiveness of insecticides implemented in long-lasting treated bednets (known as LLIN), the most widespread control strategy currently available for malaria. Despite the gravity of this impending threat, the extent of IR and its consequences for public health remain poorly understood. A fundamental assumption in this debate is that resistant mosquitoes are identical to susceptible ones in all aspects other than their response to insecticides. However, variation in basic ecological features between mosquito species such as life-history traits, behaviour and reproductive success may allow insecticide-based control methods to retain a higher than expected degree of efficacy, even in areas where IR levels are high. Unfortunately, these parameters are difficult to directly measure under natural field conditions, and may be poorly reflected in laboratory bioassays. However, recent developments in ecological modelling offer an innovative approach for deriving this type of information from the types of data that are routinely collected in vector surveillance. I propose to use a state-space modelling (SSM) approach to investigate the population dynamics and ecology of malaria vectors in an area of high IR, and to quantify the impacts of both traditional and novel control methods on mosquito life history under field operational conditions. I will focus on the Banfora district of Burkina Faso, a region of high IR, and will make use of mosquito surveillance data, including vector abundance, IR status and behaviour, and clinical incidence data being collected during a large-scale randomized trial of two alternative malaria control methods: 1) traditional LLINs that are coated with pyrethroid and target adult survival; 2) Olyset DUO nets; that are coated with a pyrethroid and pyriproxifen, an insect growth hormone expected to reduce survival and fecundity, with the latter effect expected to impact both pyrethroid resistant and susceptible mosquitoes. It is unclear whether these predicted demographic impacts occur when applied within natural populations.   The overarching objective of this proposal is to reconstruct unobserved population dynamics and life history traits of IR mosquito vectors, and use them to predict the impacts of current and novel vector control strategies. This will be achieved via novel analytical tools that integrate data generated from vector surveillance with clinical incidence and vector behavioural data. Specifically, I aim to: 1) Determine how the ecology of IR mosquitoes (e.g. behaviour and life-history) modulates their transmission potential and susceptibility to control measures. 2) Quantify the impacts of current and novel control methods on mosquito demography under natural settings and test the hypothesis that IR mosquitoes are unaffected by current front line strategies (LLINs) 3) Model the population dynamics of IR malaria vectors and use model predictions to design optimal deployment of intervention methods.  These objectives fit with my career ambition of focusing on research at the intersection of theory and data where I can develop and apply analytical tools for solving problems that lead to direct practical impacts on the control of infectious disease. The cross-disciplinary nature of this fellowship will allow me to bridge important gaps between empiricism and analysis. This will give me a greater insight into the analytical challenges and requirements of disease control programmes as they unfold, and will greatly improve my understanding of operational research in low income settings, which will allow me to engage in new productive collaborations in global health for the continuation my research career.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-08">72685.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-08">97633.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-08">98423.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-08">293497.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Skills Development Fellowships Award to University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/N015320/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-01">24163.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">24163.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">24358.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">24358.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">24358.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">24358.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">24556.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">24556.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">24556.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">24556.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">24755.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">24755.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015320_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN015320%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
