<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P004326_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moving with Risk: forced displacement and vulnerability to hazards in Colombia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project focuses on a critical but under-researched theme in studies of forced displacement: the processes through which people forced from their homes by conflict can commonly become exposed to heightened risk from environmental hazards in the places where they resettle. Effectively, such people exchange one form of catastrophic risk for another, often with little real choice in the process. The collaborative project will pioneer an innovative methodology using the expressive arts in Colombia, where five decades of conflict have generated what is currently the world&apos;s largest population of internally displaced people. Colombia is also one of the countries most prone to natural hazards including landslides, floods, earthquakes and volcanic hazards. The activities that are proposed aim to deepen understanding of how and why the transition to new risk occurs, analyse how people perceive and respond to risk in their places of resettlement, and strengthen the capacity of both themselves and the agencies responsible for supporting them to manage the implications on their lives, livelihoods and wellbeing. The work with marginalised people, struggling to rebuild their lives in hazardous settings, often with limited resources, will have strong resonance for developing countries across the world where two forms of risk - conflict and disaster - commonly interact. Moreover, the signing in June 2016 of a ceasefire agreement in Colombia creates a window of opportunity that makes work to assist organisations to support the long-term wellbeing of conflict-displaced people particularly timely. The research and engagement will centre on four case studies, working with people displaced by conflict in urban and rural settings within the Departments of Tolima, Caldas and Risaralda in west-central Colombia. To understand how men and women experience forced displacement and relocation into areas prone to natural hazards in Colombia, and to explore innovative ways through which they could be incorporated into local processes of disaster risk reduction, this project will use an innovative combination of qualitative methods. Social science methods of interviews and life histories will be merged with exploration of creative arts with study participants. The idea is that focusing on artistic expression, especially popular music which plays a special communicative role in Colombia, will provide a window for us to build relations of trust and reach a deeper and richer understanding of the diversity of their experiences, vulnerabilities, perceptions and responses. The proposed research brings together methods in a way that has seldom been robustly applied in the field of displacement and ongoing risk. But this programme is not solely about research. A key objective of the project is to build capacity, not only amongst displaced people but also within the organisations responsible for supporting them and managing risk. Through a series of workshops in which musical and other forms of artistic expression will be promoted, we intend to use creative arts to help people recognise their rights and develop their own capacities to reduce risk. Also present at these workshops will be key partners in the risk management organisations, who will take an active role and benefit from the opportunity to explore new ways of working with marginalised displaced people. The idea is that this will encourage organisations that have struggled to include these communities in risk management systems to view them less as victims and beneficiaries, and more as active partners in reducing disaster risk. If successful, we will help promote this new way of working beyond the case study areas to the national scale of disaster risk governance and support for displaced people. At a time when the potential for peace holds promise for making life better for so many who have been forced from their homes by decades of conflict, the project is particularly pertinent.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project aims to advance understanding of the interaction of conflict-forced displacement with risk from natural hazards, and to strengthen the capacity of displaced people and the organisations that work with them to manage ongoing forms of risk. It will do so via multi-site research and engagement in Colombia, a country that represents the coexistence of very high numbers of conflict-displaced people and the extensive threat of disaster associated with multiple forms of hazard. The overall research setting and the insights drawn from four distinct case study sites within Colombia will yield valuable lessons for research and support of IDPs in many regions of the world facing new risks in their places of resettlement. The central objectives are to: 1) Advance research on the experiences, vulnerabilities and survival strategies of conflict-displaced people living in hazard-prone locations.  We will undertake pioneering empirical research on the ongoing trajectories of vulnerability as a consequence of forced displacement by studying the process through which people forced out of their homes by conflict become exposed to heightened risk from environmental hazards in the places where they resettle. This is a field of intersection between displacement and disaster studies that has received little attention to date, though the problem of this transition from one form of risk to another is widespread in many countries where IDPs seek vacant urban and rural land to resettle.  2) Pilot and evaluate the use of creative arts both as a methodological tool for data collection among displaced populations and as a channel for empowerment of people and communities in managing disaster risk in their places of resettlement. We will use an innovative combination of qualitative social science methodologies with creative arts to engage more effectively with marginalised IDPs. At one level this will enable us to reach a deeper and richer understanding of the diversity of their experiences and vulnerabilities, the shape of their immediate and long-term responses and their own understandings of what constitutes risk, security and wellbeing for their communities. At another, through a series of workshops in which artistic performance will be promoted, we intend to use expressive arts as a vehicle through which to enable people to recognise their rights and develop their own capacities to reduce risk. A key output of the project will be an evaluation of the effectiveness of this approach in research and engagement.  3) Strengthen the capacities of government institutions and civil society organisations managing both displacement and disaster risk to respond to the challenge of supporting at-risk displaced people in Colombia. The Project Partners in government and the third sector have expressed their hope that the proposed work will strengthen their ability to work with these hard-to-reach urban and rural communities on disaster risk reduction (DRR). Through directly engaging the Partners and other stakeholders in all stages of the project we aim to contribute to developing their capacity and willingness to work openly, flexibly and creatively with IDPs. Our intention is to create an environment in which the focus on IDPs is shifted away from one that conceives of them as &apos;victims&apos; and &apos;beneficiaries&apos; of intervention to one that humanises them and recognises their knowledge and potential to manage risk.    To do so the project proposes an interdisciplinary research team composed of researchers from three Faculties of the University of East Anglia (UEA), collaborating with researchers and an NGO in Colombia with a track record of work with at-risk and displaced communities using expressive arts as a mechanism of engagement and empowerment. The project will be a rich but challenging endeavour, and will benefit from the guidance of an additional team of expert advisors drawn from across UEA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">120919.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">242818.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">131898.88</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">247981.344</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P004326_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP004326%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
