<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_R006741_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From Design and Construction to Discovery: Machine Learning Algorithms for Particle Physics Triggering and Tracking with GPUs and FPGAs in Malaysia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia is currently in the midst of its own Data Analytics (DA) revolution.  Through governmental policy, it supports both academic research and industrial avenues to increase Malaysia&apos;s capacity for DA and High Performance Computing (HPC).  In the proposed project, which will run for three years from April 2018, physicists at Imperial College London seek to participate in this effort by working together with leading researchers from Malaysia on the Coherent Muon to Electron Transition (COMET) Experiment.   COMET is designed to investigate charged lepton flavour violation (CLFV) by searching for the as-yet-unseen muon to electron conversion on an aluminium nucleus. This process is not allowed in the Standard Model of particle physics, but has very good sensitivity to Beyond the Standard Model physics. A positive discovery of CLFV would be a Nobel Prize-class result and revolutionise our understanding of the building blocks of the universe. The experiment is currently under construction at the internationally-renowned Japan Proton Accelerator Research Complex (J-PARC) laboratory.  The first phase of the COMET experiment will begin taking data in 2019. This phase is designed to probe this process 100 times better than the current limit, with a second phase reaching a sensitivity that is 10,000 times better. To achieve this sensitivity, we are building the world&apos;s most intense muon beam which will deliver over a billion muons per second.  Very few of these muons will result in anything that is relevant to muon to electron conversion, and instead will form the unwanted background to our sought-after CLFV signal. Therefore COMET (a search for a miniscule &quot;signal&quot; in the midst of a billion billion mundane &quot;background&quot; occurrences) presents a huge technical challenge which will be met by the use of a combination of modern technologies: these include cutting-edge applications of Field-Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs; programmable integrated circuits which allow real-time data algorithms to be implemented) and Graphics Processing Units (GPUs) as accelerative computing components, supercomputing via a cloud-based computing solutions, and Machine Learning (ML) techniques. Whilst these will be employed to allow COMET to pursue its particle-physics goals, these are technologies that are known to offer novel solutions to common problems in a growing number of global DA industries, from communications and networking to financial applications and blockchain research.  COMET&apos;s first data-taking runs are scheduled for 2019, in the second year of the project. Over a hundred physicists from 35 institutions in 14 countries currently participate, and top scientists from Malaysia will work with researchers from Imperial on the preparations for the experiment, real data-taking and the physics analysis of the data. The Imperial group designed the software that is being used by COMET and participants will take part in the global collaborative coding effort, and the production of massive amounts of computer simulations that are needed to allow us to study the data, and work with experts in FPGA and GPU programming to produce and test the hardware and software that is needed by the experiment. The project includes attachments in the UK and Malaysia to allow the exchange of skills, as well as extended time at the J-PARC laboratory to build and run the experiment together with our international colleagues.  The project will result in participants taking on valuable roles within the experiment, being trained in modern DA techniques and applying them to this world-leading experiment. In addition to a particle physics measurement that has the potential to be a paradigm-changing discovery, it will provide for a solid basis for future leadership in a broad range of pure and applied research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="MY" type="MALAYSIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-25">109013.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-25">220682.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The Objectives of the proposed project are as follows:  * to improve the big data analytics and high-performance computing skills of the Malaysian participants through collaborative efforts with the UK on the COMET experiment * to provide training and practical experience in machine learning, GPU programming, high-bandwidth data processing, FPGA programming, high-performance batch computing, parallel programming, and modern software development in an international collaborative environment to the Malaysian participants * to equip Malaysian participants with the skills to increase their involvement in COMET both during the three year project and after, as well as boosting their ability to contribute to the data-driven aspects of today&apos;s economy * to expose Malaysian participants to the research environments at both Imperial College London and the J-PARC international accelerator laboratory in Japan, both through attachments and short-term visits as well as through remote collaboration * to include the University of Malaya&apos;s Data-Intensive Computing Centre as one of several high-performance computing sites for COMET that contribute to official data-processing for the COMET Experiment in addition to those in France, China, the UK, Japan, and Germany  * to improve COMET&apos;s software and analysis capabilities by implementing parallel processing capabilities, such that multiple computing cores on a CPU can be made use of. This is important as COMET presents one of the world&apos;s most demanding data analysis challenges, as well as requiring the processing of huge amounts of simulated data * to finalize COMET&apos;s Phase-I tracking algorithm design and the track-trigger design and implement them in the experiment effectively and correctly on GPUs and FPGAs; these will run on simulated data and real data from the experiment * to participate in COMET&apos;s first data taking runs, scheduled to take place in Year 2 of the project * to create an feasible design of the tracking algorithm for COMET Phase-II building on the techniques used for the Phase-I detector to design a prototype of the Phase-II algorithm design, to be tested on simulated data * to advance COMET&apos;s capability to achieve its target of a world-leading sensitivity measurement of charged lepton flavour violation (CLFV)"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
