<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N011449_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAPESP-ESRC-NWO-Joint Call Sustainable Urban Development ...... RESOLUTION: REsilient Systems fOr Land Use TransportatION</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our objectives are listed as follows:  1. To develop an integrated assessment of the ways in which transport infrastructures in terms of their operation and provision leads to social and spatial segregation across a number of different socio-economic dimensions in S&#xE3;o Paulo and London. As we argue in the proposal, transportation both integrates and divides populations and in both cities, different social groups are locked in and out of opportunities, particularly in their labour and housing markets, with respect to their access to jobs through the differential provision of transport infrastructure.   2. In terms of the themes, to elevate resilience uppermost in this project, defined in terms of the extent to which transportation provides robust patterns that generate equitable and efficient spatial distributions of people and jobs. In fact, in both cities, different population groups are highly vulnerable to changes in the provision of transportation and it is clear that new transportation proposals in both cities, particularly with respect to mass transit, do not take account of the extent to which these reinforce and generate greater poverty, vulnerability, polarisation and income differentials due to variations in spatial accessibility.   3. To set this project within the wider context of complexity theory which the investigators here have made contributions to through modelling and simulation. In this sense, our project is intimately concerned with the various feedbacks, emergent structures, and historical path dependencies that determine the degree to which spatial populations are both resilient and adaptable to changes in transport.  4. To ensure resilience in transport infrastructure but not simply in terms of accessibility between residential and workplace locations but in terms of access to hospitals, retail facilities, education and so on. In this sense, accessibility is differentiated with respect to different facilities and there is an important focus in this project on using morphology to measure and interpret sustainability. We will develop a strong physical-functional measurement of accessibility across many spatial scales and this will focus on relationships to poverty and inequality as reflected in the segregation and polarisation of different social groups. There are clear economic implications in that transportation is associated with economic costs of energy and time and these reflect the link from residential to workplace functions in terms of the way populations allocate their income between transport and housing.   5. To link with questions of sustainability in terms of energy resources pertaining to density, mode of transport and operation. In this sense, the scenarios that can be tested using the data and models that we are developing, reflect not only the relative disadvantages and advantages of different population groups but also their exposure to sustainable transport. There are implications in this work for increasing densities of development which reflect the move to more compact cities, notwithstanding the widely divergent arguments associated with such scenarios.   6. To develop a simple and fast agent based model that will tie together the various functions noted in the previous objectives so that effective &apos;WHAT IF?&apos; scenarios related to transport and location can be effectively tested.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will explore the impact of transportation on social segregation in S&#xE3;o Paulo and London, comparable world cities in terms of their population, area and density at both municipal and metropolitan levels. In large cities, social groups classified by income, class, and ethnicity manifest extreme differences in where they locate and how accessible they are to a variety of opportunities for mobility, as reflected in the physical distribution of resources associated with different transport systems. These two cities provide us with examples of segregation enabling us to use the findings in one city to &apos;probe&apos; the other; patterns of segregation with respect to transportation are similar in some senses, different in others. This provides us with an ideal opportunity for comparative work on segregation using rich data sets for each of these cities. We first construct web-based portals that allow us to represent a wide variety of network, flow and socio-economic attribute data. We will build on the extensive experience in these systems acquired by CASA (see www.maptube.org; www.datashine.org.uk), transfer these ideas to S&#xE3;o Paulo, building on their own systems (www.fflch.usp.br/centrodametropole/en/). We will add transportation explicitly in both cities and this will provide us with a stream of analytics that will inform the development of simple agent-based models which simulate how changes to transport systems are reflected in shifting patterns of segregation.  These models will build on existing structures pioneered in various collaborations between CASA, Birkbeck, CEM, UFABC and INPE. The data systems and models we build offer prospects for practical testing of alternative transport scenarios on spatial structure by urban policy makers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">52909.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">106247.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">26668.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
