<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Precision medicine for diabetic Individuals: a joint Malaysia-UK Effort (PRIME) project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia has the highest rate of diabetes in Asia and one of the highest in the world. Adding to this problem is the growing number of obese Malaysian children and adolescents who are now or will be affected by diabetes. The harmful effects of diabetes on the vasculature or blood vessels dominate the complications caused by diabetes. These vascular effects affect the heart (to cause heart attack, stroke and heart failure), feet (leading to amputations), eyes (to cause blindness) and kidneys (to cause kidney failure). This escalating diabetes pandemic with its cardiovascular complications has huge effects both for the affected individual and their society. Despite sugar-lowering diabetic drugs and control of other cardiovascular risk factors, people with diabetes continue to succumb to the cardiovascular-related diseases. While efforts are being made to combat this diabetic epidemic through public health measures, new strategies are clearly needed to address and prevent the cardiovascular complications of diabetes. In the UK, we have pioneered the concept of personalised medicine through the use of genetics to determine who will and will not respond to commonly used drugs in diabetes, as well as for heart protective drugs such as those that lower blood pressure and cholesterol. We have also made substantial inroads in the use of artificial intelligence to analyse digital pictures of patients&apos; retinas to find features that reveal a patient&apos;s current disease status and is predictive of future risk of complications such as stroke and heart disease. However, the majority of these studies on how diabetes and the cardiovascular complications arise and how patients respond to medications are from white European ancestry populations despite the fact that diabetes in Europeans is very different to diabetes in Asians.  There is therefore an urgent need for detailed research into the specific causes and cardiac consequences of diabetes in Asians including those in Malaysia in order to identify the processes that drive the onset of cardiovascular complications of diabetes that exist in Malaysian ethnicities and use this to understand how best to manage diabetes in Malaysia.   In our proposed PRIME partnership, we propose to build upon the precision medicine expertise in Dundee that includes the on-going &#xA3;7 million NIHR Global Health Research Unit on Global Diabetes Outcomes Research INdia-Scotland Partnership for Precision medicine in Diabetes - INSPIRED (https://inspired-nihr.com/) project that is exploring specific differences in combinations of genomic, retinal and clinical determinants of complications of diabetes and therapeutic response between Scottish and the South Indian population. The plan is to embed insights from the on-going INSPIRED program into the PRIME project that will add value to each project. Using the available precision medicine expertise in Dundee, we will facilitate knowledge transfer to Malaysia for initial establishment of a similar concept using the Malaysian government initiated The Malaysian Cohort (TMC) study, that is the biggest and most comprehensive population-based cohort study in Malaysia. The overarching objective of the PRIME project is to develop an international collaboration between Dundee and Malaysia that will establish the potential for translation of precision medicine to management of diabetes and its associated cardiovascular complications in Malaysia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OBJECTIVES The overarching objective of the PRIME Partnership project is to develop a high performing and sustainable collaboration and research platform between Dundee and Malaysia that will establish the potential for translation of precision medicine to management of diabetes and its associated cardiovascular complication in Malaysia. Using the available expertise in Dundee in genomics and linkage to large electronic health record datasets we will facilitate knowledge transfer to Malaysia for initial establishment of a PRIME cohort within The Malaysian Cohort (TMC) project. Our NIHR Global Health Programme INSPIRED project that aims to combine clinical, retinal and molecular information to achieve personalised diabetes treatment in India will serve as the basis and proof of concept of our ability to translate our approach to a developing country and our experience of conducting a similar project will inform and ensure the success of the PRIME project. The specific objectives and outcomes of PRIME Partnership are:    Objective 1. To collect and digitise follow-up data on the PRIME Cohort,  comprising 5,000 individuals with diabetes in Malaysia. Expected outcome: Demographic and outcome data (including co-morbidities, cardiovascular outcomes and diabetes related complications) will be collected, cleaned, digitised and harmonised to align with that available in the GoDARTS cohort (Genetics of Diabetes Audit Research Tayside Scotland; n=30,000 individuals with diabetes) in Tayside as a basis for further analyses.  Objective 2. To conduct a pilot genome-wide analysis of the PRIME Cohort. Expected outcome: This GWAS will be used to evaluate the genetic architecture of diabetes in the multi-ethnic Malaysian cohort. Comparisons will be made between the PRIME Cohort and GoDARTS to evaluate differences between ethnicities. We expect this initial analysis to identify genetic variants associated with diabetes in Malaysians, and these will also be linked to outcomes of interest identified in Objective 1.  Objective 3. To explore the use of quantitative measurements of the retinal vasculature to better define a patient&apos;s disease status and predict future risk of complications. Expected outcome: We will use a program allowing semi-automated measurements of retinal vascular function (VAMPIRE) and determine the association of these with outcomes in patients with diabetes. As Malaysia does not have a routine retinal screening programme, a subset of patients recruited to the Malaysian cohort will be recalled for retinal photography.  Objective 4. Knowledge transfer and capacity-building. Expected outcome: As part of the PRIME project we will train a PRIME-funded MSc student. This will be a key step in training a new generation of big data analysts in Malaysia in the analysis of linked high-throughput molecular and clinical data.   It is our ambition to combine clinical, retinal and molecular information to achieve personalised diabetes treatment in Malaysia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-SC-015096" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">24462.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">83847.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">46156.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">154466.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Dundee</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/T018186/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">24462.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">23372.78</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">20104.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">20104.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">20266.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">19823.18</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-07-01">13166.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018186_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-SC-015096">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Dundee</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT018186%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
