<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S011692_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Structure, connectivity and resilience of an exploited ecosystem: towards sustainable ecosystem-based fisheries management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Shallow subtidal rocky reefs of Chile and Peru are dominated by kelps that form dense forests. In northern and central Chile this has led to one of the largest live harvest kelp fisheries in the world with ambitions to extend its spatial extent to Peru and southern Chile. Kelp harvesting leads to clearances resulting in local deforestation and habitat fragmentation with implications for the sustainable development of this fishery as well as the long-term health of kelp forest ecosystems, which support high levels of diversity and provide a wealth of goods and services worth billions of dollars to human society. Given that kelp harvesting in Chile and Peru is often undertaken by poorer members of society and that 46% of artisanal fisheries landings are of species associated with kelp forests, better management of the fishery will lead to improved economic development. Currently there are limited management strategies in place and where present, they are poorly enforced. The OECD noted that over-exploitation and illegal fishing are key fisheries challenges in the region and that ultimately a lack of governance in this area will impact the economic development of both countries. In response, the governments of Chile and Peru are committed to developing management plans for kelp resources, with the Chilean government announcing landmark plans to not only manage current stocks, but to introduce direct funding to fisherman to restock depleted areas. The Peruvian Government is on a similar path, with both countries are seeking to ensure continued biomass extraction of kelp and the maintenance of kelp associated fisheries. However, knowledge gaps exist hampering informed management and the long term sustainability of these coastal socio-ecological systems. It is unlikely that a one size fits all management approach will work in this region. The coastal oceanography is complex with areas of persistent and seasonal upwelling as well as areas with weak or no upwelling. Upwelling brings cold, nutrient-rich and CO2 saturated waters to the surface influencing population dynamics and community structure. Therefore in order to provide informed management advice there is a need to understand the impacts of harvesting intensity and environmental variability on the resilience (ability to tolerate and recover) of kelp populations. In addition, different harvesting techniques and other fisheries management devices are likely to impact the resilience of kelp forests and different restocking methods are likely to be more or less successful.  We will use a multidisciplinary approach incorporating population genetics, experimental ecology, population and species distribution modelling and social-ecological approaches to deliver tools and indicators for sustainable kelp harvesting. Specifically we will address the following objectives: 1. Quantify the total stock of exploited kelp species across the region and predict how this will change with climate change.  2. Investigate the impacts of harvesting intensity and environmental variability on the population structure and connectivity of a commercially harvested kelp species as well as five important kelp-associated species using molecular techniques and traditional ecological approaches. This will enable us to identify the physical drivers and biological traits that promote resilience within kelp forests.  3. Develop tools and indicators for sustainable kelp harvesting by exploring different management options to improve kelp resilience to harvesting as well as exploring options for promoting recovery of harvested areas.  4. Explore the role of traditional ecological knowledge and bottom-up approaches to fisheries governance on management compliance. In meeting these objectives we will make significant contributions to the development of informed management plans, which will improve the sustainability and economic development of this important fishery and region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-28"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">61558.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">283166.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">204629.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Commercial kelp harvesting is an intensive industry in northern and central Chile and there are plans to expand the fishery into Southern Chile and Peru. At present there is little management of the fishery even though fisheries induced changes in population structure and resilience have been observed at a regional scale. Both Chile and Peru are actively seeking to make the fishery more sustainable, both for kelp harvesters and those that fish for kelp-associated species. The proposed project aims to understand how environmental variability and harvesting intensity interact to determine kelp forest resilience and in particular how these processes affect local adaptation and population demography of kelp and kelp-associated keystone species. Such information can help inform spatial management plans. In addition, we plan to investigate how different harvesting techniques and other fisheries management devices affect kelp resilience as well as examining the viability of kelp restocking via transplantation to promote recovery. We expect the outcomes of our research to make significant contributions to the development of sustainable management guidelines. Our specific objectives are:   1. To quantify the total standing stock of exploited kelp species and predict the influence of future climatic changes on the distribution/biomass patterns - We use well established physical drivers of kelp distribution and biomass data to develop species distribution and stock assessment models for four commercially harvested kelp species under current and predicted future climate change scenarios to inform the spatial management of the fishery today and into the future. 2. To undertake comparative genomic analysis of connectivity and local adaptation across the kelp forest seascape - Using next generation sequencing approaches we will assess the genetic structure and local adaptation of the commercially harvested kelp, Lessonia trabeculata, and five keystone kelp-associated species. Genetic estimates of dispersal/connectivity will directly contribute to optimised spatial management strategies by providing vital insights into population boundaries, environmental and harvesting impacts on population demographics and processes of population replenishment. Signatures of local adaptation will also inform on population structure and fisheries induced evolution.  3. To determine the role of spatial variability in harvesting intensity on the resilience of kelp and kelp-associated keystone species under different environmental conditions - We will explore how differences in upwelling intensity and harvesting pressures have impacted the population structure and traits of L. trabeculata as well as five keystone kelp-associated species. This will enable us to identify regions and or traits that might be more or less resilient to harvesting under different environmental contexts.   4. To develop tools and indicators for sustainable kelp harvesting - We will undertake a series of manipulative experiments exploring different management options to improve kelp resilience to harvesting as well as exploring options for promoting recovery of harvested barrens. We will employ population models that will simulate different harvesting practices and through incorporation of information from Objs 1-4 we will provide tools and indicators on what harvesting regimes promote increased resilience under different environmental contexts.  5. Can traditional ecological knowledge improve the spatial management of contemporary harvesting? We will use social science approaches to explore the effectiveness of different fisheries governance approaches used by Peru (top-down) and Chile (bottom-up). These contrasting approaches provide an opportunity to assess compliance different management regimes"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
