<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M010864_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Investigating mechanistic causes of C9ORF72-related amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cells constitute the basic building blocks of the human body converting food and oxygen into energy to produce proteins. The blueprint for making up proteins, the DNA, is housed in the nucleus, a cell centre separated from the surrounding compartment, the cytoplasm, where proteins are assembled into the machinery supporting life. Small messenger species (messenger RNAs) copied from the blueprint are able to pass from the nucleus into the cytoplasm where each guides the building of one protein. The quantity and function of proteins account for survival or death of cells including motor neurons. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) is a fatal adult disease caused by progressive death of nerve cells that connect muscles to the brain and the spinal cord. This provokes gradual paralysis and death usually 3-5 years from symptom onset. There is currently no cure and the only drug available, Riluzole, has modest effect prolonging life for only approximately 3 months. Expansion of a repeated sequence in the C9ORF72 gene is the commonest alteration found in the DNA of patients with ALS. This genetic alteration causes damage to thousands of messenger species resulting in the potential malfunction of multiple aspects of the cellular machinery. However, the actual culprit(s) causing motor neuron injury have not yet been found. This project aims to identify the contribution of each potential abnormal mechanism that causes motor neuron injury in C9ORF72-related ALS, their pathological mode of action, and will help us to find biomarkers useful in diagnosis and disease monitoring. We have used cutting-edge scientific methods to produce nerve cells from healthy and C9ORF72-ALS patients&apos; skin cells and have generated other cell models engineered for studying individually the effects of one potential mechanism of disease at a time. Using these models, we will now be able to carry out experiments aimed at understanding how decreased electrical/survival properties of nerve cells, altered content of messenger species and abnormal passage of messengers from the nucleus into the cytoplasm, occur in disease. In the future, we expect that a better understanding of the basic biological mechanisms of C9ORF72-related ALS from this study will allow the development of novel strategies for neuroprotective therapy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The principal objective of this project is to discover whether the molecular mechanism of C9ORF72 ALS is to trigger gain-of-function toxicity and to further characterise this using multiple in vitro tools interrogated by gene expression profiling, electrophysiological experiments, toxicity assays, metabolic profiling and mRNA nuclear export assays. Findings of interest such as altered levels of RNAs/proteins identified in C9ORF72-ALS cell models (of unknown function or with neuroprotective/ neurotoxic functions) will be validated in CNS tissues from ALS and control patients available in the Sheffield Brain Tissue Bank. Specific Aim 1: To generate C9ORF72-ALS iPS-derived motor neurons (MNs) and astrocytes from 6 ALS patients and 6 controls.  In addition we have built cell models which will allow interrogation of whether sequestration of proteins by RNA foci and/or RAN translation of dipeptide repeat proteins or both is necessary for neurotoxicity.    Specific Aim 2: Electrophysiological evaluation of iPS-derived MNs to identify the mechanisms underlying the altered electrophysiological properties of iPS derived motor neurons from C9ORF72 ALS patients.  Potassium, calcium and sodium channel properties will be examined as well as the properties of GABA abd AMPA-receptor induced whole cell currents.  Specific Aim 3: Investigating cellular stress responses, including oxidative stress, DNA damage responses and excitotoxicity in C9ORF72-ALS iPS derived motor neurons and G4C2-mediated RNA toxicity cell models.  We will also examine the potential contribution of astrocyte mediated toxicity to motor neuron injury.   Specific Aim 4: Identify mechanism(s) of neurodegeneration using gene expression-profiling approaches in iPS-derived MNs and astrocytes using methods previously successfully applied to other genetic subtypes of ALS. Specific Aim 5: To characterise the molecular mechanisms driving aberrant nuclear export of the C9ORF72-ALS pre-mRNA which allows the expression of cytoplasmic RNA foci and the translation of dipeptide repeat proteins in the presence of hexanucleotide expansions in C9ORF72. This collaborative project combining the expertise of SITraN and the Tongii University Centre for Stem Cell Biology will provide important information on pathophysiological mechanisms underlying C9ORF-related ALS. Completion of the proposed research is expected to transform our understanding of the molecular mechanisms and establish therapeutic options for this devastating neurodegenerative disorder which causes both ALS and fronto-temporal dementia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">31117.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">124722.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">125733.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">94871.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">10164012.192</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M010864_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FM010864%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
