<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R003947_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INVESTIGATING A ROLE FOR THE ARTS IN SUPPORTING RELATIONS OF CARE IN RAJASTHAN&apos;S TRADITIONAL WATER INFRASTRUCTURES</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research network will explore how community-based arts can contribute to understandings and improvements in the welfare of those living in conditions of water scarcity. We expect the network to result in far-reaching multi-disciplinary collaboration on the themes of water, infrastructure, gender and social relations, care, sustainability, and inclusive communities between the UK and India. For this foundation-setting network project, our work will centre on the care practices associated with the development and maintenance of traditional water infrastructures in Rajasthan, India.  Rajasthan is the driest state in India and has a long history of using simple rainwater harvesting and conservation practices to manage water scarcity.  However, in recent decades these techniques have fallen out of use in favour of modern, centralised water extraction and distribution processes which have, unfortunately, largely failed to meet the needs of people in rural Rajasthan.  As a consequence, many water experts in India are now advocating a return to smaller, decentralised and traditional rainwater harvesting to address water scarcity. Our project will take a careful look at the renewal of interest in traditional rainwater harvesting practices and the role these infrastructures play in both local social relations and the delivery of sustainable water security.   Our project will draw together water and development specialists, government stakeholders, water providers and managers, socially engaged and community-based artists and gender experts in the exploration of traditional water conservation practices and infrastructures in Rajasthan.    Socially engaged arts practice is at the heart of our approach. Knowledge and experience of harvesting in Rajasthan is embedded in local village cultures.  By working with Indian artists who have specialised in processes of creative facilitation and inquiry we expect not only to collaboratively explore traditional practices, but also to disseminate this knowledge and experience in an accessible form to national and international policy circles and stakeholders.  Our approach to &apos;care&apos; draws on the experiences associated with the AHRC-funded project &apos;Towards-Hydrocitizenship&apos; (2014-2017) through which PI Dr Buser studied the practices of urban water infrastructural maintenance and mending. Following Joan Tronto, we understand care to be &apos;everything that we do to maintain, continue and repair our world so that we can live in it as well as possible.  That world includes our bodies, ourselves and our environment, all of which we seek to interweave in a complex, life-sustaining web&apos; (1993, 103). Within the context of Rajasthan&apos;s traditional water infrastructures, this means looking to the way care is both a disposition and (often unacknowledged or unrecognised) practice that permeates social relations.  It also explicitly acknowledges the non-human as a key agent in care assemblages.    Our programme involves three workshops through which we will facilitate cross-disciplinary and international collaboration.  The first two of these will take place in Rajasthan where we will discuss and explore the conditions of water scarcity and water infrastructure in Rajasthan.  This will include working with Indian-based arts practitioners and traditional water infrastructure users and caretakers. The third workshop will take place in Bristol, UK and centre on widening creative, academic and policy engagement with the concepts of infrastructural care and furthering our research agenda. This will include a mini-conference and an exhibition of materials and creative outputs from the first two workshops and Indian arts commissions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-10-02"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-14">33363.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-14">14298.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Our broad aim is ongoing multi-disciplinary collaboration on the themes of water, infrastructure, gender and social relations, care, sustainability, and inclusive communities between the UK and India.   Our specific objectives include to:  Collaborate with individuals and organisations involved with addressing issues associated with water scarcity and access in Rajasthan, India.    Investigate how collaborative arts practice can address issues of water scarcity and access and contribute to the local enrichment and overall welfare of people in Rajasthan, India.   Examine and document care practices associated with traditional water infrastructures in Rajasthan, India.  This includes consideration of the role and use of water infrastructures in social, cultural and physical well-being; the practices of looking after and mending water infrastructures; and the role of infrastructures as agents in care assemblages  Study and draw attention to the experiences, impacts and possibilities for traditional water infrastructures and practices in contemporary settings.   Contribute to local, national and international water infrastructure policy and practice through modes of collaborative arts practice and inquiry.  Develop a network that will bring together environmentalists with artists and arts facilitators in India and the UK who focus on community engagement around social and environmental issues.  Develop new knowledge regarding the effects of infrastructure on inequality, particularly with respect to access to clean water and relations of gender equality.   Connect Indian partners with water managers and stakeholders as well as socially engaged artists and practices in the UK."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">33363.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R003947_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007164">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West of England</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">14298.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R003947_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007164">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West of England</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">-682.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R003947_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007164">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West of England</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
