<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P010083_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peace, Dialogue and Citizenship Education in West Africa: Non-Formal Learning for the Development of Strong Institutions and Civil Society</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">My doctoral research relates to the sustainable development of countries on the DAC list. I examine the interface of dialogue, peace and education in conflict-affected and fragile societies. In particular, I consider how dialogue is often viewed as a pathway to reconciliation and social transformation in both peacebuilding and educational discourses and I challenge the linear approach often taken between personal and societal change. I highlight the importance of non-formal learning spaces and daily life as vehicles for such dialogue and potential change and I argue that these spaces take on a critical role in conflict-affected areas where formal schools often cease to function but where peace and citizenship education is acutely needed.   My thesis has developed a concept of &apos;humanising dialogue&apos; drawn from the works of Paulo Freire and Martin Buber and applied it to a real-world situation: street discussion spaces in Abidjan, C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire. These spaces were composed of two distinct forms: plenary-style spaces called agoras or parlements that once amassed hundreds of people and small, informal circles of friends and neighbours called grins where issues were discussed whilst preparing traditional tea.    These spaces became important political milieus in the early 2000s during C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire&apos;s political crisis and represented sites of both learning and action, sometimes veering towards violence in the 2010-2011 post-electoral crisis. The sites also exemplified political and social divisions, with grins generally regrouping northern, Muslim Ivoirians who supported Alassane Ouattara while agoras generally catered to Christian Ivoirians, many from the West and South, who supported Laurent Gbagbo.   In my research, I consider these spaces in the post-conflict context, exploring their transformation in peacetime and examining how dialogue occurs in different spaces and how members view their participation as contributing, or not, to peace and reconciliation. My qualitative study conducted in 2014 involved over 100 observation hours in 40 discussion spaces and in-depth interviews with 30 participants. Findings showed that members of both grins and agoras actually viewed peace as a top-down process that needed to start with the government; nevertheless, spaces often became the starting ground for local-level change and improvement, through social networks and the creation of small associations. This research also highlighted the value of single-group dialogue in settings where intergroup dialogue was not a possibility. For example, in considering Freire&apos;s concept of reflection and action, the research demonstrated that through discussion spaces, sites of grassroots change were actually developed where neighbours would form associations to combat the issues they found most pressing to their community.   During the GCRF postdoctoral fellowship, I will be able to expand upon this research while simultaneously applying it in a multinational education project. The United Nations and other development organisations have recently made prominent declarations regarding the role of youth in peacebuilding, globally and in the Sahel region. As a Research Fellow for UNESCO&apos;s current Global Citizenship Education project in the Sahel, I will use my research and experience to develop strategies for non-formal education for out-of-school youth and those at risk of recruitment into extremist groups. In addition, my theoretical knowledge of peace and citizenship education and dialogic learning will also contribute to the development of learning materials and evaluation systems. More so, during the fellowship I will be able to engage with academics, students and development practitioners in the region to share my findings and to mobilise them in projects, research and policy. Thus the GCRF Postdoctoral Fellowship provides an ideal continuation of my previous research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="C&#xD4;TE D&apos;IVOIRE"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="WESTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1030</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The Global Challenges Research Fund (GCRF) Postdoctoral Fellowship will allow me to further develop my skills as a researcher, engage with users and beneficiaries, maximize the policy impacts of my research and develop a professional network that can secure career opportunities within and outside of academia. For this reason, I have structured the 12-month fellowship to build on my previous research on peace, dialogue and non-formal education in C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire while also focusing on making impact through academic publications and conferences as well as engagement with users of research in the development sector.  Academic impact will be accomplished through submitting articles in three peer-reviewed journals. One of these articles will be in collaboration with an Ivoirian sociologist and country director of Interpeace, Dr S&#xE9;verin Kouam&#xE9;, who works in the field of education and peacebuilding.   Additionally, I will spend three months at the UNESCO Dakar office as a Research Fellow where I will contribute to their recently launched Global Citizenship Education project in eight West African countries. My doctoral research provides a unique perspective on youth non-formal education and effective ways of reaching young people, relevant to UNESCO&apos;s Theme &apos;Learning to Live Together&apos;. Furthermore, UNESCO Dakar wishes to increase research-informed projects, especially based on qualitative studies that explore acquisition of citizenship values. As a Research Fellow, I will have the opportunity to conduct small-scale research, building on my doctoral research in C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire, about of-of-school youth at risk for violence in Senegal. This placement offers valuable experience in the UN and provides important contacts for future research opportunities or jobs and strengthens ties between university and policy makers.   I will present at two conferences: UKFIET and the European Society for African Studies (ESAS). UKFIET&apos;s biannual conference regroups top researchers and practitioners in the field of Education and International Development and will be an important opportunity to build networks and to share findings. ESAS&apos;s annual conference will be my first entry into the field of &apos;African Studies&apos; and will allow me to share my research with users in a different academic discipline.   I aim to foster a dynamic network of GCRF fellows that will promote learning and provide support. I found this critical to my academic success throughout the PhD and feel certain that such a network will play an important role in the GCRF fellowship. I will help to arrange regular meetings of Bloomsbury Doctoral Training Centre fellows to critique one another&apos;s work and will collaborate in planning a national meeting of all GCRF fellows. I also hope to organise a GCRF conference symposium at UKFIET.    A second trip to West Africa will consist of a short visit to C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire to engage with actors in the field of dialogue and reconciliation at the Centre for Action Research for Peace, the University of Boauk&#xE9; and the UNESCO Chair for Peace. I will further develop North-South collaboration between academics in C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire through networks I have fostered since 2014 and will build capacity of research students, educationalists and peacebuilders.  The above aims will be accomplished with the support of two mentors, Dr Avril Keating of UCL and Dr Phil Clark of SOAS. Dr Keating has lead multi-country studies of citizenship education and has knowledge of both in- and out-of-school learning for youth and will direct me in integrating quantitative research into my work and in better conceptualising &apos;citizenship education,&apos; a main component of my proposed placement and research at UNESCO. Dr Keating will also guide me in applying for research funding and in participating in department activities. Dr Clark is an expert in African politics, specialising in community-based justice and will provide academic support in the field of African studies."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">0.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P010083_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P010083_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">-0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P010083_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P010083_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
