<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T023864_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performing Violence, Engendering Change: Developing Arts-Based Approaches to Peacebuilding</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Performing Violence, Engendering Change: Developing Arts-Based Approaches to Peacebuilding&apos; connects artists and researchers from ODA recipient countries across Africa, the Middle East and South Asia working with peacebuilding practices rooted in the arts. It does so by bringing together GCRF and British Academy projects on the impact of the Lebanese civil war on infrastructure; gender and resistance to violent extremism in Kenya; the relationship between transitional justice and development in conflict-affected societies; and gender justice and gendered insecurities. The Cluster will enhance participants&apos; roles as stakeholders in peacebuilding by providing opportunities for research collaboration and knowledge exchange during three week-long workshops held in Kenya, Lebanon and Sri Lanka.  In recent years, scholars, policy makers and practitioners have begun to acknowledge the benefits of using arts-based methods for violence prevention and peacebuilding. Evidence suggests that arts-based methods hold significant potential for improving human security and relations between groups in areas affected by violence and conflict. Arts-based methods, especially when combined with community-centred participatory methodologies, can act at once as analytical tools and dissemination media, whilst creating spaces for practical interventions in difficult contexts.   Despite the growing awareness of the positive impact of arts-based methods, there are scarce opportunities for communities of practice and research to learn from each other, co-create research and establish networks. Spatial and existential isolation can result from living with extremist violence and conflict, with debilitating but different consequences for women, men, youth and other social groups. The silence and seclusion, secrecy and loneliness that conflict zones engender have been linked with the presence of PTSD and other mental health conditions.   Whilst violence and conflict disrupt and often devastate communities, the shared experiences they generate can also be used to connect people. The Cluster aims to break isolation and achieve impact by connecting communities in Kenya, Lebanon and Sri Lanka affected by conflict and extreme violence, who are working to build positive peace. The grant will be invested almost exclusively in bringing together community activists, practitioners, artists, academics (including early career researchers and PhD students) and policy makers in three workshops that will focus on network- and capacity building through intensive research production, knowledge exchange and training sessions on the use of filmmaking, theatre, performance and visual arts as tools to confront violence and promote positive peace. Workshops will include substantial focus on the ways that arts-based approaches can enhance gender approaches to conflict research and peacebuilding.  The Cluster is designed to accelerate the impact of the contributor projects by building deep and lasting links between researchers, partners, policy makers, civil society actors and communities affected by violence, with a view to the network expanding to include other participants and cases in future research. In addition to traditional academic outputs, the Cluster will produce short documentary films on arts-based peacebuilding practices and an open-ended interactive Online Archive providing wide access to the Cluster&apos;s research via a dedicated website. The website will be the main portal for public engagement, featuring videos, podcasts and case studies, as well as serving as a resource beyond the end of the award. These activities and outputs are geared towards achieving three specific and measurable impacts on the practices of violence prevention, the prevention of violent extremism and peacebuilding: the creation and transfer of knowledge on arts-based approaches to these challenges; context-driven learning and capacity building; and fostering gender and social inclusion.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Engender impactful research and collaboration on the use of arts-based approaches to peacebuilding. The primary objective of the Cluster is to allow researchers and practitioners working with arts-based methods in areas affected by conflict and violence to share best practices, exchange knowledge and develop collaborative research projects to address the most pressing knowledge gaps around arts-based methods and peacebuilding. The activities of the Cluster will enable a creative and critical exchange of practices and approaches to peacebuilding rooted in the arts to generate new, effective and emancipatory research projects that cross geographical and disciplinary divides. In particular, participants will focus on an area which has received relatively little attention: the potential of arts-based approaches to produce more gender-sensitive research findings and to give voice to marginalised groups. Workshops in three countries - Kenya, Sri Lanka, Lebanon - will generate a community of research and practice through engagement with diverse approaches articulated by workshop participants. This community will co-create the Cluster&apos;s outputs and use these same outputs for further community engagement and learning.  Central to achieving objective 1 is the active engagement of Co-Is and project partners from the three focus countries. Local Co-Is and partners will work together to shape the workshop agendas and provide insights on the relation between arts-based methods and community peacebuilding initiatives in their contexts.    2) Build capacity among communities affected by conflict and violence. The primary activities of the Cluster are three workshops at which all Cluster participants will meet. In addition to Cluster participants, a number of local practitioners and researchers will be invited to each workshop. The workshops will include both structured and less formal meetings to enable participants to build durable and self-sustaining relationships. The workshops will include training sessions during which participants will engage practically and experientially with a specific arts-based method. This will be introduced and discussed in relation to its specific context, before participants will take part in interactive group work. Training sessions will build capacity by facilitating participants to engage with the latest practices and applied scholarship. Participants will also develop their interdisciplinary skills through exposure to alternative approaches to their field of study and opportunities to collaborate across disciplinary and professional boundaries.  3) Map and disseminate existing knowledge. Whilst there is growing evidence of the effectiveness of arts-based methods in peacebuilding, there are few cross-case studies. Information will therefore be gathered from projects in the three focus countries and beyond to synthesise and disseminate existing practices and knowledge to increase understanding of the specific impacts of arts-based methods in peacebuilding and conflict resolution. Gaps will also be exposed by engaging with the perspectives of less powerful stakeholders in the three countries and by giving space to underrepresented groups. This mapping will crystallize in the Online Archive, which will offer links to current research projects and initiatives underway within and outside the Cluster to provide the fullest possible picture of existing work. The Online Archive will be interactive and open-ended, thus allowing for more material to be uploaded and for the research team to update relevant sections. The Archive and links to all open access material will be made available publicly via the Cluster&apos;s website. This exercise of synthesis and dissemination will also allow non-academic stakeholders to document and archive their practices and analyse their own work against comparable cases or the field more broadly.  4) Engage policy makers, advocacy groups and publics. See Impact Summary for details</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brunel University London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-05" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">90723.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">30241.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">120965.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to Brunel University London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T023864/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brunel University London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">30241.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T023864_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brunel University London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">30241.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T023864_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brunel University London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT023864%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
