<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M006050_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing an innovative primary health care system for pastoralist community</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pastoralists in Ethiopia constitute about 15% of the over 86 million people. Although pastoralists are socio-economically important segment of the population, they are subjected to harsh environment and extreme poverty with poor infrastructure and social services. As a result pastoralists have poor health status with high infant, child and maternal deaths. Cognizant of the challenges and socioeconomic importance, there have been continental and national efforts to improve the livelihoods of pastoral people. Ethiopia introduced a community-based Health Extension Program (HEP) in the pastoral areas to address the poor health status and achieve equitable health outcomes. The HEP model, which was originally designed and piloted in 2004 for adaption to the context of the agrarian sedentary population, was introduced into pastoral areas with minor adjustments on human resource taking into account the cultural context, language and scarcity of high-school graduates. Although there has been a significant improvement in the performance of the health system in the country, the impact has been less successful in the pastoral areas demonstrating that the adaptation of the HEP model to pastoral areas was not based on adequate consideration to the local context. We propose to follow the following steps to develop an appropriate public health interventions for pastoral settings: 1) description of the local context including existing health systems; 2) selection of potential interventions; 3) testing interventions (feasibility, acceptability and efficacy); 4) formulation of appropriate public health intervention; 5) implementation at a scale; and 6) monitoring effectiveness and adequacy.  The purpose of this &apos;development grants&apos; proposal is to address the first two steps, which will be used to develop a well-informed research project (moving forward through the steps) for submission to the &apos;full-scale research project grants&apos;. We aim to describe the morbidity patterns, characterize the context and identify health determinants, and address the question as to what are the most appropriate interventions for pastoral areas. We will describe the wider context and barriers to service delivery to inform the design of strategies that ensure acceptability and service utilization addressing the question as to how to most effectively delivery health interventions building on existing structures. We will also explore existing venues that are potentially adaptable for service delivery in the pastoralist setting and address the question as to how to most effectively delivery health interventions using existing social events and services. The study will be conducted in Borona zone, Oromia region. It will involve documentation and analysis of contextual factors and existing health services. The research will employ basic epidemiological study based on health facility records and registers, and community level surveys. Behavioral and social processes that put the pastoralist community at high risk will be described through qualitative study. Process evaluation will be conducted through case-study approach to thoroughly examine the underlying context at various levels of implementation and stakeholders using key informant interviews and Community Focus Group Discussions. The designing process of potential health interventions will involve community participation, adoption of innovative and adaptive approaches, and consider cultural sensitivity. The study will contribute to achieving equitable health outcomes and the MDGs in Ethiopia and beyond, and to ensure the widest use of the research findings, we aim to establish a collaborative partnership involving policymakers and relevant stakeholders. Results of the research will be communicated through presentations in national and international conferences, publications, the Internet, and mass media.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the research project is to improve the poor health status of the pastoralist communities in Ethiopia. To meet the proposed goal, the research project aims to develop a primary care strategy appropriate to pastoral context. As a prerequisite to developing health strategy adapted to pastoralist context, there is a need to acquire information on the health problems and associated risk factors, health determinants, socio-economic, demographic and cultural characteristics, and the existing formal and informal health systems. Understanding these contextual factors will address the questions as to what are the most appropriate intervention packages, and as to how to most effectively delivery such interventions building on existing structures in pastoral areas. The subject of the &apos;development grants&apos; research project is to collect this critical information, which is not available in any data source in the country, and propose possible and potential interventions for pastoral communities. Once this research is completed, we aim to use the information and prepare a well-informed research project for submission to the &apos;full-scale research project grants&apos; with the objectives of testing the interventions and formulating an appropriate public health intervention for pastoral communities. The specific objectives and research questions proposed under this &apos;development grants&apos; include: Objective 1: To describe the major causes of morbidity and mortality among pastoral people. This requires basic epidemiological research to describe the nature and magnitude of the health problems in the pastoralist communities in terms of population groups or geographical areas. Specific information on the burden of diseases resulting from their proximity to animals (such as anthrax) and on the burden of malnutrition due to their dietary habit, which is limited to milk and meat will be collected. Objective 2: To describe the pastoralist communities in terms of geographic features, socio-economic and demographic characteristics, livelihood style, and relationship with livestock. This research objective will involve both qualitative and quantitative approaches to understand and assess the prevalence and distribution of risky behaviors, and examine associations with possible determinants. Characterizing the context and identifying the determinants that are related with the health status of the people will give insights into approaches to the interventions. Designing and selection of health interventions need to build upon people&apos;s own perceptions and motivations, and take into account the cultural, social and economic factors that may facilitate or hinder behavior change.  Objective 3: To describe the formal and informal health systems in pastoral areas and document the pattern of utilization between the two services.  Objective 4: To assess the process and the degree to which the HEP has been implemented and identify the factors that could explain the level of performance.  Objective 5: To assess the engagement and acceptability at the level of the community in the implementation of the HEP.  Objective 6: To identify possible and potential intervention strategies for the pastoralist context. The information and results of the above objectives will be the bases in the identification of the potential health interventions for pastoralist context. Key relevant stakeholders including the FMOH, the Ministry of Federal Affairs, the Regional Health Bureaus (RHBs), the District Health Offices, and other relevant stakeholders and experts will be involved in the discussion and decision process. This collaborative process will ensure the widest possible use of the findings of the project and ownership of the project by the stakeholders and will ensure the uptake in the development of appropriate delivery strategies for pastoralist communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ctr for Nat Health Dev Ethiopia (CNHDE)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-02-09">79557.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-02-09">20040.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-02-09">119638.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to Ctr for Nat Health Dev Ethiopia (CNHDE)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/M006050/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ctr for Nat Health Dev Ethiopia (CNHDE)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">20040.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M006050_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ctr for Nat Health Dev Ethiopia (CNHDE)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">19789.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M006050_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ctr for Nat Health Dev Ethiopia (CNHDE)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FM006050%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-03-03"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
