<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T026979_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of an intervention for improved management of self-reported abnormal vaginal discharge by women in rural north India.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Background: We propose an early phase study to develop an intervention to address the public health issue of self-reported &apos;abnormal vaginal discharge&apos;(AVD), a highly prevalent syndrome worldwide and in South Asia in particular. AVD is a public health concern as it may signal a sexually transmitted infection like gonorrhoea, chlamydia or trichomoniasis, or an endogenous reproductive tract infection like bacterial vaginosis or candida. The World Health organization has advocated use of syndromic management guidelines for AVD (referred to as vaginal discharge syndrome in the syndromic guidelines) which follows a stepwise approach to detect and manage infections in low resource settings where laboratory facilities are unavailable. However it is now accepted that the syndromic approach is a poor predictor of infections, especially the sexually transmitted ones and the flowcharts lead to considerable over treatment with antibiotics.    Moreover in South Asia, there are complex cultural and psychosocial factors associated with the complaint of an AVD. It may be linked with traditional Ayurvedic beliefs about the importance of bodily fluids. AVD signifies the loss of vital bodily fluids resulting from various physical and psychosocial causes like weakness, worry, &apos;melting of bones&apos; and &apos;sexual promiscuity&apos;, as expressed by women in different studies in India, Bangladesh and Sri Lanka. Studies in India and Pakistan have found strong associations between AVD and mental health problems (mostly mild and moderate ones) that could be linked with stress, social conflicts, gender disadvantage, poverty and marital discord that women experience. In fact it has been suggested that AVD is a cultural idiom of distress among women in S.Asia where seeking care for mental health is stigmatised. AVD is a common reproductive complaint of women in India, Bangladesh, Nepal and Sri Lanka, reported by up to 30% women in the general population in India and nearly 50% of pregnant women in Bangladesh. So its management should be a healthcare priority in these settings.  With the availability of (a) Rapid Diagnostics or Point of Care tests for bacterial vaginosis, candida and trichomoniasis, (b) validated tools for mental health screening in primary care setting and (c) proven success of a stepped care model of mental healthcare (in which trained lay health workers provide a basic level of psychosocial counselling to patients with mild mental health problems and doctors and specialists manage the severe cases), the management of AVD in S. Asia calls for a transformation. Our aim in this study is to develop an intervention that integrates these three elements (together with molecular testing for chlamydia and gonorrhoea for those assessed to be at sexual risk) in a novel risk assessment tool or protocol and compare this revised tool with syndromic management in a future trial.     Methods: Using qualitative research methods we will explore AVD perceptions and current practices amongst women in the community and health workers who are most sought by them for AVD. Interviews with other stakeholders in the health system including medical officers, women&apos;s health specialists, mental health experts and laboratory staff will be conducted to understand health system needs with respect to operationalising the laboratory and patient management procedures. Working closely with a small group of selected local experts and health department staff, we will develop the revised assessment tool and  implement this with 20 health workers (identified through consultations with women and health department staff) and 40 women presenting with an AVD, who will be followed up at 3 and 6 months. Their outcomes (self-reported AVD, infections and mental health) will be analysed and a final process evaluation using stakeholder interviews will lead to an outline of a plan for piloting the intervention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The specific objectives of this early phase study are to:  1. Investigate the current knowledge, perceptions and practices related to abnormal vaginal discharge among      women and primary care health workers in rural communities in Tehri Garhwal district.  2. Develop the contents of an intervention including:      - An integrated risk assessment protocol for screening infections and common mental disorders     - Laboratory procedures for rapid tests (point of care tests)     - Management procedures for infections and common mental disorders, based on a stepped care model that         utilises frontline health workers to deliver psychosocial counseling for mild disorders and doctors/specialists to manage the severe cases.   3. Assess the utility and acceptability of the protocol in a cohort of 40 women and analyse the final treatment     outcomes for self-reported abnormal vaginal discharge, infections and common mental disorders.  4. Assess health system readiness for piloting the intervention in a future trial.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133903" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-31">25199.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FQ2 2021-2022 spend on Development of an intervention for improved management of self-reported abnormal vaginal discharge by women in rural north India.</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T026979_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-08">151602.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T026979/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT026979%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
