<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_P013821_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Safe Biodegradable Packaging (SafeBioPack)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective This grant application will underpin an UK-Malaysian &quot;Research and Innovation&quot; bridge to accelerate the deployment of knowledge and the exploitation of research aimed at solutions that will  a) improve the preservation of food during transport/ storage between the producer and the consumer (in urban settings),  b) reduce urban solid waste from plastics going to landfill, and  c) improve health and well being of the population by reducing risk of communicable diseases.  To achieve these objectives, the project will develop innovative sustainable packaging with improved shelf-life performance, that would be recyclable and compostable.  The packaging system will be based on the use of cost-competitive, presently un-used agri-waste (empty fruit bunch from palm, or cereal straw) that will be foamed, and the use of a  new concept, of active packaging - a packaging that interact with food to (in our case) reduce/eliminate pathogen microbial growth, increasing life of packaged food (meat and vegetables). This will reduce food loss across the supply chain. The packaging system will be designed with palm-bunch fibres (non-food agricultural residues) that will be compostable and recyclable, setting-up a platform for other subsequent broader uses , and will contribute to minimising waste-to-landfill problems. The approach will also develop a tool to reduce problems of food poisoning. Consumption of meat, vegetables, ready meals and other foods contaminated with pathogen micro-organisms is considered to be the most common source of food poisoning both in the UK and in Malaysia, reflecting a more general case both in Europe and Asia. The project will use bioactive molecules produced using herbs, sourced from the UK and from Malaysia to coat the packaging and provide antimicrobial properties. This proposal focuses on the issue from both the UK and Malaysian perspective and practices within the industry that will also have wider international relevance and impact.  To deliver this 34 month project, a UK-Malaysian consortium, including technology providers, major commercial businesses, and academic support from both countries has been set-up. The project will seed knowledge exchange between major academic centres and commercial entities in both countries, that will secure post-project activities, contributing as such to the 3 pillars of the Newton Fund (improving capacity in research and science; facilitating research collaboration; and providing innovative solutions to socio-economic problems related with food supply and population growth in the context of accelerated urbanisation and of climate change in Malaysia).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will underpin an UK-Malaysian &quot;Research and Innovation&quot; bridge to accelerate the deployment of knowledge and the exploitation of research that will a) improve the preservation of food during transport/ storage between the producer and the consumer (in urban settings), b) reduce urban solid waste from plastics going to landfill, and c) improve health and well being of the population by reducing risk of communicable diseases transmitted by foodborne pathogens in meat or vegetables. To achieve these objectives, the project will develop innovative sustainable packaging with improved shelf-life performance. The packaging system will be based on the use of cost-competitive, presently un-used agri-waste and the use of a new concept of active packaging; a packaging that will reduce/eliminate pathogen microbial growth, increasing shelf-life of packaged food (meat and vegetables). This will reduce food loss across the supply chain. The packaging system will be designed with agri-waste (palm empty fruit bunch), setting-up a platform for other subsequent broader uses, and will contribute to minimising waste-to-landfill problems.  The approach will develop a tool to reduce problems of food poisoning, as food poisoning. Consumption of meat/vegetables/ready meals spoiled with pathogen micro-organisms is considered to be the most common source of food poisoning both in the UK and in Malaysia, reflecting a more general case both in Europe and Asia. The bioactive molecules will be produced using herbs, sourced from the UK/ or from Malaysia. This proposal focuses on the issue from both the UK and Malaysian perspective and practices within the industry that will also have wider international relevance and impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-20">124939.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-20">250890.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-20">238076.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
