<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007850_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Questioning the form:Re-imagining identities through zine-making in Kampala, Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This follow-on funding proposal&apos;s overall aim is to draw on previous AHRC-funded research on language and identity, (Language as Talisman AHRC grant AH/S003916/1) to create opportunities for marginalised groups to find emergent identities within poetry and art. Working with two organisations, and co-directed by poet Kiconco, the project team aim to develop a new project, focused on zine-making workshops, with poets and artists working in Kampala, Uganda. The organisations are concerned with supporting marginalised women, many of whom have mental health difficulties. Two organisations will collaborate with the PI and the lead artist (Kiconco) to develop a project that explores form, in this case, zinemaking, as a model that can support creative ideas to be articulated within a workshop format culminating in a travelling exhibition. The resulting zines will also be accessed into poetry libraries both locally in East Africa (Mombasa), and in the UK, in Manchester. The two organisations include: ArtVism, a human rights organization supporting women, and StrongMinds, an organisation that supports women&apos;s mental health (https://strongminds.org/). Both organisations place equalities at the heart of what they do. We have identified that zine making offers a potential space of exploration and drawing on previous research on language and identity we will have the following objectives: 1. To work with small groups of up to 10 women drawing on language (poetry) and art as a combined form; with the aim of exploring what each gives to each other, and to produce completed zines after three 4 day workshops (one at the end to complete the work, two at the beginning), each with a different focus and theme; 2. To consider in a new context, the implications of the &apos;Language as Talisman&apos; project with a particular focus on the power of language in particular contexts and to explore the idea of &apos;questioning the form&apos; and what the zine form can give to creative exploration; 3. To develop zines that express or counter particular stories in complex, nuanced ways; 4. To work with networks of poetry libraries world-wide to disseminate these zines and to forge worldwide links with the help of these networks; In order to support the project, we have links with the Kampala Poetry Library via the Ugandan Arts Trust 32 Degrees East Art Gallery and with the African Poetry Book Fund. We will aim to produce zines that are both available on-line and in print. Each group will curate and be in charge of the zine-making and where it goes. An exhibition at the end of the project will be curated by the team in a final workshop, and will becoming a travelling exhibition. A link to the African Poetry Library will bring curation opportunities to the team with a link to a newly created poetry library in Mombasa, Kenya and the zines will also be hosted in Manchester, through the Manchester Poetry Library. StrongMinds will also evaluate the work in relation to its mental health efficacy using its own research processes. Evaluator Lisa Damon will diary the project and put up her reflections in her own visual and poetic zine/catalogue.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project draws on research from a project called &apos;Language as Talisman&apos; that explored how everyday language can be offer opportunities for creative expression. The team is composed of PI Pahl and poet Gloria Kiconco, based in Kampala, Uganda. Kiconco is a published poet and zine maker who has previously run zine workshops for women. Together with artist Charity Atukunda she will work with two organisations to create zine-making workshops. Each workshop will last for 4 days. There will be three workshops in total, two in partnership with the organisations and one in order to prepare for the exhibition. The resulting zines will be displayed in a travelling library, originating in Kampala and disseminated via the African Poetry Fund to a library in Mombasa, and poetry library networks in the UK via the newly created Manchester Poetry Library. The organisation, &apos;StrongMinds&apos; argues on its website that depression is one of the most serious challenges facing African women. Women suffering from depression have very little support (https://strongminds.org/the-need/). Life is particularly hard for those on the margins and women and girls face challenges if they are considered &apos;outsiders&apos; in any sense of the word. This project draws on the idea of the zine, as a form that can be adapted and autonomously used by individuals to express themselves. Zines can be about anything; in this project they will combine poetry and art to be formed in workshops with skilled facilitators Kiconco and Atukunda. Equipping women with life writing and expression skills is a key part of this project. Drawing Artvism&apos;s vision that women in particular need writing skills to equip them in life, the project will place creation and autonomy at the heart of its vision. Our vision is to do that in collaboration with these organisations dedicated to supporting women. The project team includes an evaluator, Lisa Damon, who has experience of working with refugee groups as a researcher, and is currently a doctoral student at the University of Makerere. Gloria Kiconco is the lead in Kampala. She is a published poet, who works closely with arts organisations to realise her zines, which are a mix of poetry and art. She has previously been part of the AHRC funded project on New Enhancements to Enhance Artists&apos; Livelihood in East Africa (PI Andrew Burton). Charity Atukunda is a visual artist who worked with PI Pahl on the AHRC funded &apos;Belonging and Learning&apos; project, which worked with young refugees in Kampala to create art that would directly speak to policy-makers. The team will be led by PI Pahl, drawing on her experience of co-production, and includes Co-Investigator Su Corcoran, who has developed strong links with organisations within Kampala through the &apos;Belonging and Learning&apos; project, and researcher McMillan, a poet, and Kratz, who is working in the field of poetry libraries. The project will create a new travelling library of zines that speak to express the creativity of women through poetry and art.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manchester Metropolitan University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-13">32252.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-13">32252.808</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to Manchester Metropolitan University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007850_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Manchester Metropolitan University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT007850%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-03-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
