<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_P001076_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China&apos;s Creative Communities: Making Value and The Value(s) of Making</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China&apos;s Creative Communities: Making Value and The Value(s) of Making is a four-part cross-disciplinary scoping research project to bring together UK and China partners to network, research, workshop and publically disseminate ideas and innovations around the multi-faceted value of making in China. It aims to strengthen China&apos;s multiple maker communities in partnership with the UK, as part of broader support for China&apos;s creative industries and knowledge economy.  The project results from the British Council/AHRC&apos;s Living Research: Making in China initiative, in which a group of UK academics and makers were immersed in China&apos;s maker culture in October 2015. Initial findings and discussion identified key themes and approaches to develop to further contribute to Living Research&apos;s aims.  China&apos;s Creative Communities take place amidst a growing, but differentiated, emphasis on making in China and the UK. The UK&apos;s first makerspace opened in the 1990s, while China&apos;s first makerspace only opened in 2010. Now China has a rapidly expanding maker movement set to only grow following Premier Li Keqiang&apos;s first visit to a makerspace in Shenzhen in 2015 and the subsequent publication of the Report on the Work of the Government, which identified &apos;makers coming thick and fast&apos; as part of its growing creative industries.  As in the UK, China&apos;s makerspaces vary widely, from self-funded hacker workshops to sites of middle-class leisure. Chinese policy and private investment focus on makerspaces as accelerators and incubators for product innovation. This is most evident in Shenzhen, China&apos;s electronics manufacturing capital, whose readily available manufacturers, materials and componentry has attracted a global community of makers looking to benefit from a production ecosystem largely absent in Europe and the USA. The technology-based innovation focus on makerspaces should be understood amidst economic uncertainty in China over its mass manufacturing future. A concomitant threat to China&apos;s status as the world&apos;s largest producer and economic emphasis on makerspaces tallies with Made in China 2025, the initiative to move its economy up the value chain to focus on design, quality, innovation and sustainability. These are areas of UK expertise potentially valuable in China: the UK has a strong, ever-more socially and sustainably responsible, design culture, and its maker movement is seen as potentially able to encourage a similar ethos.   Despite the excitement and potential for China&apos;s makerspaces, their future is uncertain, with some lacking strong community presence. Yet China also has a strong design and making culture, in other, less supported communities currently seen as external to its maker movement: urban villages; traditional crafts, and shanzhai. Matching China and UK researchers and makers to investigate makerspaces as part of this broader making ecology could offer ways to maximise the social, cultural and economic benefits, and extended values, of making in China.   Overall, this project aims to provide forums for making-based knowledge exchange in the UK and China through which the diverse values of making in China can be explored and enhanced. It will consolidate connections and build new networks between China and UK&apos;s making-related communities and extend the types of values and communities associated with making. We will also use this project to test methods and approaches and identify research questions that will create a foundation for future projects to benefit making communities in China and the UK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The following, interconnected objectives are identified to achieve the aim of strengthening China&apos;s multiple maker communities in partnership with the UK, as part of the UK&apos;s broader support for China&apos;s creative industries and knowledge economy.  Consolidate existing and build new relationships and networks between UK and China. The timetable of activities - the roundtables, workshops, tours and salons in the UK and China - will act as forums for international knowledge exchange, collaboration and dissemination through which the diverse values of making in China can be explored and enhanced. They have the objective of consolidating connections established during Living Research, building new networks between China&apos;s maker communities and UK academics, organisations and practitioners and increase entrepreneurial opportunities for China makers.  Introduce new research perspectives and areas of innovation. The participants involved offer a broad range of cross-disciplinary perspectives, approaches and areas of innovation that will enhance the value of making in China. The project combines academics, makers, entrepreneurs, curators and other related specialists from a variety of backgrounds.  They offer perspectives, knowledge and areas of innovation which have either not been investigated in relation to China&apos;s making communities yet, or not investigated in the internationationally collaborative, cross-disciplinary approaches proposed.  Participants will also introduce areas of innovation, include smart textiles, and guidance on enterprise and innovation more generally, that will benefit China&apos;s makers economically.   Enhance the value of making. The project seeks to enhance the value of making in China and expand the definition of value beyond the purely economic. The project will enhance the cultural, economic, social and sustainable values of making in China, thereby strengthening these communities. This is evident specifically in the &apos;circular economy&apos; workshop (stage 3) and the desire to introduce a more considered and critically engaged making culture.   Enhance recognition of the value of making. In connection with enhancing the value of making in China&apos;s making communities, the research and events proposed will enhance the understanding, visibility and public awareness of China&apos;s maker communities. This heightened &apos;brand&apos; value will strengthen the making communities of makerspaces, but also those currently not supported - such as urban villages, traditional crafts, and shanzhai.  Understand makerspaces as part of a broader community of making in China A key objective is to contextualise China&apos;s makerspaces as part of a broader design and making community.  Specifically, the project will investigate makerspaces in relation to three making communities currently seen as external to China&apos;s maker movement but which are part of China&apos;s broader multi-faceted ecology of making and which are significant to this research agenda: urban villages, traditional crafts and shanzhai. Matching China-based researchers and makers with UK expertise to investigate makerspaces as part of this broader ecology of making could offer more ways to maximise the social, cultural and economic benefits of making in China. This joined-up approach will strengthen these communities individually and collectively.  Enable future research projects.  Scale is key to the objectives and aims: we are expanding the breadth and diversity of making communities prioritised by the Chinese government, and introducing a broader range of disciplinary perspectives and approaches to understanding making in China holistically. Scalability is also integral to the project&apos;s structure, given the limited timescale and resources available. We will test methods of international engagement, networking and dissemination, such as workshops and roundtable discussion formats, creating a foundation for future scaled-up projects to benefit China and UK makers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China (People&apos;s Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-20"></value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
