<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing automated detection and monitoring of peat fires in Indonesia with thermal infrared sensors under drones</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate change presents the single biggest threat to sustainable development across the world. Its widespread, unprecedented impacts disproportionately burden the poorest and most vulnerable. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change concluded it is extremely likely that human influence has been the dominant cause of climate change since the mid-20th century. The global rise in atmospheric concentration of CO2 has been a major driver in the change of climate.  Scientists estimate that peat forest fires can contribute up to 15-20% of all yearly global anthropogenic CO2 emissions -- more than the global transport sector. Currently the severe (dry) conditions leading to these extreme fires occurs roughly every decade, but with climate change their frequency may increase. The annually re-occurring peat forest fires in Indonesia represent a substantial fraction of the global anthropogenic CO2 emissions. Efforts are underway to find and contain the fires, but the challenges faced in achieving this are considerable. For example, to completely extinguish a peat fire with an area of only 1 square meter requires 200-400 litres of water(!). Identifying the precise location of fires when they are small and more easily contained and extinguished is therefore vital. Once a peat fire has become established, it can burn for weeks and is incredibly difficult to extinguish, leading to large areas of forest loss, plantation and property damage, huge carbon emissions, enormous economic losses, and prolonged exposure of local people to toxic haze pollution. This haze, plus the sometimes thick vegetation at fire sights and the fact that peat fires can burn underground, means fire-fighters frequently struggle to ascertain where best to focus their efforts to control the fires, in addition to creating health and safety issues for fire-fighting team members.   Working closely in collaboration with key stakeholders in Indonesia, our pilot study in July 2018 showed that our drone plus thermal infrared camera system can easily identify hot spots in peat fires burning both underground and through the smoke -- current fundamental bottlenecks in stopping the fires. We now propose to use GCRF funding to hire a PDRA to develop our system to achieve automated, real-time detection of above- and below-surface fires on the drone, so that real-time fire detection and monitoring in the field can be achieved. We will train local NGOs, Government partners and local fire-fighting teams in the usage of the system, to facilitate local uptake of the technology and deliver technological knowledge transfer, thus improving longer-term local fire-fighting capacity and reducing the negative impacts associated with these fires. At the end of the funding we aim to: (i) have demonstrated the system&apos;s use in the field during two full fire seasons; (ii) have quantified a significant increase in firefighting efficiency by statistically comparing the extent and duration of the fires tackled with/without the system; and (iii) estimate the resulting long-term reduction in atmospheric CO2 emission and haze (which we estimate will be a factor &gt;10). We will then be in a position to apply for future funding to take the system to fire zones around the world, concentrating on those with the biggest global impact on increasing atmospheric CO2 levels and ill health due to toxic haze.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our fundamental goal is to significantly reduce the extent and duration of peat fires in Indonesia. These fires comprise a significant fraction of annual anthropogenic CO2 emissions -- a main driver of climate change -- and create a toxic haze which, in severe years, seriously affects the health of millions and has caused &gt;100,000 deaths. To achieve our goal, the main objectives of the proposal in order of priority are:    1. Develop a drone plus thermal infrared camera system that can automatically detect above- and below-surface fires and fire-fighters through smoke. These are the current fundamental bottlenecks in controlling and stopping the fires. The system will use Deep Neural Networks, so that real-time fire detection in the field can be achieved.    2. Train local NGOs, Government partners and local fire-fighting teams in the usage and maintenance of the system, to facilitate local uptake of the technology and deliver technological knowledge transfer.    3.Substantially improve long-term, local fire-fighting capacity and reduce the negative impacts associated with these fires. Specifically, at the end of the funding we aim to:        i. have demonstrated the system&apos;s use in the field during two full fire seasons, with increasingly independent use by local fire-fighting teams        ii. have quantified a significant increase in firefighting efficiency by statistically comparing the duration and extent of fires tackled with and without the system       iii. estimate the resulting reduction in atmospheric CO2 emission and toxic haze. We estimate the reduction will be at least a factor of 10.     4. We will then be in a position to apply for future funding to extend the fire monitoring system to fire zones around the world, concentrating on those with the biggest global impact on atmospheric CO2 levels and toxic haze.  The innovations needed to achieve these objectives come from science, technology and expertise developed through the STFC core Science Astrophysics Programme. Over the last few decades STFC has invested heavily in thermal-infrared astronomy. For example, the UK Astronomy Technology Centre has played a key role in building the Michelle camera for UKIRT and Gemini, the MIRI (Mid InfraRed Instrument) camera for the James Webb Space Telescope, and is involved in the planned METIS (Mid-Infrared E-ELT Imager and Spectrograph) instrument for the European Extremely Large Telescope. Our project uses data reduction, source detection and analysis software developed to extract science from this thermal-infrared astronomy data, but now with the &quot;telescope&quot; pointing back towards Earth, rather than into space. We have demonstrated that this STFC-funded astrophysics software developed by astronomers to detect emission and identify objects in thermal infrared wavelength astronomical images is extremely well suited to identifying and characterising the properties of fires in aerial thermal video footage.  Our previous work towards the long-term objectives -- adapting astrophysics expertise to help tackle problems facing humanity in the 21st Century -- has been funded through STFC grants ST/R002673/1 (Astro-ecology: the solution from the skies to save Earth&apos;s biodiversity) and ST/P003273/1 (Astrophysics meets conservation biology) and the host institution (Liverpool John Moores University) provided &#xA3;20k of pump-priming funds from its Research England QR GCRF allocation for the PI and Co-Is to conduct a pilot study to adapt the astro-ecology drone system to detecting peat fires in Indonesia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-18">180078.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-18">181536.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">45019.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">45019.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">45019.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">45019.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">45384.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">45384.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">45384.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S00288X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
