<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N029097_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding the mechanisms for the variation in beneficial effects of dietary fibre in Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS): an old concept in new light</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IBS is a major, growing public health problem affecting 10-15% of adults worldwide. The profound morbidity places a huge financial burden on individuals, the healthcare system and the workplace. For example, Mexicans with IBS on average spend 20% of their income on IBS-related medical expenses, are 50% more likely to report increased medical visits and have a 3-fold greater risk of absenteeism. Pharmaceutical and dietary interventions have some efficacy in IBS, although the latter encourage self-management. More recently dietary management has focussed on dietary restriction (e.g. the low FODMAP diet), but the limitations of these include physiological sequelae (e.g. impaired nutrient intake, altered gut bacteria) as well as the complexity of advice, access to dietitians and comprehensibility (e.g. people with low literacy). Dietary approaches to manage IBS that are easy to implement and inexpensive, therefore widely applicable across socio-economic and ethnic groups are required - a challenge this proposal aims to address.   In recent years, our understanding of dietary fibre has progressed considerably uncovering potential therapeutic opportunities applicable in IBS. At present national and international guidelines provide limited and often conflicting recommendations regarding fibre supplementation in IBS. These guidelines are based upon trials of dietary fibre in IBS symptoms that report opposing effects reflecting four key issues that this proposal addresses: (1) variations in the types of fibres used in historic trials, which due to out-dated crude classification of dietary fibre were not supported physiological actions; (2) our limited understanding of the physiological and functional impacts of different fibres specifically in IBS; (3) limited investigation of the physiological effects of novel fibres or the co-administration of different fibres; and (4) variations in the physiology of different sub-types of IBS (i.e. IBS-D, IBS-C). Given these limitations, we believe the therapeutic potential of dietary fibre as a low-cost management strategy is underexploited  In order to gain a robust understanding of the fibre characteristics that may offer therapeutic benefit for IBS this research will consist of two studies investigating the acute (Study 1) and longer-term (Study 2) physiological and therapeutic effects of fibres in IBS.  Study 1 will explore how artificial dietary fibre combinations (resistant starch + psyllium) and naturally occurring combinations (nopal, a native crop to Mexico) (informed by our team of experts in carbohydrate chemistry, gut physiology and gut microbiology) affect gut physiology (e.g. colonic gas production) using non-invasive MRI techniques. This will provide unique insight into underlying mechanisms of action, tolerances and variations in response both between different fibres and within IBS subtypes. These key principles will be used to guide selection of an optimal dietary fibre formulation as well as the most responsive sub-type of IBS to inform a 2-month clinical trial (Study 2).  Study 2 will aim to assess the longer-term microbiological and physiological effects of dietary fibre supplementation and whether this translates into symptom relief in IBS. This study will be undertaken in both the UK and Mexico IBS populations exploring specific impacts of the selected fibres on fundamental mechanisms including gut microbiota and gut transit time using the latest sequencing and gastrointestinal motility technology, respectively. In addition, this study will translate several novel mechanisms, based on experimental work, to gain a better understanding of how dietary fibre may exert a benefit. Lastly, study 2 will investigate whether a non-invasive diagnostic model developed by our group can be used to identify IBS patients most likely to respond to dietary fibre, which, if successful will help better characterise the IBS population and pave the way towards personalised treatment plans.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1: To determine the optimal dietary fibre formulations (based upon tolerance and fermentability) and target population based on variations in response to dietary challenge (Study 1). This will be achieved by exploring the effect of different types and combinations (artificial, naturally-occurring) of dietary fibre on GI physiology using MRI and patient-reported symptoms in IBS-D and IBS-C.  Rationale: Considering the potential for some types of dietary fibre to manage IBS symptoms and address the microbial dysbiosis, which is likely involved in its pathogenesis, there is a desperate need to better understand the physiology of fibre metabolism in IBS. More specifically, insight into the mechanisms underpinning tolerance and fermentation patterns (colonic gas production) of different fibres is necessary to build a scientifically robust rationale behind fibre selection to inform intervention studies (Study 2). This is fundamental to overcoming limitation of previous fibre interventions in IBS, such as poor tolerance and limited mechanistic rationale underpinning fibre selection.  Objective 2: To investigate  the longer-term microbiological and physiological effects of dietary fibres in IBS (Study 2), specifically: a) Impact on the gut microbiota and their metabolism. Rationale: The altered gut microbiota (dysbiosis) plays a key role in IBS. Certain types of fibre increase the growth of Bifidobacteria and suppress Firmicutes, which addresses the dysbiosis reported in IBS. Further to this, fibre may affect the gut microbiota and their metabolism (fermentation e.g. short-chain fatty acids SCFA) through its effect on gut transit and therefore the rate of delivery of fermentable compounds to the colon. Given this, comparison between the different types and combinations (artificial, naturally-occurring) of dietary fibres and how they impact the gut microbiota and their metabolism will increase understanding of mechanisms of action in vivo.  b) Whole gut transit time and motility variance. Rationale: Abnormal whole gut transit time is often found in IBS, which some types of fibre may normalise. However, the direction of the required effect varies depending on IBS subtypes (i.e. IBS-D, IBS-C), which are often merged in clinical trials. Moreover, the effect of dietary fibre and its fermentation (e.g. gas, SCFA) on colonic motility patterns is ill explored in IBS sub-types and likely responsible for variations in the effectiveness previously reported.   Objective 3: To investigate the effectiveness of dietary fibre on symptoms in IBS to inform clinical practice guidelines (Study 1 and 2). Rationale: Current clinical guidelines regarding dietary fibre in IBS are both limited and conflicting reflecting the low quality evidence in this area. There is a real need for a well-designed dietary fibre intervention based on a fibre formulation that is supported by a scientifically robust rationale with due consideration for carbohydrate chemistry, gut physiology and gut microbiology. Translation of strategies such as co-administration (mixed fibre interventions) to increase tolerance whilst maximising the impact on gut physiology (microbiota, transit) and therefore maximise therapeutic potential are warranted.   Objective 4: To identify whether faecal volatile organic compounds (VOC) can predict variations in response to dietary fibre intervention in IBS (Study 2). Rationale: VOC provide unique insight into the functionality of the gut microbiota, complementing microbiota analysis. Our team has recently developed a computer algorithm that identifies resistance patterns to differentiate IBS patients from healthy controls using faecal VOC. Further to this, preliminary data suggests the algorithm could be applied in dietary intervention studies the goal to increase our understanding of variations in responses (ie. differentiate at baseline those who will respond and not respond).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-06" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1032" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-09">403980.94</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Newton Fund Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N029097/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN029097%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-08-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
