<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006299_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Constructions of Public Office  (HN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project starts from the understanding that public office is not a single thing, but is understood in different ways, comes with different expectations and responsibilities, and is seen as serving different purposes, in different contexts.    In Britain between the 16th and 19th centuries a distinctive conception of public office emerged which involved stripping away a number of features that had previously been central features of office - in relation to how they were appointed, the duties they carried out, the boundaries between the interests of the occupant and the interests of the office, the criteria by which they were evaluated, how they were held accountable, and what purposes they were seen as fulfilling within the state.  The British conception of public office is still evolving (the Law Commission is currently in the middle of an inquiry into malfeasance), and it is far from universal, differing markedly in certain respects from both US and European models.  One major area of variation is how the line between public and political office is drawn, if at all.  Yet the idea that we can use a standard model to identify and eliminate dereliction of public office in the less developed world is a widespread mantra of the anti-corruption and development movement.  Moreover, the suggestion seems to be that derilictions are essentially similar, and that standards can be made the same.  That view has driven a multi-billion anti-corruption movement over the last 20 years, although this has not been notable for its successes.   This project seeks to take seriously the different national and local contexts that have shaped how office has evolved and is regarded today. It takes three countries, Britain, Mexico and Kenya, with different traditions and practices and seeks to create a dialogue between them, not only so that British development policy might better address issues of governance and better understand the issues affecting office in these countries, but also, through discussion of the British experience, to examine how improved forms of governance and administration that have purchase on local mentalities and habits of mind and practice can be facilitated.  Comparative research on different constructions of public office - how they have emerged, how they are understood, how they are legitimated and when office holders are seen as falling short - is rare.  There is a tendency to assume both a universal standard, and to assume that there will be a single understanding of office in any particular context, whereas it is likely to be the case that a number of competing constructions operate in many contexts, perhaps especially in ex-colonial contexts.  It is, then, a necessary step to understand the expectations and norms that operate and to appreciate the way that particular conceptions of office might be more or less dysfunctional in certain contexts.  What now seem to us to be obvious norms of office in fact developed over a long period, in quite specific local contexts, and often in response to pressing local exigencies. We should not expect the emergence of conceptions of office in other contexts to short-circuit such processes in their entirety, or to end up in the same place. But we might hope that bringing these different experiences into dialogue with each other will have beneficial outcomes for all concerned, creating an approach that seeks less to castigate developing countries for failing to conform within a very short space of time to British or Western norms and does more in the way of encouraging a productive and practical process of thinking how, in the light of certain ideals and restraints, public office can best be configured in relation to local contexts. The project seeks to move discussion away from a focus purely on corruption (which can often be used as a politicized stick) to maximizing good governance in context, and from bribery to the proper benefits of public office.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-04">42460.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The project aims to improve understanding of what constitutes good office-holding in different international contexts. It seeks, through critical reflection on local traditions and practices, to find a basis for tools that can provide the basis for local training and can militate against the more damaging forms of malfeasance.   The project seeks to explore the historical development of ideas and practices of public office-holding in three countries, Britain, Mexico and Kenya (two countries on the OECD Development Assistance Committee&apos;s list of ODA Recipients) and to bring these different traditions into dialogue with one another. Such dialogue is a essential first step towards thinking about how conduct by office-holders can be opened up to change or development in ways that fit with other social, cultural and political commitments within each society. Too often aid and development programmes are caught up with western assumptions about how office and responsibilities should be exercised, but are applying them in contexts in which they have very little purchase and as a result have little impact. This project seeks to find ways in which developed countries might better understand and respond to different traditions in developing countries.  Bringing the experience of Britain into the picture as a contrast is designed to help us think about how questions of governance and administration might be developed in ways that will have purchase on local mentalities and habits of mind and practice. The aim is to bring academics from these countries into dialogue with politicians, civil society bodies, policy makers and those training public officials and to influence the training that these societies provide for those holding public office. We focus discussion on public office and its understanding because this provides a relatively neutral arena for debate, in contrast to, for example, focusing on bribery and corruption.  More broadly the project&apos;s objectives address the UN Sustainable Development Goals, and in particular Goal 16 to &apos;build effective, accountable and inclusive institutions&apos;. The objective of Goal 16.5 is to &apos;substantially reduce corruption and bribery in all their forms&apos;; Goal 16.6 to &apos;develop effective, accountable and transparent institutions at all levels&apos;; Goal 16.7 to &apos;ensure responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative decision-making at all levels&apos;; Goal 16.a to &apos;strengthen relevant national institutions, including through international cooperation, for building capacity at all levels&apos;; Goal 16.b to &apos;promote and enforce non-discriminatory laws and policies for sustainable development&apos;. Goal 17.5 aims to &apos;respect each country&apos;s policy space and leadership to establish and implement policies for ... sustainable development&apos;. The aim of integrating a cultural and historical approach with a development one also reflects UNESCO&apos;s conclusion that &apos;placing culture at the heart of development policies constitutes an essential investment in the world&apos;s future and a precondition to successful globalization processes that take into account the principle of cultural diversity&apos;.  The project is a pilot project that seeks to test an approach that might, if successful, be widened to other national contexts.  It will produce a report summarizing its chief findings, training materials for each of the participant states, and it will seek to disseminate this to a wide audience in order to stimulate further debate and policy development.  The project &apos;team&apos; in addition to the PI and CI includes Warwick History Department members - Prof David Anderson and Prof Dan Branch, both major Kenyan modern history experts, and Prof Mark Knights, currently writing a history of corruption in Britain from 1600-1850.  The whole team will be involved in setting up the three events using their connections to bring in partners in the UK and in Mexico and Kenya, and in the execution of the events."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">42460.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006299_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">5072.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006299_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
