<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015104_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Towards controlling antimicrobial resistance in global aquatic animal food systems by enhancing collective resilience (AMFORA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aquatic animals such as fish and shellfish are an increasingly important source of protein for the growing world population. In 2014 the contribution of aquaculture to supply food for human consumption overtook that for wild-caught fish for the first time. Fish diseases are still considered to be a major constraint to aquaculture globally and it has been estimated that 10% of all farmed aquatic animals are lost because of infectious diseases alone, amounting to &gt;10 billion USD in losses annually on a global scale. Farmed fish are often kept in intensive systems where antibiotics are heavily used. Effective vaccines exist for use in Atlantic salmon aquaculture and the use of antibiotics has been reduced by over 99%. In comparison, although many other species (e.g. carp and tilapia) are well established cultured species, there are few vaccines available, and antibiotics are still heavily used. Aquatic animals are increasingly traded worldwide, partly due to growing awareness for balanced diets and healthy eating in high-income countries and as a vital source of quality animal protein in low and middle income countries (LMIC). This creates opportunities and supports livelihoods in countries such as Bangladesh, Egypt and Vietnam, that together contribute to 9% of the global aquaculture production.  Despite the importance of antibiotic use in aquaculture and the size of the global trade, the contribution of aquaculture to the burden of consumer exposure to antibiotic resistance genes is currently not being addressed. Reasons why this issue is currently not been tackled include; i) the complexity of global food systems that involve different actors (producers, suppliers, intermediaries) spanning different countries across the world, ii) the lack of knowledge of the so called &quot;drivers&quot; of resistance in aquatic systems (i.e. the influences, e.g. through animal husbandry and farm management, that result in the emergence of resistance in bacteria) and, iii) the fragmented responsibilities in global food systems. However, it is important that antibiotic resistance in aquaculture is addressed as a global issue, because hazards emerging in producer countries will have public impact on consumers elsewhere through global trade and travel. Also, opportunities to learn from progress made in European fish farming remain underexploited. To address this complex challenge we need innovative research strategies that combine different disciplines and approach the system as a whole rather than its individual components in isolation. Our plan for the full proposal stage is to apply research methods that allow us to integrate societal, legal, governance and economic drivers in addition to biological risk, creating new approaches to better describe, analyse and assess the resilience of a global food system. In the first phase of the project, two workshops will be conducted to develop the model framework and plan the activities for the second phase. These workshops together with a review of published studies, reports and interviews with key stakeholders will allow us to map the different components of the system, the drivers, responsibilities and governance and to identify knowledge gaps for the main project. Our focus will be on selected fish species farmed in Bangladesh, Vietnam and Egypt, all of which are traded internationally. In the full-stage proposal, intervention strategies to reduce antibiotic use will be developed and implemented and their impact assessed using novel approaches. Our aspiration is that this project increases risk awareness for consumers, enhances surveillance and develops a novel set of indicators of system resilience in the context of antibiotic resistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our vision for the full proposal is to apply innovative, multidisciplinary, systems-based research to implement and evaluate strategies that have the potential of reducing vulnerability of the global fish farming system to the threat of antibiotic resistance. In the development phase we will establish robust foundations for these activities working with strategic partners (World Fish, FAO, ILRI) in 3 low and middle income countries (LMIC) that contribute to 9% of global aquaculture production: Bangladesh, Egypt and Vietnam. The specific objectives of the development award are: 1) To map key drivers of antibiotic usage in fish farming systems in LMIC using  Bangladesh, Egypt and Vietnam as case-studies. 2) To identify ways in which drivers of antibiotic usage impact on resistance development and global public health.  3) To develop a framework suitable to assess resilience of of the fish farming system and the potential impacts of antibiotic usage and resistance development.  4) To identify key knowledge gaps that currently preclude assessment of the consequences of antibiotic usage in fish farming and resistance development.  5) To identify interventions with the potential of enhancing resilience of the fish farming system to the threat of antibiotic resistance.  6) To identify shortcomings in the current surveillance systems of Bangladesh, Egypt and Vietnam and propose a model for risk-based surveillance and risk indicators for antibiotic resistance emergence and spread in global aquatic food systems. Successful completion of the development stage will therefore allow us to develop a focused, realistic and ambitious full proposal that could eventually increase risk awareness for consumers, enhance context-specific surveillance and develop and apply a novel set of indicators of fish-farming system resilience in the context of antibiotic resistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-03">49042.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">49042.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015104_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Veterinary College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">27678.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015104_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Veterinary College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
