<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T030569_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of next generation anti-malarials targeting the essential parasite protein kinase PfCLK3</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Despite the success of initiatives such as roll back malaria which have distributed millions of insecticide-impregnated bed nets and effective drug treatments for malaria including artemisinin combination therapies malaria still affects over 200 million people worldwide and is the cause of nearly 0.5 million deaths per annum. These figures alone might be enough to justify continued efforts to find new malaria drug treatments but more alarmingly is the fact that resistance to the current frontline treatments is now emerging which means that we are in a race to develop the next generation of drugs. This grant is designed as a pre-clinical drug discovery programme. The aim is to develop early stage drugs that can offer the potential of curing the symptoms of malaria but also importantly to prevent transmission of malaria from one person to another. The way that drugs are developed against malaria is to have the backing and support of key malaria drug discovery organisations. This includes the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, Medicines for Malaria Venture (MMV) and the Malaria Drug Accelerator (MalDa). It is through these organisations that drugs are ultimately developed for clinical trails. This grant is aimed at generating novel molecules that can then be used by these organisations to develop into drugs that can be tested in patients. We will do this by screening hundreds of thousands of compounds to discover molecules that inhibit our target protein called PfCLK3. We already know that molecules that inhibit the protein PfCLK3 rapidly kill the malaria parasite in a way that leads us to believe that drugs can be developed that target this protein. Once we have discovered molecules that inhibit PfCLK3 and kill the parasites we will develop these so-called hits to have properties that are necessary if they are to be effective and safe drugs. At the end of the grant we aim to have developed these hits to a sufficient extent to be fed into the MMV/Gates drug development pipeline. Such a programme is described as a hit to lead drug discovery programme and is an essential phase before further development of the lead compounds to drug candidates that can be used in trials on patients.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We previously established that 36 of the 65 eukaryotic parasite protein kinases encoded in the genome of the most virulent form of the human malaria parasite P. falciparum were essential for blood stage survival. Among these kinases were all four members of the cyclin-dependent like (CLK) protein kinase family (PfCLK1-4). This family is closely related to the human CLK and the serine-arginine-rich (SR) protein kinase families that are mediators of phosphorylation events on splicing factors necessary for the correct assembly/catalytic activity of spliceosomes.  We reasoned that inhibitors against one or more members of the PfCLK family would disrupt splicing and kill the parasite. Through a Tres Cantos Open Lab Foundation award we screened ~25K compounds against PfCLK3 and discovered a variety of structurally distinct inhibitors selective for this kinase. We prioritised a series exemplified by TCMDC-135051 which showed nM inhibitory potency for PfCLK3 whilst showing no activity at the human orthologue PRPF4B  and very little activity at the closely related human protein kinase CLK2. Importantly, molecules in this series also showed potent sub micro-molar parasiticidal activity against the asexual blood stage of P. falciparum.   Using TCMDC-135051 we employed adaptive resistance coupled with whole genome sequencing, chemogenetics, micro-RNA arrays, in vitro and in vivo molecular parasitology and insect transmission experiments to validate PfCLK3 as a target with curative, transmission blocking and prophylactic potential. These data are now published in Science1.  Here we plan to continue this work in a programme aimed at generating a lead molecule and back up series that meet the criteria set by Medicines for Malaria Venture (MMV) for an Early Lead for development to a Clinical Candidate. We will do this by delivering on three objectives; 1. Conduct hit to lead development on our current front-runner, TCMDC-135051 Building on our excellent in vitro PfCLK3 kinase assay (in 384 and 1536 well format (Z&apos;&gt;0.8) and an already established structural activity relationship (see; ChemxRvii https://chemrxiv.org/s/fe5a13c85804d242cd59) and aided by structural based drug design we will conduct medicinal chemistry to build further potency and selectivity into TCMDC-135051.     2. Screen for novel chemical matter and develop in a hit to lead campaign Although our current front-runner (TCMDC-135051) has high potential for development it will be essential to generate back up hits representing alternative scaffolds. Supported by screens at the European Lead Factor (ELF) and a focused hinge binder screen at the Dundee Drug Discovery Unit we will use our high throughput PfCLK3 assay to screen for new chemical matter. The ELF screen together with hit evaluation and resynthesis will be funded by the ELF (not by this grant). Hinge binder screen and hit to lead development will be funded by this grant.  3. Test front running molecules for properties that meet MMV criteria for subsequent Lead to Candidate optimisation. Since the aim of this programme is to generate Early Lead compounds that meet the Target Candidate Profiles set by MMV we will test front-runners emerging from objectives 1 and 2 in a range of parasite assays, in vivo mouse models and technology platforms (including CRISPA-parasites) in collaboration with MMV and the Malaria Drug Accelerator - these technologies/assays will be made available at no cost to the grant. We will also conduct DMPK and selectivity screens in a work flow that will build further desirable properties that meet MMVs criteria for development to a clinical candidate.  This highly collaborative grant draws together leading malaria drug discovery resources and expertise together with MRC funding in a programme designed to generate an Early Lead that would be subsequently fed into the MMV/Gates pipeline for Lead to Candidate development.  1. Alam et al. Science 365, eaau1682 (2019).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gambia (the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-11">688272.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T030569/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT030569%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
