<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_R003521_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">REhabilitation of Vibrio Infested waters of VembanAd Lake: pollution and solution (REVIVAL)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To identify the principal reservoirs of Vibrio cholerae and pathogenic viruses in Vembanad Lake. We will determine through in situ sampling if the Vibrio bacteria are associated mainly with particular types of phytoplankton, zooplankton, macrophytes or the surficial sediments, and the dependence of the reservoirs on environmental conditions (temperature, salinity, light). Here we would deploy specially-developed hyperspectral sensors mounted on drones in support of remote sensing, and carry out detailed analyses of water and sediment samples for bacterial flora, phytoplankton types and zooplankton types. 2. Assess the seasonal and spatial variation in the hosts/reservoirs of pathogenic Vibrios employing remote-sensing and in situ methods, and explore similar methods for viruses. The spatial distribution and seasonality of the Vibrio pools will be established using results from Obj. 1, using remote sensing and citizen science data to extrapolate point observations to the scale of the whole lake.  3. Use laboratory and modelling studies to assess conditions that induce virulence and proliferation of Vibrios.Vibrio are present throughout the year in Vembanad Lake, but outbreaks of cholera are irregular and sporadic. A combination of laboratory studies and mathematical modelling (including bioinformatical, statistical and epidemic modelling) will be used to establish the range of conditions under which outbreaks are likely to occur. It is believed that in the vicinity of the lake, low-level cholera is a chronic affliction of people in some localities, outside the times of epidemics. We will examine the validity of this belief and the relevant environmental conditions. 4. To present the results of the work in geo-referenced form and use them in mathematical models to forecast potential outbreaks of cholera. Having the results in the form of a map will enhance their utility to policy makers and regulators responsible for reconciling the competing interests in Vembanad Lake. Provision of cholera forecasts would be a great help to the public health sector. 5. Implement Awareness programmes on pathogenic Vibrios and viruses and make recommendations to responsible parties for preventing cholera and other outbreaks; for design of a rational monitoring system; and for drafting of related legislation. Though the Vembanad Lake is of undisputed economic and cultural importance, there is no consolidated effort at governmental levels to monitor the pollution in the entire lake or to undertake remedial action. In fact, the highest interest in lake revival has been shown by the local population, whose livelihood depends on the lake. We propose to build on such grass-root interest, informing the local people through their engagement in citizen science, community meetings and articles in local newspapers, of the threats posed by poor water quality and how they might be eradicated. We can expect an overall enhancement of public health and a consolidation of the tourist industry centered on the lake, such that the revenue from tourism, important for Kerala and all India, will continue and increase in future years, instead of diminishing through further progressive deterioration of water quality. Involvement of those who live around the lake is seen as key to spurring remedial action at the municipal and state levels. As a group, the people of Vembanad Lake are at home on the water, which is part of their cultural heritage. We propose that they be involved in the monitoring program by deploying, on their regular transits of the lake, equipment that we have designed and prototyped which would be produced in numbers and made available to the citizens at no charge, in return for their help. The measurements could be made daily by many tourist operators and used as part of the environmental characterization of the lake. Their value to the project wouldbe explained to the public through a series of open meetings conducted in the local language.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">REVIVAL is a project addressing the water quality in Vembanad Lake , the largest water body in Kerala, draining 40% of its surface area and holding 30% of its surface water resource. Some 1.6 million people live around its shores. Its fishing and farming communities  follow traditional ways of life; it is a cultural icon of India. Tourism there contributes strongly to state and central revenues. But Vembanad is highly polluted. The inhabitants are not assured of access to water that is safe for drinking and bathing. In this proposal, we will study the risk to public health from biological pollution in the lake. We will examine how pollution affects health, and how it might lower performance in the workplace, cause loss of revenue, and lower quality of life, threatening orderly and sustainable economic development of the region. Scientists from India and the UK will join forces to study microbiological pollution in the lake to understand the conditions that allow pathogens to proliferate in the lake.  They will find the major point sources of biological contamination in the lake. They will ascertain the organisms in the lake with which the pathogens are associated, how pathogens move within the lake, how their number changes with season, how they infect people, and the environmental conditions under which their virulence is expressed. Data will be collected in the field and by instruments carried on satellites in Earth orbit, as well as by instruments mounted on miniature drones, allowing. Detailed and extensive measurements with daily repetition and observations in places that would otherwise be dangerous to reach. Mathematical modelling will help integration and understanding of the observations, suggest actions for remediation of water quality and reduction of risk to public health, and provide a capability to forecast times and localities vulnerable to disease outbreaks. The results will help the team to design a rational protocol for monitoring water quality in the lake after the project is completed and recommend procedures for water quality remediation. Scientists will advise regulators, environmental managers and above all, the local community on policy actions that will help to maintain good water quality into the foreseeable future. Indian and UK scientists will teach young Indian scientists how to use these methods to address similar problems elsewhere. A key activity will be the engagement of stakeholders (local communities, economic interests, civil servants) in the planning, execution, and interpretation of the work and translation of the results into action. There will be public awareness meetings at the outset, building on grass-roots initiatives already under way in the community. The project will have a citizen science component in which members of the community will be supplied with novel but inexpensive, simple but effective equipment to monitor water quality properties (temperature and turbidity). The measurements will increase the spatial coverage and frequency of the observations.. The citizen scientists will be informed about the significance of their results, how they help to understand the dynamics of water quality in the lake (including the dynamics of the epidemics) and how that might be translated into evidence-based action for lake restoration. Improving the water quality in Vembanad Lake will provide a solid foundation for augmentation of public health and welfare, an essential step in improving quality of life and securing a sustainable economic development of Kerala. Involving the general public, as well as economic and administrative interests, will ensure that proposed solutions for lake restoration have a high probability of being implemented, such that economic growth can proceed hand in hand with maintenance of traditional life styles of fishing and farming communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plymouth Marine Laboratory</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-22">37784.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-22">151442.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-22">152669.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-22">76797.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-22">11884413.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to Plymouth Marine Laboratory</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_R003521_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plymouth Marine Laboratory</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FR003521%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
