<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003537_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Informed mining: risk reduction through enhanced public and institutional risk awareness (IM AWARE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lax governance policies allow poor business practices which can lead to dramatic disasters and shocking fatalities. In reaction to the consequent public outcry, legislation tightens governance policies. There have been countless examples of this cycle, including laws resulting from boiler explosions, drug scams, and events such as the Johnstown flood. We must short-circuit this upward spiral so it does not require the fatalities to drive it forward. Scientifically grounded multistakeholder governance has been proposed as a scheme to accomplish this, but little empirical evidence shows it is useful, especially in the context of countervailing economic forces and entrenched interests. Despite the enhanced awareness with several recent high-profile mine tailings dam disasters, mine operators and site workers do not practice good risk management. Several factors have been proposed including a lack of trust and fear of reprisal. This is exacerbated by failed efforts to reduce the vulnerability of communities through relocation of settlements, which are usually met with suspicious protests. A general climate of fear is precipitated by the misconception that risk management is counterproductive to economic competitiveness.  The project explores the beliefs of stakeholders constructed because of dominating actors, cultural factors, and the local context. Interviews will explore individual perceptions of risk and their implications for the co-development of mitigation strategies. The results will inform the multistakeholder workshops, each convened to address specific challenges relating to participatory management. Participant experience will be evaluated, as will approaches for communication and the role of science in this interaction. Sociocultural metrics for (i) risk neglect, (ii) low propensity to trust, (iii) distance to power (empowerment and social responsibility), and (iv) short-termism/commodity mentality will also be evaluated in the initial interviews and throughout the project. This creates an evidence base for the efficacy of multistakeholder governance models for mine tailings storage. Applying this across two case studies at different sites will evidence the adaptive capacity of the approach, and justification for its adoption across Brazil. A problem in participatory management is information asymmetry. Science can assuage this problem and provide a context for discussion and common decision making.  The project will evaluate the effect of risk awareness on motivating near-term engineering interventions (e.g., decanting, pipe draining, etc.) and directing long-term construction and business practices of the industry that will reduce deaths and other risks suffered by economically disadvantaged vulnerable downstream populations, and preventing destruction of agricultural lands and the environment generally. The work will seek to demonstrate risk awareness does not threaten but can enhance economic competitiveness, addressing disaster management and sustainable development, even for mining operations, by sustaining mine operations, improving health of workers, reducing adverse impacts on workforce, reducing legal liabilities from dam failures and leachate releases, and forestalling legislative and regulatory strictures. The interests of mine owners and at-risk communities are not commonly seen as aligned. However, using science as the medium for identifying common interests, the project will create an evidence base addressing the efficacy of different schemes in efforts to reduce information asymmetry and, particularly, the use of scientific analysis to enhance risk awareness and communication which are fundamental to participatory management. The project&apos;s empirical results will be broadly relevant to other implementations of multistakeholder governance schemes, and its specific software developments are directly applicable to stability of water dams and landslides which are among the deadliest hazards.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project&apos;s objectives were co-developed with our colleagues in three major Brazilian universities, the Brazilian regulator for mining, the regulator for the oil and gas industry, the association of risk and reliability assessors in Brazil, and a leading think tank in Latin America.  In increasing order of priority, the objectives of the project are to 1. Develop and validate near-real time monitoring tools to identify dam structural performance under changing conditions and quantify the relative likelihoods of dam failures with sound scientific methods;  2. Develop and validate software tools to quantify the impact of tailings dam failure along all dimensions of exposure including the immediate threat to life, long-term human health, and environmental damage; 3. Engage with Brazilian regulatory authorities to implement and deploy these tools on their data collection platform. The tools will support planning and regulatory actions based on ranked risks to humans and local environments from mine tailings dams, and enhance the capacity of the regulator to scrutinise mine operations with independent analysis; 4. Facilitate multistakeholder governance of mine tailings storage by organising collaborations and making the results of the scientific risk analyses accessible to all stakeholders, focusing on the marginalised and at-risk, leading to a social licence for mining operations (UNEP 2017; Golder 2016); and, most importantly, 5. Helping to empower at-risk communities to actively engage with the risk-reduction agenda by enhancing transparency to recognise their own risks, reducing information asymmetry, and identifying and tackling the social, cultural, organizational, and individual factors hampering on-site/at-work risk awareness, and understanding the perspectives of different stakeholders (Migueles 2007; Bowker 2011). These objectives support the project&apos;s greater goals to A. Reduce the severity of disasters through cooperation to strengthen disaster risk planning and preparedness, accounting for specific local characteristics with site-specific scientific modeling using local geographic and demographic data, B. Facilitate shared responsibilities between national authorities, operators and other stakeholders to support inclusive decision making and empower local communities with accessible science and decision-making responsibilities, and C. Gather an evidence base about the efficacy of the multistakeholder governance approach to resolving a regulatory crisis, and the use of science in shared decision making and disaster planning. The project is aligned with the Sendai framework (UNISDR 2015) and addresses all four of its priority areas. Objective 1 and especially objective 2 seek to improve &quot;understanding of disaster risks&quot; (Sendai priority 1) at mining sites in Brazil in all dimensions of vulnerability of people, assets and the environment for risk assessment, prevention, mitigation, preparedness and response. Through objective 3 this research will enact policy, and objective 4 will create a partnership in the multistakeholder scheme to address Sendai priority 2, to &quot;strengthen disaster risk governance&quot; by fostering collaboration and equitable partnerships. The proposed GCRF project is a significant &quot;investment in disaster risk reduction for resilience&quot; (priority 3), which is augmented by investments from the Brazilian regulators ANM, ANP, the Brazilian university PUC-Rio, and the University of Liverpool, which together are financially supporting five PhDs aligned to the project. This proposal is in response to the recent dreadful disaster and the shift in public sentiment in Brazil. Now is an opportune time for GCRF funding to &quot;enhance disaster preparedness and build back better&quot; (priority 4). Brazil is in a &quot;reconstruction phase [after these disasters; this] is a critical opportunity to build back better&quot;, creating infrastructure that will help to reduce the severity and prevent disasters in future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-08">155506.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-08">224641.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-08">69694.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-08">69694.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-08">866331.608</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003537_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT003537%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
