<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Identification of specific metabolites in mycolactone producing mycobacteria and Buruli ulcer infection: diagnostic biomarkers through metabolomic</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Buruli ulcer is a severe, slow progressing skin infection which destroys tissue and is caused by bacteria found in the environment called Mycobacterium ulcerans. The disease is classified as a neglected tropical disease despite being described in over 30 countries including Ghana, Togo, Benin, C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire, Cameroon, Mexico, Papua New Guinea, South East Asia and Australia, and mostly affects individuals in rural communities living in infected areas. The World Health Organisation&apos;s Global Buruli Ulcer Initiative has identified the development of simple diagnostic tools as one of the priority areas in the control of the disease. Metabolomics is a growing field in analytical science and biology which seeks to identify novel biomarkers that can distinguish between diseased and non-diseased individuals. In a pilot study, funded under the Cambridge-Africa Partnership for Research Excellence (CAPREx), we sought to determine the best types of sample for the identification of metabolites from the bacteria  that can be found only in Buruli ulcer patients. We collected tissue biopsy, swabs and fine needle aspirates from 28 Buruli ulcer confirmed patents and 21 patients with tropical ulcers that were not Buruli ulcer. The samples were pre-processed at the Department of Biochemistry, Cell and Molecular Biology at the University of Ghana, to extract the required components for gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) at the University of Cambridge. We identified tissue biopsy and fine needle aspirates as the best specimen for the identification of metabolites in preference to lesion swabs. Interestingly, metabolites identified in both groups of patients included cadaverine, putrescine, pinitol, palmitate, naphthalene, chlopyrifos and oxaspiro. The former two metabolites are interesting because they classify all the samples as containing degenerating tissue. The fatty acid palmitate is a common metabolite present in human tissue. Pinitol and the later three identifies metabolites are chemical residues that may have been present in the treatment poultice used as unorthodox remedies by the patients.  In this proposal, we are seeking to further this pilot study, building on our observations and collecting the tissue biopsies and fine needle aspirates from a larger patient sample group to allow us to perform a more detailed analysis of the compounds found within the bacteria and also within infected tissue. We also intend to expand the scope of the biological samples from affected individuals by including urine samples in our analysis which may provide a more convenient biofluid to sample. To gain more insight into the novelty of the biomarkers we identify, we will include another phase of experimentation which involves the characterization of the compounds found in M. ulcerans and other similar bacteria strains that infect people in Ghana including M. pseudishottsii, M. liflandii and M. marinum DL. Data generated from this project will be important in the identification of new diagnostics and also give us insight to the biology of the mycobacterium during infection which may lead to better prospects for future treatments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal aims to develop a low cost, sensitive biomarker of Mycobacterium ulcerans infection for deployment in rural areas of Ghana and C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire. We intend to do this be screening lesion samples and urine from Buruli ulcer patients and healthy volunteers in the hope of identifying potential discriminatory biomarkers for the infection. We will employ a multidisciplinary approach involving microbiology, molecular biology and metabolomics in this study to confirm cases and eventually identify and characterize promising metabolites. Our specific objectives are to:  1. Characterize the metabolome of M. ulcerans with respect to other mycolactone producing mycobacteria. To address this aim we will use liquid chromatography high resolution mass spectrometry (LC-HR-MS) and gas chromatography mass spectrometry (GC-MS) to measure the metabolite compliment of cultured cells. These studies will contribute significantly to the metabolome data base of these pathogeneic mycobcateria and give insight to target metabolites that alter host biochemical and metabolic pathways during infection. Data from this specific objective will also serve as a library of metabolites to monitor during our subsequent two specific aims. 2. Identify key M. ulcerans associated metabolic markers in tissue biopsies and fine needle aspirates that can be found only in Buruli ulcer patients. Samples will be analysed by a combination of LC- and GC- MS, and the data compared using pattern recognition techniques. The data obtained from Buruli ulcer patients will be compared with matched healthy control samples so as to rule out any ambiguity. 3. Identify key M. ulcerans associates metabolic markers in the urine of Buruli ulcer patients. In addition to our MS approaches we will augment the analysis with high resolution NMR spectroscopy of urine.  The studies presented in this proposal are novel to the Buruli ulcer research field and we envisage that the data we generate will be of immense contribution in the search for a diagnostic biomarker which can be used in identifying early cases of Buruli ulcer.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-19">101606.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-19">96071.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">25401.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">25401.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">25401.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">25401.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">25600.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">25600.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">44871.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">21370.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P024416_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
