<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015411_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meeting the SDGs: creating innovative infrastructures and policy solutions to support sustainable development in Global South communities (GS-DEV)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GS-DEV propose four interdisciplinary projects in the areas of health, nutrition, education and environment with great potential for innovation and impact. Evidence and lessons from these projects will be collected and analysed to develop general guidelines for improving the impact of future ODA-based research projects. 1) Development of child micronutrient supplements with regional partners (Brazil, Jordan, Malaysia &amp; Thailand) and regulatory bodies/manufacturers using locally sourced materials and building their R&amp;D capabilities to enable future development of similar products independently. Creative writing and film-making will allow i) communication/engagement with users (children, youth and parents), the general public and the local government on the importance of balanced nutritional diet for child growth &amp; development, and ii) debate the complex causes of malnutrition. 2) Address food and nutrition insecurity in India, a problem confronting a vast majority of women and children, especially in rural, indigenous communities. This will be achieved by working with communities, especially women&apos;s groups, youth groups and students to generate and share knowledge on sustainable food systems, in particular production choices and technologies, diets and consumption practices, and their relationship to health and nutrition outcomes. Content, generated using a range of creative tools and strategies, will inform and be shared at scale through an interactive, audio community media platform; supplemented by a mobile app for smartphone users, to provide 24-h real-time response to community needs. Sustainability will be ensured through capacity-building of educational institutions, government functionaries and the wider public at multiple scales - local, regional, national and international. 3) Development of a more sustainable, relevant and &apos;bottom-up&apos; approach to family literacy, embedded in people&apos;s everyday activities and indigenous learning practices that can influence family well-being and livelihoods. In collaboration with UNESCO Institute for Lifelong Learning and UEA UNESCO Chair partner universities in Ethiopia, Nepal, Malawi &amp; the Philippines, comparative ethnographic studies will be conducted on indigenous approaches to intergenerational learning and knowledge creation, alongside documentary analysis of existing family literacy programmes in these countries. The project includes research-policy interaction and dissemination activities to engage international, national and local stakeholders. Its major contribution will be to bring policy makers&apos; and educators&apos; attention to the disjunction between current mainstream approaches to adult/family literacy instruction and the ways in which adults and children learn in everyday life in order to enhance the contribution of education to sustainable development. 4) Build a network of academics, industry partners and policy-makers in Malaysia to identify and quantify the distribution of microplastics and assess its potential environmental risks. Globally, around half of total plastic production is used for single-use packaging; around 10-14 million tonnes of this ends up in the oceans every year. Plastic gradually breaks down to produce ever-smaller microplastics, which are eaten by and cause stress to a wide variety of organisms that are vital parts of food webs. Counting microplastics in water and sediments is challenging. Through ongoing collaborative work, a cheap and quick methodology has been developed to map microplastic levels and distribution across a range of habitats and ecosystems. Alongside supplying simple equipment, the network will develop a multilingual video manual to aid its use and ensure consistency of practice for data comparisons. A &quot;public information&quot; film will disseminate microplastics-associated problems and research findings to the general public and policy influencers through a range of media options.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Meeting the SDGs: creating innovative infrastructures and policy solutions to support sustainable development in Global South communities (GS-DEV) proposes four ongoing &amp; interconnected projects that tackle health, nutrition, education &amp; environment issues. Building on existing partnerships in Brazil, Jordan, India, Nepal, Malaysia, Thailand, the Philippines, Malawi &amp; Ethiopia, these projects work across disciplines &amp; scales, supporting the strengthening of capacities at multiple levels - from communities to implementers, researchers, universities, media agencies, industry &amp; policy-makers, with a view to long-term sustainability. Collectively, they will generate a valuable guide for UKRI researchers to evaluate the impact of GCRF projects involving a range of stakeholders in geographically and culturally diverse contexts to identify most effective impact strategies in ODA-based research, which will benefit ultimately people living in DAC nations. GS-DEV&apos;s main objectives are: 1) To develop regional low-cost supplements for children to effectively combat micronutrient deficiencies in Brazil, Jordan, Malaysia and Thailand. This includes i) technology training provision, support on formulations &amp; product development, ii) development of commercialisation and scalable manufacturing strategies, iii) support in regulatory approval processes for marketing the product, iv) establish dialogues with other relevant stakeholders &amp; policy makers to discuss governmental support. 2) To address food &amp; nutrition security alongside gender equality in the poorest regions of India through systematic &amp; sustainable upscaling of small-scale innovations on the ground. A two-pronged strategy combining community participation and knowledge exchange with political will and institutional acceptance will be used to achieve this, by: i) Building a proof of concept for upscaling a community-led virtual knowledge and innovation centre, which combines a digital platform &amp; a creative practice hub, to ensure gender-sensitive and reciprocal knowledge production and exchange; ii) Conducting evidence-based advocacy to ensure political uptake &amp; galvanise financial and other resources from MPs and MLAs in their respective constituencies. 3) To demonstrate how a community-based intergenerational approach to family literacy &amp; learning can contribute to achievement of selected SDGs in Ethiopia, the Philippines, Malawi and Nepal, by i) developing intergenerational &amp; indigenous approaches to family literacy that can be integrated into national adult literacy strategies based on pilot studies; ii) investigating how intergenerational &amp; indigenous learning approaches can be included within international adult literacy/lifelong learning policy strategy (including Early Childhood Care and Education) and sectors outside education, particularly in agriculture, women&apos;s development and health, iii) sharing and discussing the results of this approach with key stakeholders at the national and international levels in order to set the base for future integration into related policies, strategies &amp; plans. 4) To quantify microplastics &amp; map plastic contamination levels across Malaysia, with the aim of informing &amp; influencing evidence-based policy decisions on waste management, through i) Setting up a coordinated network for microplastics analysis with centres in East and West Malaysia (test-pilot), ii) Building &amp; providing equipment sets and training, to make analysis available and accessible across the country to academics &amp; beyond (water companies, NGOs), iii) Producing a multilingual &quot;video manual&quot; to support effective use of equipment sets to ensure comparability of data, iv) Collecting and curating environmental data to contribute to the GEO Blue Planet Initiative on marine litter in support of SDG 14-Life Below Water, v) Developing &quot;report cards&quot; &amp; a public information film based on research findings to enhance plastic waste public understanding &amp; its link to human behaviour.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">473746.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">885718.66</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">48940733.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015411_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT015411%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
