<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T004002_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Improving Community Resilience and Sustainability Through Operational Research Capacity Building in Southeast Asia (CREST-OR)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operational Research (OR) has significant potential to contribute to meeting Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and disaster risk management (DRM) objectives of developing countries. However, most ODA countries lack the research capacity to develop and apply relevant OR methodologies. The CREST-OR project is a collaboration between three of the UK&apos;s leading universities in the field of OR - Kent, Lancaster, and Southampton - and prominent universities in four Southeast Asian (SEA) countries - Vietnam, Indonesia, Laos, and Cambodia. CREST-OR will establish a long-term UK-SEA partnership to build research capacity in OR methodologies, improve community resilience to natural disasters, and achieve national SDGs and DRM objectives. SEA partners will benefit from advancing their OR research capabilities, and the formation of new institutional links among project partners. UK partners will benefit from increasing knowledge in the application of OR to international development and disaster management challenges. The project will support longstanding initiatives in SEA countries through engagement of policy-makers and practitioners at national and local levels (e.g. emergency response agencies, local authorities, and development NGOs).  CREST-OR will build capacity in the use of OR for solving challenges in four focal areas: disaster management, food security, resilient transport infrastructure and smart cities. These areas were identified with the SEA partners based on existing collaborations within the UK researchers and, most importantly, on development priorities of their respective countries. In SEA countries, rapid economic growth and infrastructural development has not been supported by sufficiently robust planning. Social and environmental priorities have been regularly forfeited, while population growth has intensified development challenges. Climate change is now raising disaster risks and threatening to derail development achievements, with the greatest effect felt by the poorest and most vulnerable segments of society. OR offers a powerful set of tools to support more informed, evidence-based decision-making by government agencies and NGOs to address challenges related to disaster risk and its impact on food supplies, infrastructure and cities development. By building OR research capacity in these areas, CREST-OR will contribute to address several UN SDGs: SDG2 (Zero Hunger), SDG9 (Industry, Innovation and Infrastructure), SDG11 (Sustainable Cities and Communities), SDG13 (Climate Action) and Priority-2 (Strengthening Disaster Risk Governance) of the Sendai Framework.  The project will undertake the following capacity building activities: - Capacity assessments to identify educational and research gaps in the knowledge and use of OR methodologies, especially in relation to the SDGs, and understand the policy landscape in which CREST-OR will operate. - Three workshops, including: a Scoping Workshop to develop a prioritised list of relevant research projects, which will form the basis of CREST-OR research agenda; an Academic Workshop with specialised research training sessions for SEA researchers at different career stages; a Final Workshop to share developed research project proposals, receive end-user feedback and plan future research strategy. - Secondment of SEA Early Career Researcher in UK partner universities to develop research proposals, take part in research activites, and receive training in advanced and contextualised OR methods (e.g. simulation, optimisation). - Short visits of UK academics to SEA institutions to consolidate understanding of local context, run short training workshops, and support the development of OR curricula and research units. - Attendance of SEA researchers to the UK OR Society annual conference to facilitate their engagement in international debates and integrate them into a wider research community. - Development of a website for research networking and knowledge exchange.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching aim of the CREST-OR project is to establish a long-term UK-SEA partnership to build research capacity in Southeast Asia (SEA) in mathematical OR tools that can be used to address pressing needs in the target areas of disaster management, resilient transport infrastructure, food supply security, and smart cities. UK partner universities (Kent, Southampton, Lancaster) of CREST-OR have developed world leading expertise in OR that can be used to address development challenges in these target research areas. Through the exchange of knowledge and resources, CREST-OR will build OR research capacity in four SEA countries (Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos, Indonesia) and pave the way for embedding OR research and teaching within the region. Additionally CREST-OR will provide a platform to facilitate academic engagement with government (e.g. Ministry of Rural Development, Cambodia; Ministry of Natural Resources and Environment, Vietnam), NGOs (e.g. Humanitarian Forum, Indonesia; OXFAM International, Laos), emergency response agencies (e.g. Indonesia National Disaster Management Authority), and the private sector. Stakeholder engagement activities will generate better understanding and appreciation of how OR methods can be leveraged to address target research areas and facilitate closer collaboration among SEA partner institutions and outside organisations. This initiative will contribute to improving SEA community resilience to natural disasters and achieve national Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) and Disaster Risk Management (DRM) objectives.   In line with this, the main objectives of the CREST-OR project are to:  1) Build OR research capacity across career stages, including leadership and early career levels, that goes beyond technical skills necessary to conduct quality research and covers the full research cycle (research funding, research design and delivery, research management and administration, dissemination, and policy engagement). 2) Develop a portfolio of co-designed research proposals in the target areas of disaster management, resilient transport infrastructure, food supply security, and smart cities. 3) Create a self-sustaining OR community in SEA, including the establishment of a new SEA OR Society.  Achievement of CREST-OR&apos;s objectives will provide a unique set of capabilities for addressing sustainable deployment challenges in SEA. Research capacity building (objective 1) will provide the necessary supply of OR expertise in SEA. Development of co-designed proposals in target research areas (objective 2) will further increase demand for OR solutions. Finally, a dynamic SEA OR community (objective 3) will enable the research agenda of CREST-OR to continue well beyond the life-time of the project.  The long-term vision for CREST-OR is to develop a vibrant, independent, and resilient OR community in SEA, which extends to other SEA neighbouring countries not currently included in CREST-OR. During the project, SEA academics will receive specialised OR training and research skill development and be supported in developing a number of OR studies in target research areas. The training provided by CREST-OR and the foundation of a supportive regional OR environment will, in turn, provide a lasting legacy, one that equips participating SEA researchers to carry out and publish high-quality, internationally-recognised research in OR independently and promotes collaboration with researchers/organisations in neighbouring SEA countries to tackle new and emerging sustainable development challenges using OR methods. UK academics will also benefit from OR capacity building in SEA and the creation of a regional OR Society as this will pave the way for research engagement and co-development of new ideas and approaches for advancing the field of OR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-31">265126.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Kent</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T004002/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">66281.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T004002_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT004002%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
