<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T025832_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adapting the Stepping Stones intervention to strengthen HIV-related outcomes, and enable scale- up, for young men in South Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa (SA) has an estimated 7.2 million people living with HIV - the highest in the world and HIV remains the leading cause of death, with 110,000 deaths per annum.  Men continue to have a higher HIV related mortality than women, whilst HIV incidence has remained stubbornly high, especially in KwaZulu-Natal (KZN) where we have shown an annual incidence of 8% amongst females aged 20-24. There has been considerable progress in developing efficacious and cost-effective HIV prevention tools. These include HIV point of care tests (POCT) and HIV self-tests; voluntary medical male circumcision (VMMC), condoms, and the use of daily oral tenofovir/emtricitabine for Pre-Exposure Prophylaxis (PrEP) which can reduce the risk of acquiring HIV by up to 90%; and HIV treatment with antiretroviral therapy (ART) that, when taken consistently, reduces mortality and eliminates onward transmission of HIV to sexual partners to zero. However, the promise of eliminating HIV in young people has not materialised in part due to the fact that young men still have poor use of these technologies. This undermines our efforts to end AIDS.   In this project we propose to take interventions that have previously been used successfully with young men to reduce their use of violence in relationships and alcohol use, and adapt them to strengthen HIV-related outcomes. This will be done in a district of South Africa with one of the highest HIV-prevalence globally.   The adaptation process will comprise a mixture of working with other academics, non-governmental organisations (NGOs) and the young men themselves to co-develop a framework and intervention. Over a period of five months we will then pilot this intervention. The intervention will have two versions: the first version will be delivered over approximately 8 weeks, with sessions run twice a week, while the second version will be delivered over a one week period. We will follow up men to see whether after attending the intervention they will attend an HIV-test at a clinic, and then engage in a discussion about HIV-treatment (if positive) or HIV-prevention options if HIV-negative.  We will collect a mixture of data on service uptake, and service users, service providers and the community experience, and adverse events and our ability to follow participants up for three months. We will also talk to men about their experience of the intervention and to those who are delivering the intervention about what it was like.   By the end of the study period we anticipate that we will have an acceptable and scalable scalable group-based participatory intervention that will improve men&apos;s health through transforming masculinities and strengthening livelihoods After this process we will revise the manual and it will be ready for a larger evaluation in a formal trial to see whether it has impact on men&apos;s lives and HIV-prevention and treatment.    Our experienced multidisciplinary team of clinical researcher, social scientists, and biostatisticians together with the implementing partner Project Empower, will conduct the study over 16 months.  We believe that we will be able to help provide answers to the important scientific question: Can a scalable group-based participatory intervention improve men&apos;s health and reduce their high HIV related mortality through the pathways of transforming men&apos;s masculinities and strengthening livelihoods in rural South Africa?</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim:  Our over arching goal is to arrest the HIV epidemic and it&apos;s negative effect on young people in sub Saharan Africa, including the high male mortality and high HIV incidence in young women through improving the effective engagement of men in HIV testing, prevention and treatment pathways. Our aim in this development grant is to develop a scalable group-based participatory intervention that will improve men&apos;s health and reduce their high HIV related mortality through the pathways of transforming men&apos;s masculinities and strengthening livelihoods among men living in an area of rural South Africa with a high burden of HIV infection. This proposal is to support the development stage of an intervention in preparation for a future effectiveness trial, focused on young (18-30) men.   The specific objectives of this development grant are:  1. To co-develop and refine a theory of change for an intervention to strengthen men&apos;s HIV-testing, prevention and treatment through the pathways of transforming men&apos;s masculinities and strengthening livelihoods 2. To co-develop and refine an intervention manual to strengthen men&apos;s HIV-engagement 3. To assess feasibility and acceptability of the intervention for young men through a rigorous process evaluation that uses quantitative and qualitative methods 4. To assess the feasibility of collecting the primary outcome - HIV testing and linkage HIV-prevention counselling around evidence-based HIV-prevention technologies (PrEP, VMMC) if HIV-negative, and uptake of HIV-treatment if HIV-positive- through the Africa Health Research Institutes electronic data collection systems in all primary health and mobile clinical services.  5. To refine the secondary outcome measures of intimate partner violence, alcohol use, sexual and mental health.  We anticipate that the findings of this development work will not only inform a large-scale trial of the intervention, but will separately provide South African and other southern Africa health policy-makers with evidence to inform adaptation of widely used Stepping Stones based interventions to support men delivering ART based prevention. This synergises with the current policy focus in southern Africa to try and get the missing men into HIV care and prevention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-08">150627.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T025832/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">25979.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T025832_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">25979.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T025832_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">25979.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T025832_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT025832%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
