<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_R008434_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Residential building energy demand reduction in India (RESIDE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The RESIDE (Residential building energy demand reduction in India) project will establish a pioneering nationwide socio-technical research programme to measure, model, map and manage energy demand reduction, temporally and spatially, in urban residential buildings in the five climatic zones of India.  The aims of the project can be broken down into 8 key objectives: 1. Conduct analyses and synthesis of the existing and available residential energy and comfort datasets for India that are currently scattered in fragmented studies, and to engage with existing and prospective data users (government, academe, industry) to identify user needs, data gaps and how best to meet them through RESIDE field studies. 2. Develop, customise, pilot and refine low-cost methods for monitoring and benchmarking of energy use and survey of thermal comfort in relation to the home indoor environment, in order to support the development of a rigorous Indian post-occupancy evaluation regime. 3. Establish a detailed picture of current residential energy demand patterns by undertaking a large-scale monitoring campaign of electricity use and indoor temperatures, alongside a field survey of household and property characteristics of 2000 dwellings (single-family/ multi-family) selected to represent the population (low/medium/high income) and housing stock (new-build/existing) across five geographically spread cities representing the five climatic zones of India. 4. Design, trial, evaluate and refine a low-cost, easy-to-deploy smart home energy management (SHEM) system in order to enable residents to participate in overall energy saving and peak demand reduction (in response to (future) time varying tariffs), and to gather high-quality data characterising temporal load profiles of a subsample of 200 recently-built dwellings. 5. Conduct post-occupancy evaluation studies of 200 recently-built dwellings across five housing developments in order to assess the physical and human factors that influence energy demand in dwellings, and identify which energy-using practices can be adapted for demand reduction.  6. Build dwelling-level energy models of 10 residential archetypes to assess opportunities for substantial demand reduction by deploying, singularly and in combination, improved building envelope (insulation, shading), low-energy cooling/heating (passive solar, fans, radiant system) and behavioural measures (increasing set-point temperatures) for current and future climates. 7. Create novel GIS-based community-level models to map 2000 dwellings across five cities to estimate and visualise energy demand in urban areas, and to predict potential for local demand reduction by targeting widespread deployment of energy saving measures and rooftop solar. 8. Develop and refine a data-driven residential energy code informed by adaptive thermal comfort and an outcome-based POE-lite tool for ensuring code compliance at scale, and investigate the policy implications of implementing the code through Delphi engagement methods involving both policymakers and practitioners in the Indian energy and built environment fields. RESIDE mainly focuses on Topic 1 of the call (Peak demand reduction through improved building envelopes, low-energy cooling &amp; heating) by developing residential building energy code [Work package (WP)5 &amp; WP7], social practices of adaptive thermal comfort [WP1, WP2] and post- occupancy evaluation [WP4]). By extending from energy efficiency at dwelling level to development of policy support tool [WP6] for use and assessment at community and city levels, and proposals for the residential building code [WP7], the project also addresses Topic 2 of the call. Thirdly, through development of SHEMS [WP3] and integrated community level assessment tools [WP6] the project addresses Topic 3 of the call on &apos;Integration of information, communication and renewable energy technologies at building, community, and city level interventions&apos;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The RESIDE (Residential building energy demand reduction in India) project will help support the improvement of living conditions for millions of Indian citizens through establishing the knowledge base to develop a residential building code for high quality, low-energy housing across all five climatic zones in India.  The project brings together an interdisciplinary team of architects, engineers, digital scientists, urban planners and behavioural researchers to assess all aspects of the residential energy use problem, including performance of the building fabric; in-home appliances including heating, ventilation and air conditioning; indoor environment and occupant behaviour. RESIDE will undertake surveys and monitoring of energy consumption in 2000 homes spread across the five different climatic zones in India in order to build up a new, open access database for policy and practitioner communities in India and other countries in the Asia-Pacific region. In 10% of these homes, we will also trial and evaluate a Smart Home Energy Management System, to be designed within the project, to enable householders greater control over their comfort and energy consumption. These activities will be used to develop low-cost monitoring and post-occupancy evaluation protocols suitable for the Indian situation.  This will not only improve Best Practice, but allow a framework by which consistent data can be collected and added to the RESIDE database.  Using novel techniques developed by the project team for assessing the potential up-scaling of individual household measures and actions to a neighbourhood level, RESIDE will explore and establish protocols for assessing the potential for, and likely benefits of, widespread take up of energy efficiency and rooftop solar technologies at a community scale. By engaging with a wide range of stakeholders involved in planning and construction throughout the project, and by undertaking an extensive review of policy experiences in similar countries, the RESIDE project will establish the key factors essential for consideration in the development of a new residential building code for India.  Then, building on the extensive data collected through the project, and a set of co-design workshops, the project will develop a proposed framework for a new residential building code.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-15">47678.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-15">191487.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-15">193038.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-15">145755.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-15">5405246.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_R008434_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FR008434%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
