<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_T007168_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Capacity Building for Thai Astronomy Phase 3: Establishing NARIT Millimetre Laboratory for Developing State-of-the-Art Astronomical Receivers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In previous years, Thailand has invested heavily in developing the human capital required to build, operate and fully exploit the science and industrial opportunities afforded by the research in radio and optical astronomy, largely supported by the STFC Newton fund programmes. These programmes have shown to be hugely successful, and have benefitted all the partners involved in these development schemes.  The main objective of this project is therefore to enable NARIT to extend its technological capabilities and infrastructures to the millimetre (mm) wavelengths region. We aim to build the human capacity in Thailand, through the transfer of knowledge in the field of millimetre science and engineering, which would create new industries and new jobs locally in the near future, and consequently improve the quality of life of the general populations.  The educational infrastructure in Thailand is in place, and has prepared well the skilled and enthusiastic graduate and postgraduate students to undertake the challenging research topics in millimetre astronomy at the MSc and PhD level. Within this collaboration, we aim to provide training platforms for Thai students, scientists and engineers via bilateral exchange scheme between UK and Thailand to engage in this advanced field of millimetre science and technologies, which involves several high-tech know-how such as cryogenic engineering, superconducting physics and ultra-precision machining technology etc. This includes an extensive programme of technological development and skills/knowledge transfer focused at technologies and scientific enquiries skills, and novel outreach programmes designed to exploit Thailand&apos;s leadership in astronomy education in local region, and showcase the millimetre astronomy research that will be carried out at NARIT. We aim to achieve this via the three technical work packages proposed as follow: - Establishing a millimetre laboratory at NARIT as the foundation for future research and development in millimetre instrumentations; - Construction of a 350 GHz 1x4 compact linear array in anticipation for NARIT to take a lead in upgrading a heterodyne array instrument at the James Clerk Maxwell Telescope (JCMT); and - Design and test Low Noise Amplifiers (LNAs) for frequencies above 70 GHz and produce the initial designs of a compact and highly integrated packaging scheme for use as components in large format focal plane array (FPA) receivers.  At the end of the proposed research, we aim to have helped NARIT and Thailand&apos;s scientific community (including astronomers) by equipping our collaborators with relevant knowledge and skills required to operate state-of-the-art millimetre laboratory, and have trained the engineers, scientists and students involved in this project to run the new laboratory. We expect that by the end of this 24-months programme, the laboratory will be equipped with the required skilled personnel and high-end equipment, including the cryo-system and prototype receivers developed through this programme, such that the laboratory will be able to further their engagement in new research activities in this area and beyond, expanding the acquired technologies to other academic research fields.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">JCMT is the largest existing single dish millimetre (mm) and sub-millimetre telescope in the world, originally built by UK, and stationed at the Mauna Kea peak of the Haiwai&apos;i island. The telescope is currently owned and operated by the East Asia Observatory (EAO), in which NARIT is a member of the organisation. NARIT is also heavily involved in the EAO up-coming plan to upgrade the various receiver instruments hosted in JCMT, in particular the heterodyne array HARP-B, which is a 16-pixel superconductor-insulator-superconductor (SIS) mixer receiver. The plan is to replace HARP-B with a cutting-edge compact high sensitivity instrument with even larger pixel count to expand the mapping area and increase the mapping speed by at least an order of magnitude. The new receiver needs to be housed within the existing restricted space in the receiver cabin of JCMT without the need for major re-engineering of the facility, and this could be done by employing the latest heterodyne receiver technologies.  The success of this upgrading programme relies on the combination of various state-of-the-art technologies and support from numerous resources, which inevitably comes with significant human capacity and skills development challenges. Currently, Thailand has few astronomers or engineers who can design, construct and operate the instrument. But the pool of talented candidates whom can be trained and performed the job is large, due to the country&apos;s strong educational programme that equips the students with the required fundamental skills to uptake the challenging tasks. On the other hand, the scientific community in UK, particular the group in the University of Oxford and the University of Manchester, have many years of experience in developing technologies in the mm-wave and building instruments for various astronomical applications. Therefore, through this proposal, we aim to address these challenges by tapping into the UK&apos;s long heritage and highly developed skills in mm-wave astronomy and instrumentation, to train and prepare the personnel in NARIT with the fundamental skill-sets and technical know-how to contribute to the long-term programme of constructing mm-wave instruments for JCMT, and many other instruments, in the near future.  The two main research topics proposed in this program that would allow us to use these as platform to provide training and knowledge transfers are 1) Constructing a prototype linear 1 x 4 SIS mixer array at 350 GHz that could be further extended and stacked to form a much larger array e.g., an 8 x 8, 64-pixel array, aiming to upgrade the existing HARP-B in JCMT; and 2) Development of Low Noise Amplifiers (LNAs) above 70 GHz and produce compact and highly integrated packaging scheme for Focal Plane Array (FPA) receivers. These LNAs would have applications on the new Thai National Radio Telescope (125 GHz receiver) and JCMT (200-350 GHz), both of which NARIT have access to. We will use these research targets as the vehicle for technology transfer via bilateral UK-Thailand collaboration. Both projects will also incorporate many key skills of value to a developing knowledge economy such as engineering, electronics, cryogenics and telecommunications technology etc. We will also partner with the Thai astronomical and technical community to further propagate the technical knowledge acquired from astronomy instrumentation to the wider audience, bolstering the Thai general population skill base e.g., via public talks and outreach programme. This programme will not only help to develop the skills that Thailand urgently needs at this stage, but will also have impact on the wider economy through the increased uptake of undergraduates and graduates in Science Technology Engineering and Medicine (STEM) area, and up-skilling of current graduates and postgraduates in various other advanced science and technological fields.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-03">146421.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-03">22302.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
