<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003835_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conflict Resolution through Classical Literature</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil and Colombia remain in a state of political flux. The thirty-sixth President of Brazil, Dilma Rousseff, was impeached in 2016; in that same year, the Colombian government brokered a fragile peace with the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia - People&apos;s Army (FARC). These crises and revolutions constitute but two of the most recent developments in a region marked by upheaval. Indeed, the present social and economic instability in Brazil and Colombia is comparable to that of the ancient world, and particularly to that of late Republican and early Imperial Rome, which was likewise plagued by civil war, divided by partisan conflict, and weakened by frequent leadership changes.  With these similarities in mind, the proposed project reframes Classical literature within the context of contemporary conflict-ridden Brazil and Colombia. It explores the theme of conflict resolution through Greek and Roman literature, thus examining how ancient methods of obtaining peace map onto modern conflict resolution theories in War Studies and whether they can be used effectively in these regions. Researchers from War Studies and Classics from the UK, Brazil, and Colombia will collaborate on re-thinking conflict resolution through Classics and determine how this framework can play a central role in providing tools for resolving current troubles and preventing future conflicts. By applying findings about the long-term role of humanities education to conflict resolution, the proposed project will actively engage conflict-affected communities in discussion by initiating and supporting outreach programmes in Brazil and Colombia. The key approach governing these initiatives, which will be designed and implemented through the co-operative effort of foreign academics and local stakeholders, entails providing crisis-affected populations with conflict resolution skills through the teaching of Classical literature.  These parallel goals of research and outreach characterise our project, which will not only engage with modern political conflict in Brazil and Colombia, but also create tangible change in these beleaguered societies by providing a new framework for teaching conflict resolution skills.  Accordingly, the main objectives of the proposed project are: 1) To explore the theme of conflict resolution combining War Studies and Classical literature, thus refining and deepening existing knowledge on this subject  2) To define, categorise, and consider methods of conflict resolution within the context of ancient and modern approaches 3) To assess the strengths and weaknesses of conflict resolution models - ancient and modern - as potential frameworks for current crises  4) To hold workshops in Brazil, Colombia and the UK, which facilitate mutual knowledge transfers between specialists in conflict resolution and Classics from the UK, Brazil and Colombia  5) To tap into existing Classics-related community projects from Brazil and Colombia and to engage students with models of conflict resolution and how these relate to contemporary crises  6) To utilise Classics education, especially at the secondary and tertiary levels, as a method of promoting conflict resolution skills in Brazil and Colombia</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project will research, develop, and implement ways in which Classical education can help conflict-affected populations to acquire conflict resolution skills and overcome trauma. The first research stage will identify, categorize and study key examples of conflict resolution in Classical literature across genres, including council scenes in epic poetry from Homer to Valerius Flaccus as well as judicial speeches in Greek tragedy, as exemplified by Orestes&apos; trial in Aeschylus&apos; Eumenides and Antigone&apos;s defense in Sophocles&apos; play of the same name. Researchers from both Classics and War Studies will thus assess these resolution methods both within the framework of the original crises and in the context of contemporary political upheaval in Brazil and Colombia. The key questions to be answered during this initial exploration are: What can the ancient world teach us about conflict resolution? How does this compare to modern approaches? And how can we apply these lessons to Latin America, given the unique challenges posed by its troubled history, complex society, and heterogeneous culture?  Researchers will address these questions at a series of three workshops. The first of these will be held in Year 1 of the project at the Universidad de los Andes and the Colombian War College in Bogot&#xE1;, Colombia. Both Classicists and scholars of War Studies from Brazil and the UK along with colleagues from Colombian universities will attend the event so as to discuss and compare frameworks of conflict resolution. In so doing, they will examine case studies from both Classical literature and peace-building strategies in Latin America. In Year 2 of the project we will present two major panels at the Semana Internacional de Estudos Cl&#xE1;ssicos do Amazonas, in Manaus, Brazil, where participants will explore the extent to which Classical education can contribute to teaching conflict resolution skills to populations in crisis. The third workshop, to take place in Year 2 of the project, at King&apos;s College London, will draw on the themes of the two preceding workshops by exploring how conflict resolution frameworks - both ancient and modern - can address conflicts in Brazil and Colombia when combined with Classical education. As part of the proposed project, participating researchers from the UK, Brazil, and Colombia will also collaborate on pedagogical materials, which will be published online as open access resources for local educators. Moreover, the Investigators will tap into and extend existing long-term outreach programmes with partner universities. In so doing, the proposed project will not only put its research conclusions into practice, but also complement existing programmes such as Project Minimus in S&#xE3;o Paulo, which teaches ancient languages and mythology to students in the fourth and seventh grades, two outreach projects at the Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora which introduce ancient literature to underprivileged youth, and the Las Troyanas project in Bogot&#xE1;, which supports victims of sexual violence by recording their stories through art and literature. The latter echoes the central theme of its namesake - Euripides&apos; &apos;The Trojan Women&apos; - by improving the welfare of women affected by war.  We will focus scholarly interest on the modern applications of ancient conflict narratives and develop professional networks between researchers in Classics and War Studies from the UK, Colombia, and Brazil. The project will thus lead to major research outputs and public impacts, building on the Investigators&apos; established track records of scholarship, publication, and public engagement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">35104.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">14930.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">49583.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003835_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FS003835%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
