<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mitigating basis risk in weather index-based crop insurance: harnessing models and big data to enable climate-resilient agriculture in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Livelihoods of millions of smallholder farmers across the developing world are under threat from extreme weather events, such as droughts, floods, and heatwaves, with risks projected to increase significantly in future years due to climate change. Crop insurance protects farmers against financial risks posed by extreme weather events, and has been widely advocated as a tool to help farmer households to escape poverty traps and invest in climate-smart high-productivity agriculture. Yet, to date, the success and uptake of crop insurance schemes across the developing world has been extremely limited.    Several reasons can be identified for problems in scaling crop insurance in developing countries. Traditional indemnity-based insurance schemes require time-consuming verification of actual losses experienced by individual farmers resulting in high transaction costs, claims disputes and delays that deter farmers from purchasing insurance. To counteract these issues, governments and insurers seek to develop more cost-effective and reliable tools to determine when, and at what level, insurance should payout to farmers if an extreme weather event occurs. Parametric insurance, for example weather index-based insurance, triggers payouts based on pre-established relationships between meteorological indices and crop yields, removing the need for expensive crop loss assessments. However, a major challenge for current weather index-based insurance is that payouts often are poorly correlated with farmers&apos; actual yield losses, a problem known as &apos;basis risk&apos;, creating a major barrier to use of index insurance for climate risk mitigation.  In this context, how can scientists contribute to the design of smarter index insurance products that meet the needs of farmers, insurers, and governments? The overall aim of this project is to improve the current poor performance of index-based crop insurance by using state-of-the-art environmental modelling and big datasets to reduce basis risk and better protect farmers against weather risks. Our proposed research will develop novel weather index-based insurance contracts that reliably and accurately predict weather-related crop yield losses by combining crop growth modelling, satellite and smartphone imagery of crop growth status, and high-resolution gridded estimates of spatial weather variability. Importantly, our work will produce novel tools and approaches that address two stated needs of the index insurance sector: (i) to reduce temporal basis risk by designing weather index triggers that reflect accurately how yield sensitivity to extreme events varies during the growing season, and (ii) to minimise spatial basis risk by exploiting datasets that capture spatial heterogeneity in weather conditions, crop development, field conditions and management practices.     Working in collaboration with HDFC ERGO General Insurance, a major provider of weather index-based insurance for smallholder farmers across India, we will apply these approaches to design and test new weather index-based insurance products to protect farmers in the major agricultural states of Punjab and Haryana - the breadbasket of India - against combined production risks from extreme temperature and heavy rainfall events. Leveraging unique field data collected through the recent IFPRI-HDFC Picture-Based Crop Insurance (PBI) Project, we will conduct agro-economic impact evaluations to quantify reductions in basis risk, increases in farmer welfare and demand for insurance from our new contracts relative to both current index insurance products and government area-yield insurance schemes. Our work will contribute directly to improvements in the quality of index insurance for farmers in India, and, more broadly, will provide the scientific foundations for weather index-based insurance to more effectively support climate-smart smallholder agriculture across the developing world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this project is to improve current poor performance and uptake of weather index-based crop insurance in developing countries by combining novel crop growth modelling techniques with spatially disaggregated weather data and crop status observations to reduce basis risk, and enhance farmers&apos; resilience to weather and climate risks.  To achieve this aim, the specific objectives of our project are to:   (1) Estimate the impacts of weather-related risks, such as extreme heat or excess precipitation and the timing of these events during the growing season, on crop yield losses using biophysical simulation models of crop growth. (2) Validate approaches for automated collection of information about field-level crop growth status and farmer management practices via smartphone applications and satellite remote sensing (3) Design new index-based crop insurance contracts that capture the response of crop yields to the timing, magnitude, and duration of weather risks, and the interaction with field conditions and management practices. (4) Evaluate the impacts of new smart index contract designs on spatial and temporal basis risk, insurance demand, and farmer behaviour and welfare outcomes.   Reaching these specific objectives will result in new tools and methods to enable insurers and governments to easily design and implement robust weather index-based insurance contracts in developing countries. In particular, significant reductions in basis risk will be achieved as a result of the ability of novel methods to capture more accurately the intraseasonal sensitivity of crop yields to extreme weather events (lower temporal basis risk) and account for impacts of spatial variability in weather patterns, crop development, and management practices on yield losses experienced by individual farmers (lower spatial basis risk) without the need for expensive field assessment and verification of damage.   Working with our practitioner partner - HDFC ERGO General Insurance Ltd - we will co-design and test new index insurance contracts to better protect wheat growers in Northwest India against co-variate risks from extreme heat and excess rainfall. New contracts will enable HDFC to offer farmers more reliable protection against weather risks, and will provide a clear demonstration of the value of our proposed approaches to support effective index insurance design for other crop types and in different countries worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">40555.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">156729.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">59766.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">40555.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">40555.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">40555.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">40555.41</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">35063.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">33972.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">25793.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
