<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Molecular mechanisms of sporogonic development in malaria parasites</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaria parasites possess unique subcellular organelles, named crystalloids, that are uniquely found in the ookinete and young oocyst stages of the parasite. Crystalloids have an essential function in sporogonic development and parasite transmission from mosquito to human. Accordingly, crystalloids are of interest from both cell biological and transmission intervention perspectives. A crystalloid-specific palmitoyl-S-acyl transferase (DHHC10) is essential for crystalloid formation and sporozoite transmission, indicating that post-translational S-palmitoylation of crystalloid proteins plays a critical part in these processes. This project aims to investigate the molecular mechanisms of sporogonic development focussing on the role of palmitoylation in crystalloid biogenesis and function. Using the rodent malaria parasite Plasmodium berghei as a model, we will dissect the substrate range, spatiotemporal dynamics and mechanisms of DHHC10-mediated palmitoylation in crystalloids. This will provide important new insights into the molecular mechanisms that facilitate crystalloid biogenesis and function, and will form a platform for the identification of new drug targets specific for this part of the life cycle, providing novel strategies to prevent malaria transmission. The proposed research has three specific objectives:  Objective 1: Determine the crystalloid palmitome. Using acyl-biotin-exchange (ABE) biochemistry and label-free quantitative mass spectrometry (LFQMS), the ookinete palmitoylated proteome (palmitome) will be determined of DHHC10-positive and DHHC10-negative parasite lines, facilitating the identification of DHHC10 substrates and the cystalloid palmitome. In parallel, the ookinete palmitome of a DHHC-positive, but crystalloid-negative, parasite line (LAP3-KO) will be determined to shed light on the spatiotemporal dynamics of DHHC10-mediated palmitoylation. The results will provide a global view of the palmitoylated protein repertoire in the whole ookinete and in the crystalloid, and will identify new crystalloid components.   Objective 2: Identify proteins that interact with DHHC10. Proteins that interact with DHHC10 (either subunits of a DHHC10 protein complex, or DHHC10 substrates) will be isolated by GFP immunoaffinity pull-down from ookinetes expressing GFP-tagged DHHC10, followed by LFQMS. As a complementary approach, interactors for DHHC10 will be identified by BioID: DHHC10 and its neighbour molecules will be biotinylated in live ookinetes expressing DHHC10 fused to the biotin ligase BirA*, allowing their isolation by streptavidin affinity capture and identification by LFQMS analysis. BioID analysis of mature versus immature ookinetes will identify potential changes in the DHHC10 interactome during ookinete development and crystalloid assembly. Furthermore, BioID analysis of ookinetes expressing the crystalloid protein LAP3 fused to BirA* will be carried out to validate the DHHC10 interactome results. The results will identify new protein partners and substrates of DHHC10, as well as new crystalloid components, and provide new insight into the spatiotemporal dynamics and mechanisms of DHHC10-mediated palmitoylation.   Objective 3: Validate new candidate crystalloid proteins. To make sure that newly identified proteins of the crystalloid palmitome (objective 1) and DHHC10 interactive (objective 2) are genuinely associated with crystalloid biogenesis and/or function, they will be functionally characterized using fluorescent protein tagging and gene knockout approaches in transgenic parasites. The results will give new mechanistic insight into the function and mode of action of DHHC10 and other crystalloid proteins, and provide new insights into the molecular mechanisms of sporogonic development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New therapies for prevention and treatment of malaria, and for reducing transmission, are urgently needed. This project aims to increase our understanding of the molecular mechanisms underlying the formation and function of the crystalloid - a malaria parasite organelle found uniquely in the ookinete and young oocyst stages that is essential for sporogonic development and sporozoite transmission from mosquito to human. A palmitoyl-S-acyl transferase enzyme named DHHC10 resides in the crystalloid and is essential for crystalloid formation and parasite transmission. DHHC10 catalyses the addition of a palmitoyl lipid to proteins, a reaction known as palmitoylation. This project will focus on the role of palmitoylation in crystalloid biogenesis and function. Using the Plasmodium berghei mouse malaria model, we will determine the substrate range, spatiotemporal dynamics and mechanisms of DHHC10-mediated palmitoylation in crystalloids via three specific objectives:   Objective 1: Determine the crystalloid palmitome. Using a method called acyl-biotin-exchange (ABE) the palmitoyls on palmitoylated proteins are chemically exchanged for biotin, which allows their specific capture and purification with microbeads that bind biotin. Following this, the palmitoylated protein fraction (palmitome) is analyzed by mass spectrometry (MS) to determine the identities of the individual protein components. By comparing the palmitomes from ookinetes that express DHHC10 and those that do not (DHHC10-knockouts), the substrates of DHHC10 can be identified, which correspond to the crystalloid palmitome. In parallel, the ookinete palmitome of a DHHC-positive, but crystalloid-negative, parasite line (LAP3-knockout) will be determined to study the spatiotemporal dynamics of DHHC10-mediated palmitoylation. The results will provide a global view of the palmitoylated protein repertoire in the whole ookinete and in the crystalloid, and will identify new crystalloid components.  Objective 2: Identify proteins that interact with DHHC10. Proteins that interact with DHHC10 (either subunits of a DHHC10 protein complex, or DHHC10 substrates) will be identified by two approaches. (i) GFP pull-down: ookinetes that express DHHC10 fused to green fluorescent protein (GFP) will be used to capture DHHC10 protein complexes using magnetic beads that can bind to the GFP, and these complexes will then be analyzed by MS to determine their protein composition. (ii) BioID: ookinetes that express DHHC10 fused to a biotin ligase (BirA*) can be used to specifically biotinylate DHHC10 and its neighbour proteins upon addition of excess biotin to the cells. This allows their specific capture with magnetic beads that bind to biotin, followed by MS analysis. BioID analysis of ookinetes expressing a different crystalloid protein (LAP3) fused to BirA* will be carried out to validate the DHHC10 results. The results will identify new protein partners and substrates of DHHC10, as well as new crystalloid components, and provide new insight into the spatiotemporal dynamics and mechanisms of DHHC10-mediated palmitoylation.   Objective 3: Validate new candidate crystalloid proteins. To make sure that newly identified proteins of the crystalloid palmitome and DHHC10 interactome are genuinely associated with crystalloid biogenesis and/or function, they will be functionally characterized using fluorescent protein tagging and gene knockout approaches in genetically modified parasites.   The combined results obtained from this project will build a better and more comprehensive picture of the molecules that are associated with the crystalloid organelle and are involved in, or subject of, crystalloid-specific S-palmitoylation. They will provide important new insight into the molecular mechanisms that facilitate crystalloid genesis and function, and form a platform for the identification of new drug targets specific for sporogonic development, providing new strategies to prevent transmission.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-20">37092.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-20">148671.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-20">149875.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-20">113088.04</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">37092.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">37092.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">37092.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">37092.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">37393.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">37393.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">37393.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">37393.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">37696.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">37696.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">37696.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
