<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P002498_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Higher Education, Inequality and the Public Good in four African countries: South Africa, Kenya, Nigeria and Ghana</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is widespread agreement amongst policy makers and practitioners across Africa that higher education is a public good, and it has been given significance in the Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) agenda. However there are sharply different views regarding what is meant by the notion of public good, and how unevenly distributed higher education connects with this notion. The project aims through the collection of some new data, and re-analysis of existing data sets, to consider what views different constituencies i -students, staff, governance bodies, employers, government, and civil society - have regarding a definition of public good and its connection with higher education.   The study involves researchers working in and on 4 African countries -South Africa, Ghana, Kenya and Nigeria. These have some similarities in their higher education systems but also some differences regarding the size and shape of the public and private sector in higher education in the four countries. However, all have in common unevenly distributed levels of economic growth, and high levels of poverty and different kinds of inequalities. We will analyse the data we collect, and that from past projects and will also look at the existing publicly available information on how higher education links with wages, attitudes, and views of the public good.   From our review of these 3 bodies of data, we will aim to develop an indicator of higher education and the public good that can be used across countries. We will involve stakeholders as our development of this indicator emerges, and at the end of the project hope to be able to offer this to the academic, policy and practitioner community as a useful way to understand the connection between higher education and the public good. We hope that this indicator will help users in interpreting data on levels of student enrolment and progression, graduate destinations, earnings and assist in reviewing arguments about public funding for higher education, when basic education and other sectors of post secondary provision are also in need of support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ZA" type="SOUTH AFRICA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1029</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-11">42378.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-11">169856.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-11">171232.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This research project aims to advance understanding about how different constituencies - students, staff, governance bodies, employers, government, and civil society - understand the connection between higher education and the public good in four African countries with university systems that share some common features. All 4 countries are experiencing unevenly distributed economic growth and this puts the question of how higher education addresses issues of poverty and inequality high on the agenda.  The project involves a collaboration among scholars with long experience of working on questions of higher education in Africa, and all the objectives we set out are connected by a concern to facilitate discussion across academics and stakeholders in the 4 countries. We will draw on an analysis of some newly collected qualitative data and some analysis of quantitative and qualitative data already collected for projects with students and staff in the four countries. We will also examine a range of publicly available economic and demographic data in the public domain. A critical assessment across the 4 countries of these data will be used to develop an indicator of higher education and the public good, which we will offer for review in cross country comparisons with academics and stakeholders. The overall research question and our main objective is to understand how similar and different the debates and views about higher education and public good in selected African countries are, whether theories of the public good and higher education can be built across countries with different histories and experiences of poverty and inequality, and whether the data collected and analysed in objectives 2 - 4, can be used to develop an indicator of higher education and public good that can be used comparatively across countries by policy makers and practitioners. Our second objective is to understand how differently situated constituencies understand the connection between higher education and the public good. We plan to collect and analyse data from 15 interviews in each country with senior figures from politics, higher education governance, key sectors of the economy, relevant unions, and activist organisations concerned with human rights and poverty, These data will be analysed through collaborative cross country reflection, and the implications of this for the proposed indicator will be considered.  Our third objective is to reanalyse data collected for projects for which members of the research team were PIs. This quantitative and qualitative data will be analysed to generate insight into the views of staff and students at universities in the 4 countries regarding the connection between higher education and the public good. Collaborative cross country reflection on this analysis will also feed into the development of the proposed indicator. Our fourth objective is to critically review publicly available economic and socio-demographic datasets regarding labour force participation, sectors of economic growth and innovation, aspects of political and social engagements with poverty across the four  countries to try to identify sources of information that could be used to underpin the development of an indicator of higher education and the public good that can be used across countries. Our fifth objective is to engage openly and critically with selected stakeholders from the section involving them in research design, assessment of findings and considering their user responses to the indicator as it is developed."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
