<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029315_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation Network for Sharing Population Information from Research Entities in East Africa (INSPIRE-EA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Decisions on health policy and provision should be made using high quality data from multiple sources.  The UN have encouraged data to be Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable (FAIR) but much of the data in Africa has not reached the standards of FAIR data. Population data on health are important to measure many of the indicators for the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG), including the Universal Health Coverage (UHC).  In most Eastern African countries, health and demographic sentinel surveillance (HDSS) sites are used to collect health data from within populations. The ALPHA network has demonstrated how HIV data from HDSS can be used to show how HIV affected the population, and the impact of HIV services and policies (including the delivery of anti-retroviral therapy) on the health of people living with HIV. The overall aim of this project is to create the Implementation Network for Sharing Population Information from Research Entities (INSPIRE) network in East Africa. This recognises the value of sharing harmonised, FAIR data across countries and across settings, and it sets up the mechanism by which these data can be produced.   The INSPIRE network will build the key components for the data platform.  Firstly we will bring together the institutions that collect primary data through HDSS, and to outline the benefits and support that such a network could bring to HDSS.  The proposed network would be modelled on the INDEPTH network, and use SAPRIN in South Africa (www.saprin.mrc.ac.za) as an example of how it could work. The goal of this component is to establish a partnership which leverages population health data from different institutions into FAIR data that enables high quality analysis to answer policy relevant questions. The second component is to establish the technical requirements of FAIR data and to make the foundations to produce the data.  Building on the work of ALPHA network, we will use automated methods for HDSS partners to extract, transform and load their own HDSS data into a common database. We will retain the provenance of the data through industry standard data documentation which is important for FAIR data. The project will develop and standardise the vocabulary to describe longitudinal population health data in Africa, contributing to international standards so that researchers can understand and search the data. The project will explore the way in which the population health data can be linked with the electronic health records (EHR), which are being developed in Eastern Africa. The third component will encourage the use of the data in order to make the platform sustainable. The project will identify the value of the data, and change the culture towards population health data, demonstrating how the data can be analysed to answer important health questions. Longitudinal, population data on health, while essential to understanding the demand for health services, has been left behind by the digital revolution. There is an urgent need to change this situation and find a solution which will provide harmonized FAIR data that can be compared across countries and across different health conditions.  This project would establish the partnerships that are needed to develop and maintain such a system, and will set up the technical capacity to be able to set up a FAIR harmonised database for population health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this proposal is to develop a network where health data from longitudinal populations in Africa can be brought together safely and securely, to answer important questions about the health of the population in East Africa. Health data from the population is needed to complement the clinical data from service providers, in order to answer the sustainable development goals (SDG).  To do this we will need to bring together the producers and users of the data and enable the culture change in the data use. We will have to build the secure and accredited processes for the data, the environments for the analysis, and identify the questions that such data can answer. This overall aim of this phase 1 proposal can be broken down into three overarching objectives: 1. To build the network of data professionals in East Africa 2. To build the tools by which FAIR data can be shared 3. To identify policy relevant questions and indicators that can be answered from the initial database. The first objective to build the network that contribute and use longitudinal population-based health data is based on previous projects, such as the INDEPTH network and the ALPHA network. In the initial Phase 1, the data will come from existing health and demographic surveillance systems (HDSS), which are ideally placed to explore human health and the health of the natural environment in which they live. However, the proposed network will not be limited to HDSS. This objective will use the experience of the South African Population Research Infrastructure Network (SAPRIN) to bring together data in a way that can be used to answer real policy-important health questions. Those who contribute data need to get benefits from the network, and the first objective is to bring stakeholders together to formulate the environment to enable deep and meaning collaboration between HDSS in East Africa. The second objective is to produce FAIR data that can be used to answer the research questions. The FAIR data principles come from the International Council of Science (ISC), and the Research Data Alliance (RDA) to ensure high quality data which are Findable, Accessible, Interoperable and Reusable (FAIR). Through the ALPHA network we have shared data that have been used to answer questions about the HIV epidemic in East Africa.  These data will be developed into a demonstration model dataset that could be applied to many other health conditions using longitudinal population-based data. The project will build the portal for FAIR data that is searchable by human (google search) and computer algorithms (such as RDF). Beyond the existing data, this objective is to prepare the work for linking population health data with the electronic health records in Eastern Africa. The third objective relates to the use of the data in the network. We will work with national and international policy makers and analysts to identify questions and indicators that need robust FAIR data to provide accurate answers to guide health policy.  This objective is essential to provide the sustainability of the network going forward, as it enhances the value of the data collected by the individual HDSS and enables the buy in from regional and national governments. This objective will include the training of analysts within Eastern Africa to undertake new analyses using machine learning and artificial intelligence algorithms. These three objectives form the core of this proposal, which will identify the first steps towards integrating health data from population cohorts with clinical health records in order to establish the right environment and infrastructure to health research. The ultimate vision is to develop the network into an active means to support diverse research studies in East Africa and to provide the two-way communication with policy makers and analysis needs of national and international users.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">138112.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">2071681.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029315_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT029315%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
