<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N017722_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Optimizing strategies to diagnose and control intestinal Schistosomiasis in low and moderate endemicity areas of Brazil</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over 200 million people suffer with the disease Schistosomiasis which is caused by the presence in the human blood vessels of trematode worms of the genus Schistosoma. This leads to long term disability and can be fatal. Therefore, intestinal and urinary schistosomiasis are considered serious public health problems in vast regions of Africa, Asia and Latin America. The current mainstream diagnostic method for intestinal schistosomiasis is the detection of eggs in stool by Kato-Katz. This method, however, is limited costly, time-consuming, and may be particularly unreliable where there is low levels of infection, as would be expected after several rounds of treatment or in regions where transmission is low. In order to overcome some of the pitfalls of this diagnostic method, there has been interest in developing new and more sensitive tests for the diagnosis of schistosomiasis.   Antigen detection in urine (CCA) has been documented to be a sensitive and specific alternative to Kato-Katz in several moderate and high endemnicity settings. Data comparing the performance of stool microscopy (Kato-Katz) and a urine dipstick (CCA) in low Schistosomiasis prevalence settings, however, is currently lacking. In this context, the aim of this project is to compare the performance of CCA with Kato-Katz in the low endemic area of Minas Gerais State, and in a moderate endemic area of Sergipe State Brazil.   Furthermore, the study aims to enhance knowledge of the spatial distribution of schistosomiasis in Brazil that will assist planning of the preventive chemotherapy strategy for the national schistosomiasis control programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">11270.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">45174.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">22724.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="1. The primary aim of the proposal is to compare the performance of urine POC- CCA test with Kato-Katz (KK) for the diagnosis of S.mansoni in a low endemic setting of the State of Minas Gerais and moderate prevalence State of Sergipe, Brazil.  2. The secondary objective of this study is to use the findings of this study to assist the National Schistosomiasis Control program to plan the longitudinal preventative chemotherapy strategy in low and moderate endemic districts.  3. These survey results will also facilitate the redefinition of thresholds of S.mansoni infection for the frequency of preventive chemotherapy (PCT) set by the WHO. Currently these guidelines are based on KK results but increasingly CCA is being recognized as a mapping tool and, therefore, the WHO guidelines need to be amended accordingly based on studies such as this.  4. The performance of POC-CCA as a tool to measure the impact of chemotherapy will also be evaluated 30 days post treatment.  5. To compare the performance of POC-CCA with KK to detect re-infection levels six and twelve months after treatment."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
