<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T038861_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Calcium supplementation to prevent pre-eclampsia in Low- and Middle-Income Countries: IPD meta-analysis, network meta-analysis and economic evaluation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHAT IS THE PROBLEM? Pre-eclampsia, a condition in pregnancy associated with high blood pressure and protein in the urine, is a major cause of avoidable deaths in mothers and babies, particularly in low and middle-income countries. Calcium supplements in pregnancy could prevent pre-eclampsia and potentially save 21,500 mothers every year from dying in these countries. Although calcium is on the national essential medicines list of these countries, and the World Health Organization (WHO) recommends high-dose calcium (&gt;1.5g/day) to prevent pre-eclampsia, calcium deficiency in pregnancy continues to be a major preventable public health challenge. We can attribute this to the reluctance of mothers to take large, unpalatable high-dose calcium tablets 3-times a day that is often associated with side effects such as vomiting and constipation. Furthermore, large numbers of bulky tablets pose logistical difficulties with transport and storage, limiting their availability in rural areas. The healthcare professionals also have concerns about the large calcium doses affecting the absorption of iron needed to treat anaemia.    WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE? There is an urgent need for us to identify a) the group of women who will benefit the most from calcium supplementation (based on individual characteristics) b) the most effective and acceptable minimal dose of calcium, and c) the best time to start the supplement to prevent pre-eclampsia and complications. Policymakers and healthcare professionals also need information on the barriers to the uptake of calcium and its implementation, and the cost implications of supplementation within limited healthcare resources.  WHAT HAS BEEN DONE SO FAR? To-date, despite over 30,000 women participating in numerous studies on calcium supplementation to prevent pre-eclampsia, we were able to answer the above questions due to differences in the characteristics of women, the dosage and timing of calcium in these studies. Our international collaborative network (i-CIP) has established a partnership between researchers from low, middle- and high-income countries who conducted the above studies, WHO guideline developers, and experts on calcium supplementation in pregnancy to answer the gaps in research.  WHAT DO WE PLAN TO DO? In this proposal, we plan to combine the data from individuals who participated in studies on calcium supplementation by a technique called &apos;IPD meta-analysis&apos; to determine if the effects of calcium differed between different groups of women, and if it varied according to the dose and duration of calcium use. We will obtain the views of mothers and healthcare professionals through surveys and interviews on what they consider may hinder the uptake and use of the calcium supplementation strategy that we find to be most effective. We will study the costs of calcium supplementation against the costs saved in low- and middle-income countries by avoiding pre-eclampsia and its complications. This economic model will be provided in a format that can be used by experts in other countries to determine the relevant economic impact. Research capacity strengthening of our partners is the key to the long-term sustainability of the project.   WHAT DO WE EXPECT WILL HAPPEN? We expect our findings to lead to an update of the existing WHO guidelines on calcium supplementation in pregnancy, inform policymakers on optimal strategies and costs to promote calcium supplementation, reduce calcium deficiency in pregnant women, and improve outcomes for mother and baby by preventing pre-eclampsia. We planned this proposal in partnership with the patient and public involvement groups so that women are involved in the co-development of the study and dissemination. Our collaboration with WHO (Reproductive health, Nutrition, Human Reproduction Programme HRP Alliance) is key to the development and dissemination of our work through guidelines and existing networks.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-09-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="GH" type="GHANA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="WESTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1030</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">52124.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">153415.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">198509.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="PRIMARY OBJECTIVE  1. To determine using IPD (Individual Participant Data) meta-analysis of randomised trials, the overall and the differential effects of calcium supplementation according to maternal characteristics (risk status, age, parity) and intervention type (dose, timing, duration) on pre-eclampsia, when adjusted for effect modifiers such as baseline dietary calcium intake and other co-interventions.  SECONDARY OBJECTIVES  2. To evaluate the overall effects of calcium supplementation on (i) early-onset pre-eclampsia (&lt;34 weeks&apos; gestation); (ii) adverse maternal outcomes (death, eclampsia, abruption, postpartum haemorrhage, caesarean section, preterm birth, admission to intensive care unit); (iii) adverse offspring outcomes (stillbirth, neonatal death, admission to the neonatal intensive care unit); and (iv) maternal side effects (vomiting, anaemia, HELLP syndrome with Haemolysis, Elevated Liver Enzymes, Low Platelets).  3. To undertake an IPD network meta-analysis to produce a rank order of calcium supplementation strategies according to the recommended daily dose (mg; low vs. high), timing (gestational age; peri-conception, first, second and third trimester), and total dose taken (mg), whilst accounting for effect modifiers (identified from previous steps) to improve consistency (coherence) in the network.  4. To determine the views of women and healthcare professionals in low- and middle-income countries (LMIC) through systematic reviews, Delphi surveys, and Patient and Public Involvement (PPI) on the barriers to the uptake and implementation of the calcium supplementation strategies identified to be effective in preventing pre-eclampsia.  5. To develop a framework for PPI engagement to facilitate mothers&apos; involvement in research in LMIC.  6. To assess the cost-effectiveness of calcium supplementation in pregnancy through a model-based economic evaluation that is presented in an open-access format for use by various economic regions.   7. To establish a living database of randomised trials on calcium supplementation to facilitate future research (prediction and prevention), sustain interdisciplinary collaborations between LMIC partners, WHO, and high-income countries in evidence synthesis (aggregate and IPD meta-analysis) through research capacity building."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
