<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_T012366_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ecological management to benefit ecosystem services and sustainable production in smallholder oil palm systems in Malaysia and Indonesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The expansion of oil palm cultivation has come at a significant cost to tropical biodiversity, but oil palm is also the most productive vegetable oil crop worldwide, is critical for the economies of several ODA countries, and provides jobs and important income sources for millions of people. This project builds on findings from two NERC-funded projects, based within a large-scale experiment in oil palm plantations in Riau, Indonesia, that investigated the potential of alternative understory management practices to increase biodiversity, ecosystem functioning, yield, resilience of ecosystem processes to environmental perturbations, and to control greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. Key findings include beneficial impacts of enhanced understory, where herbicide use was limited, on predators, understory plants, soil invertebrates, below-ground processes, and leaf litter decomposition, with little impact on GHG flux or yield. Although these findings have been well-publicised for large-scale plantations, they have not yet been promoted for smallholder areas, nor management recommendations tested within a smallholder context.   This project has five key objectives: 1. Recruit a network of smallholder farmers in both Indonesia and Malaysia to disseminate the results from earlier work, solicit input on understory vegetation management options via participation in workshops, and quantify the current range of understory management practices across smallholders, using a questionnaire-based approach.  2. Identify smallholders with varying levels of understory vegetation complexity and quantify existing levels of biodiversity, ecosystem functioning (including soil health and fertility), and yield across these plots. Results from this part of the project will allow us to assess the impact of different understory management practices on biodiversity, ecosystem functioning (including greenhouse gas emissions) and yield, and to validate the results of earlier work in a smallholder context.  3. Trial alternative understory management options, informed by results of previous work, and quantify their impact on biodiversity, ecosystem processes (including soil health and fertility), yield, and food security. We will select smallholders with low existing understory vegetation complexity, within which to trial different understory management options. Treatments will include non-herbicide understory management and the planting of understory crops. We will use a split plot design, including both treatment and control sites, to assess the impacts of these treatments on biodiversity, ecosystem functioning and yield. 4. Share results of the project with smallholders to receive feedback and accelerate the uptake of achievable understory management solutions. Management options trialled in this project have the potential to benefit smallholder production and food security, while reducing the environmental impacts. Enhanced uptake of management options could therefore enhance biodiversity and associated ecosystem functions, smallholder food-security and societal prosperity, while reducing herbicide application and the environmental impacts of production. 5. Publish and publicise results widely in the peer-reviewed scientific literature, selected conferences, and in white-papers to engage accreditation bodies and develop tractable management guidelines that are applicable in a smallholder context. Accreditation bodies will include the Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil (RSPO), Indonesian Sustainable Palm Oil (ISPO) and Malaysia Sustainable Palm Oil (MSPO). This approach will ensure impacts continue after the lifetime of this project and over larger scales than this project alone can achieve, benefitting economic and societal prosperity of smallholders, increasing uptake of sustainability schemes by smallholder farmers, and enhancing the sustainability of management practices in the long-term.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will build on a large-scale experimental project, based within large industrial oil palm plantations in Riau, Indonesia, that investigated the impact of varying herbicide use and manual cutting of understory vegetation on biodiversity, ecosystem functioning, greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, resilience to drought, and palm oil yield. Key findings from the work included a positive effect of reducing herbicide use and allowing more understory vegetation to grow on predator numbers, plant diversity, soil biodiversity, rate of decomposition and below ground processes, but with only limited impacts on GHG emissions and yield. In addition to benefitting biodiversity and ecosystem processes in oil palm, reducing levels of herbicide spraying can also potentially save money and pollution risk through runoff of herbicides into waterways . Although these findings have been well-publicised for large-scale industrial plantations, they have not yet been disseminated to small-scale farmers (&quot;smallholders&quot;), although they produce roughly 40% of palm oil production in Indonesia and Malaysia.  This project brings together a strong team of researchers and practitioners from the UK (University of Cambridge and NERC Centre for Ecology and Hydrology (CEH)), Indonesia (IPB University (Bogor Agricultural University) and Sinar Mas Agro Research and Technology Research Institute (SMARTRI)) and Malaysia (Universiti Putra Malaysia (UPM) and Wild Asia), who have expertise in oil palm management, experience of working with smallholders, and a diverse range of viewpoints (researcher, industry and NGO). Using existing strong connections between project team members and the smallholder community, this project will run workshops with networks of smallholders in both Indonesia and Malaysia, to promote uptake of management recommendations from the previous project and solicit feedback from smallholders on the feasibility of using different understory management options within their farms. To assess whether findings from the original project also hold true in a smallholder context, we will measure biodiversity, ecosystem functioning (including GHG emissions) and yield across a range of smallholder plantations that currently use different understory management practices. We will then experimentally trial three different understory management options within smallholder farms that currently have low levels of understory vegetation. We will collect data on biodiversity, ecosystem functioning and yield within these areas as before and use results to identify  management options that benefit both biodiversity, ecosystem processes and food production.  We will ensure outcomes from the project are disseminated clearly with opportunities for feedback, by running workshops and field visits with participating smallholders in both Indonesia and Malaysia. We will also work with sustainability schemes, such as the Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil (RSPO) to make sure that results feed into sustainability guidelines, promoting the uptake of successful management options on a wider scale and over a longer timeframe than this project alone can achieve. By identifying management options that promote more environmentally friendly palm oil production, greater diversity of crops, as well as reduced herbicide applications, the results of this work have the potential to benefit the environment, as well as smallholder productivity, health, income and food security.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133903" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-25">252697.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF Standard Grant Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB/T012366/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-03-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-03-31">43943.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FQ2 2021-2022 spend on Ecological management to benefit ecosystem services and sustainable production in smallholder oil palm systems in Malaysia and Indonesia</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_T012366_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">LONDON SCHOOL OF HYGIENE AND TROPICAL MEDICINE</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FT012366%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
