<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002888_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">How do local participatory governance reforms influence equitable access to health services? The role of Panchayati Raj Institutions in Kerala, India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Public Health Foundation of India, the London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine and the National Health Systems Resource Centre (NHSRC) of the Ministry of Health &amp; Family Welfare, Government of India will come together to explore how local participatory governance (LPG) reforms influence equitable access to health services. LPG of social sectors (such as health or education) entails decentralised planning and oversight of services, undertaken through participatory and deliberative processes involving local communities and stakeholders. The salutary impact of LPG on health access is widely acknowledged, however the actual pathways of such change are not well researched, and the role of context in influencing these pathways also remains poorly understood.  This research aims to address these gaps in the knowledge, using the case study of Panchayati Raj Institution (PRI) reforms in Kerala state, India. In India, LPG is synonymous with PRIs - locally elected bodies operating at village, sub-district and district levels with financial and administrative powers over social services including health care. Kerala is an example of extensively implemented PRI reform, and hence offers a best-practices scenario for clear identification of contexts and pathways of influence.  Our conceptual model is informed by global evidence suggesting that LPG reforms have influences on multiple governance arenas, including politics, civil society and public administration. Resultant improvements in political accountability, community empowerment and health system responsiveness can act synergistically to enhance equitable access to health care. These broad putative pathways of influence provide a basic framework for more detailed empirical investigation.  Specific objectives: 1. Explicate the pathways through which institutions of local participatory governance (LPG) influence access to health care for the poor and vulnerable, through a case study of the Panchayati Raj Institution (PRI) local governance system in Kerala state, India 2. Understand the policy context of implementation of Kerala&apos;s PRI reforms for LPG in health care 3. Explore and strengthen the application of innovative Health Policy &amp; Systems Research (HPSR) approaches in exploring LPG and its influence on equitable access to health care across different low &amp; middle-income country (LMIC) settings  The study will engage innovative HPSR approaches drawing on the social sciences, including realist enquiry and actor-focused approaches to policy implementation. Qualitative methodology, including in-depth interviews and focus groups conducted in four districts, will help access the lived experiences of involved policy actors (representing PRI committees, service users, civil society and health systems). Data will be analyzed using the &quot;framework&quot; approach for policy research developed by the UK National Centre for Social Research, combining pre-determined and emerging themes.  Data collection strategies will be revised iteratively as the study progresses, an approach that will be fundamental to innovating with HPSR methods. Towards the end of the study, we will convene a workshop to share preliminary findings and develop a larger proposal. The larger proposal will examine the role of LPG mechanisms in facilitating greater access to services in several Indian states and countries in sub-Saharan Africa.  The study emerges from needs expressed by policymakers in India, for deeper understanding of how to support LPG for health, and will fulfill that need. The integral role of NHSRC in the study will facilitate policy uptake of findings. The findings will support accountability and greater citizen participation in decisions that affect them - and ultimately greater access to healthcare for marginalized people, across LMIC settings. The study will also contribute to conceptual innovation and methods in the field of HPSR, and help strengthen UK-India research collaborations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2014-08-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-05-04">62299.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-05-04">15674.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This proposal for a development grant is focused on the question: &quot;How do local participatory governance (LPG) reforms influence better and more equitable access to quality health services?&quot;. We will investigate the case of Panchayati Raj Institution (PRI) reforms in Kerala state, India, with a view to extending the focus to LPG reforms in multiple low and middle-income country (LMIC) settings, as part of a full proposal in the next iteration of the call.  PRIs are locally elected governing bodies operating at village, sub-district and district levels in India, that are granted financial and administrative powers over all social services including health care. Specific objectives are as follows:  Objective 1. Explicate the pathways through which institutions of local participatory governance (LPG) influence access to health care for the poor and vulnerable, through a case study of the Panchayati Raj Institution (PRI) local governance system in Kerala state, India  Objective 2. Understand the policy context of implementation of Kerala&apos;s Panchayati Raj Institutional reforms for local participatory governance in health care.   LPG reforms are widely understood to have a salutary influence on access to quality health services, especially for the poor and vulnerable (Bossert et al. 2003, Rifkin 1996). Governance reforms are complex, and LPG reforms are theorized to improve health service responsiveness, community empowerment, and political and administrative accountability, with an eventual impact on better health care access.  However these putative pathways of change are not well substantiated by empirical research from different settings. Furthermore, the role of context in shaping these pathways of influence is poorly understood.  This research is proposed to address these gaps in the knowledge. (The causal link between better access to health services for the poor and vulnerable, and improved and more equitable health outcomes, is assumed based on evidence from multiple settings (Mosquera et al. 2012, WHO Commission on Macroeconomics &amp; Health 2002), and does not form part of this enquiry.)  This research will be conducted in Kerala state of India, in the context of the national, constitutionally mandated, yet partially implemented, Panchayati Raj reforms for local participatory governance. Kerala is an example of extensively implemented PRI reform, with deep involvement of PRIs in health care provisioning and financing, and demonstrated positive impact on health care access for vulnerable communities. Kerala offers a best-practices scenario that facilitates rich enquiry and clear identification of contexts and pathways defining the influence of LPG reform on health care access.    Objective 3. Explore and strengthen the application of innovative Health Policy &amp; Systems Research (HPSR) approaches - focusing on actors, processes and complexity - in exploring local participatory governance and its influence on equitable access to health care across different low and middle-income country (LMIC) settings  We will explore applications of innovative health policy and systems research (HPSR) approaches, to investigate the relationship between LPG reforms and equitable health care access. Principles of &apos;realist&apos; enquiry (Pawson and Tilley 2002) can be helpful in understanding how contexts and mechanisms of governance interact to create desired outcomes.  Actor-centred approaches (Hjern and Hull 1982,Walt and Gilson 1994) view policy implementation as involving interactions and negotiations between groups of actors within complex social and organizational contexts. The important final objective of the development grant thus focuses on identifying and refining the research approach, while developing the subsequent, full proposal for further research in India and Africa."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q1">15674.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002888_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Health Foundation of India (PHFI)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">7583.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002888_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Health Foundation of India (PHFI)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
