<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_S012885_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SAFERGUARDING SONORA&apos;S WHEAT FROM CLIMATE CHANGE</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sonora contributes 45% of the total wheat production in Mexico, however this is becoming increasingly compromised by high temperature and drought, which are an increasing problem in Sonora and globally due to climate change. There is therefore a growing urgency to &quot;safeguard&quot; Sonora&apos;s wheat from heat and drought stress.  Within this project, a unique wheat panel will be assembled representing the most tolerant wheat genotypes and varieties currently known, globally. This Heat and Drought panel will be evaluated and analysed under field conditions in Sonora to select the best-performers and these will be analysed in detail at the molecular and physiological level to unravel the tolerance mechanisms and identify the underlying genes. Most molecular-physiological studies on stress responses have been conducted using intolerant reference genotypes, mainly because genetic resources are available, and in addition, plants are often grown under laboratory conditions. We therefore presently have very little information on tolerant-specific stress responses in crops, and even less in wheat. This project will therefore generate a first-of-its-kind comprehensive study on &quot;true&quot; tolerance mechanisms in wheat and this will have large implications for the research community and for breeding programs.  One of the drought responsive pathways that will be analysed in detail within this project is related to the role of sugars in stress tolerance and the regulation of sugar allocation to seeds via trehalose-6-phosphate (T6P). It has already been proven that external application of T6P can enhance drought tolerance and the genes within this pathway are therefore prime targets of this project. One of these genes (TPS) is of particular interest and has already been subjected to gene editing using CRIPR-Cas9 technology. There are currently very few studies that go beyond the proof-of-concept that this technology works in wheat and this project will therefore pioneer this breakthrough technology for applications in wheat improvement, providing a land-mark study.   Sharing expertise and joining forces, this project will be conducted in collaboration between CIAD in Sonora and Rothamsted Research (RRes) in the UK, building on the broad expertise and pre-existing collaborations of the PIs, their established partnership with CIMMYT and ICARDA, as well as integration with ongoing wheat research programs, such as &quot;Designing Future Wheat&quot; (DFW) in the UK, &quot;International Wheat Yield Partnership&quot; (IWYP) or &quot;Wheat for a Hot and Dry Climate&quot;, an Australian Industrial Transformation Research Hub.   The data generated within this project will not only greatly enhance our understanding of tolerance mechanisms in wheat, but, via this existing network, will inform breeders about which traits and genes to target and select for. Through provision of validated heat and drought tolerant germplasm, detailed information on tolerance mechanisms for better targeted phenotyping and selection, as well as molecular markers for selection of superior tolerance-related genes, this project will enable tolerance breeding whilst doing excellent science.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project has four main objectives that are interdependent, building on the germplasm assembled in objective 1 and leading to the translation of the findings in objective 4:  Objective 1: Identify heat &amp; drought (H&amp;D) tolerant wheat genotypes for Sonora  Within this project we will compile a unique, global heat and drought tolerance wheat panel with genotypes nominated by CIMMYT and ICARDA, and based on new unpublished data (activity 1.1). This panel will comprise around 20 genotypes that will be tested under field conditions in Sonora during two years under early and late planting, and farmer&apos;s practise (activity 1.2). Performance of the panel under heat and drought stress will be assessed by monitoring tillering, phenology, pollen fertility, &amp; yield components, and photosynthetic capacity (activity 1.3). Based on the outcome of these field evaluations, best performing genotypes will be selected and plant samples and seeds used (activity 1.4) for in-depth analysis within objectives 2 and 3.   Objective 2: Dissect physiological and molecular mechanisms underlying heat &amp; drought tolerance To distinguish tolerant and intolerant wheat genotypes, we will analyse pollen fertility and seed size and shape using field samples (activity 2.1). In parallel, we will evaluate known plant stress-responses to establish which processes, pathways and genes are truly relevant for tolerance (activity 2.2). For this, we will grow the panel in controlled environments under heat, drought, heat &amp; drought stress at RRes and at CIAD to quantify selected metabolites and measure a suite of enzymes targeting relevant pathways. Tolerant-specific pathways will be validated in field-grown material (activity 2.3) and the underlying genes will be analysed to establish tolerant-specific expression patterns and/or gene alleles (activity 2.4). Sequence variations will be targeted for molecular marker design (see objective 4) to reveal opportunities for gene editing approaches.   Objective 3: Establish the role of the T6P signalling pathway in wheat under heat &amp; drought stress The T6P signalling pathway has been demonstrated to improve yields during drought at flowering and to enhance drought recovery. Within this project, we will establish how this pathway can be used to improve tolerance in wheat. Wheat gene candidates have already been identified and one candidate gene is currently being targeted in wheat with genome editing and performance of the edited lines under heat and drought stress will be assessed within this project (activity 3.1). At CIAD, transgenic wheat lines expressing the yeast TPS1-TPS2 bifunctional enzyme have been generated and showed improved drought tolerance and photosynthesis. These lines will be analysed in detail under heat and drought stress at CIAD (activity 3.2). Expression of the trehalose pathway genes will be analysed in the panel (activity 3.3) and re-sequenced in selected genotypes (activity 3.4) for in-depth analysis and marker development (see objective 4).   Objective 4: Translation of findings for breeding applications Tolerant-specific gene alleles can be directly translated into the design of molecular markers. Depending on the nature of the sequence variation, we will develop single nucleotide or insertion-deletion markers, but ideally KASP markers (activity 4.1). These markers will be provided to CIMMYT, CIRAD, and breeding companies that are partner within &quot;Designing Future Wheat&quot; and in the Australian research hub &quot;Wheat for a Hot and Dry Climate&quot; (activity 4.2). This network will also provide access to mapping populations for trait and gene validation and gene-trait association using the data and markers developed within the project. It might however be necessary to develop novel populations using our best performing wheat genotypes (activity 4.3). Depending on the progress made and the targeted sequence variation, we will explore opportunities for gene editing via CRISPR-Cas9 (activity 4.4).</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-03">170827.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-03">172211.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-03">173606.13</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
