<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R020345_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harnessing the benefits of African leafy vegetables for smallholder farmers and their households</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa is one of the most unequal countries in the world; 55% of the population live in poverty with 25% in extreme poverty. Food shortages and poor nutrition affect many households, with 24% of under-fives stunted. Poor nutrition is not just a lack of macronutrients but of micronutrients, minerals and vitamins which have an impact on health. 17% of children and 19% of pregnant women in South Africa are deficient in vitamin A. The smallholder sector comprises approx. 2 million farms most of which are on land with degraded soil and low rainfall; these areas have the highest prevalence of poverty and food and nutrition problems. Productivity is low. Most areas in South Africa are prone to drought and 8 out of 9 provinces have received progressively less rainfall since 1970. Inadequate rainfall causes reduced yields, especially in the smallholder farming sector where farmers cannot afford irrigation. Hence, there is an urgent need to develop strategies to ensure sufficient nutritional food and a source of income for these farmers and their households in a sustainable manner, i.e. produced in a way that is resilient to environmental fluctuation and does not deplete natural resources. Although neglected and underutilised, African leafy vegetables (ALVs) offer unique opportunities to diversify farming systems, contribute to climate change adaptation, ensure food security, alleviate poverty, increase income and improve human health (particularly malnutrition and lack of micronutrients). Most communities affected by poverty and undernutrition live in areas rich in biodiversity, including ALVs. A key attribute of ALVs is their high nutritional content with many studies indicating higher levels of vitamins and minerals compared to cultivated vegetables, such as cabbage and spinach. The consumption of ALVs is in decline in many rural communities which has contributed to poor diets and increased incidence of nutritional deficiencies. Currently, ALVs are harvested from the wild rather than cultivated. This is unsustainable and already a decline in the wild population of ALVs has been reported due to over-harvesting and lack of seed production. ALVs are well-adapted to local growing conditions. ALVs grow on marginal land with little input. They are hardy and able to thrive in both drought and flood times. As a result ALVs are available during harsh environmental conditions when most cultivated crops would have failed, and indeed harvesting and consumption of ALVs from the wild increases in rural regions during times of drought to help meet food shortages. The cultivation of ALVs would play a role in increasing agro-biodiversity which helps suppress pests and disease, as well as protect against the effects of climate variability. ALVs also have the potential to contribute to household income because of their relatively high value. With increased reliability of supply, it would be possible to develop new value chains such as selling through supermarkets. Thus increased cultivation and utilisation of ALVs would improve nutrition, provide resilience of food supply in the face of climate change, improve the environmental sustainability of smallholder agriculture and diversify income opportunities. However, to help increase cultivation and utilisation of ALVs it is necessary to develop lines which maintain their ability to grow with low inputs and under fluctuating climate, and maintain their nutritional benefits but have increased yield. In this proposal we will develop such varieties for the most common ALV in Southern Africa, Amaranthus, using a combination of molecular analysis, metabolic profiling of nutrient content, genomics, participatory breeding with smallholder farmers, and analysis of susceptibility to pests. We will deliver improved lines which can then be promoted by the Agricultural Research Council in South Africa to improve the nutrition, livelihoods and environmental sustainability of smallholder households.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this proposal is to develop improved lines of amaranth to facilitate the cultivation and consumption of this African leafy vegetable by smallholder farmers in sub-Saharan Africa. Growing and consuming amaranth would increase the nutritional content of smallholder household diets, provide agro-ecological benefits, improve food security by being a climate-tolerant crop, and provide opportunities for income generation. One key aim of this proposal is to facilitate faster improvement by developing the biological knowledge and tools for molecular analysis, and using the genetic diversity within the ARC amaranth germplasm collection. Specific objectives are to: 1. Capture and utilise genetic diversity in amaranth to generate lines with robust increased leaf volume (yield) under the variable growing conditions typical of smallholder farmers We will determine the variation in yield and nutritional content in the ARC amaranth germplasm collection to identify lines with particularly beneficial traits and highlight excellent parents for future crossing and breeding strategies. We will generate an F2 mapping population from parents differing in yield and nutritional value and use the mapping population diversity to select higher yielding lines. The segregating F2 population will be used in participatory plant breeding both on the research station and on smallholder farms to select lines with increased leaf volume and good sensory qualities when grown under low input, highly variable conditions. Smallholders in regions of South Africa with varying rainfall will be involved to determine whether the same lines perform well in different locations.  2. Determine the genetic basis of secondary metabolite accumulation (hence nutritional value) in amaranth and link specific metabolites to important agronomic traits (pest resistance and yield) In addition to increasing genetic variation for yield, the mapping population will be used to understand the genetic regulation of nutrient and anti-nutrient accumulation, and highlight any correlations between nutritional value, yield and pest resistance. The F2 mapping population will be genotyped and phenotyped for metabolite profile (nutritional value), yield and pest resistance to determine genomic regions and markers linked to metabolites of nutritional importance and understand potential trade-offs between micronutrients, yield and pest resistance. This will drive further breeding and development of improved amaranth lines (and ultimately stable distinct varieties) and help prevent development of material with enhanced nutritional benefit but poor performance in the field. We will train South African plant breeders in the use of molecular breeding strategies (including GBS and marker development) and develop markers that can be used in breeding for nutritional content and to ensure quality of seed production going forwards.  3. Determine the water use efficiency of amaranth and the impact of water limitation on nutritional content.  There is a lack of detailed information on the drought tolerance and water use efficiency of the diverse locally adapted amaranth accessions, hence we will investigate this in our improved yield lines, the mapping population parents and accessions from the germplasm collection with highly diverse nutritional profiles. We will also determine the nutrient water use efficiency of these lines. This is a measure of how much the nutrient profile is impacted by water availability. For example, a line could have a high nutrient content under well-watered conditions, but a low nutrient content if water is limiting.  Understanding the molecular basis of nutritional content, how it correlates with pest resistance and yield, and how it is impacted by water availability will be essential for improvement of yield whilst ensuring nutritional value and key traits for amaranth&apos;s value in diversified low input smallholder farming systems are maintained.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-07">208436.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-07">279603.23</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-07">137280.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-07">67238.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-07">827035.392</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF Standard Grant Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R020345_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FR020345%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
