<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008024_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Creating Safer Space: Strengthening Civilian Protection Amidst Violent Conflict</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Network Plus &quot;Creating Safer Space&quot; supports the enhancement and expansion of effective local unarmed civilian protection (UCP) practices for and with civilians in conflict regions. To work toward this vision it pursues 8 objectives: 1) Strengthen exchange and collaboration of the UCP community of practice/research An active global community of practice/research engaged in exchange and learning is key to creating an evidence base of effective UCP. The Network connects UCP actors across countries and regions through networking events and scoping visits, and incentivises South-South collaborative research to enable in-depth and cross-case insight. [Strands 1, 2] 2) Develop the research capacity of UCP academics and practitioners Local civilian protection is best understood, enhanced and expanded through collaborative research and engagement activities that involve conflict-affected communities. This Network sets workshops around participatory, creative and digital methods to expand knowledge of inclusive research strategies and incentivise participatory research that is context-sensitive, needs-based and potentially transformative - with the aim to build/strengthen local civilian protection. [Strand 1] 3) Develop a tailored evaluation and monitoring mechanism for UCP Evaluation and monitoring (E&amp;M) are essential to UCP work but challenging in practice due to its context-specificity and bottom-up approach. The Network collaborates with the Everyday Peace Indicators project to develop a tailored, context-sensitive, community-focused E&amp;M method able to capture the primacy of the local and the dynamic interplay of factors affecting protection outcomes. [Strand 1] 4) Enhance understanding of civilians&apos; vulnerabilities in violent conflict Foundational research into the complexities, intersectionality and dynamics of vulnerability, agency and resilience of civilians in violent conflicts is essential to a contextualised understanding of the need for and impact of UCP. The Network encourages in-depth research that enhances and nuances understandings of vulnerability in order to improve protection. [Strand 2, Theme A] 5) Provide a solid evidence base of successful local UCP/self-protection Understanding how local unarmed protection by outside actors and community self-protection work and interact is central to building local protection infrastructures that have the potential to become self-sustaining and provide safer space for development. The Network incentivises in-depth single-case studies and research that engages in cross-country or cross-regional collaboration, to establish a solid evidence base of success factors in the interplay of outside protection and community self-protection strategies with the aim to establish/enhance long-term local protection infrastructures. [Strand 2, Theme B] 6) Explore potentials to expand effective UCP in scope, size and actor range UCP has so far been successfully implemented on a relatively small scale. The Network supports research, through South-South collaborations and Sowing Seeds grants, that explores how existing approaches can be scaled up in size, transferred to new contexts, and/or adopted by new organisations or communities working to protect civilians in conflict. [Strand 2, Theme C] 7) Develop a UCP typology Synthesising research findings from four paradigmatic cases of UCP (Colombia, Myanmar, Philippines, South Sudan), the Network will develop the first typology of conditions of possibility of effective unarmed self-/protection. [Strand 2] 8) Share knowledge to protect more people The Network&apos;s dissemination and impact activities work toward enhancing existing protection work, expanding successful UCP approaches in size and scope, and consolidating the political, institutional and financial support for local protection, with a view to protect more conflict-affected persons from harm, decrease forced displacement and facilitate development. [Strand 3]</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&quot;Creating Safer Space&quot; is a four-year international, interdisciplinary research network, which supports local civilian processes that build sustainable structures of protection from physical harm for and with communities affected by violent conflict. The Network brings together conflict-affected communities, protection practitioners, academics, policymakers and artists to jointly work on the vision of enhancing unarmed protection practices, which create safer space for communities and individuals amidst violent conflict, raise their levels of resilience and help prevent displacement. According to the UN Refugee Agency, there are now a record high of 68.5 million people forcibly displaced by violent conflict (UNHCR 2019), and the majority of deaths in conflicts are among civilians. This makes the protection of civilians from physical harm in contexts of war a pressing issue of our time. While the international community has acknowledged the need for protection, the physical safety of civilians is still seen almost exclusively as a task of armed outside actors like UN blue helmets. The originality of this Network is its focus on protection provided by unarmed actors and deployed at the local level of communities, be it by &quot;outside&quot; specialists or &quot;insider/local&quot; protection actors. Unarmed civilian protection (UCP) organisations accompany human rights defenders and deter armed actors from carrying out attacks against them through their presence and proactive engagement strategies. They use networks of relationships built with armed and unarmed parties to a conflict to negotiate safe passage of internally displaced persons to a safe camp or to bring forcefully recruited youth back to their families. They also monitor ceasefires &amp; agreements. Moreover, some violence-affected communities self-protect by setting up peace communities and weapons-free zones, creating safer space for civilian life amidst violent conflict. There are over 40 international NGOs and a growing number of national and local organisations currently undertaking protection work in 24 countries in conflict, in addition to local self-protection initiatives. They illustrate that the protection of civilians by civilians without the use or threat of force can work to create physical safety, and may even do more: by providing a role model, and by not fuelling further violence, UCP can help break cycles of violence and thus contribute to longer-term peacebuilding. Initial research has suggested that UCP may often be more effective than armed protection and indeed, latest UN Security Council and General Assembly resolutions mention the potential of UCP, indicating some change in thinking. &quot;Creating Safer Space&quot; aims to enhance and broaden the practice of UCP by engaging a wide range of stakeholders in networking, capacity-building, research and impact activities around three broad themes: A. Understanding vulnerability to physical harm in violent conflict: Which different kinds of vulnerabilities interact in what ways in situations that require protection, and which different protection strategies do they require? B. Building local protection infrastructures: How can outside protection strategies and self-protection mechanisms in communities work together for best protection results and without undermining each other? C. Developing civilian protection capabilities: How can unarmed local protection be scaled up in size/scope and include new actors and collaborations with a view to protect more people from violence and displacement and develop stronger protection capacity? To address these questions, our Network delivers activities for academic and non-academic partners from the Global North and South across three strands of work: networking and capacity enhancement; collaborative and innovative research; and knowledge sharing and advocacy. Taken together, these activities aim to increase the number of people benefiting from civilian protection worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aberystwyth University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-12">231204.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-12">116538.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-12">117482.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-12">236867.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-12">78633528.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Large Grants Award to Aberystwyth University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008024_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aberystwyth University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT008024%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
