<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S011811_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ARBOLES: A trait-based Understanding of LATAM Forest Biodiversity and Resilience</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latin American forests cover a very large latitudinal and climate gradient extending from the tropics to Southern hemisphere high latitudes. The continent therefore hosts a large variety of forest types including the Amazon - the world&apos;s largest tropical forest - as well as the diverse Atlantic forests concentrated along the coast, temperate forests in Chile and Argentina as well as the cold rainforests of Valdivia and the Nothofagus forests of Patagonia. These forests are global epicentres of biological diversity and include several tropical and extra-tropical biodiversity hotspots. For example, the  Amazon rainforest is home to ~10% of terrestrial plant and animal species and store a large fraction of global organic carbon. hotspots.   Some of these Latin American forests still cover a large fraction of their original (pre-colombian) extent: the Amazon still covers approximately 5 Million km2, which is 80% of its original area. However, others, such as the Atlantic forest, have nearly disappeared and are now heavily fragmented. Temperate forests have also shrunk, despite efforts to halt further reduction. However, economic development, population rises and the growth in global drivers of environmental change mean that all forests now face strong anthropogenic pressures. Locally stressors generally result from ongoing development, selective logging, the hunting of larger birds and mammals, over-exploitation of key forest resources such as valuable palm fruits, mining, and/or forest conversion for agricultural use.   Global environmental drivers stem from the world&apos;s warming climate. Yet it is not clear how these local pressures and changing environmental conditions will alter the composition of Latin American forests, and whether there are thresholds between human impacts - such as the lack of dispersers in heavily fragmented forest landscapes or climate conditions exceeding limits of species tolerance - and the community level responses of forest plants.  We aim to investigate this, supporting the development of strategies that can preserve the diversity of these forests and their functioning. We achieve this by investigating the relationships between diversity and functioning of these forests; exploring whether there are thresholds in functioning resulting both from pressures of forest use and changing climate; by experimentally testing responses; and by generalizing predictive capability to large scales.  ARBOLES aims to achieve these goals by integrating established forest inventory approaches with cutting-edge functional trait, genomics, experimental and remote sensing approaches.  Our approach involves combining forest plots with plant traits, which will enable us to characterize state and shifts over time in the face of local human disturbance and changing climate and atmospheric composition. We will focus on traits along the following axes: (i) life-history strategies measuring investment in structure (like wood density, leaf mass per area, maximum height), (ii) investment in productive organs (like leaf nutrients), (iii) investment in reproductive organs, (iv) tolerance to water stress and heat stress. The work is being conducted in collaboration with research groups in Argentina, Brazil, Chile and Peru - and will provide a first cross-continent assessment of how humans are influencing Latin American forests.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching objective of ARBOLES is to assess how plant functional traits underpin 1) biodiversity patterns, 2) shifts in biodiversity in responses to global environmental change and 3) regeneration success along gradients of anthropogenic influence across LATAM forests.  We achieve this by first synthesizing the wealth of forest tree traits information across the wide spectrum of forests extending from the tropics to Southern hemisphere high latitudes in South America and long-term forest plot observations.  As important gaps exist in some regions - such as our understanding of climate &apos;resilience&apos; traits - we will also collect new data where needed. The resulting large-scale dataset on tree inventories and traits will become a powerful tool to understand and predict future biodiversity trajectories.  Within this component:  Objective 1 (O1) examines the trait-basis of biodiversity patterns across LATAM forests.  Objective 2 (O2) assesses the trait basis of biodiversity shifts across old-growth LATAM forests, linking these to global environmental change.  Objective 3 (O3) investigates the trait basis of regeneration success along gradients of forest loss, disturbance and defaunation across human-modified LATAM forests.   We also use targeted case studies to investigate whether plant functional traits underpin germination/survivorship success in restoration activities, to yield insights for climate-smart restoration, agriculture and forestry. Here, specific Objective 4 (O4) will evaluate the trait-basis of restoration success (O4a) and climate-smart forestry/agriculture (O4b) through case studies in Brazil and Peru.   We develop two complementary approaches to scale up community-level traits to produce high resolution ecosystem trait/function maps spanning tropical, montane and temperate LATAM biomes. This is Objective 5 (O5), which provides scaled-up knowledge of trait variation in space and time, developing proof-of-concept work in Brazil and Peru and applying this to Argentina and Chile. This aims to provide the basis for rational and effective future biodiversity conservation strategies as well as tools for low-cost future surveys.   Finally, although not a specific project objective, we aim to use our novel understanding to support decisions about biodiversity conservation and restoration. We also aim to support capacity building and scientific development in ODA eligible partner countries - Argentina, Brazil and Peru - and create a network of LATAM and UK scientists that will last well beyond the lifetime of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">95976.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">384684.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">363028.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">263365.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-25">1107054.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE/S011811/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FS011811%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
