<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N016491_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Upscaling Catchment Processes for Sustainable Water Management in Peninsular India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic development and population growth in Peninsular India have resulted in rapid changes to land-use, land-management and water demand which together are seriously impacting and degrading water resources. Urbanization, deforestation, agricultural intensification, shifts between irrigated agriculture and rain-fed crops, increased groundwater use, and the proliferation of small-scale surface water storage interventions, such as farm-level bunds (usually to conserve soil moisture in fields) and check-dams (to replenish local aquifers) all have contributed to significant changes in the hydrological functioning of catchments. The impact of such changes and interventions on local hydrological processes, such as streamflow, groundwater recharge and evapotranspiration, are poorly constrained, and our understanding of how these diverse local changes cumulatively impact water availability at the broader basin-scale is very limited. Focussing on the highly contentious inter-state Cauvery River basin (with an area of c.80,000 km2, the Cauvery is one of India&apos;s largest river basins) our study addresses the key scientific challenge of representing the many local, small-scale interventions in Peninsular India at larger scales. Using observations from established experimental catchments in both rural and urban settings, the project will first explore how changes in land-use, land-cover, irrigation practices and small-scale water management interventions locally affect hydrological processes. In tandem we will then develop novel upscaling methods to represent the improved process-understanding in models at the larger sub-basin (Kabini, ~10,000 km2) and basin (Cauvery) scales. In so doing, the project will demonstrate the capability to generically represent the cumulative impact of abundant small-scale changes in basin-wide integrated water resources management models. The impact of local-scale interventions will further be modelled alongside projections of population growth, climate- and land-use-change and water demand to assess future impacts on water security across the basin. Key stakeholders are involved throughout the different stages of the project to ensure that project outputs reflect their interests and concerns and provide useful input to their decision making.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-28">224557.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-28">175971.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-28">133047.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Focussing on the highly contentious inter-state Cauvery River basin the project addresses the key scientific challenge of representing the many local, small-scale water management interventions in Peninsular India in larger scale decision making. Using observations from established experimental catchments in both rural and urban settings and multi-scale hydrological modelling, the project will meet the following objectives to:     1) Further understand of how small-scale anthropogenic drivers of hydrological change cumulatively impact on water security at the basin-scale;     2) Develop novel methods for upscaling improved local-scale process understanding in basin-wide integrated water resources models through:          a. Exploring how small-scale rural water management and urban heterogeneity can be represented at large-scales;          b. Applying two exemplar models to the Cauvery basin to demonstrate the applicability of new upscaling methods;          c. Understanding future pressures on water resources within the Cauvery basin through modelling of population, climate, land-use, cropping, damming, sectoral water demands and irrigation efficiency scenarios.     3) Investigate the key hydrological processes operating in rural Peninsular India catchments, applying coupled surface and groundwater models to assess how local interventions affect water availability including:          a. Characterising key parameters controlling the connectivity of the system: aquifer permeability and stratification, soil permeability, key anthropogenic changes such as check-dams, reservoirs, and irrigation transfers;           b. Quantifying the dynamic water flows in Berambadi catchment, including stream flows, evapotranspiration, infiltration and groundwater recharge, soil moisture, and groundwater levels, using a combination of existing infrastructure, targeted hydrological monitoring, and campaign sampling;          c. Exploring the net impacts on water stores and flows of different physical processes, interventions and water demand scenarios (including land-use and irrigation technologies) at a local field-scale using numerical models at hillslope- and catchment-scale;          d. Using models to assess the hydrological system sensitivity to: abstractions and impoundments for storage or recharge; land-use, cropping and irrigation technology; and climate change.       4) Explore how urban and peri-urban development in Peninsular India impact on groundwater recharge and surface hydrology through:          a. Understanding the complexity of urban water processes and establishing parameters and a typology of the urban water balance to inform basin-scale model;          b. Describing the evolution of chemical and microbiological contamination and changes in shallow and deep groundwater stores and surface water stores;          c. Quantifying changes in consumptive use of surface- and ground-water alongside water quality changes in the Jakkur Lake and Binamangala-kere urban catchment observatories.       5) Demonstrate how the new science and integrative systems-level modelling can be encapsulated into water resource management planning in Peninsular India through:          a. Developing a decision support system capable of evaluating water resources management strategies at local, catchment and basin scales;          b. Providing policy guidance on surface-groundwater use which identify future agricultural and urban water management options for state, municipal and basin authorities."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
