<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T003138_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Regionalism in East Africa c. 1900 to the present</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will undertake the first comprehensive historical study of regionalism in East Africa in the twentieth century and will assess both the successes and limitations of regional integration projects to the present. The project will employ a combination of history and politics methodologies to examine political and economic strands of integration projects and explain both continuity and change in projects of regional integration over time. The project will provide new perspectives on East Africa&apos;s history beyond a nation-state framework, whilst simultaneously demonstrating the significance of the nation-state and nationalism in shaping regionalism as a political and economic phenomenon. The project will contribute to policy and educational initiatives in East Africa and in Europe related to this theme, in a political context where the benefits and costs of regional integration remain the subject of vociferous debate in East Africa and across the world. Working with organisations in both East Africa and in Europe, this project will build on a pilot phase (Regionalism in East Africa 1960-1977) funded by the British Academy to undertake the following: a) build an international research team of historians and political scientists with interests in both political and economic approaches to ensure a comprehensive methodological approach b) archival and library research in East Africa, Europe, the USA and Britain to gather a range of archival documentation, press material and official reports pertinent to the project c) conduct interviews with (current and retired) regional and national officials, politicians, journalists, civil society and business representatives, and donor officials regarding the politics of regionalism in its national, regional and global dimensions.   d) write the first book-length study of the history of regionalism in East Africa and one accompanying peer-reviewed journal article. These outputs will be of comparative interest to historians and political scientists working on regionalism in other parts of the world, as well as East Africa specialists.  e) write policy briefings and an end-of-project policy report for the East African Community (EAC), African Union (AU), European Union (EU), Foreign and Commonwealth Office (FCO), Department for International Development (DFID) in partnership with Co-Is and collaborators. f) organise a conference in Nairobi, Kenya for policy practitioners, civil society groups and East African academics and students to reflect on the contemporary and historical politics of regional integration, and thus build further communication between the EAC and some of its key stakeholder groups in the region. g) contribute to curriculum development and delivery of research-informed teaching in East African Higher Education on the theme of regional integration (specifically at the Institute for Regional Integration and Development at the Catholic University of Eastern Africa). Materials gathered and archived during the course of the project will be made available to scholars and students working on the subject matter.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will undertake the first comprehensive historical study of regionalism in East Africa in the twentieth century. Ideas about formal political and economic integration among the various territories of East Africa have a deep history in the region, dating back to the colonial period, and currently manifested in the institutions of the (second) East African Community, an intergovernmental organisation comprised of six eastern African states: Kenya, Tanzania, Uganda, Rwanda, Burundi and South Sudan.  Partly owing to this deep and continuing history, East African regionalism has often been seen as a beacon of effective regional integration in Africa, and assertions of a powerful sense of common regional identity - even destiny - have been an important part of the official rhetoric of the EAC over several decades. But the extent to which regional integration has delivered positive public outcomes or alternatively simply served the interests of a small regional elite in East Africa remains hotly contested (reflecting broader global debates on this issue). This project will engage this central question within both a regional and global setting, examining the origins, character and outcomes of regional integration initiatives as the product both of East African internal dynamics as well as of interlinked global structures and processes (colonialism, decolonisation, global regionalisms, and neo-liberalism). In so doing it will fill a major lacunae in the current scholarly literature on the history and politics of East Africa, moving beyond methodological nationalism to write a history of attempts at building region alongside nation. More broadly, the persistence of regionalism as a political and economic phenomenon in East Africa over time also makes the region an excellent case for examining and historicising wider debates around regionalism in Africa and the world. This project, which builds on a successfully completed pilot study (British Academy funded - regional integration in 1960s-70s East Africa) brings together a team of historians and political scientists to examine  a) the colonial origins of integration projects - ideas of &apos;closer union&apos; and federation that were debated amongst settlers and colonial officials in British East Africa during the first half of the twentieth century, alongside the establishment of regional institutions by the British b) ideas of federation and &apos;community&apos; that emerged among nationalists and East African publics in the years of decolonisation and independence,  c) the establishment and collapse of the first East African Community between 1965 and 1977  d) the revival and expansion of the East African Community from the 1990s to the present Throughout we will focus on key themes including a) the shifting intellectual content of regionalist visions (pan-Africanism; federalism; state-led developmentalism; neo-liberalism)  b) the politics of integration in the context of intra-regional relations more broadly  c) the (uneven) economic impact of regional integration d) the role of external actors in shaping regional integration projects, and the role of local elite agency in mediating or transforming external interventions e) continuities and changes in the above themes over time. The research will utilise archival documentation, press material, official reports and interviews with figures involved in regional integration to produce academic and non-academic outputs that will make a major contribution to academic debate on global regionalisms and to policy discussions on the future of regional integration in East Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-28">48907.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-28">24652.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-28">196423.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Grants (Early Career) Award to Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T003138_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT003138%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
