<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P00959X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dealing with missing data in verbal autopsy reports: application to estimates of maternal mortality and HIV-related mortality.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">During my PhD, I examined the impact of having HIV during pregnancy, focussing on women in eastern and southern Africa. There were several important findings from this work: - Approximately 25% of deaths to pregnant and postpartum women are due to HIV infection in sub-Saharan Africa. - Women who are HIV positive are at increased risk of sepsis compared with HIV negative women, but are not at increased risk of having other complications directly related to pregnancy. - Pregnancy does not appear to accelerate HIV disease progression.  The finding that HIV-infected pregnant and postpartum women are at approximately eight times the risk of dying compared with their HIV-uninfected counterparts, and prediction that around 25% of pregnancy-related deaths in sub-Saharan Arica are attributable to HIV, has important public health implications. Specifically, it suggests that safe motherhood programmes need to consider interventions to prevent pregnant and postpartum women from dying from HIV, extending their remit beyond just dealing with complications directly related to pregnancy.  However, these HIV-attributable deaths are likely to be caused by both AIDS-related conditions and also other conditions, not considered as AIDS-related, but which HIV increases the risk of (e.g. sepsis).  Teasing out the exact causes of death in HIV-infected pregnant and postpartum women will help direct interventions to prevent these women from dying.   To establish the causes of death in pregnant and postpartum data I used verbal autopsy data from three sites in the ALPHA network which brings together ten community based studies from sub-Saharan Africa, all of which collect or are planning to collect data on the HIV status of the population: Karonga in Malawi, Kisesa in Tanzania and uMkhayakude in South Africa. Verbal autopsies are interviews where information on the medical signs and symptoms preceding a death is gathered from the deceased&apos;s caregivers or close family members. They are an important source of data on the causes of death in regions where there is no vital registration and many deaths occur in the community. However, the verbal autopsy data proved to be very challenging to work with as we were missing information on the HIV and pregnancy status of many individuals who died.  In this programme of work, I plan to re-calculate the causes of death in pregnant and postpartum women using sophisticated methods to deal with the missing data. To learn more about the methods required to deal with missing data I will work with researchers The State University of Ohio. These estimates will be of great importance to numerous groups of individuals including researchers who work with verbal autopsy data, policy-makers and programmers who are looking to implement interventions to prevent women dying during pregnancy, delivery and in the postpartum period, and the international agencies which require this information for producing global level models which predict the levels of maternal mortality. A substantial amount of the fellowship time will therefore be dedicated to ensuring that the results from this verbal autopsy work reach these groups of people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this fellowship is to disseminate findings from high-quality research using novel verbal autopsy methods to identify cause of death, with a particular focus on pregnant and postpartum women in high HIV prevalence settings.   The specific objectives are as follows:  1. To provided updated estimates of the underlying causes of death in pregnant and postpartum women across three sites in eastern and southern Africa, and new estimates for one site in Kenya, adopting sophisticated missing data techniques and using InSilicoVA, a new automated method for interpreting verbal autopsy data.  2. To disseminate findings widely, through engagement with the global health and academic environment (notably by publishing findings in peer-reviewed journals and presenting at an international conference). Dissemination to a wider audience will be achieved by press-releasing key findings to the media, and by preparing materials to be presented to policy-makers and to be put on the ALPHA network website. This will extend to sharing results with the DTC (through internal seminars) and the wider ESRC community, through attendance at ESRC events.   3. To foster existing, and to develop new, research collaborations with: a. Two health and demographic surveillance sites (one in Kenyan and one in Tanzania), including through site visits, collaboration on analysis, and dissemination of results.  b. A team at The Ohio State University with expertise in the interpretation of verbal autopsy data, and statistical expertise on dealing with missing data.  4. To develop a future research programme which will build on this work beyond the duration of the fellowship.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-09">0.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Post Doctoral Fellowship Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/P00959X/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FP00959X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
