<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_P017541_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transmission dynamics and molecular epidemiology of arboviruses in Indonesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Large scale outbreaks of dengue virus (DENV) and dengue haemorrhagic fever are reported every year in Indonesia. In addition, Chikungunya virus (CHIKV) is endemic in parts of Indonesia, and two positive cases of Zika virus (ZIKV) have been described, one from an Australian who travelled to Indonesia, a second from Jambi province. DENV, CHIKV, and ZIKV are all transmitted by the mosquito Aedes aegypti, and are co-circulating in the same population. They also cause overlapping symptoms in adults, and hence are difficult to differentiate by symptoms alone. Indonesia has a large population - around 250 million people - with around 90% of the population living in areas suitable for the transmission of &apos;arboviruses&apos; (short for arthropod-borne viruses), and collectively, arboviruses represent a major public health concern in Indonesia. The number of cases varies both geographically and over time, and relatively little is known about the drivers of this variation in Indonesia.  DENV, CHIKV, and ZIKV are all RNA viruses, which evolve at a high rate. Consequently, these viruses are genetically variable, and through the application of statistical models to viral sequence data, information on the dynamics of transmission, both over time and space, can be obtained. However, although the number of arbovirus infections per year is high, the number of viral sequences from Indonesia is relatively low, and often, these sequences only span a small part of the viral genome.  This project aims to characterise the transmission dynamics of DENV, CHIKV, and ZIKV through viral sequencing of clinical samples from humans.  We will harness a network of collaborators to provide archived samples, and prospective studies in locations representing west (Sumatra - Palembang City), central (Kalimantan - Banjarmasin city), and east (Maluku - Ambon city) Indonesia. In addition, we will study outbreaks that may occur during the study period. Using next-generation sequencing platforms, we aim to generate a large dataset of full-length viral genomes that will significantly add to the existing body of viral sequence data currently available.  Sequences of DENV and CHIKV (and potentially ZIKV) will be analysed using a &apos;phylodynamic&apos; approach, integrating the sequence data with epidemiological data using mathematical models in order to gain a more complete understanding of the transmission dynamics of these arboviruses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-12-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ID" type="INDONESIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">66407.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">133352.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">33472.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Despite a high burden of dengue and Chikungunya in Indonesia, as well as the presence of Zika virus, relatively little is known about the transmission dynamics of these arboviruses in Indonesia. Pathogen sequence data can provide a great deal of information about how pathogens spread, especially when combined with other epidemiological information using mathematical modeling. However, to date, sequence data of arboviruses from Indonesia are relatively scarce, especially compared to the incidence of infection, and the sequence data that are available are comprised of short sequences, which provide limited information. Using a combination of viral sequencing, and mathematical/computational models, we will address the following questions:  1. What are the patterns of genetic variation of arboviruses over time? 2. What is the extent of spatial clustering of infection? 3. What are the characteristics of viral strains associated with outbreaks? 4. How do phylodynamic patterns differ between dengue virus and Chikungunya virus? 5. What additional information on transmission dynamics is gained by full genome versus partial genome sequencing?"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
