<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_R003122_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Fund: An ORC power plant integrated with thermal energy storage to utilise renewable heat sources for distributed H&amp;P</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China, as the largest energy consumer, relies heavily on power generation from fossil fuels such as coal, leading to serious air pollution issues. It is therefore crucial for China to transit towards cleaner energy supply. Solar energy resources are abundant in China, particularly in the poorest western provinces, and renewable power generation can potentially play a vital role in energy supply for China in the future. On the other hand, although China became the second biggest economy in the world, it still remains a developing country and its per capita income is ranked as NO. 84 in the world. The exploitation of the abundant renewable energy resources in the underdeveloped regions in China can also help to boost local economy and tackle poverty.    This project aims to develop a heat storage enhanced ORC power technology to utilise renewable heat sources (e.g. solar energy) for localised power and heat supply. ORC power generation technology is believed to be the most promising technology for power generation from low temperature heat sources. Unlike solar PV panels converting sun light into electricity, ORC power plants convert solar thermal energy to power. Integrated with heat storage, solar thermal ORC systems can overcome the intermittency of sun light and provide more stable power generation and heat supply. By increasing the running time of the ORC system, the payback also increases making this technology more affordable as compared to conventional, fossil based sources of energy. Furthermore, their reliability is also increased as the heat input and output are buffered and regulated.  Apart from its application to solar energy, such technology is also attractive for utilising geothermal energy or waste heat sources. The wide installation of the developed system will make contribution to the decarbonisation of the economy China, and ultimately reduce the air pollution improve the urban populations&apos; life quality.    The proposed research and development will address several challenges that hinders the commercialisation of these technologies. On the Chinese side, Beijing University of Technology (BJUT) will develop high efficiency single screw expander technology for this project, and contribute to the development of high temperature heat storage technology using molten salts. The business partner, China Investment Yixing Red Sun Solar Energy Technology Company(CIYR), will manufacture the expanders and develop the solar powered technology demonstrator. On the UK side, Sunamp will develop and provide medium to high temperature heat storage technology using phase changer materials. The University of Glasgow (UOG) team, building upon their two on-going EPSRC projects on small scale ORC technologies, will focus on the design of the integrated system, the control strategy, and power electronic systems for the connection with grid. The four project partners, having expertise of different subsystems of this integrated technology, form a uniquely strong consortium to address these challenges and to bring the TRL of the proposed technology towards the commercialisation stage.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This China-UK joint project aims to develop heat storage enhanced Organic Rankine Cycle (ORC) power plants to utilise renewable heat sources, such as solar and geothermal energy, for distributed heat and power supply. To achieve this main goal, several important steps are listed as follows:   1) Develop efficient single screw expanders with large expansion ratios for small-scale application. The research will be focused on improving the expander&apos;s performance at partial load through optimising lubrication and dynamic seal between the screw and star gate. Innovatively, the discharge port will be optimised to convert the residual kinetic energy of the discharging vapour to useful shaft work.   2) Develop an optimised system design for constructing small-scale ORC power plants, including the optimal combination of power and heat utilisation, thermodynamic cycle architecture, working fluid selection, heat exchanger, and the coupling mechanism between subsystems.   3) Develop a ORC power plant prototype with an operating temperature at around 120 degrees Celsius for demonstrating solar thermal power generation in China.   4) Develop a ORC power plant prototype with an operating temperature in the range 80-100 degrees Celsius in the UK for demonstrating the use of geothermal energy and waste heat sources. Hot water will be used as heat source for this low temperature prototype.  5) Develop high temperature PCM based heat storage systems: One with a melting temperature around 120-150 degrees Celsius for the Chinese solar thermally powered pilot plant, and the other with a melting temperature in the range of 80-100 degrees Celsius for the hot water powered pilot plant in the UK.     6) Develop cost-effective molten salts with a melting temperature around 150 degrees Celsius, pumps for circulating them, and the heat exchangers for coupling the heat storage with ORC power plants.   7) Develop a low-cost autonomous control system allowing the integrated system to operate in response to changing operating conditions.   8) Develop cost-effective power electronic systems for connecting the ORC power plants to the grid.   9) Develop a solar thermally powered pilot plant in China.  10) Develop a hot water powered pilot plant in the UK to demonstrate the utilisation of geothermal energy or waste heat.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">178542.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">162930.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
