<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_S020896_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK-China Agritech Challenge: Aquaculture 4.0 -- Advancing Digital Precision Aquaculture in China (ADPAC)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to advance digital precision aquaculture in China towards &quot;Aquaculture 4.0&quot;, which is a highly connected and automated cyber-human-physical system using advanced technologies. The project aligns with the scope of &quot;Challenge 1: precision agriculture, agriculture digitisation and decision management tools&quot;; it also addresses Challenge 2 in terms of improved production efficiency, reduced use of labour, energy, water and other resources, reduced risk of adverse environmental impact and food safety, all leading to economically and environmentally sustainable aquaculture production. The project will bring together several cutting-edge digital technologies including connected sensor networks for online monitoring, diagnosis, control and optimisation of aquaculture production, 5G communication for low-latency, high data rate, real-time transmission of big data, internet-of-things (IoT) system for big data storage, analytics, modelling and model-based decision making. By integration of these digital technologies, the project will deliver a prototype system of precision Aquaculture 4.0, and demonstrate the economic, environmental and social benefits through pilot applications in China.  The specific objectives are:  1. To develop a project roadmap to guide the implementation of the state-of-the-art technologies for achieving Aquaculture 4.0 in China.  2. To apply, test and validate the latest sensor technologies for real-time monitoring and diagnosis of aquaculture production, including water quality and fish behaviour.  3. To design and implement a novel 5G based internet-of-things (IoT) platform for real-time transmission, storage and analysis of vast sensor network data, which will be inter-operable with existing narrow-band IoT systems for practical applications.  4. To design and implement advanced data analytics and visualisation system for data-driven real-time control, optimisation and management of industrial aquaculture production.  5. To design and prototype a digital precision Aquaculture 4.0 system that integrates sensor technology, 5G wireless communication, data analytics and automation.  6. To pilot the application of the prototype Aquaculture 4.0 system in two industrial mariculture farms in China and demonstrate the economic, environmental and social benefits.  7. To develop and implement an Exploitation Plan for commercial roll out of the system and technologies across China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to advance digital precision aquaculture in China towards &quot;Aquaculture 4.0&quot;, which is a highly connected and automated cyber-human-physical system using digital technologies. Aquaculture production in China reached 45.5 million tonnes in 2014 (60%+ of world&apos;s production, UN FAO). The grand challenge is the extremely low production efficiency, leading to high labour intensity, high energy/water consumption and environment pollution. Innovation is urgently needed for a transformation to digital industrialised aquaculture. The proposal is a timely response to the needs; it will apply and integrate the latest technologies of advanced sensors, 5G-based Internet of Things, Big Data analytics and automation to pilot highly digital precision aquaculture in China. The system is expected to deliver 10-fold increase in production efficiency. The project will open new business opportunities, gaining a competitive advantage by entering the Chinese market at this critical time and by partnering with the key innovators in Chinese aquaculture represented in this consortium. The solution will be also applicable to aquaculture worldwide opening up additional revenue stream.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Surrey</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-17">25324.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-17">166910.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-17">178001.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-17">87027.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-17">457264.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Surrey</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/S020896/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Surrey</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FS020896%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
