<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N011473_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">FAPESP-ESRC-NWO Joint Call Sustainable Urban Development. Smart Governance of Sustainable Cities (SmartGov)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The SmartGov research project assesses the value of ICTs for engaging citizens in the governance of sustainable cities. The societal objective is to present the acquired insights in the form of a research-based knowledge system for government officials, which can be utilised to enhance sustainable urban goverance and service delivery. This knowledge is in dire need, since the alignment of ICTs and strategies for urban governance is a key challenge for cities: new technologies such as social media and open data promise &apos;smart governance&apos; - if/when the technologies are integrated in strategies for citizen participation. Examples are abound: the City of Amsterdam uses Citizen Toolkits to engage citizens in environmental monitoring, the Greater London Authority uses open data to stimulate sustainability initiatives and Porto Alegre gathers information from residents to stimulate a dialogue about urban development. These new technologies are &apos;in vogue&apos; but little is known about their effectiveness - and the drawbacks - in different organizational, institutional and political contexts. To assess the effectiveness, the research incorporates three main empirical research case studies which form a comparative analyses of smart governance in infrastructure, economy and poverty in Utrecht, Curitiba and Glasgow. The project elicits the mechanisms of smart governance, identifies the conditions that matter and assesses its contributions to (economic, democratic, social and environmental) sustainability. A novel theoretical perspective at the interface of e-governance and urban governance studies is developed to realize this aim and innovative research methods such as virtual ethnography are used. This project is carried out in close collaboration with officials from the Cities of Utrecht, Curitiba and Glasgow to ensure its value for policy-makers, practitioners and citizens. The term &apos;Smart governance&apos; refers to the use of new technologies, such as social media, the Internet, open data, citizen sensors, and &apos;serious&apos; gaming, to strengthen the collaboration between citizens and urban governments (Hoon Lee, Phaal &amp; Lee, 2013). In this research &apos;smart governance&apos; is defined as aligning technological potential with urban governance strategies to form a consistent socio-technical approach to tackling urban problems (cf. Meijer &amp; Thaens, 2010). The promise of smart governance is to create collaborative innovations for sustainable urban development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research aims to elicit the mechanism through which smart governance can improve the (economic, democratic, social and environmental) sustainability of the city, to identify the relevant conditions and to assess the impact of smart governance. The main research question for this project is: - How, when and to what extent does smart governance strengthen sustainable urban development? This question is of great importance since, especially in times of financial crisis, innovative solutions to tackle urban challenges such as pollution, poverty and traffic congestion are needed. Cities all around the world aspire to be &apos;smart cities&apos; (Inayatullah, 2011; Winters, 2011; Walravens, 2012; Batty et al., 2012; Hoon Lee et al., 2013). Little is known, however, about the effectiveness of these strategies for sustainable urban development. This research aims to fill this gap by eliciting the contextual mechanisms of smart governance for sustainable urban development and to develop a knowledge system on the basis of these insights. Key research objectives: - To enhance understanding of the contextual circumstances necessary for the successful development of sustainable urban governance in smart cities - To develop a context-sensitive theory of smart governance - To design an analytical framework to enhance understanding and to guide empirical research - To undertake in-depth case study research with three smart cities in the UK, Brazil and the Netherlands - To analyse the mechanisms for smart governance in the three smart city case studies - To engage practitioners/policy-makers in all aspects of research (co-)design and implementation - To engage citizens and service users in research activities and findings - To develop a research-based smart governance knowledge system - To produce a contribution to knowledge via range of high quality academic outputs - To facilitate research capacity building amongst the early career scholars involved in the research - To map pathways to impact</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Stirling</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-12">51497.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-12">69080.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-12">69640.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-12">70204.25</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-12">17586.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-12">13066423</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Stirling</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N011473_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Stirling</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FN011473%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-08-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
