<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_M020169_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Measured dynamic loading and power performance of tidal turbines in realistic flow conditions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Question: How can we aid industry to best validate dynamic (real time) array models for: (a) optimised array design and layout, (b) prediction of dynamic loadings and fatigue effects (rotors and blades) through inflow turbulence and device-device interactions and (c) reliability or planning for O&amp;M considering the lack of publically-available data?   1. To provide real, time -series data of loadings and power performance experienced by tidal turbines under realistic inflow conditions and when devices interact with one another (in array type configurations). At present there is little if any data on this (mostly average values or short time-scale experimental runs) which cannot sufficiently validate models. We will provide scale test data with all parameters required to use data sets for validation purposes  2. To provide measured time-series data for larger multiple-row arrays than has been previously conducted 3. To quantify so-called &quot;steady loads&quot; and measure changes in performance over time through long-term testing of a scale device(s) in the sea  4. To make project data available directly to relevant marine energy stakeholders in a very timely manner</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tidal turbines (akin to underwater wind turbines) are at a stage of development where full-scale prototype devices have been deployed and tested in the seas surrounding the UK and other locations in the world. The next step is to deploy farms or arrays of multiple devices to demonstrate operability, cost reduction and the ability to generate electricity at a larger scale.   In order to do this device developers and funders of the technology must have confidence and assurances that these arrays of tidal turbines will perform as predicted; but how do you predict something that you have never done before? Computer-based numerical models can simulate things before they are constructed or installed but without data to validate these models how can anyone know if they will be accurate?   This project addresses such a question &quot;How can we aid industry to best validate dynamic (real time) array models for:(a) optimised array design and layout, (b) prediction of dynamic loadings and fatigue effects (rotors and blades) through inflow turbulence and device-device interactions and (c) reliability or planning for O&amp;M   considering the lack of publically-available data?   Our answer is to:  1. To provide real, time -series data of loadings and power performance experienced by tidal turbines under realistic inflow conditions and when devices interact with one another (in array type configurations). At present there is little if any data on this (mostly average values or short time-scale experimental runs) which cannot sufficiently validate models. We will provide scale test data with all parameters required to use data sets for validation purposes  2. To provide measured time-series data for larger multiple-row arrays than has been previously conducted 3. To quantify so-called &quot;steady loads&quot; and measure changes in performance over time through long-term testing of a scale device(s) in the sea   And to make project data available directly to relevant marine energy stakeholders in a very timely manner</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-09-28">101072.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-09-28">42314.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-09-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-09-28">185700.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC Newton Standard Research - NR1 Award to University of Southampton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP/M020169/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FM020169%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2014-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
