<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_V031171_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Yaba guy che &quot;for the guys&quot;: Intervention co-development to increase men&apos;s HIV service use</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adopting a participatory approach to intervention development, the overall aim of this early phase study is to co-develop a multi-component intervention with men. The intervention will be responsive to the needs and preferences of men, and respond to gaps within the current system within which HIV services are delivered and men reside. The intervention will optimise delivery of HIV services to increase men&apos;s engagement with these services, including HIV testing services, linkage to prevention services, and initiation and adherence to HIV treatment.   To meet this aim, the specific objectives of the study are to:  1) use crowdsourcing and participatory workshops to finalise the design of a multi-component intervention that is acceptable to men and considered feasible to implement at low-cost; 2) establish a logic model of how the complex intervention is expected to achieve its intended outcomes by addressing current gaps in the system that inhibit men&apos;s engagement with HIV services (as described by a socio-ecological model); 3) identify community-based spaces that would be acceptable locations from which to deliver HIV testing services; 4) assess whether an alternative sampling method, namely time location sampling, is feasible and can identify men, and therefore could be used to determine the impact of the intervention in the main study, and 5) prepare an outline of a grant proposal for the main study to garner support for a CRT from relevant stakeholders, including men resident within study communities, policymakers and district health managers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Zambia, as in other sub-Saharan African countries, men are less likely than women to access HIV services, including HIV testing services, which acts as a gateway to prevention services and the HIV care continuum. As a consequence, men are less likely than women to know their HIV positive status, men initiate HIV treatment (ART) at later stages of infection, thus experiencing higher levels of morbidity and mortality once initiated on ART. Without knowledge of their HIV status, HIV positive men are more likely to transmit HIV to their sexual partners.   The barriers to men&apos;s engagement in HIV services are complex and multifaceted, and operate at national- through to individual-level. These include how healthcare services are funded, delivered and promoted, leading to healthcare facilities being seen as &quot;female-spaces&quot;; harmful gender norms related to masculinity, restricting men&apos;s use of HIV-related services and influencing their perceptions regarding their peers use of HIV-related services, and men&apos;s mobility for work, limiting their ability to access health facilities operational during conventional working hours. To improve men&apos;s engagement with HIV services, including HIV prevention and treatment services, a systems-wide approach to understanding and addressing these interacting barriers to service use is needed.   Through participatory qualitative research and crowdsourcing, this early phase study will work closely with men in an urban community in Lusaka, Zambia, to: 1) establish the barriers to HIV testing services and linkage to prevention and care that men perceive to be most inhibitive to their service use, and 2) co-develop a multi-component intervention to address barriers to service use. The multi-component intervention is intended to address barriers related to how and where HIV testing services are delivered, to transform norms related to HIV testing uptake and establish social support for use of HIV prevention services, in particular medical male circumcision, and initiation and uptake of ART.  In parallel, we will use time location sampling to assess whether this alternative sampling method, often used to reach &quot;hidden populations&quot;, could be used to evaluate the impact of the multi-component intervention in a cluster randomised trial. The intervention will be finalised through a series of workshops with men residing in the study community and other stakeholders, including district health managers and healthcare workers, with support from these groups obtained before progression to a cluster randomised trial.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133903" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-11-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-09-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-09-02">142564.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/V031171/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FV031171%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
