<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N012240_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience to EArthquake-induced landslide risk in CHina (REACH)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">O1: Integrate science and policy via engagement with organisations that straddle the science-policy divide (boundary organisations), and through co-producing a model for analysing earthquake resilience across Sichuan under various demographic and policy scenarios. We will ensure that the project generates fundamental, policy-relevant science for improving disaster resilience in China. We will dedicate a member of staff to engage with organisations that straddle the science-policy divide, building on existing partnerships with intergovernmental (World Bank) and governmental (Ministry of Land and Resources) institutions. We will develop a model in collaboration with policy-makers and non-governmental actors for exploring the evolution of Sichuan&apos;s earthquake resilience profile under various socio-economic scenarios and policy interventions. O2: Create an early warning system for post-earthquake landslides, embedded within a 3D WebGIS-based platform. We will use detailed monitoring of 7 landslide catchments to characterise the critical rainfall thresholds required to initiate debris flows in this catchment. Using a wireless sensor network that can telemeter rainfall and other data we will create an early warning system for rainfall-induced landslides.   O3: Map the spatio-temporal variations in the vulnerability of the social and built environment across seismically active regions of Sichuan, and explore their relationship to seismic hazard and earthquake impacts. We will quantify the extent to which social vulnerability explains the variance in fatalities from the Wenchuan earthquake and in post-earthquake landslide events, using local census data. We will map out the evolution of social vulnerability across seismically active areas of the province over space and time, and combine these with characterizations of physical earthquake hazard to generate risk maps, using these to inform resilience modelling and policy. O4: Characterise the physical mechanisms governing earthquake- and rainfall-induced landslide hazard at a regional scale. Here we seek to understand the mechanisms governing the development of risk and resilience through the earthquake-induced landslide hazard chain. In particular, we will use topographic, field, and laboratory analysis understand how and where post-earthquake landslides initiate. We will instrument 7 rainfall-induced landslide catchments in detail, and conduct field studies in a further 120 sites. Using a 100m long landslide flume, we will create experiments that examine a dam-breach mechanism for landslide initiation. We will also utilise and extend existing remotely sensed datasets of landslides to the event scale, seeking to understand the relative role of aftershocks and storms in governing landsliding. We will produce landslide hazard models that combine the effects of aftershocks and storms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ability for communities to &quot;bounce back&quot; from major disasters is essential for poverty alleviation and economic development. Termed &quot;disaster resilience&quot;, this process is of particular importance in China as rapid economic expansion and urbanization has increased Chinese susceptibility to a number of major disasters, including the 2008 Wenchuan Earthquake. Earthquake-induced landslides represent a particular challenge to resilience as increased rates of landslide hazard may persist for many decades. The proposed research seeks to understand what controls this persistent landslide hazard and the processes that cause landslides to jeopardise recovery. To understand the recovery process and how it affects resilience, we will investigate the role of &quot;social vulnerability&quot; in modifying the response to earthquakes and their related hazards.  We will assess the underlying drivers of social vulnerability and the spatio-temporal differences across Sichuan province. We will combine our estimates of landslide hazard and social vulnerability across the decade after the Wenchuan Earthquake, investigating both the spatial patterns of risk and how these change with time. To achieve these goals, we will focus our work on the areas affected by the Wenchuan Earthquake, where the Chengdu Institute of Technology-State Key Laboratory of Geohazard Prevention and Geoenvironment Protection has created an incredibly large dataset of landslide hazards since the earthquake. In collaboration with landslide scientists and social scientists at Cardiff University&apos;s Sustainable Places Research Institute, we will expand this dataset in two ways; (1) increasing the resolution of landslide hazard mapping to understand the relative role of aftershocks and rainfall in controlling hazard, and (2) using local census data to understand social vulnerability and how the interaction between social vulnerability and landslide hazards has changed in space and through time. The unprecedented detail of our data will enable us to develop a new probabilistic landslide hazard model that incorporates landslides caused by both aftershocks and rainfall events that can be applied across earthquake-prone China and perhaps even globally. Field data collected as part of this effort will help to constrain threshold values and so help support the construction of a landslide early warning system for Sichan. Finally, we will model the resilience of the built environment and key infrastructure through state of the art machine learning algorithms. As evidence of our commitment to improve the welfare of earthquake-prone China through better planning for disasters we will engage with an extensive network of governmental and non-governmental institutions. From the first day of the grant we will engage with organisations with interests in both science and policy to achieve this goal. We will also model resilience under different demographic and policy scenarios, using this as a tool to understand and communicate the challenges of building resilient communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">28138.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">184803.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">177174.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">112835.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">17603337.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to Cardiff University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N012240_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FN012240%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-25"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
