<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N012313_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Active tectonics and seismic hazard assessment in Shaanxi, Gansu, and Ningxia Provinces, China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The provinces of Sha&apos;anxi, Gansu, and Ningxia lie between the southern and western margins of the Ordos block and the northeastern Tibetan plateau. The population of the region is about 70 million, of whom approximately half live within large cities, which have grown rapidly and recently around the nuclei of much smaller cities that are known to have been destroyed by earthquakes in the historical past. The remainder of the population is rural, and live in highly vulnerable buildings. The region has suffered three of the most deadly earthquakes in recorded history; the 1556 Huaxian earthquake was responsible for the deaths of over 800,000 people, and other historical earthquakes are known to have killed over 100,000 people.  This project aims to make a significant improvement in the assessment of seismic hazard in the region, and is particularly timely because the study area covers the most populous part of the Chinese end of  the Silk Road Economic Belt, a planned investment of hundreds of billions of dollars that will transform  communications, transport and trade across Eurasia. Unlike countries around the Pacific Rim, where earthquakes occur quite frequently, on faults whose  locations are well known, China is exposed to hazards from earthquakes that occur on a widely distributed system of faults, whose locations are poorly known -- or not known at all until an  earthquake occurs. The central aspect of this earthquake hazard is that the intervals between successive earthquakes on the same section of fault are thousands of years. In order to characterize accurately the deformation of a region, therefore, we need to determine the distribution, rate, and role of the active faults across the region over the past 10,000 to 100,000 years. We shall shall achieve this by combining techniques of field geology, geophysics, satellite-based mapping, and measurements of the deformation of the Earth&apos; surface using GPS and satellite radar. We shall  combine these observations into a coherent picture of the deformation of the region, which will be used to make a new map of seismic hazard of the region that is both more accurate and more detailed than existing maps.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We shall identify the major active faults of the region, investigate historical surface ruptures and palaeo-earthquake events, slip rates on major faults, and produce a strain-rate field for the region with a horizontal resolution of about 50 km. We shall combine these observations with remotesensing data and physical models of the deformation to yield a greatly improved assessment of seismic hazard in the region. 1. Historical earthquake ruptures: During the past two millennia, large earthquakes (M&gt;7) are recorded to have occurred on most of the major faults in this region. All of these earthquakes are likely to have been accompanied by surface ruptures, few of which have been well documented. We shall make measurements of rupture length and coseismic displacement for these earthquakes, to constrain their seismic moments, hence improving seismic hazard assessment. 2. Slip rates and palaeo-earthquakes of major active faults. The major faults shown in Fig 1 will be mapped by a combination of remote sensing and geological fieldwork. Using detailed geomorphological surveys, fault trenching, and Quaternary dating techniques we shall obtain Holocene slip rates, palaeo-earthquake history, and elapsed time since the last earthquake for these faults. These field observations will act as &quot;ground truth&quot; for remote-sensing observations, which can then be used to obtain information on other faults that we may not have the time or resources to investigate in the field. 3. Kinematics of present-day deformation. Our third objective is to produce a detailed strain-rate field for the region by combining GPS, InSAR and repeated geodetic levelling. Although it is important to characterise the major faults, most of the destruction in continental earthquakes is associated with earthquakes of M~7, which often take place on previously undetected faults [5]. The measurements under this objective are essential to seismic hazard assessment because they will detect the strain that eventually leads to such earthquakes. 4. Mathematical modelling of deformation. The previous objectives will give greatly improved pictures of the kinematics of deformation and distribution of seismic hazard in the three provinces on which this project focuses. This information cannot be exported to other areas, however, without an understanding of its physical cause. We shall develop this understanding by comparing the observations against mathematical models of a range of kinematic and dynamic models for the active strain of northeast Tibet and the Ordos in particular, and of continental deformation in general. 5. Induced geological hazards. The study region lies in the western part of the Loess Plateau, and is covered by a few tens to hundreds metres of loess. Landslides in this poorly consolidated material have been major secondary hazard in earthquakes of the region; for example large fractions of the 830,000 deaths in the 1556 Huaxian earthquake and of the 200,000 deaths in the 1920 Haiyuan are attributed to landslides. A parallel proposal by Fan and Densmore is devoted to quantifying this hazard. We have included a modest budget for collaboration with this project. 6. Probabilistic seismic hazard assessment. Current seismic hazard assessment models used in China do not account for geological fault slip rates, palaeo-seismic recurrence intervals and present- day deformation. Such data are now, however, central to the assessment of seismic hazard. In this proposal, we plan to establish physical and probabilistic models of earthquake recurrence in the region, and to integrate seismological, geological, and geodetic information into these models.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">42199.13</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">169138.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">170508.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">119809.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">7023166.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N012313_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FN012313%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-25"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
