<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N019113_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral BBSRC-Embrapa: Exploiting natural and induced variation to increase Fusarium head blight and brusone resistance in wheat</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fusarium head blight (FHB) and wheat blast (brusone) are two devastating diseases of wheat that cause major yield losses in Brazil. Both pathogens severely affect wheat heads with direct damage to the grain, both in terms of quality and yield. In the absence of resistant varieties, current disease control relies heavily on fungicides that are costly, non-sustainable for Brazil, and only partially effective.  Brusone, caused by the fungus Magnaporthe oryzae, was first identified in southern Brazil in 1985 but has since spread into Argentina, Bolivia, and Paraguay. The disease can cause total yield loss of yield and in 2009 brusone cut Brazilian wheat production by up to 30%. Importantly, the susceptibility of Brazilian varieties to brusone precludes their cultivation in the Cerrado region, an unused potential of 5 million ha for expansion that would improve Brazilian self-sufficiency of this essential staple.  Fusarium head blight, caused primarily by the fungus Fusarium graminearum, is a serious disease in both Brazil and the UK. In addition to the very significant yield and quality losses, a major concern with FHB is the contamination of grain with trichothecene mycotoxins such as deoxynivalenol (DON). Both the European Union and Brazil have imposed maximum permissible levels for DON in cereals and cereal products. In Brazil, severe FHB outbreaks have increased in frequency. In 2014 FHB was so severe that more than 60% of wheat yield was lost in the State of Rio Grande do Sul and in the western region in 2014 some farmers lost more than 80% to the combination of brusone + FHB.  There is an urgent need to identify and characterise sources of resistance to both FHB and brusone and ensure that the introduction of genes to control one disease does not compromise resistance to the other.   Moderate levels of resistance to brusone have been identified in Brazilian wheat but the genetic basis of this resistance is unclear. Resistance expressed in seedlings is not always expressed in adult plants making it essential that resistance is assessed in adult plants. Resistance to FHB is generally controlled by several genes of moderate/weak effect that are defined genetically as quantitative trait loci (QTL). Although Brazilian wheat varieties differ widely in their resistance to FHB with some being moderately resistant, no variety was found to possess the major Fhb1 resistance originating from Asian sources. Thus the genetic basis of the most FHB-resistant Brazilian cultivars is not known and suggests that they contain novel resistances that could be combined with those from elsewhere to breed very highly resistant wheat varieties.  This project will use a range of cutting-edge approaches to identify the genetic basis of resistance to brusone and FHB disease. We will identify which parts of the genome contain genes that increase FHB and/or brusone resistance and determine whether increased resistance to one disease is associated with increased susceptibility to the other.   We will also identify genes in wheat that reduce resistance to the two diseases. This will provide a complementary approach to increasing resistance to FHB and brusone in wheat. We will produce DNA markers to enable plant breeders to follow the presence of the beneficial genes in their breeding programmes and ensure that their varieties are highly resistant to both diseases.  The results from this work will benefit plant breeders in Brazil and elsewhere across the world where these diseases are prevalent. This should lead to reduced risk of crop losses to growers and reduced risk to consumers from mycotoxins accumulating in grain. It will lead to a reduced reliance on fungicides to control these diseases which, in turn will benefit, growers and the environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-26">176647.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-26">236961.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-26">238880.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The aim of this project is understand the genetic basis of resistance to FHB and brusone in wheat. This information will enable Brazilian plant breeders to produce wheat varieties with high levels of resistance to both FHB and brusone. We also aim to produce tools and resources that can be used to address other yield and quality limiting factors in wheat production.  This project comprises four objectives:  1) Genome-wide association studies (GWAS) of FHB and brusone resistance in Brazilian wheat varieties Disease resistance data has been collected for a large number of wheat varieties and breeding lines. Very high density marker sets will be produced by combining SNP information on these lines obtained in the Pump-Priming project with genotyping by sequencing data to be obtained within the proposed project. The DNA and disease phenotype data sets will be subjected to GWAS to identify DNA markers linked to resistance to these two diseases among this diverse set of Brazilian wheat germplasm.  2) High precision QTL mapping of FHB and brusone resistance in Brazilian wheat varieties Extensive field trials will be undertaken of bi-parental mapping populations selected for differences in resistance to brusone and/or FHB and phylogenetic relatedness. High density genetic maps will be produced for each population using 35K SNP arrays. These detailed and high quality data sets will be used for QTL analysis of FHB and brusone resistance to identify markers associated with resistance in these wheat varieties.  3) Identification of susceptibility and resistance factors for FHB and brusone A forward genetics approach will be taken to identify susceptibility and resistance factors to the two diseases. A large EMS mutagenized population has been developed in a Brazilian wheat variety. The mutagenized population will be screened at multiple locations for altered FHB and brusone resistance. Selected lines altered in resistance to either disease will be analysed using a novel TILLING-exome capture platform to detect mutations. TILLING populations of hexaploid (Cadenza) and tetraploid (Kronos) wheat will be analysed in silico to identify lines carrying mutations in the candidate susceptibility/resistance genes. These lines will be screened for FHB and brusone resistance to establish the role of the candidate genes in disease resistance.   4) Develop and enhance scientific capabilities of Brazil and UK partners.  This project will involve numerous and extensive exchange of personnel, materials and information between UK and Brazilian researchers. Training will build on that undertaken within the Pump-Priming project. Training of Embrapa personnel in GWAS analysis will expand to enable maximum leverage of information from the large FHB and brusone data sets along with training in exome capture technologies, TILLING, analysis of next generation sequencing data, and quantitative genetics. The project will produce new information on the genetic basis of resistance to two devastating disease of wheat. It will provide new insight into potential mechanisms of disease resistance and susceptibility that will greatly benefit both UK and Brazilian researchers.  Furthermore, the project will develop GWAS and TILLING platforms that can be used in future studies to increase resistance to other stresses (biotic and abiotic) or enhance agronomic performance or grain quality. These platforms will assist breeders to produce high yielding, high quality wheat varieties adapted to the diverse Brazilian growing conditions."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
