<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014985_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preventing cervical cancer in older Vietnamese women</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Pilot an innovative screening study in older Vietnamese women The burden of cervical cancer is high in Vietnam as in most LMICs. This study would assess the feasibility of a large-scale population-based screening study, involving once in a lifetime HPV testing at age 45 or above, to measure the impact on cancer incidence and mortality. We shall estimate response rates by inviting a random sample of women aged 45-64 for HPV screening plus a group of former sex workers who have a much higher risk of developing cervical cancer. (2) Strengthen the existing LSHTM-Pasteur Institute, Vietnam research partnership Prof Mulholland has an office at both LSHTM and the Pasteur Institute where he has worked with partners on other community-based vaccine and HPV studies. This partnership will be enhanced by introducing Prof Julian Peto and Clare Gilham from LSHTM who have decades of experience in HPV research and cancer screening strategies in the UK. A further extension is to develop a partnership between LSHTM, Vietnam and Mongolia. Vietnam and Mongolia are similar ex-communist countries with an existing good relationship. Vietnam would be the primary focus of the research with a view to extending the research to Mongolia.  (3) Share UK experience of analysing cancer cohort trends with cancer registries in Vietnam and Mongolia Prof Julian Peto and Clare Gilham have decades of experience analysing national cancer incidence and mortality rates. The cancer registries in both Vietnam and Mongolia are well organised but poorly resourced. Interviewing at least 50 cancer cases in Vietnam will help understand the effect of urban/rural migration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cervical cancer is a leading cause of cancer mortality in Vietnam with over 80% of deaths among women aged over 45 years.  In Western countries, regular cervical screening allows cancers to be detected and treated, but cervical screening in Vietnam is rare and less than 5% of the population have ever been screened. This means that cancers are detected later and are often fatal.  Human papillomavirus (HPV) causes cervical cancer and is common in younger people in Vietnam. Research into how best introduce a vaccine to prevent future cervical cancers is currently being undertaken. However, little is being done to help women who are too old to be vaccinated and are now at highest risk of developing cancer. We propose to strengthen existing research partnerships between LSHTM and both the Pasteur Institute and Cancer Registry in Ho Chi Minh City (HCMC) in order to pilot an innovative HPV screening method among older Vietnamese women. Our research in the UK has indicated that the majority of invasive cancers could have been detected by sensitive HPV testing compared to very few by cytology (a smear test). This project will pilot HPV testing in two districts of HCMC in 300 women aged 45-64 years. The women testing positive will be invited for repeat testing after 1 year and those still positive will be invited to undergo a therapeutic biopsy with the aim of greatly reducing their future cancer risk. In addition, 100 former sex workers will be identified and also invited to take part. These women are estimated to be at much higher risk of developing cervical cancer than the general population and therefore are an important target group for HPV screening. This pilot project will allow us to assess the response rate and also the attitudes to screening in those that accept their screening invite compared to those who refuse. The cancer registry in HCMC is well organised but poorly resourced. Analysis of the data is required to understand unexpected changes in cancer rates which are likely to be due to migration in and out of the city. At least 50 cervical cancer patients identified by the registry will be interviewed in this pilot study to between understand their characteristics including whether they have moved from a rural area to HCMC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">47547.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">40515.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">17791.46</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">105854.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014985_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FS014985%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
