<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N011333_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public accountability to residents in contractual urban redevelopment (PARCOUR)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contracts, deeds, by-laws and other regulatory instruments are used as planning tools to regulate actors (from the public, private and civil sectors) involved in the regeneration of previously developed land. PARCOUR argues that contractual relationships create a specific form of governance that have important implications for the democratic legitimacy of projects for Sustainable Urban Development (SUD). More specifically by studying diverse planning tools in Brazil, UK and the Netherlands, PARCOUR will engage in the comparative evaluation of public accountability in relation to residents. It is also important to acknowledge that both the realisation of the public interest through the use of these planning tools and the accountability of the public sector in contractual processes are under researched. This topic is relevant to section 3.2.3 of the Call on &quot;Governance and Democracy&quot;, specifically to the &quot;Poverty, inequality and vulnerability&quot; section in answering &quot;How governance decisions on the urban environment interact with land, property markets, rights, and the private sector. And the extent to which planning tools take account of these interactions.&quot;   The main outcome of PARCOUR will be the clear evaluation of public accountability, and clear definition of public interest, focusing on dissemination of this knowledge among public authorities with interactive research. The project has 3 phases: 1) Desk research: Understanding different ways in which the public interest is constructed and operationalised in diverse contexts; 2) Field work and analysis: Testing the legitimacy of the planning tools that are able to implement actions for the public interest; 3) Dissemination: Distributing the results to academy and practice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PARCOUR focuses on the extent to which, and how, governance forms, associated with the use of contractual approaches in regeneration projects dealing with previously developed land (PDL), impact on inequalities and the implications for SUD. We argue public accountability may decline where regulatory arrangements involve the private sector as a facilitator of the regeneration of PDL. This may undermine the authority of public agencies and residents&apos; interests and thus affect SUD (see CEC, 2009) negatively.   PARCOUR addresses social sustainability by concentrating on the rights of urban residents vis-&#xE0;-vis contracts and associated governance processes. Regeneration projects involve complex regulations for redeveloping land requiring remedial work to make it suitable for redevelopment; this has technical and social dimensions involving the explicit or implicit termination of formal and informal rights and uses that impede redevelopment. Thus, regeneration projects involve not only property development but also activities to prepare the land for sustainable re-use. This process is complicated by the involvement of urban residents and communities. In public-private partnerships the relationships between these actors and the preparation of land for re-use are regulated by a set of contracts which create complex, often opaque, governance structures. These arrangements create challenges for SUD given the need for coordination and integration of actions to achieve a coherent approach (Atkinson and Klausen, 2011: 3; Atkinson, Terizakis and Zimmermann (eds), 2011). Moreover, they require the creation of, often project specific, governance arrangements to bring together different actors to agree goals, work together and enable them to combine, in a coherent manner, the different resources/forms of knowledge they possess to achieve agreed goals (see Andersen and Atkinson (eds), 2013; Van der Veen and Korthals Altes, 2011a; 2011b).  To what extent does private sector involvement in regeneration of PDL and property serve and support SUD in this complex governance landscape? How is the public interest, and more specifically the rights and needs of the urban residents, incorporated into contractual agreements and regulations? These questions are crucial given that multi-actor regeneration projects structured by private contracts are widespread development instruments in cities today. The achievement of public interest by planning tools, the accountability of the public sector contractual processes and the impacts on residents are under researched, making this project timely and relevant to SUD.   Regeneration processes involve complex legal and regulatory activities that frequently involve forms of privatisation that may be subject to &apos;governance through detail&apos; (Raco, 2012; 2013) which runs the risk of undermining SUD through the marginalisation of issues related to the public interest and of creating social exclusion through processes of community involvement if community actors are unable to influence the contractual/regulatory instruments governing the regeneration process (Atkinson, 2003). Moreover, contractual arrangements frequently result in limits being placed on decision-making by public authorities, worsening financial results, and undermine the accountability of public authorities (Kang and Korthals Altes, 2014).   Current work mainly critiques this process (Tasan-Kok, 2010), while studies seeking to understand how the public can benefit are rare. Moreover, little empirical knowledge is available about how public and private actors collaborate on and manage private sector-led urban development projects and the tools designed to structure and facilitate projects (Heurkens 2010).</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">46606.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">93590.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">94348.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-28">15861.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
