<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S011676_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A multi-isotope base map for Jordan: a tool for re-examining movement and community in the past</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The relationships between mobile pastoralists and sedentary agricultural communities, between &quot;the steppe and the sown&quot;, have historically played a key role in the formation of the national identity of the modern state of Jordan. In recent decades, however, a high rate of immigration has had a significant impact on Jordan&apos;s social fabric and its natural environment, with substantial implications for sustainable development and for its sense of self. Issues of identity and community, and of how these are constructed, have become matters of significant debate. We seek, therefore, to use a case study from the past to advance new perspectives on the nature of community and expand consideration of these issues.   A recent project at Durham University demonstrated through isotopic analysis of skeletal remains that more than 50% of the individuals interred in a major 7th-9th century CE cemetery at Bamburgh, capital of the Anglo-Saxon kingdom of Northumbria, did not originate from northeastern England, but from a world extending from the Mediterranean to Scandinavia. The diverse nature of the community at this major Anglo-Saxon site raises important questions about traditional narratives around British identity. We therefore seek to explore issues of diversity in a Jordanian context through a comparable case study. For this purpose, we have selected the site of Pella, an important community in the Jordan Valley that has produced a long sequence human skeletal material spanning a period of ca. 4000 years.   Traditional ways of identifying migration and mobility in the archaeological record, which often rely on substantial changes in material culture, are problematic. Isotopic analysis of skeletal remains, in contrast, can provide direct evidence for mobility, and its application has informed major reconsiderations of the European past. The accurate interpretation of patterns of movement requires an understanding of spatial variation in local isotopic signatures in the natural environment - in effect, baseline mapping. The absence of this information in Jordan has hampered previous efforts to employ isotopic studies and has prevented the kind of nuanced understandings of past communities that are now reshaping our view of the European past. As a result, this project seeks to create through laboratory analysis an essential baseline dataset that will enhance the value of existing archaeological collections by using isotopic geochemistry as a technique to understand patterns of movement in the past. We will use this technique to investigate the relative homogeneity/diversity of an important Jordanian community at different points in time. While this case study offers exciting possibilities, we first aim to create a major piece of research infrastructure, in the form of a multi-isotope base-map for Jordan. This will provide the underpinnings for this project, but will also provide an essential point of reference for all future isotopic analysis in the country. We believe that this base-map will spur a rapid increase in the uptake of isotopic techniques within Jordanian archaeology. We therefore propose a two-part project:  1) Construction of a multi-isotope base-map for Jordan (87Sr/86Sr, 18O, 34S, 13C, 15N), comparable to the Biosphere Map of Britain. This would represent the first bioavailable multi-isotope map for any country in the Middle East. The data underlying the construction of this map will be made available as an online database, and map resources of spatial variability in bioavailable isotope values will also be made freely available online, to allow them to be used for future studies. 2) Undertake a study that employs a deep-time approach to the history of mobility and community in Jordan, by analyzing human remains from multiple periods at Pella. This site, located in the Jordan Valley, has one of the longest sequences of human burials in Jordan, and thus offers an ideal long-term case study of changes in mobility.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project has among its primary objectives the following two major research outputs: 1) Construction of a multi-isotope base-map for Jordan (87Sr/86Sr, 18O, 34S, 13C, 15N), comparable to the Biosphere Map of Britain. This would represent the first bioavailable multi-isotope map for any country in the Middle East. The data underlying the construction of this map will be made available as an online database, and map resources of spatial variability in bioavailable isotope values will also be made freely available online, to allow them to be used for future studies. 2) A case study that employs a deep-time approach to the history of mobility and community in Jordan, by analyzing human remains from multiple periods at a single site. For this purpose, we propose to focus upon Pella in the Jordan Valley, as a site with one of the longest sequences of human burials in Jordan. Pella thus offers a unique opportunity to act as long-term case study of changes in mobility. Through the production of these outputs, we aim to achieve the following indirect objectives: 1) Academic Capacity Building: Through a collaboration between Durham University and Yarmouk University, this project aims to make a major contribution to capacity building by creating a major piece of Jordanian research infrastructure. The multi-isotope base-map will be the first of its kind for any country in the Middle East, and will become an essential point of reference for all future isotopic analysis in the country. Limited access to analytical facilities has hampered previous isotopic research in Jordan, and we aim to ensure that the isoscape maps produced will be widely used by Jordanian archaeologists and researchers in other fields who do not have access to the resources necessary to create systematic isotope baselines for their areas of study. 2) Facilitation of Future Research: We believe that the creation of this dataset will position Jordan at the forefront of developments in isotope research, and will encourage more widespread adoption of isotopic techniques in Jordanian archaeology and in numerous other fields. More directly, we foresee that Yarmouk University&apos;s large collections of skeletal material from other sites across the country provide a substantial opportunity for continuing similar isotopic research in future, building upon the established relationship between Durham University and Yarmouk University.  3) New Perspectives on Community and Mobility in the Past: Through the case study&apos;s focus on the long-term development of communities at the important Jordan Valley site of Pella, this project aims to contribute to ongoing discussions about the nature and formation of past identities and communities in Jordan. By investigating the changing patterns of mobility and relative heterogeneity and diversity within the lifespan of one particular ancient Jordanian community, we hope to provide new perspectives to enrich public discourse and popular conceptions of community and identity in the past. These perspectives will be shared through the creation of a bilingual Arabic-English exhibition to be displayed at Yarmouk University and used as teaching resources in schools and other educational settings, as deemed appropriate. Among the goals of this research, therefore, is to offer new perspectives that will help to challenge, in both the academic community and the popular imagination, entrenched assumptions about how we view and recognize change in the past. We aim to create a means for alternative possibilities about the nature of diversity in past communities and the ways this is reflected in the archaeological record to be heard and explored, and in doing so, to re-energize discussions regarding the scale, direction, timing and nature of mobility in the past.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-28">19065.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-28">107862.1</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-28">73477.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-28">6012163.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to Durham University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S011676_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FS011676%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
