<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008067_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social protection and sustainable peace in the Middle East and North Africa Region: Building a new welfare-centered politics</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">(1) Advance comparative and multidisciplinary scholarship on the interconnections between community-level social justice grievances and the macro-level governance of social policy in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA). Focusing on the Arab countries of the South Mediterranean region (Algeria, Egypt, Syria, Tunisia, Morocco, Jordan, Lebanon, Iraq, Gaza/West Bank and Yemen), we will propose a paradigm shift in conflict-prevention research that highlights how social protection affects peace and conflict . This supports the core Network Plus aim of cross-disciplinary innovation. We will create new epistemic spaces for cross-disciplinary problem-solving across a range of conflict-relevant fields of study: social policy, security and peace studies, gender equality, disability and mental health, environment and resource management, Middle East History, economic policies and visual arts. This will improve knowledge bases, data, methodologies and research practices for conflict prevention and sustainable peace in MENA, thereby better integrating conflict-afflicted MENA societies into the existing literature. Our paradigm shift is oriented by the three core social policy concepts of membership, entitlement and allocation which allow in-depth study of how core questions of resource distribution and social inclusion influence conflict. This new scholarship incorporates CO-I proof of concepts and commissioned grants that will address a major gap in research and practice on social policy governance in MENA.   (2) Enable actionable social policy research for conflict prevention and peace-building in MENA through interdisciplinary problem-solving and experiential policy learning. We will focus on the core social protection fields of employment-based social insurance, non-contributory social assistance to vulnerable groups and labour market policies. This will happen by supporting policy innovations for feasibility, transferability, scalability and good practice learning related to social protection such as cash transfers to citizens and refugees, food/fuel subsidy reforms and access to public services. Our theory of change will entail a framework for actionable research that will integrate our three strands of work as follows: strand (i) scoping will entail comprehensive mapping of MENA stakeholders and a communications plan with our partner organisations to ensure the research objectives address gaps in policy knowledge and link micro with macro social policy governance; strand (ii) commissioning will include a funding stream for pilot interventions so that effective conflict prevention strategies and new policy learning can be shared with key stakeholders; strand (iii) legacy/evaluation will ensure long-term policy change occurs thanks to the new evidence base and capacity building activities of strand (ii).   (3) Embed our network in an ethos of equitable North-South partnership for conflict-prevention policy research that is based on a due diligence protocol promoting inclusion and integrity. The Network will undertake a suite of capacity building and knowledge sharing activities among partner organisations, grant-holders including ECRs, civil society groups and policy stakeholders using various activities such as a social policy governance seminar (year 2), an e-learning course and regular dissemination through our project partners. This will support the Network Plus goal of capacity development. Its target beneficiaries are both researchers and policy makers in MENA and beyond. We will enhance research cultures in our chosen DAC countries through the commissioned calls, peer mentoring of grant-holders and training seminars such as on research ethics. Thanks to the existing epistemic space provided the MENA social policy network (www.menasp.com) upon which this Network Plus proposal builds, we will nurture a new generation of social policy analysts in MENA who are attuned to the policy challenges of conflict prevention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Led by the MENA Social Policy Network, University of Bath, www.menasp.com (founded in 2012 and convened by Jawad, PI), in partnership with the Overseas Development Institute (ODI), this proposal brings together a host of UK and international research leaders and partner organisations to undertake an ambitious programme of cross-disciplinary innovation and capability development in the governance of social policy in MENA. The distinctive contribution this network will make is to introduce a paradigm shift in MENA conflict prevention research, policy and practice that will enhance the social welfare politics of Arab countries in the Sothern Mediterranean region (Levant and North Africa) - our geographical focus. These are ODA compliant countries, the highest exporters of economic migration to Europe and historically, at the nexus of armed conflict in MENA. The Network management team includes expertise in ethics, mental health and disability, Middle East history, anthropology, urban planning and the environment, gender, visual arts and education.   Our Network vision is: to demonstrate, through a mutually supportive framework of innovative, cross-disciplinary research and capacity development for policy change, how effective social policy governance in MENA can provide nuanced and contextualised pathways to peace and emerging localised solution-driven initiatives.  We will do this through a programme of work that will serve GCRF goals as follows:  (1) maximising the impact of Co-I-led proof of concepts and an &#xA3;800,000&apos;s worth of LMIC and UK-led commissioned research strand that is co-designed with LMIC partners and builds on localised expertise; (2) fostering shared learning across innovative peacebuilding research projects and testing the feasibility, scalability, transferability and effectiveness of different approaches across diverse fragile MENA countries; (3) bringing conflict prevention research more centrally into sustainable development planning and programming through the apparatus of social policy governance and its affiliated concept of social protection thereby addressing directly SDGs 1, 3 (reduce poverty; achieve wellbeing across life course), 5 (achieve gender equality), 10 (reduce inequalities) and 11 (promote inclusive peace). Our aims are: (1) Cross-disciplinary innovation: to improve knowledge bases and practices in conflict prevention and sustainable peace in MENA by focusing on the interconnections between community-level social justice grievances and the macro-level governance of social policy; (2) Capacity development of existing research and policy practice: we will support policy learning and &quot;design thinking&quot; such as through policy labs, social policy governance seminars and an e-learning course for policy-makers.   We argue that there is momentum for a fresh and expanded reassessment of the nature and scope of conflict in MENA which directly addresses the long-overlooked question of community-level social justice grievances and how these react against or are reproduced by macro-level political decision-making. We will advance current knowledge and practice by showing how conflict prevention and social policy governance share common concerns: how to enable communities to live cohesively and share resources equitably. This is a fundamentally cross-disciplinary question about state-society relations, otherwise referred to in the contemporary international development literature as &quot;political settlements&quot;. It is an issue of relevance to volatile MENA countries that are now implementing austerity policies at a time when they are also mandated to produce national development plans supporting the universal social protection vision of the SDG 2030 agenda. The challenges of social and income inequality in MENA are stark: in a 2015 report, the World Bank acknowledged the need to address the &quot;quality of life&quot; grievances that had fueled the Arab uprisings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">454725.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">198502.15</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">462121.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">725771.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">113681.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008067_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">113681.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008067_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">113681.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008067_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
