<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P004040_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Boosting growth through strengthening investor and creditor protection in China: How China can learn from the UK experience</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This application demonstrates that the quality of legal institutions can matter for economic development and that important policy lessons can be learned by China from the UK in this regard. This application recognises that China has been a remarkable economic success story but the country also faces new challenges as its economy enters a more mature phase.  In particular, it needs to avoid the &apos;middle income trap&apos; i.e. where a country has costs that are now too high to compete with low-income countries but where productivity does not match those in high-income countries.  There are economies in Asia including Singapore and Hong Kong SAR that have emerged successfully from middle income status. Both these economies  are built on UK law and are renowned for the quality of their legal infrastructure in supporting development of the financial system. The application suggests how China might also benefit from the UK experience in building its legal infrastructure.  But the application recognises China&apos;s singular journey and avoids simplistic conclusions that certain consequences will inevitably follow form certain formal changes.  It recognises the need for a continuous process of adaptation and development; learning appropriately from experience and responding sensitively to local conditions.  The application demonstrates in particular how legal reforms can support economic growth through  - enhancing the protections available to minority investors - supporting the availability of credit and contributing to lower-cost credit - supporting the restructuring of ailing businesses. In  these areas we seek to provide options for enhancing and reforming the legal and financial system in China that are based upon the UK and other experience. We acknowledge that there are choices to be made between means and ends and that the relationship between means and ends is contingent and uncertain.  The data we rely on will come principally from the World Bank Doing Business (DB) reports and rankings which are grounded on the notion that smarter business regulation promotes economic growth. The DB rankings have been issued annually since 2004 and the 2016 rankings includes 11 sets of indicators for 189 economies. Each economy is ranked on the individual indicators and also in an overall table. Currently, the UK is 6th in this table and China 84th but Singapore is 1st and Hong SAR is 5th which shows that it is possible for Asian economies to rank highly. In our project, we will explore deep into the detail underlying the Protecting Minority Investors, Getting credit and Resolving Insolvency indicators. These 3 indicators appear particularly pertinent to the development of a mature financial system and in relation to them all China ranks far below the UK. On protecting investors, China is ranked as 134th whereas the UK is 4th.  We show how the gap can be bridged and how China can learn from the UK experience by examining critically how the UK has protected minority investors and ascertaining what measures of protection might work most effectively in Chinese conditions.   Our approach takes the relevant DB rankings as a guide but subjects them to critical scrutiny  and engaging systematically with the methodology underpinning the rankings; addressing the robustness of this methodology and considering alternative approaches. For instance, we will test the robustness and limitations of the DB &apos;resolving insolvency&apos; data on China using Jiande Municipal People&apos;s Court in Zhejiang Province as a case study.  This makes the process of data collection and analysis more manageable. 20 interviews with creditors and practitioners will be undertaken in Zhejiang Province and data on business closures from the local branches of the China Business Registration Authorities and the China Pension Management Authorities will also be collected. We will also use econometric analyses based on detailed micro data from other data sources</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project demonstrates how China might benefit from the experience of the UK in building its legal infrastructure and creating a more competitive financial and legal system with increased opportunities for all. The World Bank &apos;Doing Business&apos; indicators - www.doingbusiness.org/ measure the quality of legal institutions in supporting economic development.  In the latest rankings, the UK is ranked 6th and China 84th.   The project addresses what legal reforms are required to promote the balanced development of integrated financial markets in China and serve the needs of an increasingly open economy. It addresses in particular how growth can be sustained through legal reforms that will  - enhance the protections available to minority investors - support the availability of credit and contributing to lower-cost credit - support the restructuring of ailing businesses. The project will demonstrate what reforms are needed in these specific areas and how reforms can be made compatible with Chinese conditions. It aims to show, on the basis of the UK experience, World Bank data and other international benchmarks, how a sound financial system fosters economic growth and what part legal institutions can play in facilitating a sound financial system. It also aims to show that legal changes must be sensitive to local conditions and take account of different implementing environments. The project recognises that there are choices, or a set of choices, to be made between means and ends and that the relationship between means and ends is contingent and uncertain. The project provides options for enhancing and reforming the financial system in China that are based upon the UK and other experience rather than setting out answers. it asks how legal institutions in China can be made to work more effectively in such a way as to support economic growth rather than asking whether legal rules can be transplanted from the UK to China.   The project will lead to the production of four 30-40,000 word reports in both English and Chinese.  The reports will take the following form - A report highlighting Law and Development thinking and the general relevance of law and development orthodoxies in Chinese conditions.   - A report detailing the present state of minority investor protection in China; the potential relevance of World Bank indicators as well as possible lessons that might be drawn by China from the UK experience and other international norms. - A report highlighting how the legal rights of creditors might be improved in China with possible positive impacts on the availability and cost of credit.  The WB &apos;getting credit&apos; indicator will be addressed in this context as well as law reform projects in the UK. - A report on how procedures for the bankruptcy and resolution of financially distressed companies might be enhanced in China with consequent benefits for financial soundness and the overall health of the economy.  The report will draw on equivalent processes in the UK, the WB &apos;Resolving Insolvency&apos; sub-indicators and other international norms. These reports will also form the basis of a research monograph to be published by a leading firm of academic publishers such as Cambridge University Press.  The project will have a number of other outputs including a website detailing the progress of the research; 6 papers in key academic and professional journals; 12 conference presentations and submissions to policy makers on the design and execution of possible reforms. Two major conferences are planned  - one in China and one in the UK and also two dissemination events - again one in China and one in the UK. The conferences will help to set the parameters of the project and to refine the research agenda; provide the opportunity of interacting with key policy makers; help in the formulation and articulation of the final conclusions of the project andenhance its practical impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-25">26879.82</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-25">107736.99</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-25">108609.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-25">81951.07</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-25">3576952.368</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P004040_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP004040%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-02-13"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
