<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R018448_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Establishing a child and adolescent twin register for research and capacity building on the aetiology of mental illness in Sri Lanka and other LMIC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Medical Research Council is offering a one year grant opportunity to lay the grounds for future large scale research to study mental health issues in low and middle income countries (LMICs). This will build on existing UK-LMIC partnerships and initiate new ones.   Through this grant, we plan to take the initial steps for such research, and to establish a register of infant, child and adolescent twins, and of mothers pregnant with twins, in Sri Lanka (the capital Colombo in the Western province and Vavuniya in the Northern Province). Once the register is developed, our research will start exploring what causes mental illness; the impact of early brain development and the role of genetic, developmental, environmental, social and cultural contributions on the origin of mental disease. Research on twins has several advantages over studying non-twin people since it is possible to study the similarities and differences of identical and non-identical twins in order to understand the relative contribution of genetics and the environment.   We believe that as a result of the initial work undertaken during the first year, we will be able to establish a large register of young twins, some with linked data from their parents via an existing adult twin register, and identify initial data from routine records on children&apos;s health and education. Being included on the register does not automatically mean involvement in research. Future research projects will need separate consent and ethics approval from the country of origin of the research proposal and SL.  Our long term vision is to increase the amount of research that can have an influence on health and social care in SL and South Asia. The main partner in this venture is the Institute for Research and Development (IRD SL), which has already established one of the few large functioning population-based adult twin registers, successfully carried out two rounds of published studies, recruited a matched non-twin sample and established a biobank and genetic laboratory. We have also partnered with three South Asian institutions: Independent University of Bangladesh, Health Services Academy-Islamabad, Pakistan, and All India Institute of Medical Sciences.  The UK partners are Keele University, Kings College London, and University of Bristol. We will work towards establishing a virtual centre of excellence on cohort studies (following up a large group of persons to do research).    The three main pillars of the initiative are: (i) high quality research, (ii) ethics, (iii) patient and public involvement and engagement (PPIE).  Our team includes world leading experts in twin research, mental health, research methods, ethics, PPIE, and grant development. Increasing the skills of junior academics across the partnership will develop future research leaders and essential skills in all three pillars. We will bring together senior researchers from the partner organisations and form the planning and coordinating units, the steering committee, and the research, ethics and PPIE expert groups to organise these activities. Strengthening the ethics framework within the initiative is very important and we will revise the guidelines developed previously by the IRD.  PPIE is a novel concept to South Asia. Evidence from the UK demonstrates that the quality of research is better and the likelihood of successful recruitment and implementation of the findings is improved when patients and the public are involved in research. We aim to establish a culture of PPIE in Sri Lanka, working with both academic colleagues and lay members; in this instance specifically with twins and their parents.          We plan to develop at least two proposals within the year for further in-depth research and funding. We will decide on the key research questions guided by the research gaps, data gathered during the first year and discussion with patients and public.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective is to establish a register of infant, child and adolescent twins in the Colombo (Western Province) and the Vavuniya Districts (Northern Province) of Sri Lanka (SL), with consent from twins or parents to be approached for future research projects. This will provide the platform to investigate the aetiology of mental illness and the impact of challenges to early brain development. We will expand existing research capacity-building activities on child and adolescent mental health, twin methods, further consolidate existing partnerships and establish new collaborations. The initiative is underpinned by three pillars: developing (1) high quality research, (2) ethics and (3) patient and public involvement and engagement (PPIE), which is a relatively novel concept for South Asia. The specific objectives (in order of priority) are: 1. To establish governance, ethical and logistical systems for the creation of the infant, child and adolescent twin data base register in the Colombo and the Vavuniya districts.    a. Bring together named LMIC and High Income Countries  investigators from the key partner organisations, and establish the planning and coordinating units, the steering committee, and research, ethics and PPIE expert groups to develop strategy and plan relevant activities.    b. Strengthen the ethics framework within the initiative by revising the existing guidelines developed previously by the Institute for Research and Development (IRD) SL.   2. Initiate exploratory activities in Sri Lanka to generate preliminary information needed to develop future applications, and continue to gather information on twin and mothers pregnant with twins in the two districts and encourage them to register with the data base.  3. Initiate PPIE work in SL. We will plan to organise a high profile event by involving celebrities and leading professionals who are twins / have twin children. We will also use the IRD tri-lingual magazine Gaveshana (The Explorer) which promotes health and social care research and ethics among school children and parents to promote PPIE activities.   4. Initiate small scale exploratory activities in India, Pakistan and Bangladesh..  5. Develop two grant proposals, taking into consideration research gaps in child and adolescent mental health research and submit within the year  6. Initiate twin research specific capacity building process at Keele and LMIC, through an introductory course on twin methods and advanced course at Kings College, further strengthening the early and mid-career capacity enhancement by offering the opportunity to work with expert groups  Background, feasibility and justification Colombo district is predominantly urban (80%) and has 10% of the SL population (2,324,349). The ethnic distribution is 76% Sinhala, 12% Tamil and 11% Moor and, 15% of the district population is concentrated in the Greater Colombo where the ethnic distribution is different; 39% Moor, 33% Tamil and 25% Sinhalese. The Vavuniya district has predominantly a rural population (80%) of 172,000, and 83% Tamil, 10% Sinhala and 6% Moor. These new cohorts provide a good ethnic and urban/rural mix.  Twinning rate in SL is 10 per 1000 live births. The Colombo district has 40,000 births per year, with an estimated number of 7,000 twin pairs and the Vavuniya district 4,000 births per year and 700 twin pairs,up to the age of 18 years.   The Institute for Research and Development in SL established an adult cohort of 9500 twin pairs, imaintained it and conducted a longitudinal study with two successful waves of data collection. The details of twins aged up to 5 years can be accessed through the Family Health Bureau, Ministry of Health, collected through Primary Health Care workers (1:3,000 population). All mothers pregnant with twins are registered with these Primary Health Care workers. Twins aged 5-18 we plan to gain access to through schools.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-01">199435.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Rapid Response Research Grants Award to Keele University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R018448/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">199435.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R018448_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR018448%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
