<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_P017622_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of serology diagnosis of chronic aspergillosis and histoplasmosis in Indonesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chronic pulmonary aspergillosis (CPA) is a progressive and usually fatal complication of multiple pulmonary disorders, notably pulmonary (TB), chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and those with non-tuberculous mycobacterial infections. Its radiological and clinical manifestations are similar to TB and it is often mistaken for smear negative TB. The detection in serum of Aspergillus fumigatus IgG is the key diagnostic test, but is barely available in low and middle income countries (LMICs). Treatment options are amphotericin B or itraconazole, or the newer azoles and echinocandins, which are ~60% effective. Surgery can be curative in selected cases with localised disease. There are thought to be about 1.2 million post-TB cases of CPA, and at least double that in other conditions. In all pulmonary TB patients clinically and microbiologically diagnosed in 2012 (WHO data) whose sputum was analysed by microscopy, 1,900,000 of 4,400,000 (43%) were smear negative. Smear negative &apos;TB&apos; (or smear not done) was therefore diagnosed in 2.75 million people in 2014 (Table). Later culture confirmation of TB is expected in ~19-39% of these patients. TB cases             All Cases notified Pulmonary TB cases Total deaths                    Survived                                                                               Total Smear positive Smear negative HIV positive 1,100,000    n/a             935,000             360,000     629,000  358,530          270,470 HIV negative 7,900,000    n/a          6,715,000          1,100,000   5,780,000     3,294,600       2,485,400 Total                9,000,000 5,719,753          7,650,000          1,500,000   6,409,000     3,653,130       2,755,870 The differential diagnosis of smear negative TB includes CPA and chronic pulmonary histoplasmosis (CPH). The key test for disease is Aspergillius or Histoplasma antibody, along with imaging. While Aspergillus antibody testing is widely available in specialist laboratories, it is not yet integrated into TB programs. A simple screening test is required that can be read locally and would allow CPA to be provisionally diagnosed with additional imaging, quantitative Aspergillus antibody measurement and initation of antifungal therapy. CPH is probably less common, but is impossible to diagnose without fungal culture of sputum (and H. capsulatum is a class 3 pathogen) as current IgG serology is (probably) insensitive and is not widely available. In this joint program of work, we will 1) construct the world&apos;s first ever point of care test for Aspergillus IgG antibody, evaluate its performance in Manchester and Jakarata, and aim to make it ready for full commercialisation, 2) develop a new ELISA antibody test for Histoplasma IgG antibodies, using classical antigen finding tools and evaluate its performance in areas of Indonesia where histoplasmosis is endemic. The clinical evaluation will require identifying some &apos;hot spots&apos; for histoplasmosis to find enough cases (aim 3). We also intend to make this assay ready for commercialisation, as an ELISA.  This proposal has the potential to transform several aspects of the management of patients thought to have pulmonary TB, in Indonesia and beyond and improve the general health of 100,000s.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chronic pulmonary aspergillosis mimics pulmonary tuberculosis, and can follow it. An estimated 1.2 million are affected worldwide, and ~85,000 in Indonesia. Histoplasmosis is endemic in Indonesia but no burden estimate is possible as the only tools for diagnosis are culture and histopathology, which are slow and insensitive. The burden of histoplasmosis is not known in the world or in Indonesia, partly because of poor diagnostic tools. Chronic pulmonary histoplasmosis complicates other lung disease, notably COPD, and mimics tuberculosis.  Both fungal infections are misdiagnosed as &apos;smear negative TB&apos;. These patients are often investigated for MDR TB, and treated inappropriately with anti-tuberculous medication. The 5 year mortality of chronic pulmonary aspergillosis is 75-80%, but reduced to ~40% with antifungal therapy.  In this grant we will: 1. Develop and evaluate in the UK and Indonesia the world&apos;s first point of care Aspergillus antibody screening assay to enable the diagnosis of chronic pulmonary aspergillosis. 2. Develop and evaluate in Indonesia a new Histoplasma antibody assay to enable the diagnosis of acute and chronic pulmonary histoplasmosis. 3. Identify for the first time &apos;hot spots&apos; for histoplasmosis in Indonesia, so as to develop a sera bank for evaluating the antibody test, to support subsequent commercialisation. We have access to highly purified recombinant Aspergillus fumigatus proteins, that have been used in an ELISA format to detect Aspergillus IgG antibody with a 97% sensitivity and a 90% specificity. In Manchester at the Mycology Reference Centre laboratories and National Aspergillosis Centre, we will use these proteins to develop a lateral flow device utilising our huge sera bank from patients with chronic pulmonary aspergillosis and other respiratory disorders to optimize performance against a gold standard assay (ImmunCap). We will then utilize the assay in field trials in the UK as a prospective screen for Aspergillus antibody in the laboratory, and in Jakarta in a cross-sectional study (n=600 patients) and a longitudinal study (n= 200 patients) both in patients with PTB. In the UK, the gold standard assay will be the ImmunoCap and in Jakarta the Siemens assay. During the field trials we will open up commercialization discussions.  In Jakarta, we will identify additional immunodominant proteins in Histoplasma capsulatum yeast phase. We will standardize growth and purification conditions for supernatant production to optimize sensitivity and specificity of a new ELISA Histoplasma antibody test using sera from non-immunocompromised patients with histoplasmosisand controls. We will further validate this assay on additional sera (see Aim 3), to optimize performance. We will prepare the materials for subsequent production of recombinant proteins for a second generation antibody test.   In parallel with this laboratory activity, we will undertake several skin testing surveys with histoplasmin in Jakarta and its surrounding cities (Bogor, Depok, Tanggerang and Bekasi - Jabodetabek), Bandung, Semarang, Surabaya, Bali, and Manado. This will be done by setting up a new Histoplasmosis network in Indonesia. We need to identify more sera for test validation and cutoffs, and the simplest way to do this in Indonesia, is to pinpoint areas of high endemicity and then actively seek out patients in those areas with chronic pulmonary histoplasmosis, through existing TB clinics, focusing on those with &apos;smear negative&apos; TB. So in areas of &gt;10% local skin test positivity, we will ask the local participating clinicians to identify possible patients and submit fungal diagnostic samples. Fungal culture of sputum or bronchoscopy fluid will be the gold standard for diagnosis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">71004.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">141101.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">46379.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">3877291.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_P017622_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP017622%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-11-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
