<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S002278_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluation of a Mask Aerosol Sampling System (MASS) as an Active Case Finding Approach Focused on Infectious TB in Low-Resource Settings.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Globally, tuberculosis (TB) is the most important cause of death and disease due to a single bacterial agent. TB is transmitted by aerosols (tiny droplets expelled by coughing and other respiratory efforts) generated by infected individuals. The bacteria-containing droplets are breathed deep into the lungs where, over months and years, disease is produced in about one in ten of those who get the initial infection.  Over one quarter of humanity is infected with the bacterium that causes TB, Mycobacterium tuberculosis (Mtb), but only people who go on to develop lung disease can spread the infection. Mtb must cause lung disease and be spread by aerosols to survive in the long term; if we prevent transmission, eventually the organism will die out and the disease will be eliminated. Thus, detection and treatment of infectious cases is of paramount importance. TB is a disease associated with poverty and, in resource constrained settings, many cases of TB go undiagnosed. This is particularly so in sub-Saharan Africa where healthcare is resource limited. Here, detection of individuals with suggestive symptoms (e.g.  prolonged cough) and Mtb positive sputum (coughed up mucus) provides the main means of diagnosis. However, many symptomatic individuals do not access healthcare, even when enabled to do so by community health workers (CHWs) and a significant proportion (20-50%) are not able to produce sputum. The Leicester team have been developing the use of adapted face masks to capture aerosols in a way that allows detection of Mtb in the World Health Organisation-recommended Mtb detection system, called Xpert MTB/RIF. The mask samples allow detection of Mtb positive individuals at a similar frequency to sputum analysis. However, unlike sputum samples, everyone who can wear a mask produces a sample in our mask aerosol sampling system (MASS). MASS is very low cost and requires only modest expertise to take and analyse the samples. In this project we shall evaluate use of the MASS as a low cost community screening tool. Our study is based in the Tshwane district of South Africa (around 1% are estimated to have lung TB) where the Pretoria team have developed a community oriented primary care (COPC) programme (http://www.up.ac.za/en/family-medicine/article/2077127/launch-video) directed to patient and household (HH) centred health promotion. Building on our established TB aerosol collaboration (MRC and Wellcome Trust funded) and, critically, with the support of the 1670 COPC CHWs, we now plan to evaluate application of MASS as a TB screening tool in Tshwane. If favourable, this evaluation will enable us to develop a large scale intervention trial where we will compare the in-practice capacity of MASS-based screening to detect infectious cases with the conventional approach of symptom and sputum screening. If a high proportion of such cases can be detected and treated, the approach has clear potential to reduce the overall frequency of TB in this and other poor communities. We will first test MASS in the CHWs to optimise the 15 minute procedure and train them for the study. We will then use the standard CHW review programme to detect HHs with individuals showing TB-related symptoms. Following informed consent, all members of such HHs aged 5 years and above will be mask sampled. We aim to sample 120 HHs with symptomatic individuals and expect to detect at least 20-40 positives. In parallel, through data collected from the near 300,000 individuals registered on the COPC programme we will identify 120 HHs matched for key socioeconomic indicators. All members of these HHs will be sampled as above. Symptomatic individuals and MASS positive individuals will all be referred to local clinics for standard diagnosis and treatment. We believe MASS could enable resource-constrained health systems to focus control efforts on the most infectious TB cases and their contacts, thereby reducing transmission and consequently reducing disease.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this study is to evaluate use of a simple face Mask Aerosol Sampling System (MASS) as a novel tool with potential to support community-based tuberculosis (TB) control. The study will be based in Pretoria, South Africa. TB is transmitted by patient-generated aerosols. To date, sampling of expectorated aerosols has been limited to resource intensive approaches such as the Riley/Wells guinea pig transmission facilities and, more recently, the Cough Aerosol Sampling System (CASS) established by Fennelly and colleagues. Here we will evaluate use of face masks adapted by inclusion of a sampling matrix filter as a means of detecting individuals producing aerosols containing Mycobacterium tuberculosis (Mtb). The work builds on the applicants&apos; established programme of aerosol sampling studies in Leicester, Pretoria and The Gambia using both MASS and CASS. Critically, MASS is compatible with analysis on the Xpert MTB/RIF (XP) system that is heavily supported by WHO. Our individual MASS studies to date have been small scale (~100 samples) and clinic-based. This PHIND study will enable us to evaluate use of 15 minute MASS samples in a community setting on a sufficient scale to determine whether the approach can be used for active case finding in a follow on (main) intervention trial. While the specific achievable outcomes of the main trial will be determined by the results of this study combined with our parallel transmission-related studies, our aspiration is to use MASS to identify infectious individuals in populations with high TB prevalence. We hypothesise that MASS will enable early community-based detection of highly infectious individuals and that a combination of focussing limited resources on rendering these individuals non-infectious and protecting their contacts from developing disease will reduce transmission and rapidly impact on disease prevalence. This PHIND study will enable us to determine the feasibility and design of a trial to test this hypothesis. Outstanding value is added to this proposal by the programme of Community Oriented Primary Care (COPC) supported by funded Community Health Workers (CHWs) and established by our key collaborator, Professor Janni Hugo and colleagues in the department of Family Medicine in the University of Pretoria (UP). The programme is focused on the Tshwane municipality of Gauteng province and the target population here will be high TB prevalence communities. Our specific objectives for the present study are:   1.To optimise the MASS procedure for use in the target population by test sampling of CHWs   2.To determine mask XP positivity rates in:      a.120 households* (HHs) containing individuals with pTB-related symptoms.       b.120 HHs matched for financial, food security and immunisation status (key correlates of TB prevalence in this community). All household members of 5 years and above will be sampled (~1200 individuals). Sampling in group b will not depend on the presence of a symptomatic HH member.   3.To compare pTB diagnostic pick up rates for       a.MASS vs sputum analysis in 2a,       b.Symptom-triggered MASS vs non-selective sampling (2a vs 2b). All symptomatic and all Mtb aerosol positive individuals will be given diagnostic clinic access. Attendance and follow up rates will be assessed.   4.To determine the overall performance of and acceptability of MASS sampling compared to conventional symptom based screening and sputum analysis. *From previous prevalence surveys we estimate that 2a will yield 20-40 pTB sputum XP positive cases. We anticipate that results of mask sampling will equal or exceed this number because a) all individuals will be able to give a sample and b) some asymptomatic HH members will also be positive.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-13">54257.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-13">72902.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">30021.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S002278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">24235.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S002278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">24235.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S002278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">24235.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S002278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">24431.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S002278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">24431.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S002278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
