<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T030240_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Co-produced mobile consulting for remote, marginalised communities in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is a United Nations Sustainable Development Goal to achieve universal health coverage with access to quality healthcare for all. Our network plans to evaluate the contribution to this goal of mobile consulting (mConsulting). This is when patients consult with health providers about their health using digital communication. Our concern is remote, marginalised communities in Africa that have difficulty accessing quality health care.  The digital infrastructure of Africa is its best infrastructure - much better than the roads, and most people own a mobile phone. We want to test whether using digital infrastructure for mConsulting improves access to quality healthcare for remote, marginalised communities and whether this is sustainable. mConsulting needs to be affordable to the community and for providers. However, improved healthcare can improve the health of the community and so increase economic activity and use of mConsulting can stimulate investment in digital infrastructure benefiting the community.  Commercial companies are delivering mConsulting services in Africa. Currently they target urban communities but could extend their reach to remote communities. In addition to good mobile signal and sustainable business models they need community acceptance and integration with local providers for certain diagnostic tests and treatments. Existing health services (public or private) can add mConsulting to their services e.g. a health worker using a mobile phone for consulting. This needs planning to ensure professional standards and patient acceptability.   We are academics/researchers, mConsulting providers and policy organisations. Four of the academic/research teams (Kenya, Nigeria, Tanzania and UK) have collaborated on research and research capacity building for ten years. We have extended our team to further organisations in our countries and in Uganda and Rwanda. Our expertise includes, technical, medical, nursing, education, social and behavioural science, health systems, economics and epidemiology.  We aim to evaluate the impact of mConsulting on healthcare access and health outcomes for remote marginalised communities and explore how it can be optimally delivered. We will do this in varied contexts of East and West Africa so we learn what works well (or not) in different places, with different histories, policies and health systems. Our results will be relevant to diverse settings across Africa.   To do this we will develop a research proposal for funding. We will first use the seed network funding to: 1. Extend and consolidate our networks to include all relevant and necessary people/organisations; 2. Work with remote community representatives, local healthcare providers, mConsulting providers, policy makers (and telecommunication providers where needed) to collaboratively identify plans for mConsulting including challenges to be overcome before implementation and evaluation; 3. Explore innovative ways of working across commercial, research and policy sectors to build research capacity and create opportunities for exchange.  We expect our follow-on research will evaluate mConsulting for primary care, for certain types of health problems e.g. acute conditions, long-term conditions, child and maternal health, mental health. Our choice will depend on what is priority for the communities. Our research objectives are to:  I) Evaluate whether mConsulting results in change in community access to healthcare and in measures of health outcomes for selected tracer conditions (e.g. blood pressure for hypertension, patient reported symptoms for depression); II) Evaluate what aspects of mConsulting work well (or not), where, when and for whom. We will observe, interview and collect activity data; III) Identify contextual factors that need to change to ensure scalability of mConsulting (e.g. professional training, regulations, financing).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This seed fund network will facilitate the development of an interdisciplinary, inter-sector and international team working on Digital Health and Digital Rights. The team will focus on mobile consulting (mConsulting) that is when patients consult with healthcare providers on a health issue using some form of digital communication. The mConsulting will be aimed at remote, marginalised communities of East and West Africa. The network will catalyse the development of a large-scale proposal to be submitted for the second round of DIDA funding.  Our proposed seed fund Network includes organisations based in Nigeria, Kenya, Tanzania, Uganda, and Rwanda and has the following sequential objectives: 1. Extend and consolidate our interdisciplinary and inter-sector network to include all relevant, necessary people/organisations; 2. Co-produce with remote communities and their local healthcare providers, mConsulting providers, policy makers and telecommunication providers where needed, plans for mconsulting for the communities; 3. Explore innovative approaches to research capacity building, mentorship and partnership that will form the framework for collaborative working in future research; 4. Develop a proposal to evaluate the impact of mConsulting provision on healthcare access and health outcome and to explore what works (or not) for whom, where, when and why.  During co-production, we will identify community priorities for healthcare and what they would value about mConsulting. We expect plans to be for a domain of primary care such as acute conditions or long-term conditions or child and maternal health or mental health. In the follow-on research, mConsulting providers and/or healthcare providers developing mConsulting will implement a service for remote marginalised communities in 2 or more African countries, within a primary care health domain. We will: I) Evaluate the impact of mConsulting on health status and healthcare access; II) Evaluate what works, where, when and for whom; III) Identify contextual factors that need to change to ensure scalability of successful mConsulting.   Our seed network and follow-on research will meet DIDA programme strategic goals as we will: A) Answer research questions: What is the impact of mobile consulting (mConsulting) provision on the healthcare access and health outcomes of remote marginalised communities in Africa? How is mConsulting optimally integrated with local healthcare provision and why? B) Collaborate throughout the research with healthcare users and their local providers in remote communities, mConsulting providers, and policy makers so resulting research evidence gains immediate impact - supporting or not, implementation of mConsulting for remote communities in Africa; C) Produce research evidence on whether and how mConsulting can contribute to the United Nations Sustainable Development Goal of universal health coverage with access to quality healthcare for all in Africa; D) Produce evidence relevant to and scalable in different contexts in Africa through evaluating a variety of locally co-produced manifestations of mConsulting for remote, marginalised communities, and identifying contextual factors that enable or inhibit its success in impacting on health need; E) Strengthen research capacity in digital health research and innovation in Africa, particularly implementation of digital health solutions for marginalised communities; F) Establish new models of mentorship and partnership for digital research and innovation between Africa and the UK and between universities, commercial companies, policy makers, healthcare providers and communities so we leverage the strengths of all stakeholders to collaboratively optimise healthcare provision for marginalised communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-31">137857.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">68928.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T030240_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">34464.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T030240_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
