<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_V003828_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5G: Fusing the Istanbul theatre and games sectors for a more sustainable, productive and connected future</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">5G is the fifth generation of wireless technology that enables high speed and high quality mass connectivity in multi media digital communication. It has a wide range of potential applications, not least in the cultural and creative industries. This project brings together the strengths of technological and creative development in the UK and Turkey: Turkey has a fantastic 5G roll out programme, and the UK is leading in the area of innovative immersive creative performance, predicted to be a major application of 5G. Seeking to connect the arts and creative industries with universities and digital technology sector, the 5G:XR project will stimulate new local &apos;fused&apos; (creative + digital) networks in Istanbul and Brighton and new academic + industry partnerships between the two cities and countries.  The project will demonstrate the potential value of research institutions bringing together the established cultural sector (in this case, performing arts) and contemporary creative digital industry (in this case, games) to explore the adoption and applications of new technologies; specifically 5G and the creation of new forms of digital culture. This is a prime opportunity for knowledge exchange, utilizing the UK&apos;s immersive performance expertise combined with theoretically anchored media research, to ensure that it can have a transformative impact on prosperity, social cohesion and sustainable growth along with the rest of the 5G roll out in Istanbul. Istanbul as a region has great potential to be fused but has not engaged the creative industries in their 5G development. Creative Industries provide a great platform to engage and translate the potential for new technology to wide audiences and with its rich performing arts ecosystem Istanbul is the perfect place to enhance and take learning from and add value to the work we have done in Brighton to achieve creative experiences, which will generate prosperity to that sector in Turkey, using the potentials of 5G.  Digital media and cultural industries researchers will work together with a performing arts collective, industry partners and 5G testbed venues to explore the impact of 5G on the way arts and culture is made and shared, locally and internationally, face-to-face and virtually. We will also seek to explore opportunities for two creative sectors - performing arts and the games industry to collaborate and innovate through cross fertilisation, centred around 5G technology, and engage with the question of what artists and practitioners from the performing arts and games sector bring to the critical understanding and practical application of 5G.  In addition to the creative implications, we will look at the potential strategic and business opportunities that 5G affords for these creative industries in reaching new audiences (face-to-face and virtually), establishing new income and activity streams (diversifying content, and modes of delivery), or addressing wider social challenges (difficulties of access) and environmental concerns (carbon-heavy transportation of talent and audiences). Ultimately the objectives of the project align with the OECD Going Digital project aim to develop &apos;tools [...] to help [...] economies and societies prosper in an increasingly digital and data-driven world&apos; (OECD digital Economy Papers, July 2019).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the project are to: 1) Build a researcher and creative industries network across Turkey and the UK around the key themes of the project: Exploring the potential for 5G for the games and performing arts sector, particularly around technology supported immersive experiences of arts and gaming, e.g. mixed reality (XR), virtual reality (VR), and augmented reality (AR).   2)  Identify areas for future research and development that will form the basis for further industry/ academia collaboration and follow-on funding bid development.   3) Facilitate closer collaboration between the performing arts and games sector in the Istanbul region and explore opportunities for the cultural and creative industries to link with technology businesses, forming &apos;fused&apos; networks.   4) Internationalise possibilities for the existing performing arts and games cluster in Brighton. 5) Collate a global evidence and literature review of 5G for cultural innovation to identify challenges and opportunities. 6) Identify commonalities and synergies between the XR &apos;immersive&apos; sectors in Turkey and the UK and use these shared aspects to forge a new network. 7) Scope out specific collaborative projects that the sectors can collaborate on locally and internationally. 8) Foster stronger partnership working between academic institutions and industry in Brighton and Istanbul. 9) Support the career development of ECRs with expertise in this emerging area of research, by enabling them to work internationally; lead on particular work packages within the project; and receive mentoring by more senior colleagues.  10) Provide excellent value for money by engaging with partners who have already established fit for purpose facilities for test bed activities (Wired Sussex/ Brighton Dome Brighton Festival and Bahcesehir University Game Lab); utilise technology to limit the need to travel (i.e. hosting distributed workshop simultaneously in Brighton and Istanbul); and invest in building the network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-11">37615.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-11">37615.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Research Networking Award to University of Brighton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/V003828/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FV003828%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-05-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
