<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V004263_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Art of Healing in Kashmir: how creative activities can support child wellbeing in areas of conflict</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research will study how art-based therapies can support child wellbeing in the context of conflict. Our work is set within the Indian territory of Jammu and Kashmir. In August 2019, the Indian Government withdrew the State of Jammu and Kashmir&apos;s semi-autonomous status by repealing article 370 and 35A from the Indian Constitution. This was followed by a lockdown, which included blackout of all internet services and telephone networks, widespread curfews, and closing down of public transport and many other public services.   While there is limited research on children and conflict in Kashmir, scholarship from other contexts demonstrates that children are particularly vulnerable in militarised areas and that healing trauma is central for sustainable peace. As the lockdown in Kashmir eases, it is a critical time to facilitate healing and wellbeing for those who have experienced trauma.  According to our partners in Kashmir, many children feel isolated, &apos;numb&apos;, and are expressing emotional and behaviour symptoms consistent with PTSD. Our local partners in Pulwama, Kashmir - the Dolphin School - run a Wellness Programme through which they provide support to symptomatic children expressing a desire for assistance. The school is well-versed in the arts (the principle has studied and delivered Arts-Based Therapy) and hopes to draw on the power of creativity to facilitate healing. In this project we will support the Dolphin School to deliver drama, visual arts, and puppetry, to children for therapeutic benefits.   Our central research question: what is the potential for arts activities and arts-based therapies to support the mental health and wellbeing of children affected by conflict?  This question will be investigated via three phases over 10 months    Phase 1 (May 2020):  project initiation and establishment of draft evaluation mechanisms.  This will be a quick start up that includes two literature reviews led by the academic team and a workshop held in Bristol.  Through this phase we will: i) establish our baseline expectations regarding how we believe art therapies can benefit children at the Dolphin School; ii) agree the evaluation strategy and iii) finalise travel, risk management, safeguarding and ethics.  Phase 2 (May-June to November 2020): delivering art activities to children in Kashmir and evaluating the impact.  Following our second workshop, we will facilitate the delivery of the arts activities (by arts partners Katkatha and Vikramjeet Sinha) at the Dolphin School. Phase 2 also includes research fieldwork including: a) on-site evaluation; b) interviews with stakeholders and NGOs; and c) visual documentation.   Phase 3 (November 2020 to February 2021): involves analysis, refinement of outputs, dissemination and impact. We will hold two further workshops in Kashmir to facilitate evaluation and sharing of amongst our partners and beyond. In addition, we will facilitate the development of a training module / workbook that can be used by arts practitioners looking to advance arts approaches to wellbeing in Kashmir and other conflict areas.   Outputs: The project will result in a number of outputs including a contribution to the health and wellbeing of children in Kashmir.  In addition, we will produce: three journal articles across three disciplines; policy outputs (project report and short summaries); a website and blog narrating the experiences; a locally-produced film documentation of the project (and training for a local film-maker); and a workbook / training module for future arts activities and art based therapies in Kashmir.  Feasibility note: we have received preliminary approval from UWE Health and Safety team to travel to Kashmir.  This approval will be reviewed as the university and staff monitor restrictions and impacts associated with COVID-19. As we have robust local collaborations in place, we are confident that we can deliver this research remotely if travel restrictions limit UK travel.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-05-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-08">126783.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="&apos;The Art of Healing in Kashmir&apos; will directly support the mental health and wellbeing of children affected by conflict in Kashmir.  Our investigation is centred on Pulwama, a district which has been at the centre of clashes and violence between the Indian army and resistance groups. Many children growing up in Pulwama have lost loved ones, witnessed violence, and experienced high levels of uncertainty and trauma.  They are in need of support and care.    Our first and most central objective is to identify and address the needs of children in Pulwama who are demonstrating difficulties including the symptoms of post-traumatic stress disorder. The AHRC&apos;s urgency programme provides a unique opportunity to provide support and assistance to children as they return to school (which have been closed since August 2019).    Within this context, our second objective is to rigorously investigate the general potential of  arts activities and art-based therapies to support the mental health and wellbeing of children affected by conflict. This intervention will enable us to refine methodologies which can support future arts/wellbeing interventions in Kashmir and other areas of conflict / post-conflict.   Our third objective is to enhance the networks, skills and organisational capacity of all our collaborators. This will happen through the co-delivery of art activities  with Kashmiri-based initiatives, including Yakjah (a peacebuilding network) and WISCOMP (a South Asian think tank). This process will also provide enjoyable and meaningful experiences for the participating children, resources for educators, and catalyse new relationships between the Dolphin School, the Katkatha Puppet Arts Trust, and Vikramjeet Sinha.   The project&apos;s fourth objective is to facilitate mutual knowledge-exchange, as we work with local people in all our research and arts activities, for long-term legacy. For example, we will provide training to a young Kashmiri filmmaker (Suhai Hamid Parray), whilst benefiting from his local knowledge and language competencies. We will also respectfully utilise and contribute to the expertise of WISCOMP&apos;s research team who have agreed to provide &apos;on the ground&apos; support and fieldwork for data gathering.   Our fifth objective is to support long-term wellbeing and processes of healing through the establishment of replicable training modules which can be used by our partners and others in Kashmir, and beyond. We expect to produce a workbook with detailed descriptions of the process, measurement techniques, and other ideas to support therapeutic art activities in Kashmir and other conflict areas.    Our sixth objective is to inform the humanitarian sector regarding the role of the arts in the wellbeing of children in areas of conflict and trauma. We draw on and expand our relationships with NGOs within and beyond India.  We expect to disseminate widely through our local NGO partners and via ActionAid, Save the Children, Amnesty International, and others.   Finally, we note how the project also seeks to support the achievement of Sustainable Development Goals including: the need to work towards peaceful and inclusive societies (SDG16) ensure healthy lives and promote wellbeing for all at all ages (SDG3).  This includes specific efforts to support mental health and reduce the global suicide rate."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">44374.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V004263_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007164">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West of England</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">44374.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V004263_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007164">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West of England</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
