<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002681_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mass spectrometry techniques for rapid detection of adulteration of milk powder and vegetable oils in developing countries.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective is to continue and deepen our existing collaboration with China, India, Malaysia, Morocco, Singapore, Sri Lanka, and Uganda in the framework of International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) coordinated research project (&quot;Field-deployable Analytical Methods to Assess the Authenticity, Safety and Quality of Food&quot;, IAEA, CRP #D52040 &amp; G42007, 2017-2021). Under this project the samples of milk powder and vegetable oils will be collected from different geographical regions/ producers and sent to our laboratory for analysis.  The specific research objective is to apply the analytical capabilities of the new tabletop technology (photoionisation mass spectrometry), developed in The University of Manchester under STFC support, to the problems of food adulteration in developing countries with the aim of developing cheap and rapid analytical methods capable of screening the food adulterants in a field deployable context.    The work will incorporate the analytical campaign and knowledge transfer phases and will include the following tasks:        - Coordination of collection of milk powder and vegetable oil samples from China, India, Malaysia, Morocco, Singapore, Sri Lanka, and Uganda (funded by IAEA and UN) and their transport to our laboratory in Manchester; - Screening of milk powder samples for antibiotics residues e.g. sulphonamides, nitrofurans, tetracycline, penicillin-G, ampicillin, amoxicillin, cloxacillin, oxaxillin, dicloxacillin, cefadroxyl, cefalexin, cefoperazone and cefuroxime; - Screening of milk powder samples for nitrogen rich compounds e.g. ammeline, ammelide, melamine, cyanuric acid, allantoin, thiourea, urea, biuret, triuret, semicarbazide, aminotriazine, cyanamide, dicyandiamide, guanidine, choline, hydroxyproline; - Determination of fatty acids profiles of the collected vegetable oils and its statistical analysis for identification of the possible adulteration by addition of mixtures containing the oils of deferent kinds and/or refined products; - Sharing the developed protocols and analytical results with collaborators and joint publications and collaboration with industry partners- participants of the IAEA project (e.g. Oxford Instruments Industrial Products Ltd, UK) in order to facilitate commercialisation of technology developed under STFC support; - Organisation of visits between the UK and overseas collaborators in China, India, Malaysia, Morocco, Singapore, Sri Lanka, and Uganda for participation in the measurements and providing a technical advice on developed analytical methods and protocols to facilitate knowledge transfer to research bases available in developing countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The photoionisation mass spectrometry has been developed at The University of Manchester and matured under continuous support from STFC. It has reached an unprecedented sensitivity of fg/ sample, reduced in size down to tabletop making it cheap and transportable, opening the way for rapid screening capabilities in developing countries. The project will identify and select appropriate analytical techniques and develop protocols to assess the authenticity, safety and quality of food in developing countries. Milk powder and vegetable oils will be used as exemplar commodities to establish methods and guidance for &apos;front-line&apos; food adulteration screening. We will continue and deepen our existing collaboration with China, India, Malaysia, Morocco, Singapore, Sri Lanka, and Uganda in the framework of International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) coordinated research project &quot;Field-deployable analytical methods to assess the authenticity, safety and quality of food&quot;. The samples of milk powder and vegetable oils will be collected from different geographical regions/ producers of these countries and sent to our Manchester laboratory for analysis. They will be screened for harmful antibiotics residues and traces of nitrogen reach compounds e.g. urea and biuret. Their fatty acids profiles will be determined and statistically analysed to reveal the origin and possible adulteration by mixing with other less expensive or refined products.     Together with the collaborators from developing countries, experts from IAEA and UN and industry we will analyse and disseminate the data obtained in the analytical campaign which will help in shaping the new policies in developing countries and the UK, improve food safety and quality, and may lead to commercialisation of technology developed under STFC support. We will provide a technical advice and guidance and assist in transfer of developed analytical methods and protocols to a research and commercial bases available in China, India, Malaysia, Morocco, Singapore, Sri Lanka, and Uganda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-19">20214.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-19">20214.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">10107.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002681_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">-2179.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002681_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-19">40428.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC GCRF RCUK Award to The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST/R002681/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FR002681%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
