<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024887_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bridging national strategy on sustainable development of water-energy-food systems to local scale needs in Malawi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progress towards the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) requires addressing many interlinked challenges related to water, energy and food systems. There are inevitable trade-offs in addressing the SDGs and climate change mitigation and adaptation targets, but also synergies if policy is well designed in a cross-sectoral manner. However, nations typically do not have the tools to identify and implement interventions, including evaluating the trade-offs and synergies, and monitor their effectiveness.  Furthermore, land use decisions on water-energy-food (WEF) policy need to take into account sub-national and local scale needs and priorities, both human and environmental.  Despite being the intended targets of policy, rural people with limited resources and education are often marginalized in decision making and therefore do not benefit when trade-offs in policy implementation are made to take account of the variety of actors. This project focuses on enhancing equity of rural people&apos;s key participatory roles in shaping and making policy work in order to bridge the gap between national scale priorities/strategies and gender-sensitive local scale needs, including environmental sustainability. Our focus will be on Malawi, which is high on the DAC list, has low population density and is largely rural. It also varies culturally and environmentally, which allows us to examine gaps around a range of policies and subsistence strategies.  Bridging the scales is vital because homogenous policy formulation and implementation at the national or even sub-national scale is problematic for communities because rural people are not homogenous, with fundamentally varying kinds of and access to resources. These systems need to account for landscape diversity and gendered differences in their uptake and impacts, and therefore policies need to be tailored or disaggregated to ensure that they are relevant and are successful without unintended consequences. Many things that happen in the &quot;hidden middle&quot; that bridge the national and local scales are often ignored in policy and implementation. The hidden middle includes local to sub-national organizations; informal and formal supply chains that connect smallholders to domestic markets; kin, political, religious and other social networks. These meso-scale actors play essential roles in filling policy gaps, making up for shortcomings in infrastructure and connecting rural communities to a more diverse set of livelihood opportunities. We have identified gaps in the functioning of cross-scale interactions that affect Malawi&apos;s aggregate water-energy-food security, and its distributional access and benefits. By understanding the nature of these gaps, our objective is to identify solutions/policies that increase local livelihood opportunities and their sustainability. This will be done by better understanding: - how rural farmers of all genders and their local environments are connected to policy processes via the complex hierarchy of institutional arrangements  - how rural farmers are connected via social and other networks, and how this helps to sustain livelihoods and increase resilience to change/shocks - how biophysical heterogeneity intersects with human activity, national policy and its effectiveness. - how competing interests, for example among and between rural farmers and commercial agriculture, give rise to trade-offs in benefits from policies - how policy is implemented on the ground at the local scale as a function of these local scale connections and heterogeneities, and how the effectiveness of policy is monitored  Ultimately this will lead to deeper understanding of cross-scale interactions, while also allowing for the development of tools for better WEF policies that take into account local priorities and needs. Our aim is thus to understand how to disaggregate policy to better fit the local diversity of contexts and interests of various actors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The strategic aim of this cluster is to bring together expertise and interest in addressing the scale challenge of policy implementation, and to develop the tools for understanding how to address this challenge in real-world contexts. We know that developing and sustaining networks of researchers, practitioners, and stakeholders, is key to co-developing approaches to solving difficult development problems that require diverse, interdisciplinary approaches. We therefore will bring together a wide range of expertise and disciplinary backgrounds as represented by our contributing GROW projects and partners. The consortium of expertise and interest will initially be developed for Malawi based on existing research and applications across the projects, and their associated partners. These partners will provide key input into the development of the cluster, via proposed workshops and the development of strategic documents.   To reach this aim our specific objectives are as follows: 1. Identify and consult a broader range of interested and influential stakeholders in Malawi and the southern African region. We have an existing strong set of technical and political stakeholders already engaged via the GROW projects, but will expand this to encompass further key stakeholders at the district and national levels. The output will be a more complete picture of the multiple stakeholders operating at different levels to give rise to policy development and implementation. 2. Synthesize the research and understanding carried out under our contributing projects. There has been a tremendous amount of output generated from previous projects, which builds on a wealth of existing knowledge of various aspects of sustainable development in the water-energy-food realm. This research needs to be synthesized to understand knowledge gaps, the utility of produced datasets and tools for answering the proposed research questions. The outputs will synthesize information across sectors and scales. 3. Synthesizing the impact of our contributing projects. We will also scale-up the impacts of the research done to date through targeted communication, e.g. towards the National Planning Commission (NCP) as it develops Malawi&apos;s next long-term development. The outputs will be added value to the contributing projects as well as scoping potential for further policy-relevant research avenues. 4. Co-develop a conceptual framework for characterizing and understanding the scale gap. There are a range of existing frameworks for quantifying or characterizing coupled human-environment systems and their spatial footprint and variability, and for a range of applications. However, little has been done to apply these in order to identify the opportunities and barriers for grounded policy implementation. Co-development will ensure that we frame around current national implementation policies as well as forming the basis for broader applicability across sub-Saharan Africa. The output will be a conceptual framework. 5. Extend capacity in researchers and stakeholders in co-development of research. This will focus on developing interdisciplinary research ideas and approaches with the aim of promoting higher level strategic priorities in research and policy. Capacity building will support and draw from ongoing capacity development in the contributing projects, and the output will be more confident and mentored ECRs that are able to take up their role as the next research leaders in Malawi. By achieving these objectives, our consortium will be well-positioned to develop a full proposal to interdisciplinary calls that are informed by country needs. In particular, we will have developed a framework and plan for understanding the cross-scale biophysical and socio-economic interactions that can guide national or district policy outcomes, given the diversity of rural communities and their environments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">32541.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">32541.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">2603353.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Southampton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024887_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT024887%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
