<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N017323_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Structure - Function Relationships in Protozoan Parasites Utilising High Resolution 3D Bioimaging</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The family Trypanosomatidae contains a number of important human-infective protozoan parasites. These include Trypanosoma cruzi which causes Chagas Disease in Central and South America and there are reported to be ~18 million people infected in some of the poorest communities with no long term effective drug treatment, particularly for chronically infected patients. Trypanosoma brucei is a closely related parasite that causes African sleeping sickness and kills ~50,000 people annually in Sub-Saharan Africa. The cattle species of Trypanosoma brucei has a devastating economic impact, with large areas of countryside that cannot be used due to the prevalence of the Tsetse fly, which spreads the disease. Both parasites are on the World Health Organisation list of 17 neglected Tropical Diseases and more efforts are required to understand the biology of these parasites to help find effective treatments.  There are two aim objectives with 4 main research areas that will be developed within a context of modern molecular and cell biology of parasites and the use of novel three dimensional electron microscopy.These parasites have an indentation in the cell surface called the  flagellar pocket, which is the major site of entry and exit of molecules, nutrients and entry of drugs and is a critical factor in the pathogenicity of these parasites. It has a complex three dimensional structure and we aim to use a range of three dimensional electron microscopy techniques to really understand how the flagellar pocket and associated structures divides and functions. These parasites have completed genome projects and a range of genetic tools to allow in-depth analysis of individual genes. The partners in both the UK and Brazil are experts in understanding the flagellar pocket structure of the two parasites. However, important differences are emerging through concerted efforts by both partners. These differences and similarities are important to understand, particularly as the flagellar pocket is a major site for entry of drugs and nutrients to these cells. Our objective is to run a fully collaborative project to understand these differences in further detail and the design of the visits between staff and students over the 3 years is aimed at maximising contact and discussion between the partners in the context of 4 experimental research areas. We will also organise a mini-symposium during year 2 to ensure that the outcomes of the experiments and conclusions can be disseminated to a wide academic audience, including those working with drug discovery, endocytosis (nutrient uptake in cells) and immunology.  In order to really understand how living cells divide and interact with their surroundings we need to understand a detailed view of their three dimensional spatial organisation. This has been difficult to achieve using existing electron microscopes due to their inherent limitations.  Recently, there have been significant developments in three dimensional electron microscopy to image the detailed structure of cells and tissues of organisms in an automated manner and the partners on this proposal are leading centres of excellence for these 3D microscopy techniques. The number of trained scientists is low both nationally and internationally and during the 3 year grant our aim is to train as many staff and students as possible as we believe these techniques will revolutionise general cell biology in the next 10 years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Trypanosoma parasites cause suffering to millions of humans and livestock in Central and South America and Africa. Both T. cruzi (Chagas Disease) and T. brucei (African sleeping sickness) are on the list of the World Health Organisation&apos;s 17 main neglected infectious diseases as there are still little or no effective treatments for these important Human parasitic diseases. The flagellar pocket is key to the survival of these parasites as it is the only site of endocytosis and exocytosis and is critical for metabolism and drug delivery. Therefore a good understanding of how it functions will be important to understand in order to help find effective treatments. As outlined in the case for support, the two partners are both experts in structural cell biology of these parasites, and, in particular the flagellar pockets of T. cruzi and T. brucei. Similarities and important structural differences have been noted and this partnerships aims to clarify these and bring our joint expertise to to provide a comprehensive structural understanding of the flagella pocket of both parasites.  There are 2 main objectives to this application:  There are two main objectives to this application: 1. To bring together internationally recognised leaders in structural/cell biology of T. cruzi (Chagas Disease) and T. brucei (African sleeping sickness) to better understand the critical role performed by the flagellar pocket and associated organelles in parasite survival.  To do so, we will:- a. Use novel three dimensional electron microscopy techniques to analyse and compare flagellar pocket biogenesis and kinetoplast connections in T. cruzi and T. brucei. We will produce quantitative and qualitative spatial data on the 3D organisation and biogenesis of the flagellar pocket structure with a comparative approach between these parasites. Our extensive plan of visits and meetings will ensure maximum opportunities to better understand this important organelle. b. Use 3D electron microscopy techniques to analyse the role of the contractile vacuole complex (CVC) in response to osmotic stress in T. cruzi. The contractile vacuole has only been identified in T. cruzi and is also associated with the flagellar pocket, demonstrating one of the differences between these parasites. The Brazilian partners will provide the expertise in analysing this vacuole under different osmotic conditions and the biogenesis of this organelle.  c. Develop and combine APEX (genetic tagging) to localise proteins in electron microscopy using serial block face scanning electron microscopy (SBF-SEM) and focus ion beam scanning electron microsocpy (FIB-SEM).  d. Develop high through-put long primer PCR tagging in T. cruzi. This is an important new technique that has been developed in T. brucei and can be easily transferred into T. cruzi for endogenous tagging of multiple proteins. It will also allow mutations to be introduced to test hypotheses.  2. To train Brazilian and UK scientists in novel three dimensional electron microscopy bioimaging techniques, thereby fulfilling a key focus of the Newton Fund and UK&apos;s Official Development Assistance. Our training programme will include training on three dimensional electron microscopes, analysing data using software such as AMIRA, IMARIS and ImageJ. We will also train Brazilian scientists in new molecular biology techniques developed by the UK partners to produce high through-put endogenous tagging of proteins and genetic tags for electron microscopy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">13272.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">109669.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">110100.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">83448.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">329980.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N017323/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN017323%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
