<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_V005758_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nexus Action for Mangroves in Selangor, Malaysia: protection through value creation for community-public-private partnerships (NexAMS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mangroves contribute to businesses and communities through multiple ecosystem services, yet are undervalued and under-protected in Malaysia and globally. Using outputs and lessons from NetComFish (Newton-Ungku Omar Fund project), capacity building and co-creation, NexAMS aims to advance policy and business initiatives for improved, inclusive mangrove protection through sustainable use and build public-private-community partnerships, focusing on the state of Selangor.   Using stakeholder engagement, desk work and knowledge exchange, these aims will be achieved through: (i) analysis of local, state, federal and international plans, policies and commitments to identify gaps and learn lessons on how existing initiatives impact mangroves and can be modified to support sustainable development with mangroves; (ii) assessment of past, present and potential future social, economic and environmental threats to mangroves to identify mitigating actions targeted at public and private sectors; (iii) identify achievable actions for businesses to minimise their impact on mangroves, support mangrove restoration and contribute to coastal community development; (iv) community engagement to identify optimum areas for mangrove protection for sustainable use and facilitation of business-community linkages; (v) outreach, engagement and targeted communication along the policy pathway and among business networks.   For lasting impact, NexAMS will: work with stakeholders across local, state and federal decision-making tiers, and mutlisectorally, with local communities, the private sector, government, NGOs and academia; build the capacity of stakeholders to better manage mangrove resources through sustainable use; and facilitate increased interaction between different stakeholder groups to enable partnership building. These impacts will support coastal community livelihoods and environmentally sensitive economic development in Selangor and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-05-14"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="MY" type="MALAYSIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-13"></value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Aim: Mangroves in the state of Selangor are protected for sustainable use, optimising their value chain benefits through community, public and private sector partnerships.  Objectives targeted at policy, business and community build upon outputs and lessons learnt from NetComFish (Newton-Ungku Omar Fund): 1. Catalyse change in mangrove-relevant policies through engagement of government, private sector and community stakeholders in co-creation workshops and targeted communication along the policy pathway. 2. Work with business champions (local, national) to apply the mangrove business case including achievable actions to minimise business impacts on mangroves and connecting businesses with coastal communities for mangrove livelihood development. 3. Provide a platform for community voices to facilitate greater participation of local communities in sustainable mangrove management.  Capacity building and effective communication (direct engagement and multiple media) cross-cuts the above."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
