<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R013969_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Detailed malaria diagnostics with intelligent microscopy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our primary objective is to make malaria diagnosis faster, cheaper, and more consistent by developing intelligent, automated microscopes - and demonstrating they are both accurate and efficient.  We will create an intelligent slide-scanning microscope, capable of digitising blood smears and assisting with their analysis, that requires much less technician time per smear than manual microscopy and can be constructed locally for a similar price to current manual microscopes.  Making more efficient use of the technician&apos;s time not only allows them to diagnose more patients per day, it also helps to train new technicians, both by gaining experience faster and by being able to easily ask for a second opinion - even remotely, by sending images over the mobile phone network.  Progress towards this objective will be assessed quantitatively, by comparing the time taken and the accuracy of diagnosis using our system with a technician performing manual microscopy.   An important step in creating an intelligent microscope is acquiring data with which to build and train a learning algorithm.  Our second objective is therefore the creation of a dataset of images of blood smears, ideally hundreds of smears scanned at high resolution.  This dataset will be made available to the community, to allow new algorithms to be tested and trained on it.  We will use a combination of automatic and manual labelling to annotate this dataset with metadata including the location of any parasites in the sample, as well as the parasitaemia level and any known diagnosis for the patient who donated the blood.   Hardware is a key component of our project; in order to make a computer vision algorithm useful in this context, we must first acquire digital images of blood smears.  To do so in a scalable, affordable way will require the development of a fully automated microscope at a comparable price to existing diagnostic microscopes.  Using 3D printing and low cost electronics, it is possible to create a microscope with a highly accurate translation stage.  We will build on this design to create a slide scanning microscope capable of acquiring high quality images with a 100x oil immersion microscope objective, as required to diagnose malaria.  Its mechanical stage will have sufficient range of travel that it can cover a whole blood smear, and process multiple smears at a time.   The final objective is the algorithm used for diagnosis; we will develop a generative probabilistic model for healthy red blood cells, capable of extracting shape information for further analysis and highlighting features that should not be present in healthy cells, such as parasites.  We will further develop this model to be able to identify parasites, white blood cells, and other features commonly found on microscope slides.  Our novel approach in developing this algorithm is an key part of the objective - the ability to quantify uncertainty in its results, and explain which features of an image led to a diagnosis, are important new abilities that will help machine learning make a real impact in healthcare as well as form a contribution to the Bayesian machine learning literature.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The best way to diagnose malaria remains microscopic examination of blood smears, to identify the plasmodium parasites that are responsible.  This takes around 30 minutes of microscopy, done by a trained technician - skilled workers who are in short supply.  This project will create an intelligent microscope that can greatly multiply the skills of a technician by scanning over the smears automatically, and allowing them to review only the suspicious blood cells on a tablet computer after the smear has been scanned.   Malaria is one of the world&apos;s most prevalent infectious diseases.  It affects 200 million per year, and causes around 400 thousand deaths - most of them children in ODA countries in sub-Saharan Africa.  Impressive progress is being made in reducing the incidence of malaria, which makes good diagnosis of the condition ever more important; it is increasingly inaccurate to assume that every patient with a fever has malaria, and doing so will waste drugs and leave potentially life threatening fevers untreated.   The key to reliable, useful diagnosis with an automated microscope lies in computer vision; simply acquiring digital images and tiling them together into a digital smear is an important first step, but robust analysis of the digital images means the technician need not sift through many images of healthy cells.  Instead, they can concentrate their efforts on parts of the image where the algorithm identified suspicious features.  Once trained, our algorithm will be able to identify many parasites, only asking for the technician&apos;s opinion in challenging, ambiguous cases when it could not identify objects with certainty.  Fully automated counts of healthy and infected cells will then allow consistent quantification of test results, informing the clinician prescribing treatment and aiding in disease monitoring.   Analysis of medical images raises fundamental issues with the standard &quot;deep learning&quot; approach of training a multi-layer neural network on hundreds of thousands of images.  Such algorithms cannot accurately quantify their uncertainty (i.e. flag up when a diagnosis may be inaccurate), nor describe the reasoning that led to a given classification for an image.  They require extremely large training datasets, which must often be labelled by hand.  We will build a generative probabilistic model which, while not feasible in most applications due to the huge range of objects that might conceivably be found in a photograph, is possible in the relatively controlled imaging environment of a microscope.  This will allow us to give a probabilistic verdict on each cell, and highlight cells that couldn&apos;t be reliably classified as healthy, infected, or something else.  The generative model will also be able to identify features that led to a classification, for example highlighting infected cells in a large image of a smear.  Both of these features will enable greater trust in the algorithm, and allow it to be used to support, rather than replace, existing clinical staff as well as collecting images that will allow us to improve the algorithm&apos;s performance.   Computer vision is a powerful technique, but it requires high-resolution digital representations of blood smears in order to work.  Our project therefore has a hardware component, where we will build on our earlier work with the OpenFlexure Microscope to create a slide-scanning instrument, capable of digitising blood smears in the field.  This instrument will use low cost components and desktop digital manufacturing, so that it can be produced locally - freeing clinics from expensive international supply chains, and creating opportunities for local entrepreneurs that build valuable engineering and design skills.  We have already trialled this approach with the first version of the microscope, which will shortly be available for purchase in Tanzania and Kenya, and we hope to achieve an even greater impact with a fully automated instrument.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-04">70973.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-04">284468.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-04">286772.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-04">216383.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-04">8585974.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Bath</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R013969_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FR013969%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
