<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessing health risks associated with exposure to household and ambient air pollution in rural and urban China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Air pollution is an important cause of ill-health worldwide. This is particularly the case in China and many other developing countries, in which outdoor air pollution is worsening due to increased traffic and industrial activities. Furthermore, many people still use solid fuels (e.g. wood, charcoal or coal) for cooking and heating in rural areas, generating harmful smoke and other toxic substances inside the home. Although we know that air pollution causes death and illness at the population level, the exact extent is not fully understood because accurate information is lacking. Reliable estimation of the disease risks arising from air pollution requires measurements of individual exposures to air pollution and their subsequent disease outcomes (i.e. onset of new diseases and death). We propose to address this knowledge gap using the China Kadoorie Biobank (CKB), a large study of 500,000 men and women recruited from 10 diverse urban and rural areas in China in 2004-08 with detailed tracking of disease outcomes as a resource to study the health effects of air pollution. This represents an efficient approach that avoids the need to generate a separate expensive study to conduct this work.   Use of CKB in this way requires improvements to existing air pollution data. As in many other large scale epidemiological studies, CKB did not directly measure actual air pollution levels individually, but relied on participants to report information on the type of fuel they use for cooking or heating and how often, or how close to a main road they live. Since individuals spend a varying amount of time in different locations doing various activities, this may be inaccurate measure of individual air pollution. The ideal would be to measure in real time the pollutant concentrations in the air breathed by each person individually. However, this will be impractical in a study of 0.5 million participants, so the challenge is to achieve estimates of exposure in a cost-effective manner. This proposal represents a pilot project to test and assess different methods of measuring individual exposure to household and ambient air pollution.  In this project we will ask 300 CKB participants from 2 rural and 1 urban regions to carry a small wearable monitor with them to record particle pollutant concentration for two 5 day periods in both warm and cool seasons of the year. In addition, we will ask them to note what activity (e.g. cooking, commuting) they are doing, the duration and the location, so that we can understand how much of their pollution exposure comes from indoor or outdoor environments. Because it could be difficult and expensive to ask each participant to wear a monitor, we will also test whether it is sufficient to estimate individual air pollution by using data from ground monitoring networks, supplemented by satellite remote sensing technology. Two of the many satellites orbiting Earth carry sensors that detect infrared light transmitted through the atmosphere, providing a measure of airborne particulate matter. Using information from satellites and ground monitors, we will create a more complete map of air pollution. We will test and optimise this new approach in Suzhou, an urban CKB site that already has good coverage of ground-based pollution monitoring data. Based on the residential addresses of study participants, we can use this air pollution map to estimate an individual&apos;s ambient exposure level. We will use this information to carry out an analysis to investigate the health effects of air pollution in Suzhou participants.   This proposal will provide important new understanding and experience needed to plan a larger project involving all 0.5 million participants in CKB. Ultimately we aim to collect reliable exposure and disease outcome data to accurately understand the impact of air pollution on health in China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposal seeks to evaluate the feasibility of applying several novel approaches to estimating individual level exposure to household (HAP) and ambient air pollution (AAP), that can subsequently be used in a large prospective study to generate reliable estimates of both short- and long-term health effects attributed to air pollution in China and other low- and middle-income countries (LMICs).    There are several specific objectives, outlined in the work packages below, which will be achieved by enhancing the established nationwide prospective China Kadoorie Biobank (CKB) study in a subset of individuals from 0.5M adults across 10 diverse regions of China:  1) To construct seasonal 5-day air pollution personal exposure profiles for fine particles (PM2.5) and carbon monoxide using individual wearable and household static monitors together with time-activity diaries in 300 CKB participants from 2 rural and 1 urban regions. This will relate exposure profiles to additional measures on use of different fuel types (coal, wood, and cleaner fuels) in both warm and cool seasons and smoking status. Additionally, monitors will be placed at village centres to measure background ambient air pollution. This work package should provide reliable estimates of exposure to AAP and HAP that can be used to validate other exposure estimates obtained in the study.  2) To estimate, by combining ground level monitoring and satellite remote sensing data with geocoded residential addresses, individual exposure to ambient air pollution in 53,000 CKB participants from urban Suzhou over a 10 year period. This work package should provide reliable data to quantify individual exposures to air pollution that are scalable in large epidemiological studies including urban and rural areas where monitoring network are not sufficiently dense to provide accurate information at an individual level.  3) To develop a &quot;composite exposure index&quot; for air pollution in all 0.5M adult participants in the CKB study using a combination of objectively measured exposure data from (1) and (2) above together with the data previously collected in CKB including self-reported questionnaire exposure data collected at baseline and resurveys. The composite exposure index will then be related to major diseases (including cardiovascular disease, respiratory disease and cancer) in individual-based time series analysis of 53,000 CKB participants in Suzhou.  4) To develop and optimise novel methodologies relevant for future scaling up that could be applied to all 0.5M participants in CKB. Such approaches could enhance research opportunities to share knowledge and experience from this study with major stakeholders and other parties to increase capacity in air pollution research. The data generated will be shared with other researchers and could be incorporated into other studies to assess the health effects of air pollution in LMICs.  The work packages outlined above will reliably curate and validate estimates of HAP/AAP at both individual and household levels in samples of CKB, from which we will derive algorithms that will facilitate quantification of HAP/AAP exposure in all 0.5M adults in CKB based on existing questionnaire data. By validating exposure data using several approaches and generating a composite exposure index, the study should provide reliable estimates of the disease associations with both HAP and AAP exposure at an individual level that can then be used to guide public policy on addressing relevant sources of air pollution. With accurate quantification of disease risks in relation to specific fuel types (quantified from HAP), there is also potential for more targeted campaigns to reduce the burden of disease from fuel-related HAP. Collectively, this proposal seeks to make the initial steps to providing these reliable HAP/AAP metrics, which will be crucial to future research and public health policy in this area in LMICs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-09">301273.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-09">227785.65</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">75318.4556962025</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">75318.4556962025</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">75318.4556962025</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">75318.4556962025</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">75928.5443037975</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">75928.5443037975</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">75928.5443037975</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">67902.8101265823</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P025080_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
