<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S011455_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Commercial Law Research Network Nigeria (CLRN_N)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CLRN_N is proposed to influence the future reform of commercial law in Nigeria, as well as to provide an ecosystem through which interdisciplinary research can be generated. It invites researchers to examine the effectiveness of commercial law reform  in the global South, using Nigeria as a case study. Nigeria  has sought to modernise its laws for many reasons, including meeting international standards, as well as promoting the development of its economy. Similar to its counterparts, the reforms have been achieved largely through transplants; with the common law of England and Wales being the main source of transplants because of the colonial history between both countries. It is important to consider the effectiveness of the reforms that have been made, particularly as critics of legal transplants argue that they tend to be ineffective where they do not address the realities of the recipients. (Pistor et. al., 2000) Transplants are a method through which laws diffuse across nations. Law does not diffuse only from the global north to the south. It generally diffuses across countries that are at par also. (Twinning, 2004). Thus, the problem is not diffusion; it is with the misfit where the local realities have not been duly considered and addressed. It is therefore important that countries from the global south articulate the realities that characterise their systems; thereafter creatively determine whether and/or how to adapt modern institutions to suit their contexts.  To understand the commercial law realities of Nigeria, it is necessary that well-versed researchers interrogate the Nigerian context using inter-disciplinary research methods ranging from the theoretical to the empirical. They must critical examine the the historical, socio-economic and political contexts of the Nigerian commercial sphere. To ensure that the realities are appropriately understood and recommendations are rigorous enough to achieve their purpose, the network will also engender discussions between researchers and key stakeholders involved in the enactment and enforcement of the Nigerian commercial law through round-table discussions. Thereafter, a determination can be made about the effectiveness of reforms in each aspect of commercial law and recommendations made on the future direction of research and commercial law policy. This collaborative approach also ensures that there will be sustained dialogues with the stakeholder groups on the recommendations made. The outcomes will be relevant for Nigeria, as institutions in its commercial sphere will be rigorously assessed. They will also hold relevance beyond Nigeria. They are relevant to the debate on legal transplants which is of interest globally, as well as those interested in the development of the common law, as they show how its principles can be adapted to the context of countries from the global south.   Finally, the network also provides a forum at which to develop the research emanating from the global south.  Trubek (2014) has stated that one of the principal problems the global south faces in the quest for development is the inadequate quality of the research it generates. To improve on the rigour of research generated from a prominent country in the global south such as Nigeria, the network will organise workshops at which research methods are discussed and taught. The forum provided by the network will enable established researchers to discuss the possibility of collaborations, as well as the methods which are sophisticated enough to interrogate the realities of the global south with their peers. The network however places emphasis on the training of early career researchers, many of whom have been trained only on descriptive, black-letter analysis. These researchers will be enlightened on the value and utility of inter-disciplinary methods; the ultimate goal being to ensure that there will be an expansion of rigorous research emanating from the global south in the future</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the network is to create a key influencer in the reform of commercial law and policy in Nigeria. The research network brings together researchers across various areas of commercial law including  capital markets, insolvency law, corporate governance, intellectual property, arbitration and dispute resolution, as well as oil and gas. The goal is for these researchers to examine recent and proposed reforms to the commercial law of Nigeria with the aim of assessing their effectiveness. Put differently, they are invited to determine whether the reforms address the challenges of the system and are beneficial to it.  In addition, the researchers will engage with stakeholders and policy-makers to determine the future direction of commercial law reform. To that end, the network will facilitate discussions between researchers and key stakeholders from across the Nigerian commercial law sphere, including policy-makers like the corporate affairs commission and the Ministry of Agriculture, representatives of commercial and development banks, representatives of entrepreneur groups like the Manufacturers&apos; Association of Nigeria and the Lagos State Chambers of Commerce, as well as representatives of professional advisers like the Business Recoveries and Insolvency Practitioners&apos; Association of Nigeria, the Institute of Chartered Accountants of Nigeria and the Nigerian Bar Association.  To understand the challenges of the Nigerian system, the network advocates inter-disciplinary research methods which examine the state of the Nigerian commercial system from various perspectives, ranging from the historical, to understand the background to the extant law, to the political, to understand the key actors in the law reform process, to the theoretical, to understand the underlying aims of the law. As there is a dearth of high quality interdisciplinary outputs emanating from Nigeria, the network will provide an ecosystem through which interdisciplinary research methodologies can be discussed amongst established researchers and taught to their early-career counterparts. Against that background, the main objectives of the network are:  To facilitate informed and contextual understanding of the Nigerian commercial law by undertaking and disseminating inter-disciplinary research and analysis, as well as publishing articles, reports and policy papers that set out cogent recommendations.   To facilitate connections between researchers, who can contribute to research projects, and stakeholders involved in the enactment or enforcement of the law through multi-disciplinary debates and round-table events.  To foster the development of commercial law research and researchers from the global south by organising workshops at which established researchers can engage with one another, while early career researchers can be trained on interdisciplinary research methods.  To contribute to the debate on legal transplants, as well as the development of commercial law in the global south and beyond by engaging with other researchers/research groups.  To contribute to the enactment of considered reforms by influencing the reform process through research outputs and dialogue.  The outputs of the network will be relevant to and beyond Nigeria. For Nigeria, the outputs will provide in-depth analysis of the state of the law and the direction of future policies. Beyond Nigeria, it offers insight into the challenges faced by countries in the global south and the effectiveness of reform through transplants which many such countries have undertaken by choice or been encouraged to undertake by international pressure. It will also offer insights on how the Common Law, from which Nigeria has borrowed, can be adapted to suit a global South country more effectively. Finally, it will provide an opportunity to contribute principles and practices developed in the global South to global discussions on commercial law.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-02" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-05-01">18113.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-05-01">12124.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-05-01">36325.384</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to University of Reading</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S011455_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FS011455%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-06-03"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
