<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rapid Urine-Based Screening for Tuberculosis to Reduce AIDS-Related Mortality in Hospitalized Patients in Africa (STAMP) Trial</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PROLOGUE:  The overarching aim of this work is to determine whether a fundamentally new approach to rapid diagnostic screening for HIV-associated tuberculosis (TB) using novel, high-sensitivity urine-based testing in addition to the standard of care reduces all-cause mortality among HIV-infected patients requiring admission to medical wards in hospitals in southern Africa. In this individually randomized controlled trial, study patients newly admitted to two large regional referral hospitals in South Africa and Malawi will be enrolled and randomized to undergo one of two different diagnostic screening strategies. Survival of patients will be compared between arms.    This trial design is grounded in detailed background studies conducted in a similar clinical population in South Africa. Compared to current standard of care investigation using sputum-based diagnosis with the Xpert MTB/RIF assay, the addition of high-sensitivity rapid urine-based testing to the initial diagnostic screen resulted in a 3.0-fold increase in the early diagnostic yield of microbiologically proven TB. However, it is not known whether implementation of this high sensitivity urine-based approach will result in improved survival by increasing the yield and speed of TB diagnosis and accelerating appropriate medical management. Costs and cost-effectiveness will also need to be assessed.   The proposed laboratory intervention is feasible to implement and scale-up without modification being required. However, simplification of any laboratory process is usually desirable wherever possible, especially in resource-limited settings. A separate in vitro laboratory-based component of the study will therefore seek both to further evaluate and simplify the high sensitivity urine screening using the Xpert MTB/RIF assay with a view to enhancing post-study implementation.   1) PRIMARY TRIAL OBJECTIVE:  To determine the impact on all-cause mortality (measured 56 days from randomisation) of the addition of rapid, high sensitivity urine-based TB screening to the standard of care for HIV-infected patients requiring admission to medical wards in hospitals in southern Africa.     2) SECONDARY TRIAL OBJECTIVES:  To determine in this clinical population the impact of additional urine-based TB screening versus standard of care alone on:   2.1 The yield of TB diagnoses (defined as microbiologically confirmed disease or clinician&apos;s decision to treat for TB in the absence of confirmation).  2.2 The times from randomisation to TB diagnosis and start of TB treatment   2.3 Use of other medical interventions, including the proportions of patients receiving simple antibiotics and antiretroviral therapy (ART) and the timing of ART.   2.4 Other clinical outcomes, including duration of hospital admission, the need for hospital readmission and loss to follow-up.    3) OBJECTIVES OF ECONOMIC ANALYSES.  3.1. To determine the incremental cost-effectiveness of high sensitivity urine-based TB screening in HIV-infected medical in-patients in South Africa (a middle-income country) and Malawi (a lower income country).   3.2. To determine the 2-year and 5-year budgetary impact of implementation and scale-up of this intervention from a Ministry of Health perspective for both South Africa and Malawi.   4) OBJECTIVES OF LABORATORY-BASED SUB-STUDY  4.1    To develop alternative means of concentrating Mycobacterium tuberculosis bacilli from urine samples prior to testing with the Xpert MTB/RIF assay that does not require centrifugation.  4.2 To determine the sensitivity of the Xpert MTB/RIF assay for detection of M. tuberculosis in urine compared to culture and the optimum urine volume to be concentrated to optimise operational feasibility.  4.3 To determine whether screening for M. tuberculosis in urine affects the accuracy of the Xpert MTB/RIF assay to detect mutations that confer rifampicin resistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Saharan Africa bears the brunt of the global HIV/AIDS epidemic, with 23.5 million people living with HIV and 1.2 million deaths in 2012. Tuberculosis (TB) is the leading cause of AIDS-related illness and deaths worldwide and 75% of this disease burden is in sub-Saharan Africa. Studies from across the continent have shown that 30%-67% of HIV-infected adult hospital in-patients who die have evidence of TB at post-mortem. Much of this disease is neither clinically suspected nor diagnosed before death. This indicates abject failure of current approaches to diagnosis, which is the key problem addressed by this trial.   The very large number of HIV-TB deaths means that Africa is not on track to meet the WHO TB control targets linked to the 2015 MDGs. This has therefore become a high-level strategic priority, with calls for action from WHO, UNAIDS, STOP-TB, PEPFAR and other agencies. We believe that recent advances in TB diagnosis can be harnessed to address this challenge in a fundamentally new way.   Background studies conducted by the PI in South Africa found that the burden of confirmed TB among unselected HIV-infected patients needing hospital admission was extremely high (32.6%). Symptoms were so poorly predictive for screening, however, that in day-to-day clinical practice, much of this disease remains &apos;under the radar&apos; and undetected. We propose that, regardless of symptoms, all such patients should be investigated for TB on admission.  In these studies the diagnostic yield using the traditional approach of sputum-based testing was, however, very limited as fewer than half of the patients could produce sputum samples and much disease involved organs other than the lungs. In contrast, urine samples could be obtained from almost all patients and the yield of diagnoses from testing these with rapid diagnostics was far greater than that obtained from sputum. Urine was first tested using a simple 30-minute strip-test which is commercially available (Determine TB-LAM). Urine was also concentrated by simple centrifugation and tested using the new WHO-approved rapid Xpert MTB/RIF assay (Xpert). Compared to Xpert testing of sputum alone, addition of this urine-based testing strategy to the initial screen increased the early diagnostic yield of TB 3.0-fold - an extraordinary improvement.   Some recent studies have reported that implementation of new TB diagnostics with superior sensitivity did not improve patient outcomes. Thus, since use of new, costly tests might divert limited resources from other important healthcare needs, it is imperative that the impact, cost and cost-effectiveness of new diagnostic strategies such as this one are assessed in trials. This randomised controlled trial will enrol adult HIV-infected medical inpatients admitted to two regional referral hospitals in South Africa and Malawi. On admission, patients will be randomised to one of two TB screening strategies (1,300 patients in each arm), comparing TB diagnosis by Xpert testing of sputum (standard arm) with an intervention arm in which urine will in addition be screened with a combination of the two urine-based diagnostic tests. The care of patients provided by the routine medical team will not be otherwise altered.   The main study outcome will show whether additional urine-based screening results in greater survival due to improved yield and speed of TB diagnosis. To more fully assess the overall impact on patients and the efficiency of the healthcare received, a range of additional outcomes will be assessed. These include the total yield of TB diagnoses; times to diagnosis; the proportions starting TB treatment, other antibiotics and antiretrovirals; the length of hospital stay and the need for readmission. Implementation of this intervention will be further justified by comprehensive cost-effectiveness and budgetary impact analyses. If impact is demonstrated, this intervention could be readily implemented and scaled-up.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133903" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-08-21">165731.9</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-08-21">769316.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-08-21">756320.9</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-08-21">331357.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-08-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-08-21">2144557.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/M007375/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">189270.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-01">189270.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">189270.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">188509.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">183935.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">135035.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">12386</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">112066.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007375_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FM007375%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
