<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S008322_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY MODELS TO ACCELERATE SUSTAINABILITY TRANSITIONS - IPACST</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">IPACST aims to develop evidence-based insights into IP models and how they accelerate sustainability transitions. This enables stakeholders of sustainability transitions to select suitable IP models in different situations. To contribute to a comprehensive understanding of IP models for sustainability transitions we bring together the fields of sustainability, IP and innovation management, together with political sciences and engineering addressing the following questions:  1) Which IP models do exist of relevance for sustainability transitions and how can they be typologized (e.g. from closed to completely open)? 2) Which IP models are employed by sustainable businesses and how do they match with sustainable business models? What is the role (inhibiting, stimulating) of IP models in adopting sustainable business models? 3) How do different types of IP models and business models accelerate (or prevent) the development, adoption and diffusion of sustainable innovations? Under what conditions (technological, regulatory, cultural, demand-supply factors, infrastructures) do different IP models best accelerate sustainability transitions? 4) What can we learn from best practice in sustainable businesses? What successful models exist? What are ideal combinations of sustainable business models and underlying IP models</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Transformations to sustainability rely on innovation with complex diffusion and adoption processes. The role of intellectual property (IP) and IP rights (IPR) in sustainability transitions remains insufficiently understood. IPR can delay transitions by blocking new technologies, but if used effectively can encourage private investments, knowledge sharing and collaborative learning. The project transforms our understanding of how intellectual property (IP) models accelerate sustainability transitions integrating theories and concepts from sustainability, IP and innovation research. To date, sustainability and IP research have been studied independently. This project contributes to the integration of both fields through frameworks that conceptualize (i) which, (ii) how and (iii) under what conditions IP models accelerate sustainable transitions, in connection with sustainable business models. Hence, we build an interdisciplinary research community that furthers our understanding of dynamic sustainable economic development. An IP model typology, a sustainable business model typology and conceptual frameworks will be developed based upon case studies in clean energy and circular economy in developing and developed countries. With a Delphi study and simulations, the frameworks will be tested for further sectors. To create impact in industries at different levels, we develop and promote tools for selecting suitable IP and business models, best-practice cases and guidelines, awareness and training kits for key stakeholders such as policy makers, funding organizations, businesses and start-up incubators, education institutions and technology transfer offices.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-09">45076</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-09">135003.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-09">102794.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-09">33274.66</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-09">382697.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants - Strategic Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S008322_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FS008322%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
