<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015403_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using drones to protect biodiversity and spur economic growth in Madagascar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In a series of GCRF-funded projects we have developed a prototype low cost, robust, and simple to operate thermal-infrared drone system built from off-the-shelf components that can (semi)automatically detect, identify and locate animals and fires in thermal infrared footage. The objective of this proposal is to use the system to help conservation agencies protect Madagascar&apos;s biodiversity - a cornerstone of the country&apos;s economy - and thereby deliver significant, long-term, social and economic impact. To achieve this goal, we will overcome existing challenges [C] with innovative solutions [S] by setting strategic targets [T] with quantifiable measures of success [M] which will lead to long-term benefits [B] through the following steps:   1. [C] Madagascar is currently building a national framework and regulations for operating drones. [S] Building on our experience as part of key UK Government panels shaping drone policy, we will work with the Aviation Civil de Madagascar (ACM) [Civil Aviation Authority of Madagascar], our partner and key local stakeholder, to outline regulations required for a national qualification to fly drones safely. By implementing a national drone policy [T], drone operators applying for flying permits [M] will be required to follow the latest international aviation regulations, ensuring optimal safety and best practice are implemented in drone flight from the beginning. [B] The uptake in drone technology will open the door to the same transformative changes in all areas of economy and society seen in other countries.   2. [C] In part due to high costs of commercial drone systems, there are few drone pilots in Madagascar, and little capacity for building/maintaining non-commercial drones. [S] Building on our experience setting up a Drone Research Lab at Liverpool John Moores University in the UK, we will work with ACM and our key conservation partner, Durrell Wildlife Conservation Trust (DWCT), to develop a Drone Centre in Madagascar. [T] This will be fully equipped and staffed to (i) build and maintain drones from off-the-shelf components and (ii) train users to fly drones. [M] We will train 4 DWCT staff to build, maintain and fly drone systems so DWCT have the capacity to operate independently long-term. [B] This will initiate, and with continued training of new people over time, greatly increase the Madagascan capacity for using drone technology.   3. [C] Madagascar&apos;s unique biodiversity is crucial to the country&apos;s economy and long-term growth, but is being reduced sharply by hunting and habitat loss. An essential aspect of conservation is knowledge on animal abundance and hunting. Current conservation efforts are hampered by the high costs and large time investments of current methods to assess these. [S] With infrastructure from steps 1 and 2 in place, we will work with DWCT and other stakeholders (e.g. Madagascar National Parks, who manage National Parks in Madagascar) to use the drone systems to conduct regular, long-term, systematic monitoring of key geographical areas critical to Madagascan biodiversity and economy. [T] We will survey the entire Lake Alaotra region (which produces 50% of Madagascar&apos;s rice) and Baly Bay National Park (a hot spot for the illegal wildlife trade). [M] From these data we will derive accurate and precise densities for Aloatran Gentle Lemurs (which act as key indicators of restorative action in Lake Alaotra), and substantially reduce poaching in the Baly Bay National Park. [B] Our pilot studies show that our drone system offers between a 20-400x improvement in efficiency for detecting/identifying animals, humans and fires in surveys compared with current methods. The adoption of this research technology will provide a step change in the scale and frequency with which DWCT can conduct surveys. This will substantially reduce poaching and illegal activity and provide stakeholders with the information needed to balance conservation with sustainable growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The World Wildlife Fund for Nature estimates that up to five species of life on our planet become extinct every day. A recent study compiling surveys of animal populations around the globe shows that this rate of &quot;biological annihilation&quot; means a sixth mass extinction in Earth&apos;s history is under way and is more severe than previously feared. This astonishing rate of decline has potentially catastrophic consequences, not just for the ecosystems where the species are lost, but also for the world economy and planet as a whole. The World Bank estimates that ecosystems provide $33 trillion every year to the global economy: more than the GDP of USA and Europe combined. So it is no surprise that at a recent World Economic Forum the top business leaders, international political leaders and intellectuals around the globe identified biodiversity loss and consequent ecosystem collapse as one of the 10 foremost dangers facing humanity. There is a fundamental need to routinely monitor animal populations so that conservation strategies can be optimized with such information.   The island nation of Madagascar is at the forefront of this biodiversity crisis. Since it split from the African continent an estimated 160 million years ago, Madagascar has developed its own distinct ecosystems and extraordinary wildlife. Approximately 95 percent of Madagascar&apos;s reptiles, 89 percent of its plant life, and 92 percent of its mammals exist nowhere else on Earth. Madagascar is therefore one of Earth&apos;s hottest biodiversity hotspots. However, the current rate of biodiversity loss is so high that recent studies suggest this is the last chance to avoid many habitats and species becoming extinct.   Over the last few years, with funding from the UK government, we have developed a low cost, robust, and simple to operate thermal-infrared drone system built from off-the-shelf components that can (semi)automatically detect, identify and locate animals and fires in thermal infrared footage. In April 2019, in collaboration with the Durrell Wildlife Conservation Trust, we took the system to Madagascar and demonstrated that the system could successfully detect key tracer species of biodiversity and ecosystem health with a greatly increased efficiency over existing methods. Following this success, we are now seeking additional UK funding to build capacity in Madagascar to construct, maintain and fly drones, and begin systematic monitoring of biodiversity in key geographic areas. This will provide the key data that conservation agencies and the government need to ensure future policy decisions deliver sustainable economic growth while protecting and ensuring the long-term stability of the precious ecosystems. As biodiversity is a cornerstone of the country&apos;s economy, the proposal will deliver significant, long-term, social and economic impacts.   Throughout the project we will work closely with the Aviation Civil de Madagascar [Civil Aviation Authority of Madagascar], who are currently building a national framework and regulations for operating drones. Having been part of key UK Government panels shaping drone policy for many years, we have extensive experience to help ensure optimal safety and best practice are implemented in drone flight from the beginning. By speeding the uptake of drone technology in Madagascar, the project will act as a catalyst introducing the same transformative changes in all areas of economy and society seen in other countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Madagascar</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-25">190830.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-25">383207.7</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">95415.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015403_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">95415.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015403_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">95415.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015403_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">95415.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015403_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">96188.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015403_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
