<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Citizenship Futures: &apos;the Politics Of Hope&apos; In India And Europe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hope for the future, we contend, remain central to the political imaginations of socially excluded people. However, the relationship between hope, social exclusion and citizenship are poorly understood. Much of the existing literature primes scholars to infer that social exclusion spawns hopelessness, fear and mistrust. Policy analysts point to the paucity of &apos;aspirations&apos; among the socially excluded as a key factor for the perpetuation of poverty and inequality. Against this literature, by underscoring &apos;the politics of hope&apos; (Appadurai, 2013: 129) harboured by socially excluded people, the proposed research will provide insights into the ways in which they imagine their &apos;citizenship futures&apos;.   It seeks to analytically and empirically investigate the &apos;politics of hope&apos; among socially excluded people. The project will achieve this by ethnographically documenting the political subjectivities of socially excluded people in the United Kingdom, France and the Indian State of Maharashtra and thereby uncovering the ensemble of interpretations, emotions and practices that constitute &apos;the politics of hope&apos;. By examining the &apos;politics of hope&apos;, the project will deepen our understanding of the ways in which socially excluded people imagine their &apos;citizenship futures. It will do so by straddling disciplinary boundaries between the social sciences and the arts and humanities.  Project objective: The central aim of this research project is to develop theoretically and empirically the concept of &apos;citizenship futures&apos;. RQ1: What &apos;hopes&apos; to socially excluded people harbour for their futures, in the context of the social relations of power to which they are subjected? RQ1 will be addressed through comparative ethnographies in London, Paris and Mumbai.  RQ2: What institutional factors shape people&apos;s &apos;hopes&apos; for the future?  RQ2 will be addressed through a historical-institutionalist analysis of political narratives in the UK, France and the Indian State of Maharashtra.    For the purpose of analysis, we propose to adapt Zipin et al (2015), whose research on education (drawing on Bourdieu and Appadurai) usefully theorise three ways in which hopes are constituted through social-cultural processes. Doxic hopes are &apos;dominant norms about worthy futures&apos; circulating through media and policy discourse. Habituated hopes are embodied dispositions grounded in biographic-historical conditions (habitus). Emergent hope are &apos;future-tending impulses&apos; &apos;emerging among young people as their lives apprehend the present-becoming-future&apos;.  The qualitative data will be systematically generated, answering the research questions as directly as possible. NVivo will be used to organise and share data (transcripts, field notes and other materials).   The comparative approach proposed under the rubric of the project will make three further contributions to knowledge-production. One, by bringing the UK, France and India within a common frame of investigation and analysis, the project will blur the boundaries between such categories as &apos;developed&apos; and &apos;developing&apos; countries, &apos;Global North&apos; and &apos;Global South&apos;, and other such binaries that hinder an appreciation of the shared problems faced by people across these scholarly silos. Second, by recruiting an India-based researcher to conduct ethnographic research on poverty in the UK, the project will contribute to emerging methodological discussions on &apos;reversing the gaze&apos;. Third, by adopting a collaborative approach to ethnography, the project will encourage the collaboration of researchers across national contexts and their interlocutors in the production of ethnographic texts.  The research will be conducted by a multidisciplinary team offering complementary expertise. The in-depth ethnography favoured by sociologists and anthropologists will be complemented by innovative historical-institutional analysis developed by political scientists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The central aim of this research project is to develop theoretically and empirically the concept of &apos;citizenship futures&apos;. The project will do this by investigating the &apos;politics of hope&apos; harboured by socially excluded people. These investigations require a robust understanding of their political subjectivities. Because political subjectivities cannot be abstracted from their institutional contexts, the project will analyse the potential mechanisms that connect popular understandings with institutional change. The research objective will be achieved through two closely related empirical questions. RQ1: What &apos;hopes&apos; to socially excluded people harbour for their futures, in the context of the social relations of power to which they are subjected? This research question will enable the project to investigate the ways of thinking, feeling and acting which constitute the &apos;politics of hope&apos;, as discussed above. At the same time, the question must remain open-ended to account for considerations other than hope. This question will be addressed through the &apos;comparative ethnography&apos; outlined in Work Package 1 and the specific tasks outlined below.   RQ1 will be addressed using an ethnographic approach (WP1), which is particularly suited to investigating how and why people act, think and feel the way they do about possible futures, and especially the hopes they harbour for these futures. By shedding light on people&apos;s everyday organisation of their social life as well as their engagements with formal politics, the &apos;political ethnographies&apos; conducted for this project will contribute to our understanding of socially excluded people&apos;s imagination of &apos;citizenship futures&apos; in the context of the hopes they harbour. The ethnographies to be conducted under this project will employ an explicitly comparative research methodology. WP1 includes: - WP1.1: In-depth semi-structured interviews to enable the project to delve into the ways in which interviewees interpret the possibilities open to them for the future.  - WP 1.2: Life histories of a sub-set of the interview respondents with the purpose of examining the temporal and spatial dimensions of people&apos;s lives in the context of the hopes they harbour for their future.  - WP 1.3: Direct observations of the everyday practices: 1). Involvement in &apos;associations&apos;; 2). &apos;Consumption&apos; practices; 3). Ways of being &apos;present&apos; in public spaces; and 4). Discussions in formal forums.  - WP 1.4: Assemble an inventory of the popular aesthetics: 1). Literary outputs that interest our interlocutors from the neighbourhoods under study, including texts; 2). Public works of art in the study localities; 3). Memorials in and around the study localities; and 4). Films consumed by our interlocutors.  RQ2: What institutional factors shape people&apos;s &apos;hopes&apos; for the future?  This research question will enable the project to develop an understanding of the institutional changes that provide context to the ways of thinking, feeling and acting that might emerge from the ethnographies. By highlighting changing political narratives, it will seek to delineate the institutional manifestations of hope. This question will be addressed through the &apos;historical-institutional analysis&apos; outlined in Work Package 2 and its specific tasks below.  RQ2 will be addressed through a historical-institutionalist analysis of political narratives (WP2) in the UK, France and the State of Maharashtra. In doing so, it will draw on comparative interpretive approaches to examining and analysing institutional change in historical perspective across them.  WP2 includes: - WP2.1: investigate continuities and changes in formulations of hopes for the future in the political narratives of France, UK and the Indian State of Maharashtra: 1) Key debates in the legislatures of the three countries; and 2). Manifestoes of political parties issued during elections. - WP 2.2.: examine continuities and changes in the social composition of elected legislators.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-07">145759.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/R010978/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">12240.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">12240.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">12240.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">20095.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">20258.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">19127.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">12339.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">12339.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010978_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FR010978%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
