<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T003987_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing Relapse for People with Schizophrenia in Jakarta, Indonesia: Developing a culturally-relevant, evidence-based Family Intervention</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mental illnesses comprise the single largest source of health-related economic burden worldwide. Schizophrenia is among the most disabling conditions in these low-resource settings and 90% of those who need treatment do not receive it. Consequently, much of the burden of care is transferred to families who have few resources to support them in caring for their loved one. Often, carers lack knowledge and expertise about how to manage and having caring responsibilities significantly affects their own quality of life.  In high-resource settings family interventions (FIp) are provided as a &apos;talking therapy&apos; for relatives and carers. These types of interventions focus on helping families to cope with illness, learn how to communicate, solve problems and set goals for treatment. Families also find these interventions supportive and reassuring which helps with their own coping and emotions. These interventions are known to be highly effective but they may not translate directly from one culture to another because there are differences in the way people view mental illnesses, how they see and communicate with each other and how treatment is organised.   The aim of this study is to see whether we will be able to tailor an intervention we know is effective in the UK to the needs of people living in Indonesia. To do this, we will ask people in groups what they think of the intervention, about their experiences with getting help and how schizophrenia has affected their lives. We will ask them how they would like to receive the intervention in the future, what aspects are important to include, what type of therapist they would prefer and how and when they would like to receive the intervention. We will then gather a panel of experts to make a final decision about the intervention and ask them what kind of resources they think would help to train people. We will develop a manual to help people who deliver the intervention to deliver these interventions well and we will prepare teaching resources so that in the future, they can teach others to deliver the intervention.  The final part of this work is to train people to deliver the intervention in a primary care setting. A large trial of this intervention would use lots of valuable resources to complete and would not be a good use of resources if we don&apos;t know that we can complete the trial. For example, we might not be able to recruit people so before we get to that stage we will do a small trial and see if all the pieces work together, we can recruit everyone we need and collect all the information we need. We also need to make sure that healthcare professionals delivering the intervention can do this with the manual as it is described.  We will then need to check with the people who receive the intervention that they like it, whether we could change parts to make it better and whether people delivering it also like it. At the same time, we will be thinking about how this will work in primary care, we will be having conversations with the right people who will use or be affected by our new intervention and we will tell them about what we are doing.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this study is to adapt and refine an evidence-based family intervention for relatives and carers of people with schizophrenia in Java, Indonesia. Schizophrenia presents a major public health problem in this region. Large treatment gaps are a key contributor; the majority for whom treatment would be of benefit, do not receive any and consequently, much of the care people with schizophrenia receive is delivered by their families. In low-resource settings, family interventions are one of only three types of interventions recommended for schizophrenia by the World Bank&apos;s third edition of disease priorities. Family interventions for psychosis (FIp) have strong evidence for their efficacy in high-income countries. FIp significantly reduce relapse, re-hospitalization, increase adherence to medication regimes, enhance patient functioning and improve family environments.  We propose to use an existing intervention that is currently approved for widespread use in the NHS (according to National Institute for Clinical Excellence Guidelines) and adapt and refine the intervention to produce a culturally relevant psychosocial intervention. FIp require adaptation to different cultural contexts allowing cultural beliefs, explanatory models of illness and contextual socio-economic issues to be incorporated into the content and delivery of such interventions. This enhances acceptability, increases engagement and can enhance the efficacy of the intervention. We will explore stakeholder priorities for the intervention using an empirically-derived heuristic framework for cultural adaptation of psychosocial therapies and gain consensus from stakeholders on the components, format and delivery of this evidence-based intervention. Our objectives are: 1. Explore preferences and priorities for delivering family interventions for relatives and carers of people with schizophrenia in Java, Indonesia  2. Synthesise findings from stakeholder interviews with an existing evidence-based intervention  3. Gain consensus on the components, format and delivery of the intervention  4. Identify the training needs of healthcare workers for delivering the intervention 5. Produce a manual to support delivery of the culturally-adapted intervention 6. Explore wider factors that may hinder or facilitate the adoption, reach and effectiveness of the intervention for delivery 7. Train healthcare professionals to deliver the intervention in primary care settings 8. Assess the feasibility of testing the intervention in a full trial and explore the acceptability of the intervention to a wide group of stakeholders We will produce a manual to support delivery of a co-produced, culturally-relevant intervention and assess the training needs of community workers to promote scalability for a future trial to reduce the risk of relapse in schizophrenia. Using the Medical Research Council framework for complex interventions we will conduct this study in three phases. Following adaptation and refinement of the intervention, we will produce a manual to guide intervention implementation, develop training resources, train healthcare professionals to deliver the intervention and explore the acceptability of this intervention to a wide group of stakeholders. We will assess the feasibility of taking the intervention to full trial considering key aspects including recruitment, willingness of participants to be randomised, retention in the trial, intervention fidelity and completeness of outcome assessment. We will explore participants and healthcare workers views of receiving and delivering the intervention and wider implementation issues from key informants to ascertain factors affecting reach and scalability of the intervention for a future trial. The key objective is to assess the feasibility of testing this intervention in a randomised, single blind trial to determine the effectiveness of a culturally adapted version of FIp versus standard care in a primary care setting.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-07" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-06" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">149833.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T003987/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT003987%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-03-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
