<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000542_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operationalising Labour Rights: Access to Remedy at the Workplace</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Operationalising Labour Rights: Access to Remedy at the Workplace.  As economies grow and capital expands, conditions of employment for those who labour to create wealth remain poor in many industries and locations around the world.  This is particularly the case in sectors such as the international garment sector, where the dispersion of labour intensive production along opaque value chains allows conditions at the workplace to be obscured from scrutiny.  It is at this level that workers with low associational and structural power struggle to exert representational rights and defend their interests, while the lack of transparency within the global production network facilitates the perpetuation of abusive practices, the worst of which are all too often exposed by tragedy and loss of life, rather than audit. It is in this context that this research project seeks to illuminate local conditions against the backdrop of national and international forms of private and public regulation which fail in the absence of robust mechanisms of enforcement.  The research will involve the systematic collection of data on workplace grievances and their outcomes from garment workers employed in factories in the city of Bangalore, south India. Research partners are identified in Bangalore, including a well-established civil-society organisation, Cividep-India (Cividep), and a small but growing women&apos;s grass roots union, the Garment Labour Union (GLU).  A small amount of data on workplace grievances has already been collated in a short pilot study in 2016. In the present research project, we will compile a further, far more comprehensive bank of data on the nature and outcomes of workplace grievances. The collection of data will take place over a period of twenty-four months and will involve establishing communication with factory workers (away from the workplace), organising worker forums, and establishing a range of engagement activities, facilitated by local field workers, through Cividep, as a precursor to data collection from respondents.  Cividep will manage and monitor the fieldwork and data input in India and fieldworkers will be members of GLU. All fieldworkers will be former garment workers, experienced in the conditions that prevail in the sector.  The gender composition of fieldwork teams will reflect the gendered nature of factory workforces and the membership of GLU, which is generally around 80% female.  The data on workplace grievances, their progress and outcomes will act as a foundation for a detailed understanding of the dynamics of workplace relations.  Accordingly, the data will support us in theorising: 1. To what extent access to remedy is possible for the individual worker at the level of the workplace, and by what means. 2. To what extent it is possible to operationalise labour rights, including freedom of association, through dispute resolution at the level of the workplace.  In addition to contributing to theory and knowledge of labour&apos;s place in global value chains and affording insight into the efficacy of social auditing and statutory regulation in academic debate, the project&apos;s requirements of systematic data collection and analysis holds potential for capacity building in the field. It will further develop and hone research skills necessary to advocacy and the delivery of impact with diverse audiences of academia, practitioners and policy makers. It will also provide data affording greater transparency in workplace relations and evidence to support lobbying for meaningful mechanisms of access to remedy at the workplace. The objectives of this study are therefore to provide a deeper theoretical understanding of the challenges involved in operationalising labour rights at the workplace at the base of a feminised labour-intensive supply chain, while also developing skills and capacity in local civil society, supporting its advocacy role and thereby strengthening its transnational relationships and status.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the study will be:   1. To compile a longitudinal data bank of workplace grievances, as experienced by workers in the garment factories of Bangalore, India, as a basis for transparency and advocacy for more effective access to remedy.  There is an established tradition of civil society campaigning for better conditions in garment manufacture. Yet, in the absence of regular and reliable enforcement mechanisms at workplace level, we know that neither statutory nor voluntary standards of good practice are reliably observed or enforced. In this context, workers&apos; experiences of seeking access to remedy are largely hidden from scrutiny. In compiling a databank of grievances as communicated to us by workers we will categorise grievances to identify, for example, common concerns, contraventions of core labour standards and recurring practices and themes. The resulting databank will increase transparency and visibility of workers&apos; issues, provide academic insight, and act as a source of evidence for civil society advocacy with policy makers and international brands, around workplace mechanisms for access to remedy.  2. To monitor the progression of workplace grievances through grievance resolution mechanisms over time, from inception to final outcome, as a means of understanding power and process at the workplace. By tracking the progress of grievances, we intend to illuminate access to remedy at workplaces across the sector in a specific urban district. We wish to understand the implications for the individual of registering any form of grievance and exactly how such issues, including contravention of statutory rights, are processed and resolved.  By studying the nature, process and outcomes of workplace grievances, we will increase visibility of the concrete experiences of individual workers and the power relations of the factory environment, including the role and status of organised labour. The study will thus provide a picture of access to remedy at the workplace, in a particular urban setting.  3. To develop skills and capacity at the grass roots in civil society in Bangalore, India. Through this project, the skills demanded of systematic data collection, input and analysis will be further developed among fieldworkers and researchers in Bangalore. Our civil society partner, Cividep, will supervise and monitor data collection by fieldworkers currently active in the Garment Labour Union (GLU).  GLU is a small grass-roots, registered trade union whose leadership is dominated by female, former garment workers. GLU fieldworkers already possess invaluable local experience of the industry and organising and this project will strengthen its administrative capabilities and advocacy role. The project will also assist in providing a reliable foundation of evidence for Cividep&apos;s local and transnational civil society advocacy with clothing brands headquartered in the UK, Europe and elsewhere.  4. To publish high quality research outputs in internationally renowned journals and publications and disseminate knowledge to policy makers and practitioners in line with a broader ethos of public value in academia. The programme of research will provide a unique study of conditions of employment at the workplace in a developing country, at the base of a labour-intensive global value chain, where principles of decent work fail in the absence of robust mechanisms of enforcement.  As such, the research directly addresses aspects of policy making at national and international level.  The research project will therefore provide important new evidence of workplace relations in an area that is currently under-researched.  This evidence will be of pertinence to academics, policy makers, civil society organisations, business leaders, employers and the public, within both developed and developing economies. Our dissemination strategy will ensure that our research findings are promoted to these different stakeholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-02">84724.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-02">185414.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-02">186874.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-02">457013.374</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to Cardiff University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000542_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FS000542%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
