<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_S018719_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding the evolution of insecticide resistance in Brazilian crop pests: Towards effective Insecticide Resistance Management (IRM)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Insect pests represent a major threat to current and future food security with an average of 20% of crops worldwide lost annually to herbivorous insects. This issue is particularly acute in Brazil where agriculture forms a key component of the economy accounting for 26% of gross domestic product (GDP). Synthetic insecticides are widely used by farmers and growers in Brazil in an attempt to reduce yield loss from insect pests. Unfortunately, the growing reliance on insecticides has resulted in the emergence of insect pest populations that are resistant to many of the chemicals used for control. Two of the most economically important species in this regard are the neotropical brown stink bug, Euschistus heros, and the fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda. E. heros is a major pest of soybean and vegetable crops and causes severe damage to cotton and maize, while S. frugiperda feeds on more than 80 plant species but is particularly destructive on maize. Resistance to several important insecticides has now emerged in these species and threatens their sustainable control. Despite the seriousness of this issue very little research has been carried out to understand the evolution of resistance in E. heros and S. frugiperda and to use this knowledge to develop means to combat its emergence and spread. This is, in part, due to a lack of genomic resources for these key pest species - particularly in the case of E. heros.   This project builds on key &apos;omic&apos; (genomic and transcriptomic) and biological resources for E. heros and S. frugiperda generated in a stage 1 pump-prime project to understand the molecular basis of resistance in the two pest species. Specifically, we generated a high quality draft genome sequence of E. heros and strains of E. heros and S. frugiperda that share a common genetic background but differ in their susceptibility to several insecticides. These resources will be exploited in the stage 2 project to identify candidate genes and genetic variation associated with resistance and their causal role validated using transgenic approaches. Understanding the role of these genes in resistance will be facilitated by the generation of gene expression atlases for both species which will comprise databases and user-friendly web applications for studying the expression of genes in different tissues of adults or larvae. These resources will be used in the project to identify where candidate resistance genes are expressed in order to understand how they confer resistance. More broadly their publication will accelerate broad functional genomic research in these pest species beyond the scope of this project. Another key output of the stage 1 project was characterisation of the microbial community (the microbiome) present in the gut of both pest species and the identification of gut bacteria that degrade pesticides. The genomic and biological material generated will be used in the stage 2 project to understand how and to what extent these microbes contribute to resistance, and how they might be disrupted in order to overcome resistance.  The data from these experiments will fundamentally advance our understanding of how insects evolve resistance to insecticides. Furthermore, the knowledge generated will be of direct applied importance in relation to the sustainable control of both pest species. To translate the knowledge gained in this project to combat resistance we will develop simple DNA-based diagnostics, and use these to determine the frequency and distribution of resistance in the field in order to inform rational control decisions and develop insecticide resistance management strategies. Furthermore, we will develop screening tools (recombinant enzyme assays or transgenic insect lines) that can be used by academia and industry to develop resistance-breaking chemistry.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project addresses the growing problem of insecticide resistance in two economically important pests of Brazilian agriculture: The neotropical brown stink bug, Euschistus heros, and the fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda. The overarching aim of this stage 2 project is to leverage data and resources generated by the applicants in a stage 1 project to understand the molecular basis of resistance in the two pest species, and translate this knowledge into tools and strategies to combat resistance. The project comprises five main Objectives as follows:  1. Identification of the genetic and transcriptomic changes that confer resistance. This objective will exploit the high quality draft genome sequence of E. heros generated in the stage 1 project (and the existing reference genome for S. frugiperda) to characterise the genetic and transcriptomic changes associated with resistance. Next generation sequencing of insect lines generated in stage 1 that share a largely common genetic background but differ in their susceptibility to several economically important insecticides will be used to identify mutations and changes in gene expression associated with resistance. Identification of candidate genes and genetic variation that can be validated in Objective 4 will provide markers that can be used to develop molecular diagnostics for resistance monitoring in the field.  2. Development of expression atlases. The tissue-specific transcriptomics data generated for E. heros and S. frugiperda in the stage 1 project will be used to develop user-friendly expression atlases. These will be placed online in the public domain as a public good in order to accelerate studies on these economically important pests. In the context of this project we will use this resource to identify the spatial expression of candidate resistance genes in order to understand their capacity to confer resistance in vivo.  3. Characterising the role of the insect microbiome in resistance. We have shown that the microbes that live inside insects (the microbiome) may affect the sensitivity of the insect host to insecticides. This workpackage will exploit data generated in the stage 1 project - the metagenomic sequence data of the microbial community of the gut of E. heros and S. frugiperda, and isolated microbes that survive insecticide exposure - to perform an in-depth characterisation of the role of the microbiome of E. heros and S. frugiperda in resistance. We will also explore how the bacterial community can be disrupted as a route to overcome resistance.  4. Functional characterisation of candidate genes/mutations associated with resistance. In this objective we will use post-genomic functional approaches to validate the causal role of mutations and genes of interest (identified in objective 1) in resistance. Demonstrating the fitness benefit of key candidate genes/mutations is an important step towards developing tools and strategies that overcome or slow the spread of these mechanisms in Objective 5.  5. Towards effective IRM - developing resistance diagnostics, screening tools and resistance breaking chemistry. This objective will leverage the knowledge and data generated in this (and the stage 1) project to develop tools and strategies to combat resistance. We will use the validated resistance markers identified in the project to develop simple DNA-based diagnostics, and use these to determine the frequency and distribution of resistance in the field in order to inform rational control decisions and develop insecticide resistance management strategies. If we find that metabolic resistance plays a major role in resistance we can explore the use of enzyme inhibitors to restore susceptibility in resistant populations. Finally we can use the outputs of Objective (4) to develop screening tools (recombinant enzyme assays or transgenic insect lines) that can be used to develop resistance-breaking chemistry.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-09" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-08" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-08">257058</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-08">193810.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-08">54429.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
