<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N012143_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilient Economy and Society by Integrated SysTems modelling (RESIST)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the past decades, great progresses have been made in tackling disaster risk around the world especially since the Hyogo Framework for Action in 2005. However, there are still many challenging issues to be solved, and the disasters over recent years have clearly demonstrated the inadequate resilience in our highly interconnected and interdependent systems, including well-known devastating disasters such as the 2008 Wenchuan, 2011 Tohoku and 2015 Nepal Earthquakes.   RESIST have identified the following weaknesses and knowledge gaps in the current disaster risk assessment and management that are in need of urgent research: 1) although our understanding in individual hazards has been greatly improved, there is a lack of sound knowledge about mechanism and processes of interacting multi-hazards (cascading, concurring and altering). Therefore, the resultant multi-hazard risk are often significantly underestimated with severe consequences (e.g., the cascading disasters of 2011 Tohoku Earthquake). It is also poorly understood about the spatial and temporal changes in hazards and vulnerability during successive hazards; 2) hazard monitoring, forecasting and early warning systems have not fully utilised the domain knowledge of physical processes and the statistical information of the observations; 3) uncertainties have not been well recognised in the current risk management practice, and ignorance  of  uncertainties  could  lead  to  major  threat  to the  society  and  poor  consideration  with  inefficient  or  unsustainable  preferences  of  options; 4) the current hazard and risk assessments are fragmented with a weakness in holistically combining quantitative and qualitative information from a variety of sources; 5) there is an urgent need for the holistic (i.e., systems) thinking framework and decision support system (DSS) tools in adequate scenario assessment and resilience development from a harmonised and transdisciplinary perspective. It is our ambition for RESIST to deliver a research project that tackles the unsolved issues with a joint effort from a multidisciplinary team in social science, natural science, engineering and systems.   The overall goal of RESIST is set to develop a holistic thinking framework and the next generation systems modelling platform for sustainable economic development considering social welfare and well-being to increase resilience to natural hazards in earthquake-prone regions in China. To achieve this goal, the following objectives are targeted: 1) to develop a Disaster Risk Information System (DRIS) by literature review, field trips, and new observations; 2) to study mechanisms and processes of interacting multi-hazards influenced by earthquakes, climate change and human activities; 3) to analyse holistic disaster risk assessment and mitigation measures; 4) to develop a whole systems resilience modelling platform for sustainable economic development and social welfare.   China is a large country suffering from nearly all natural hazards of varying magnitudes, and the economic and social costs of disasters resulting from earthquakes, landslides, debris flows, and floods are immense. RESIST will contribute to increasing resilience to natural hazards in earthquake prone regions in China by a research partnership between UK and Chinese scientists.  The developed new knowledge and models will improve our understanding about disaster risks which will benefit many countries around the world including the UK that suffer from natural hazard threats.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of RESIST is set to develop a holistic thinking framework and the next generation systems modelling platform for sustainable economic development considering social welfare and well-being to increase resilience to natural hazards in earthquake-prone regions in China.  To achieve this goal, the following objectives are targeted:   1) to develop a Disaster Risk Information System (DRIS) by literature review, field trips, and new observations: Both quantitative information and qualitative information on the environment, hazards and human society are important for understanding the mechanisms and processes of hazards, assessing and managing disaster risks. Hence, development of an effective DRIS is a prerequisite for the whole project involving data collecting, processing, archiving and retrieving.  2) to study mechanisms and processes of interacting multi-hazards influenced by earthquakes, climate change and human activities: Conventional analyses of hazard assessment tend to focus on individual hazards in isolation. However, the earthquake prone zones are usually affected by multiple natural hazards with the potential for interacting relationships, in which risks across individual hazards should not be linearly summed together to produce the resultant multi-hazard risk due to their cumulative and non-linear effects. The understanding of such interactions, their impacts and the related uncertainties, are an important and topical area of research.  3) to analyse holistic disaster risk assessment and mitigation measures: RESIST will investigate the linkage between disaster risks and socio-economic systems using a holistic approach. Different combinations of structural and non-structural mitigation measures against the risks will be analysed.  4) to develop a whole systems resilience modelling platform for sustainable economic development and social welfare: RESIST will embrace a sustainability framework to understand risk management of natural hazards and their relations to ecosystems and human society. The project will identify the key actors and sociotechnical processes and their interactions with the nature which have shaped the disaster risks in the past in order to derive future scenarios. An open-source DSS will be adopted and enhanced to help the decision-making and investment for improved resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-25" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-24" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">40292.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">161496.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">162804.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">81895.88</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-22">487437.78</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE/N012143/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FN012143%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-25"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
