<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N009169_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Green Markets, regenerating the urban historic core to sustain Socio-Cultural heritage and economic activities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aims and objectives The aim of this project is to develop a network of actors that would lead to the creation of a framework and an action plan which can be used to regenerate the 19th century markets with its current users and other stakeholders. Markets as physical tangible heritage buildings and through their daily activities should support the preservation of intangible heritage; the colours, tastes and odours of a specific culture. The proposal wants to position markets as a platform for cultural fusion, a low carbon economy, employment and economic prosperity  The project objectives are:        Creating a knowledgeable and effective network that can carry on work beyond the duration of the funding to create a sustainable framework for raising awareness and public engagement over the significance and potential of the  heritage of 19th century markets in Egypt         The network will develop a multidisciplinary problem-solving approach linking social, creative and technical disciplines on regenerating derelict wholesales market buildings into new community hubs that will be useful for the specific case study and in thinking about other such examples in Cairo and beyond.        Developing a platform for sustained collaboration between the academic partners for work on Egypt&apos;s cultural heritage through publications and preparation for a larger bid. Contributing to knowledge in the academic fields of sustainable building technologies, cultural heritage and collaborative community processes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will contribute to developing understandings about broader conceptions of Egyptian cultural heritage and examine ways that such heritage can contribute to processes of social and economic regeneration, through the careful management of interventions that combine understanding of heritage value, appropriate technological innovation and collaborative processes of engagement with local disempowered communities.  The recent heritage in Egypt tends to be neglected in favour of directing funds and effort to its ancient cultural and built heritage from the Pharaonic era. This creates a situation of lost opportunities and valuable architectural heritage being left to ruin.  This project will develop frameworks for sustaining the recent cultural heritage of wholesales market buildings in Egypt.  The central location of these markets in Cairo, surrounded by a larger retail areas of different markets, urban dwellers and schools, makes them potentially valuable for cultural activities and to act as venues for museum education outside the museums of Egypt.  Currently, however, these large covered market plots are predominantly used by urban squatters that provide their services of cut vegetables, cheap electronic goods, bakery and spices to the surrounding urban dwellers. Extensions on the original shop lines, both horizontally and vertically, creates a situation where it is difficult to manage risks of fire and there is poor sanitation.  Moreover, on-going attempts to adapt the physical structure of such markets, or to build within them, have undermined the buildings&apos; architectural integrity and historic significance.  Equally, we must be aware that attempts to redevelop these buildings run the risk of gentrification, marginalising their current urban poor users and destroying their physical and cultural heritage value.   To address these issues we have assembled a multidisciplinary team of UK and Egyptian researchers, combining expertise in appropriate technological interventions into historic fabric, understandings of heritage value and collaborative processes of engagement with disempowered and disadvantaged communities. Through taking a specific case study, of the Attabba market, the project will develop and share a vision for extending the contemporary refurbishment of these markets into a wider societal role, acting as a nucleus of culture and economy.  Whilst we will develop our vision through knowledge of market refurbishment schemes elsewhere in the world and through a process of co-production with local stakeholders we will explore, for example, the potential to extend the market&apos;s current function, as a venue for food retail, into one with shared places to enjoy culinary teaching and meals, and to host incubators of cultural exchanges, in the form of exhibition space, and out of museum educational facilities. On the roof we envisage activities to familiarize communities with urban farming and renewable energy technologies. The research will principally draw from and contribute to knowledge in the fields of sustainable building technologies, cultural heritage and collaborative community process as well as urban agriculture and food and museology. A specific dimension will be an examination of the transferability of approaches developed in UK and the Europe to the very different cultural, economic and institutional context of Egypt.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-26">39645.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-26">991136.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to Newcastle University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N009169_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FN009169%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-02-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
