<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00783X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guernica Remakings, South Africa, research into the practice of cross-cultural translation through making.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since Pablo Picasso&apos;s creation of Guernica (1937), the painting has been reproduced and recreated in many forms traversing the confines of fine art. The Keiskamma Art Project located in the Eastern Cape of South Africa have remade Guernica four times since 2010. Their translation of Picasso&apos;s iconic anti-fascist artwork transforms its geography, time and narrative from: Spain to South Africa, from the early 20th century to the beginning of the 21st century, from anti-fascism to the HIV/AIDS crisis. This research project focuses on this process of cross-cultural translation through the creation of a fifth Keiskamma Guernica and asks why Guernica? Exploring what it is about this artwork that lends itself to being adapted. A series of twelve short documentary films record the making of this artwork. The makers will be interviewed and in their own voices will discuss their role in the making process and their insights regarding the visual translation of Guernica to comment on the HIV / AIDS crisis in South Africa. The makers will also be given the opportunity to express their ideas and needs for change, which will be included in the videos creating their vision of the future. The videos will be made widely available through the publication of the videos online through Guernicaremakings.com, via a dedicated channel on Vimeo (Guernica Remakings), You Tube and the University of Brighton repository. The Guernica Remakings exhibition in Brighton, UK (Jul-Aug 2017) is timely it marks the 80th year from the bombing of the town of Guernica. It is a mechanism for ensuring that the transnational relevance of the messages held within the remakings of Guernica can travel to different regions. This is particularly poignant in a period when the UK is withdrawing from Europe, in part, motivated it seems by fear around the freedom of movement of &apos;others&apos; Guernica&apos;s humanitarian message becomes relevant once again calling for solidarity and compassion transcending borders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to:  1.     Investigate the practice of translation through making; studying the collective artistic practices, technical textiles processes and developmental impact of the remakings of Guernica by the Keiskamma Art Project. 2.     Document the creation of a fifth Keiskamma Guernica in order to effectively record and share individual maker&apos;s experiences of the HIV / AIDS crisis and their understanding of the visual translation of this into the Keiskamma Guernica. 3.     Disseminate the recordings in the form of a series of short videos via the video blog: Guernicaremakings.com   The first and second project aims will be achieved through the commissioning and documentation of the creation of a small scale Keiskamma Guernica (Objectives 1 and 2). The makers will be recorded whilst creating the textiles piece, enabling them to talk about the techniques and processes they are carrying out. Through semi-structured interviews the inter-generational makers will be given a space in which to voice their own understanding of the translation of the shapes and symbols of Guernica to express the witnessing of pain and suffering related to HIV / AIDS and the fight for treatment (Objective 3). Hearing directly from the makers is key to this project, which aims to create a platform for their narrative, spoken in their own words. How their work at the Keiskamma Art Project has impacted upon them personally will also be captured exploring the impact upon their self-esteem and the alleviation of poverty. The interviews will be transcribed and the transcriptions used to aid the process of scripting the 12 videos.  The primary research findings will be used to form an in-depth study of the translation of an iconic European artwork to highlight the impact of the HIV / AIDS crisis in South Africa and the developmental use of the remaking of Guernica in the Eastern Cape. Leading on from Objectives 1, 2 and 3, Ashmore will publish this documentary work online through a series of video blogs on Guernicaremakings.com. This blog, launched in the summer of 2016, forms an international community of knowledge with the participants of four international Guernica remaking&apos;s and provides a good location for this next phase of research into the developmental impact of the small scale Keiskamma Guernica&apos;s (Objective 4).</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-10">79695.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">79695.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00783X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">-15965.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00783X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">-33.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00783X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">15965.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00783X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
