<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N008480_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Gender Politics of Demilitarisation: Examining DDR from the Perspective of Female (Ex)-Combatants</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">What is the relationship between gender, agency and international security? Do contemporary security practices provide &apos;gender security&apos; in (post)conflict settings? How and why do the gendered subjects of (in)security demonstrate agency and resistance in response to peace and security interventions?   UN Security Council Resolution 1325 (UNSCR 1325) stresses the importance of integrating women and gender issues into matters of international peace and security. Yet many argue that international security interventions still fail to address the gender-specific concerns of women in conflict settings, and overlook the agency of women in war and peace. Disarmament, Demobilisation &amp; Reintegration (DDR) programmes exemplify these issues. By eradicating weapons, disbanding armed groups and reintegrating ex-combatants, DDR seeks to secure durable peace. Mainstreaming gender concerns into DDR has potential to achieve positive change. Recognising women as agents not victims of war can help build a gender-just peace. Yet women are often excluded from or marginalised by DDR programs that neglect their interests, rights and needs.  To confront these challenges, the proposed project will develop an innovative approach to gender and security. The aims of this approach are to:  1. Develop a novel theoretical framework for understanding how gendered agency emerges and is deployed in relation to international security interventions; 2. Examine how women situated in (post)conflict settings demonstrate agency and resistance in response to security interventions; 3. Identify how &apos;gender&apos; shapes international security discourses and practices; 4. Assess the extent to which &apos;gender security&apos; is achieved in key sites of international intervention; and 5. Build a robust methodology and methods for mapping and analysing &apos;gender security&apos; in (post)conflict environments.  To achieve these aims, the project will undertake a qualitative study of DDR policies and programmes in post-conflict BiH. The study will focus in particular on &apos;gender security&apos; policies and practices relating to DDR via qualitative analysis of policy documents and interviews with implementers and beneficiaries. In particular, it will explore: the wartime roles of female (ex)combatants/women associated with fighting forces (WAFFs); their motivations for participating in the war effort; their positive and negative experiences of mobilisation; and long-term impact of participation in armed forces. The project will also analyse the gendered nature and impact of DDR policies and practices via an exploration of: women&apos;s participation and representation in the planning and design of DDR programmes; whether and how a gender perspective was incorporated into the implementation, monitoring and evaluation of DDR programming.  Overall, the study would make a major contribution to: current and future security policymaking and practice; understandings of the role of women as potential/actual agents of security; literatures on security studies, peace and conflict studies, and political sociology; methodologies within the disciplines of international relations and sociology that integrate feminist theory and empirical research and overcome divisions between scholars and practitioners; and finally, emerging debates in policymaking and academic circles regarding the importance of &apos;gender security&apos;.  The project involves diverse forms of knowledge exchange with potential beneficiaries and users. Policymakers and practitioners from international organisations, security institutions and civil society will be engaged throughout the project via targeted briefings and consultation meetings, and policy report. The wider public will be engaged via a workshop and book launch in central London.  Ultimately, the study aims to transform understandings of &apos;gender security&apos; by placing the concept of &apos;gendered agency&apos; at the centre rather than margins of security discourse/practice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-08">39618.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-08">39618.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The &apos;Gender Politics of Demilitarisation&apos; project has five main objectives. These objectives are outlined below, in order of priority:  1. Develop a novel theoretical framework for understanding how gendered agency emerges and is deployed in relation to international security interventions, with a focus on Disarmament, Demobilisation &amp; Reintegration (DDR) programming.  - The study will draw on relational understandings of autonomy from feminist moral philosophy and incorporate a feminist post-structuralist framework, in order to build a nuanced conceptualisation of the various modes of agency that are fostered and deployed in sites of (in)security. This will provide an improved analytical framework for understanding interactions between &apos;international&apos;/&apos;local&apos;, &apos;female&apos;/&apos;male&apos; security actors, and will increase our ability to reflect upon how security policies and practices work to enable and/or constrain local capacities.  2. Examine how women situated in (post)conflict settings demonstrate agency and resistance in response to security interventions, particularly in relation to DDR initiatives.  - The project will expand our understanding of how and why individual women make sense of and respond to the official discourses and practices of security institutions. These responses are likely to range from acceptance, through compliance, to outright resistance and contestation. This situated empirical research will provide a more complex understanding of the forms of agency that emerge in conflicted/post-conflict settings, in contrast to dominant discourses and practices on security which tend to construct and reproduce restrictive and often stereotypical conceptualisations of &apos;women&apos;s agency&apos;.  3. Identify how &apos;gender&apos; shapes international security discourses and practices, using DDR as a case study.  - The study will increase our awareness of the gendered nature of discourses and practices emanating from security institutions, and open up possibilities for change. It will explore how approaches to ending conflict and achieving peace and security can be &apos;gender-sensitised&apos; to adequately address the differing security needs of women and men in (post)conflict zones.  4. Assess to which &apos;gender security&apos; is achieved in a key site of international intervention: post-conflict Bosnia-Herzegovina.  - By examining the successes and limitations of the security policies and practices that emerged in a crucial site of intervention - post-conflict Bosnia-Herzegovina - the project aims to improve the outcomes of current and future interventions in (post)conflict settings.   5. Build a robust methodology and methods for mapping and analysing &apos;gender security&apos; in (post)conflict environments.  - The project will develop a systematic qualitative methodology for assessing &apos;gender security&apos; provision, providing future scholars and practitioners with a set of tools for: identifying and assessing the gender security concerns and needs of conflict-affected groups; detecting and responding to gaps in existing security provision; and developing best practices for achieving positive security for both women and men in the aftermath of conflict."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">9904.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N008480_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">9904.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N008480_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">9904.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N008480_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">9904.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N008480_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
