<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V007963_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Covid-19 in Kenya: Global Health, Human Rights and the State in a Time of Pandemic</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Covid-19 is a decisive moment for political reform and social progress in Kenya, as in many other African states. The government response to date has mixed scientifically grounded public health interventions, on the one hand, with forthright coercion, on the other. Mass testing, social distancing, and the closure of public facilities, alongside a nationwide curfew, restrictions on movement in and out of, as well as within the cities of Nairobi and Mombasa. These decrees have been implemented by police and state paramilitaries using massive, indiscriminate and, in some cases, lethal force. Quarantine, imposed on new arrivals from abroad, has also been used as an ad hoc form of punishment for curfew violations. Restrictions have had a disproportionately severe economic impact on residents of already marginalized communities, unable to travel to work or procure adequate food for themselves and their dependents.   The crisis is testing the durability of Kenya&apos;s constitution of 2010 which re-established the republic as a democratic polity based on the rule of law and is taken as model for reform across Africa. The fruit of popular consultation, the constitution broke with decades of colonial and post-colonial authoritarianism and social exclusion. It embeds Kenya in the international human rights order, guaranteeing civil and social rights, and making them enforceable by individual citizens and civil society groups. These gains are far from secure, however. The dominance of a law and order mentality at all levels of government, routine deployment of unchecked police violence, corruption, and a reluctance to abide by court orders have persisted well beyond 2010.   The project asks whether the pandemic emergency has intensified these tendencies, or whether the new constitutional order will prove to be resilient. The research will take social rights implicated by the crisis (eg. health and access to food) as seriously as civil rights (eg. life and liberty), building on accepted international law that both are interdependent and ultimately indivisible. Consonant with the constitutional value of participation, it will work with community groups, policy makers, and civil society organizations to enable lessons to be learnt from the crisis on strengthening democratic and inclusive institutions and practices. The research will generate a legal and political record of the period by analysing and contextualizing legislative and judicial developments, and through qualitative and participatory research with affected citizens, officials, and professionals working in heath, law and nutrition.   The project privileges a reciprocal process of exchange and learning, with grassroots insights informing legal doctrinal work on the one hand, and the human rights capacity of communities being developed by engagement with scholars and practitioners, on the other.  It will generate academic outputs in high quality law, political science and public health journals. A documentary film, co-produced with community journalists will create an accessible, widely shared record of experiences and attitudes to the crisis at different levels of Kenyan society. Through a responsive communication and engagement strategy, including dedicated briefings and webinars, it will disseminate findings to project partners and other key stakeholders enabling them to intervene in a robust and timely fashion to shape the political and legal landscape during and after COVID-19 in ways that favour human rights and human welfare.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will document and evaluate the legal and policy responses to the COVID-19 pandemic in Kenya, giving voice to members of vulnerable and impoverished communities affected by these measures, and to policy makers and legal actors concerned with their implementation. Through a multidisciplinary team of experts in law, human rights and public health, based in East Africa and the UK, it will use qualitative and participatory methods to gather evidence on the relative role of coercion and persuasion, science-based thinking and rights-based approaches in the government response. It will contextualize these historically with reference to the recent trajectory of Kenyan institutions, and theoretically with reference to the influence of international health governance on nation states in the global south. It is particularly urgent because of: 1) the need to gather time-critical data from state and civil society actors, and from citizens and community groups; 2) the opportunity to influence the process of reflection by policymakers, legislators, and scholars at national and international level on the rights and governance implications of the pandemic.   Measures taken to stop the spread of the coronavirus have already had considerable implications for the welfare and human rights and of vulnerable communities in Kenya. A nationwide curfew, the closing of public markets and restrictions on the ability to earn a livelihood have led to a deterioration of the diets and nutritional status of many citizens. Government and philanthropic initiatives to make up the deficit have been insufficient. Litigation and civil society campaigning has focussed on these social effects, and on the extensive violation of human rights represented by the measures themselves and their implementation by state forces. Parliament and the constitutionally mandated bodies, including the Kenyan National Human Rights Commission, the Independent Police Oversight Agency and the Committee on the Administration of Justice, have begun to scrutinize these policies and their effects. This is an evolving situation which will test the ability of Kenyan state institutions to manage a severe health crisis in a manner which attends to the needs and rights of marginalized and impoverished communities. It will also illustrate the resilience of these communities themselves, as well as their capacity to define their own interests and to challenge state and other agencies which neglect or violate them. At stake is the progress of political and social transformation, inaugurated in Kenya in the early 1990s, which led to a new, reform constitution in 2010. Widely admired and studied across the global south, the constitution contains powerful fundamental rights and rule of law guarantees intended to limit and discipline the exercise of coercive state power. Its effectiveness is a matter of keen interest to legal scholars, human rights practitioners, policy makers, and ordinary citizens in Kenya and beyond.  In studying these developments as they unfold the project has three objectives:  Objective 1: Explore the extent to which the legal commitment of the Kenyan state to human rights, particularly economic and social rights, has shaped the response of courts, parliament and the public services to Covid-19.    Objective 2: Document the experiences, perceptions and attitudes of vulnerable citizens towards government measures and the extent to which these are framed in terms of constitutional rights.  Objective 3: Develop empirically grounded, theoretically informed perspectives on the role of the state and human rights in global health governance that can inform institutional and popular processes of reflection as we emerge from the pandemic.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-09">137339.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-09">137339.89</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to Cardiff University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/V007963/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">70515.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V007963_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">66824.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V007963_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FV007963%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-08-03"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
