<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N01670X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coupled Human And Natural Systems Environment (CHANSE) for water management under uncertainty in the Indo-Gangetic Plain</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Managing water resources in the Indo-Gangetic Plain (IGP) is a tremendous challenge because of the basin&apos;s uniqueness in scale, biophysical complexity and the dynamics of its institutional and socio-economic characteristics. Agricultural intensification for food security, combined with unmanaged and inefficient water abstraction for irrigation, and poorly controlled waste management practices, has led to degradation of water resources both in terms of quantity and quality, endangering ecosystem services and human health. Extensive water use is directly linked to the energy sector, and contributes significantly to total carbon emissions. The hydrology of the basin is additionally affected by intensive urbanisation that reduces infiltration and recharge to groundwater. Ultimately, water management in the IGP is challenged by the imbalance between water demand and seasonal availability related to the monsoon cycle, and difficulties in coordinated planning of surface water and groundwater use strategies. Land use and land cover changes, which can modify evapotranspiration, may feed back to large-scale hydro-climatic processes and additionally, disturb the fragile human-natural system of the basin. Management of water resources in the IGP faces additional difficulties because of the local regulations and governance. Lack of cross-sectorial cooperation leads to competition for scarce water resources, while significant governmental subsidies for irrigation water and electricity potentially lead to significant wastage of resources. Finally, the basin&apos;s groundwater resources that are, to a large extent, a primary source for irrigation and rural and urban water supply, are independently managed by multiple agencies.   Considering expected population growth and impacts of climate change, it is clear that achieving water security in India and especially, the IGP, is a growing challenge that requires interdisciplinary collaboration across sectors, local communities, institutions and academia. This project brings together researchers from leading UK (Imperial College London, University of Exeter and British Geological Survey) and Indian (IISc Bangalore, IIT Bombay, IITM Pune, and ATREE Bangalore) institutions, in partnership with international (UNESCO) and local (CEEW) non-governmental organisations, to support water management in the IGP.  The overarching aim of the research is to improve mapping and quantification of dominant interactions and feedbacks between human activities and the hydro-meteorological system of the IGP. This project will provide information for improved decision-making on water allocation for agriculture, drinking water, ecosystems and other needs. The project builds on recent joint UK/India-funded research involving the partners, which has developed a series of highly relevant datasets, tools and models. Specifically, we will: (i) estimate surface and groundwater availability under current and future short-term weather predictions and anthropogenic activities within the IGP using a fully coupled, land surface-groundwater modelling setup; (ii) investigate the propagation, in space and time, of interactions of water uses and needs within the natural system by integrating novel consumer and ecological flow demand modules; (iii) provide regional predictions of decadal, seasonal and sub-seasonal monsoon rainfall and flood forecasting for the IGP, using the Weather Research and Forecasting model coupled with the Community Land Model version 4.0 to inform development of alternative water management strategies; (iv) translate the improved understanding of Human And Natural Systems into IGP&apos;s water management planning for water, food and ecological security. The project will use the River Gandak sub-basin, which has been impacted by these issues, as a case-study catchment for process-understanding. Water management strategies and feedbacks of water allocation to local climate will be analysed at the IGP basin level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-22">367818.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-22">320393.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-22">246241.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This project will address four principal objectives: 1) to build understanding of the hydrologic response of the coupled human-natural system of the Indo-Gangetic Plain (IGP) to current and future climate and anthropogenic pressures; 2) predict regional short-term monsoon rainfall over the IGP; 3) determine the dominant drivers of agricultural and urban water use, and ecological flow requirements in the IGP; and 4) translate this knowledge into information used to guide and inform adaptive management of the IGP&apos;s water resources.   Whilst knowledge about the drivers of irrigation and non-irrigative (human and natural) water demands in the IGP, and their impact on water, food and ecosystems security is limited, the basin has been a focus of hydrological research over the past decade. We will build on recent NERC/MoES-funded research and advanced data and tools that have been generated to address the following specific objectives: - Estimate the surface and groundwater availability under current and future climates and anthropogenic activities within the IGP.  - Improve understanding of the spatio-temporal dynamics and feedbacks in the coupled human-natural system of the IGP basin. - Develop regional predictions of seasonal and subseasonal monsoon rainfall, decadal climate predictions, and the regional weather forecast for flood forecasting that will allow improving the water management strategies.  - Identify thresholds in water requirements and desirable surface and groundwater levels to govern sustainable management of coupled water, food, and ecological systems in the IGP. The objectives will be achieved building on groundwater and land surface models of the IGP developed by the project team, which simulate daily fluctuations in the water table, surface and groundwater flows, soil moisture and evapotranspiration. First, these models will be coupled to consumer and ecological flow demand modules to simulate impacts of different competing demands on scarce water resources. Concurrently, weather predictions ranging from sub-seasonal to decadal timescales will be improved using regional atmospheric models with a better representation of regional characteristics and land surface feedbacks. This will contribute to improving understanding of future water availability and climate adaptability of management strategies.   These data and models subsequently will be integrated into the Coupled Human and Natural Systems Environment (CHANSE) framework using a system dynamics (SD) model that captures the key feedbacks between natural and human components at spatial and temporal resolutions that are meaningful to understand both water use decision-making and biophysical system responses. The SD model will be used to evaluate climate adaptability potential under a range of short-term (decadal) climate change and land use/land cover and population growth scenarios. The ultimate aim will be to enable better-informed decision making, including policy plans, for water-food-ecosystem services.  The case study for our detailed hydro-meteorological and water demand modelling will be the River Gandak sub-basin, which is representative of all the major issues in the larger IGP. New models and understanding of the fine to medium scale processes (100m-10km) will be parameterised and upscaled to the whole IGP. At the basin-scale attention will be focused on water allocation and on the analysis of hydro-meteorological feedbacks of water management strategies.  The information that will be provided by the CHANSE framework is expected to feed into key areas of IGP water resources strategy, including plans to improve short-term land use management and conjunctive water use patterns promoted by alternative water management strategies for water, food and ecosystems security. Options for improvement will be developed through a participatory approach involving all project partners and other local stakeholders at all stages of the modelling process."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
