<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S019502_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Converting natural product leads into structure- and ligand-based drug discovery campaigns against leishmaniasis and Chagas&apos; disease</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The lack of robustly validated drug targets has proved a significant barrier to the discovery of new treatments for visceral leishmaniasis (VL) and Chagas&apos; disease (CD).  Furthermore, target deconvolution studies with active leads emerging from current small molecule phenotypic screening have confirmed that the same relatively few molecular targets are being hit repeatedly. This project aims to address these issues through exploitation of more diverse chemistry hits available in the natural product (NP) arena to identify new drug targets. These drug targets can then be progressed through small molecule screening programmes and using structure-based drug discovery approaches. In addition, NPs should provide access to new areas of chemical space, poorly exemplified by current compound libraries, and hence should provide novel chemical start points for drug discovery programmes.   A fully integrated team has been formed comprised of the University of Dundee and University of S&#xE3;o Paulo, S&#xE3;o Carlos (USP), bringing together the broad range of expertise required to successfully execute this project and deliver the novel targets and novel chemical matter to aid discovery of much needed drugs for VL and CD. NP expertise in USP will be leveraged to deliver highly validated novel molecular targets which can be tackled through a small molecule screening campaign and/ or a structure-based approach. The team combines NP expertise, world renowned parasitology, expertise in target deconvolution (mode of action studies), extensive experience of developing molecules that can kill the parasites, and the substantial expertise and infrastructure required to develop drug candidates suitable for progress toward clinical trials.   In the proposed project we will explore a number of pure, active NPs that have already been isolated and structurally elucidated from microbial symbionts of social insects that demonstrate potent activity against Leishmania donovani intracellular amastigotes.  Additionally, the Nucleus of Bioassays, Biosynthesis, and Ecophysiology of Natural Products (NuBBE) from the S&#xE3;o Paulo State University (UNESP) will offer an additional source of isolated NP compounds for investigation, both against VL and CD. Some NP compounds are already available, pure and in sufficient quantity for mode of action (MoA) studies to commence immediately.  Scale-up, purification, characterization and identification of further NPs will be undertaken to deliver sufficient material. MoA studies will use a number of orthogonal approaches including high-throughput genomics, cell biology/biochemistry and/or chemical proteomics to define the principal molecular target(s) of the NPs, thus offering the opportunity to convert NP phenotypic hits into a collaborative structure-based drug discovery programme. Where possible, further scale-up of NPs will be undertaken to provide sufficient material to also assess developability of the pure NP. A hit to lead chemistry campaign may be initiated if feasible. Furthermore, consideration of the presence of underlying &apos;natural product fragments&apos; will be undertaken, and, where relevant, these then tested in isolation to find simpler pharmacophore start points for medicinal chemistry.  Deliverables: (a) novel target(s) for these key kinetoplastid diseases, enabling initiation of novel structure based small molecule drug discovery programmes. (b) early leads in novel chemical space.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The neglected parasitic diseases, visceral leishmaniasis (VL), and Chagas&apos; disease (CD), together cause an estimated 50,000 deaths annually world-wide. Most of the people affected by these terrible diseases are amongst the poorest members of society and often live in remote rural areas. Despite this death toll, the current treatments available are inadequate for many reasons. These problems include side effects, compounds not working very effectively, resistance to current drugs and the requirement for intravenous administration or repeated injections which are not suitable for the rural environments where these diseases are typically found. Consequently, the development of new, effective and safe oral drugs provides an opportunity to save many lives and improve the quality of life for whole regions of the developing world, through the reduction of the morbidity, mortality and the economic consequences of these diseases. Unfortunately there are very few compounds being developed for VL and CD.  In this proposal we aim to identify potential new targets for drug discovery programmes. These are typically enzymes, which are vital to the life of the parasites that cause the diseases. We aim to identify these start points by testing natural products against the parasites. For those natural products that kill the parasites, we will then find out how the compounds are killing the parasites. Natural products are chemical compounds that are found from natural sources, such as plants and bacteria. They often have unique chemical structures, that have not been made before by humans and are difficult to make synthetically. Therefore they provide good tools to identify potential drug targets that often would not be found by other means. Once we have identified the molecular target (enzymes) we can then carry out a drug discovery programme, either by using these natural products as starting points or using conventional drug discovery approaches to find inhibitors of the enzyme and then optimise them into potential drugs.  An established, fully integrated team comprised of the University of Dundee and University of S&#xE3;o Paulo, S&#xE3;o Carlos brings together the broad range of expertise required to discover these much needed drugs. The team combines natural product expertise, world renowned parasitology, expertise in identifying the modes of action of compounds in these parasites, extensive experience developing molecules that can kill the parasites, and the substantial expertise and infrastructure required to develop drug candidates suitable for progress toward clinical trials.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">231785.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">233662.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">230744.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
