<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N013948_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UCT - UEA Newton PhD Partnership on Understanding the Climate system and Coping with Climate Change</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The developing world is projected to suffer disproportionately from the effects of climate change. Many uncertainties remain in the likely conditions the world will experience, for example in local rainfall, and the effects of such changes on agriculture, fisheries, health and industrial development. It is today&apos;s early career researchers who will be tasked with tackling these challenges in future.  To generate the skilled people necessary, we propose an international PhD partnering between the University of Cape Town (UCT) and the University of East Anglia (UEA) in the areas of (1) understanding the climate system, including the ocean and atmosphere, and (2) developing capacity to cope with a changing climate.  The proposed partnership will exchange PhD students in the fields of climate science (e.g. climate modelling, ocean science, atmospheric science), climate impacts (e.g. social science, international development, human health, agriculture, fisheries) and adaptation strategies. UEA and UCT are two universities with strong expertise in these disciplines. These strong and complementary centres and academics are brought here together in a formal arrangement for the first time.   The PhD researchers will benefit from strong expertise in both UEA and UCT in a range of key and modern methods. They will learn the skills needed to fully develop as researchers and operate in a global research environment in their field. Our partnership includes world experts in the measurements of ocean currents, marine biogeochemistry and ecology, fisheries survey, and atmospheric trace gases, as well as experts in conducting fieldwork on climate change adaptation and on epidemiology. We also have expertise in the synthesis and analysis of global datasets such as the global temperature (CRUTEM) and global ocean CO2 (SOCAT), and expertise in the modelling of physical climate, biogeochemistry, and integrated assessments of impacts and adaptation options. Importantly, many of our academic staff are experienced in working in interdisciplinary teams, a skill that is becoming increasingly important to address issues related to climate change using the best possible solution.  The exchange of 10 PhD students on each side will take place ideally in annual cohorts of 3-4 students, with an initial cohort of UEA students going to South Africa around February 2016, and an annual cohort of South African students coming to UEA around September. Students will be paired with someone of similar interests on both sides. This arrangement will create a support group for the students both for helping to quickly integrate socially and professionally and to be productive in advancing their knowledge, skills and connections quickly. Furthermore, at least three members of academic staff from each of UEA and UCT will also take part in the exchange, one each year. Additional exchanges are envisaged from projects that are already on going.  The group will benefit from international visibility through their integration with the Tyndall Centre at UEA and the African Climate and Development Initiative at UCT, contacts with the staff developing the international Future Earth platform, and connections with staff members that play key roles in international efforts, such as the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change and the World Research Programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of this project are to promote the economic development and welfare of South Africa and the surrounding African nations, enhanced capacity to implementing climate resilient development, the cornerstone of the SA government&apos;s climate change response strategy.  This will occur through capacity building and research to enable better prediction of climate change in the region and surrounding oceans, better understanding of its effects on resources (farming, fisheries, water supply, etc) and better techniques to manage and adapt to the effects of such change on people&apos;s lives and livelihoods. To facilitate knowledge exchange and postgraduate training, we aim to develop and strengthen sustainable, long-term UEA-UCT strategic links through PhD student exchanges in the broad areas of understanding the climate system, including the ocean and atmosphere, and developing capacity to cope with a changing climate.  Specifically, our objective is to develop strategic links in the following two research areas:  (1) Understanding the climate system, particularly climate variability on seasonal to decadal time scales, and including field and lab work and modelling, on land and in the oceans.  (2) Improved approaches and capacity to deal with climate change through research that identifies and quantifies climate change risks, impact and adaptation options, including those that affect food, water, and health.  We aim to produce a cohort of knowledgeable students, able to engage with people across disciplines and outside academia, suitably skilled to be the next generation of policy makers, decision makers, industrial leaders and academics, who can lead developing nations on a path of sustainable development. Our objective is to train these students in climate science, its uncertainties and impacts. We aim to bring researchers from both institutions together through mutual supervision of students, to focus on the critical issues associated with understanding climate change and its implications. It would nurture the development of new joint research proposals to the UK and South African research councils, the Department for International Development (DFID), and through international opportunities such as Horizon 2020 (European Commission), and the Belmont Forum. Our objective is to secure opportunities for post-doctoral research projects for the PhD students taking part in the exchange.  We aim to develop common international ambitions, for example working to build respective regional Hubs of the international Future Earth platform for providing the knowledge based to global sustainability. This ambitious platform, launched at the Earth Summit in 2012, is growing. It is developing multiple regional nodes that will be connected internationally through joint activities. Both UEA and UCT are already playing important roles. Our objective is to support these international ambitions by providing more pathways to exchange ideas, and to put our PhD students at the heart of the international activities around global sustainability.  We aim to build capacity in the African region, in particular to provide expertise in international climate change and biodiversity assessments. UEA has played a substantial role in previous reports of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). Our objective is to provide contacts to facilitate input and involvement in such international programmes, and insight to better inform the IPCC next international assessment with South African research and expertise.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-19">25201.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-19">50607.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-19">51017.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-19">25611.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-19">1676818.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N013948_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FN013948%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-11-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
