<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T039140_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Challenges and opportunities of providing evidence based perinatal psychological care for couples with stillbirth (SB) in Lagos Nigeria</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives  1. To quantify the short and long term psychological, social, economic and intangible cost of stillbirth to women, their partners and families in Nigeria 2. Explore the societal view of stillbirth in the Nigeria society, including its definition, meaning and causes 3. Explore the experience of women and couples with stillbirth in Nigeria as regards healthcare workers and society&apos;s response  4. Explore the type of bereavement care and support that women and couples with stillbirth  in Nigeria would prefer  5. Explore the knowledge, attitude and practice of health care workers and traditional birth attendants in handling and providing care for women with stillbirth in Nigeria  6. Evaluate the current evidence based interventions and guidelines for immediate and longer term care and support after stillbirth  for recommendations that can useful and adaptable in designing a socio-culturally acceptable package of care and support for Nigerian couple after stillbirth  7.   To design an  intervention package for the care and support of Nigerian couple with stillbirth based on the current evidence, preference of service users and socio-cultural and health system realities in Nigeria 8. To test the feasibility of delivering such intervention package and its acceptability by the service users</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Saharan Africa faces the highest burden of stillbirths with Nigeria contributing around 12% of global burden of stillbirth (with about 314,000 stillbirths/year) and an estimated stillbirth rate of 42.9 per 1000 births . Stillbirth is associated with substantial psychological, social, economic and intangible cost to women, their families, healthcare providers and the wider society . Stillbirth in SSA countries brings many challenges to the mother including poor health, grief, sadness, and coping with community perceptions. The mothers&apos; grief experiences following stillbirth are further complicated by the biological fact of death occurring within the body; generating feelings of anxiety, failure, and guilt. Studies have shown that guild and shame plays a very important role in predicting the intensity of later grief . The father is not left out of these difficulties. High rates of depression, anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorders and marital breakup has been observed in couples with stillbirth.  For many couples in SSA, it takes a long time to recover from stillbirth, and in many instances only when another baby is born and survives, some few other never recovers. In Nigeria and many parts of SSA, the couple&apos;s grief is further compounded by many of the communities deeply rooted cultural practices and beliefs.   Many Africa communities attribute stillbirth to spirits or supernatural powers, so bereaved parents avoid public burials and displays of grief, fearing such action could evoke future malice or lead to infertility. In many Africa traditions, women with stillbirth are accused of induced abortion and couples with stillbirth are forbidden from mourning and those who repeatedly lose their babies are blamed, mistreated, and dishonored. These harsh traditional value judgments about stillbirth in most African communities&apos; results in high level of stigma and pushes many couples to keep stillbirths a secret. Problem with health systems:   Apart from the stigma from the community, mothers who experience stillbirths are often overlooked midwives and other perinatal health workers who tend to focus on maternal and child health. Many health workers are ill equipped to handle grief that comes with stillbirth. Also, studies have shown that many healthcare providers may be avoidant, feel helpless and guilty or they may experience a sense of failure when the baby dies.  Many health workers are not equipped to handle perinatal bereavement care. Also most of the guidelines of care after stillbirth reflect the western sociocultural perspectives and may not be appropriate in the African setting in view of the socio-cultural norms and nuances regarding stillbirth.   In order to design a n effective, sociocultural acceptable intervention package of care and support for couples with stillbirth in Nigeria, it is necessary to first have a detail understanding of the peculiar sociocultural issues regarding stillbirth in the community, the specific psychological and social impacts of stillbirth that needs to be prevented, the preferences and perception of the affected couple to perinatal bereavement care and the health systems challenges and opportunities for delivering the intervention. Outcome expected as immediate result of the proposal:   TThe results of this proposal will provide a deeper understanding of social perceptions of stillbirth in Nigeria and other SSA countries which is a crucial step towards reducing the isolation, grief, and stigma attached to stillbirth. It will also provide insight into the psycho-social burden of stillbirth, enumerate the challenges and opportunities for providing socio-culturally relevant bereavement care to coupes with stillbirth and most importantly lead to the development and feasibility assessment of an intervention package for support and care for Nigerian women with stillbirth</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nigeria</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="WESTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-16">59830.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-16">38660.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">40500.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T039140_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lagos State Univ Coll of Med LAUSCOM</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
