<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P028403_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing Resilient Nations - Towards a Public Heath Early Warning System via Urban Water Profiling (ReNEW)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We are proposing an innovative solution to current problems with rapidly identifying and responding to deteriorating public health and environmental conditions in fast developing urban environments in LMIC countries, aiming to manage risks to public and environmental health relating to urbanisation, population growth, lack of infrastructure and the overarching challenge of climate change. We will establish a cutting-edge, interdisciplinary research capability, based on engineering and digital technology approaches, for real-time community-wide diagnostics and tuneable multi-hazard public health early warning system (EWS) with the ultimate goal of strengthening communities&apos; resilience. We will do this through a focus on water from urban dwellings, which reflects the health status of a population and surrounding environment as it pools the endo- &amp; exogenous products of that population. Real-time measurement of these specific hazard biomarkers in urban water from different communities allows for rapid evaluation of public health status, prediction of future crises, and thus enables mitigation strategies to be developed for either rapid or slow onset hazards, even before they manifest themselves with characteristic endpoints (e.g. mortality in the event of pandemics). Thus morbidity and mortality can be reduced and resilience and sustainability within the surveyed urban system significantly increased. In this cutting-edge project we will develop innovative tools for public health diagnostics and undertake a scoping study in the city of Stellenbosch to understand the requirements for the development and implementation of a multi-hazard EWS in South Africa and beyond.  ReNEW tackles all four strategic objectives set by the Department for International Development (UK Aid, 2015) and it focuses on &quot;strengthening resilience and response to crises: (...) science and technology spend on global public health risks such as antimicrobial resistance, and support for efforts to mitigate and adapt to climate change&quot;. The UK is committed to &quot;tackling the great global challenges - from the root causes of mass migration and disease, to the threat of terrorism and global climate change - all of which also directly threaten British interests&quot;. ReNEW will address this through engineering novel integrated sensors for on-site monitoring and use of big data for modelling markers within the urban water system as part of an EWS. We will focus on infectious disease. 21st century has already seen the epidemic of SARS (2003), H1N1 (2009), Ebola (2014) and recently Zika virus (2015). The recent O&apos;Neill report (2016) commissioned by the UK government urges that &quot;by 2050, 10 million lives a year and a cumulative 100 trillion USD of economic output are at risk due to the rise of drug resistant infections. Most of the direct impact will fall on LMIC countries&quot;. This highlights global vulnerability to infectious diseases and shared global responsibility for surveillance and disease control. Easy to operate and cost effective EWSs are urgently needed to provide timely response and to tackle key public health issues in communities that need it most, and to reduce disease spread globally. Urban water profiling can provide such a response in real-time and, if linked with a timely response system, it could reduce burden on public health in LMIC and ultimately worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We recognise that cities are complex and unique systems and exist in very different geographical, climatological, socio-economic, cultural and institutional settings. There are likely to be significant differences between stakeholders that have varied priorities as well as political and economic resources at their disposal. It is therefore vital that the EWSs developed are tailored to specific communities. In close collaboration between key stakeholders and researchers with social, scientific and engineering expertise, ReNEW will develop and test a multidisciplinary framework for how to establish an effective public health EWS in response to the challenges and priorities of inhabitants &amp; institutions. In this project we will undertake a scoping study in Stellenbosch to understand the requirements for the development and implementation of a multi-hazard EWS in SA. We will identify existing constraints in the city-systems of South Africa (i.e. infrastructure-rich areas coexisting with informal settlements lacking infra-structure) and we will propose innovative solutions for future implementation in other African and Asian countries. We will achieve this via the following objectives:  Objective 1: Biomarkers - Development of novel bioanalytical approaches towards public health diagnostics at the community-level via urban water profiling - focus on infectious disease.  We will: (1) develop diagnostic indicators of infectious disease hotspots and acquisition of antimicrobial resistance and 2) screen for pathogenic and antibiotic resistant bacteria and develop community-oriented bioinformatics pipelines Objective 2: Sensors - Development of novel low cost biosensors for real-time monitoring of public health indicators in urban water.  We will develop a &apos;lab-on-a-briefcase&apos; device for simultaneous detection of a panel of biomarkers in urban water that address both exposure and effects of infectious diseases. A range of low-cost label-free sensitive and selective electrochemical biosensors will be optimised for this application using DNA, PNA and DNA aptamer biorecognition elements, and integrated with simple microfluidics and off-the-shelf electronic components for sensor readout.   Objective 3: Monitoring - Spatial and temporal monitoring study of water-derived multiple hazard indicators in Stellenbosch.  We will undertake a monitoring programme in Stellenbosch and its contrasting socio-economic areas.  We will: (1) verify changes in biomarker trends within the city-system, (2) generate large data sets to develop the system model, (3) establish a &apos;business-as-usual&apos; baseline for selected public health indicators, and (4) scrutinize any deviations from the &apos;business-as-usual&apos; baseline against other indicators and surveyed area hazard events (e.g. flooding, increased level of microbial infections or pollution instances).  Objective 4: Modelling multiple hazard indicators and predicting changes within the urban system. The system understanding developed through stakeholder engagement and field monitoring will be brought together through digital technology research in a modelling framework, representing the identified sources, pathways and receptors which can be used to communicate early warnings.  Objective 5: Engagement with key stakeholder groups including policy makers, practitioners, non-profit organisations, the public and other stakeholders in the field of water management. User engagement will be systematically embedded across the lifetime of the project through the activities of a Practitioner Panel, drawn from a range of publics and stakeholders. The Panel will inform: (1) the development and design of EWSs, (2) appropriate representations of the data collected for real-time use and (3) ethics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">392023.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">422781</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">303813.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">1118618.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Bath</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P028403_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FP028403%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
