<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029064_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Digital diagnostics for smarter healthcare in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our aim is to test the potential of open-source hardware as a new business model to establish and scale digital diagnostic solutions in LMICs.  This has the potential to disrupt the healthcare technology market, enabling frugal innovation by local entrepreneurs and reducing reliance on expensive, imported goods from multinational companies.  Empowering local entrepreneurs to work with their healthcare systems and take ownership of well-tested open source technologies will not only result in the creation of products that are adapted to the context of African health systems, it will be a step change in maintenance and support.  Service, training, and spare parts are the missing link in upgrading the diagnostic technology in most developing world healthcare facilities, and all three factors will be greatly improved by the establishment of local suppliers. Our first objective is to understand and map out the process required to implement the OpenFlexure Microscope as a diagnostic tool in three African countries (Tanzania, Kenya, Ghana).  We will identify local ``technology champions&apos;&apos; and build implementation networks in target countries that include health scientists, clinicians, and engineers.  These networks will also engage with local and international regulators, funders, and policymakers. Our second objective is to explore the specific factors that help or hinder the updake of open source diagnostics.  This will allow us to understand the different approaches needed in each target country, and reveal the common themes that should inform international policy.  As the potential for rapid diffusion of innovations between different countries is one of the big advantages of open source technology, mapping out key steps that must be taken to make this possible is important early in the project.  After learning from the implementation studies as part of the second phase of this project, we will be in a strong position to inform the policy of international actors such as the World Health Organisation to support local innovation. Our third objective is to identify other open source projects, and unmet needs for digital diagnostic technology, that could benefit from what we have learned.  This will enable us to broaden the range of technologies we consider in Phase Two.  We will support other open technologies that are becoming ready for adoption, and support the development of new open source hardware to address unmet needs in healthcare systems. Finally, our fourth objective is to connect with new and existing initiatives to build capacity in biomedical engineering in Sub-Saharan Africa, empowering them to use and create open source hardware that can rapidly diffuse across the continent.  We have already engaged with the Southern Africa Network for Biosciences, an emerging Masters-level course in Biomedical Engineering in Ethiopia, and with Concern Worldwide&apos;s &quot;Maker Movement&quot; project in Nairobi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Well-funded medical labs are highly automated; detailed digital images and results are recorded by computerised instruments.  This improves throughput, quality control, and record-keeping, and would enable training and telemedicine for rural contexts where an expert technician is not available.  Currently, automated diagnostic devices are expensive, manufactured in rich countries.  Most of the Global South is left behind, not only because of the high up-front cost, but because equipment cannot be maintained locally, due to proprietary technologies, conservative regulations, and poor supply chains for spare parts and consumables.  This network will bring digital diagnostics to laboratories and clinics across Africa, in sustainable and responsible partnership with local clinicians and engineers.  Our vision is of integrated, modern, digital healthcare laboratories that are supported by a thriving local ecosystem of biomedical engineers and developers.   The crux of our approach is the use of &quot;open source hardware&quot;, where designs for easily replicated, high-quality diagnostic tools are shared under a license permitting their use, sale, and modification.  Crucially, open source projects share not only technical know-how, but also ownership of innovations.  Local entrepreneurs are not required to enter costly licensing deals in order to make use of these designs - the only condition is that they share any improvements they make to the design, for the benefit of similar companies elsewhere.  To reach our vision we must build a body of knowledge and skills that enable a new generation of medical instruments that can be repaired and customised without relying on a handful of rich countries.  Our aim is to test the potential of open-source hardware as a new business model to establish and scale digital diagnostic solutions in LMICs, using the OpenFlexure Microscope as a case study.  The links we build between engineers, healthcare scientists, medical professionals, and social scientists will not only help us achieve this aim, but will provide local, pan-African, and intercontinental links that help to build capacity in diagnostic innovation where it is needed most. We will spend the first year of this project planning, identifying barriers to open source innovation, and forming networks of local connections to overcome these barriers.  In the following years, we will study the process of taking a locally produced, 3D printed microscope from working prototype to usable product for malaria diagnostics in three different African countries.  We will use the framework of Implementation Science to study the &quot;diffusion of innovation&quot; as the technology is taken through regulatory approval and adopted by healthcare providers.  We will engage with a number of other projects, for example low cost retinal imaging devices, to compare across different technologies, and to share what we have learned in malaria microscopy with other application areas. Our network is highly interdisciplinary, and this is crucial to its success: while many diagnostic devices are developed by physical scientists and engineers, this must be led by the needs of clinicians, and informed by the infrastructure, regulations, and political environment of the country where it is to be used.  This understanding of context needs social and policy scientists, as well as engagement with regulators and policymakers.  While there are important points for engineers to consider relating to the context (such as the availability of reliable power or data connections), many of the biggest barriers to innovation are cultural, political, or regulatory.  We will work to develop a sustainable business model that uses open source technology to empower local entrepreneurs while complying with relevant regulations and standards - bringing better access to diagnostics to some of the most underserved regions of the world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">103022.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">4120907.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Bath</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029064_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT029064%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
