<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004068_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pas en Avant: Community Integration through Dance-Based Pedagogy in the Lake Chad Region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">How can teaching and learning be delivered in communities where schools have been destroyed by war? This is precisely the problem in the case of the Lake Chad conflict, affecting millions of children and women in particular, across various countries (including Niger, Nigeria, Cameroon and Chad). Not only is the degradation and regression of Lake Chad generating economic, social and political instability in and between these countries; furthermore, insecurity has been aggravated by the emergence of terrorist militancy in the region. Children in the Lake Chad region have been deprived of their right to education in order to be used as forced labour, as soldiers, or as sex slaves. It is not only formal education that will provide a solution for the local refugee population, particularly since there is no secondary school in the single UNCHR camp found in the lake region of Chad. Non-formal education can be implemented bottom-up, so that communities can enjoy their human right to social and cultural education, through autochthonous forms of knowledge production and sharing. The proposed training and evaluation to be conducted in the chosen beneficiary communities will ensure long-term continuity of NSN&apos;s work. Implementation of dance-based pedagogy in the region will greatly support community building and social stabilisation. This project will be delivered by an expert international team of social artists and community workers based in Chad, with support from network members in the UK and in neighbouring Nigeria.   Because our leading partner and friend Taigue Ahmed has family in the lake Chad, we have been granted access by the Ministry of Interior to this currently militarised zone. During meetings held in N&apos;Djamena in May, we consulted UNCHR Chad (Nde Ndifonka) on the issue of logistics, facilitation and security. We have been assured that since the 2016 visit by the High Commissioner to Baga Sola, the UNCHR camp is completely safe for international media and researchers, and that very effective security measures will be in place for us.   In order to inform the preparation of this bid, we held a weeklong exchange with refugees from Maro and Belom camps (located in the border with the Central African Republic). This event was held as part of the previous AHRC network that feeds this proposal. This preliminary meeting has illuminated us on, and given us a sobering insight into, the extraordinary power of dance to transform lives in the region. Twenty-five refugees made an eighteen-hour bus journey in the scorching heat (up to 47 C), to be part of a weeklong series of dance workshops led by Ahmed and his team of social artists. When asked why make such extraordinary effort, the refugees replied: &quot;dance gives us strength and energy as a group&quot;&apos; &quot;otherwise we are alone&quot;. One woman said that through dance, the refugee community can collectively express their message: &quot;There is hope for integration&quot;. That woman, aged twenty, was attending with her four year-old. Many participants have suffered facial and body mutilation and trauma. To see them laugh, relax, focus and learn, is significant. To conduct contact work, massage, trust exercises, attention and posturing work, reminds us of the power of dance to break barriers and achieve real impact in the physical and mental lives of people living in conflict. Crucially, this work is being transmitted to the children present,  especially given the support provided by members of Association Tchado-Stars, who apply NSN pedagogy to support homeless children.   NSN&apos;s &quot;pedagogy for life&quot; is a unique model for social and cultural learning. It achieves humane sensitisation, peace, community building, and resilience. Moreover, with support from Tchado-Stars, NSN supports the integration of young learners within formal education, given strong links with local schools in N&apos;Djamena. This project will ensure long term sustainability and replicability of NSN pedagogy in Chad and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="TD" type="CHAD"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MIDDLE AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1028</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">38658.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">380.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">16670.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The aims and objectives of this project are in line with the Official Development Assistance objective to strengthen resilience and response to protracted crises. The proposed activities follow from an AHRC network project entitled Social Choreography (PI Salazar Sutil), which initiated a dialogue between the University of Leeds and community arts organisations based in N&apos;Djamena (Republic of Chad). Further support from AHRC will enable us to continue the research priorities identified in our earlier project, as we build collaboration to strengthen capacity for challenge-led and area-specific action research. The area we are focusing on is dance and conflict, with a particular focus on the Lake Chad refugee crisis.  Our primary aim is to establish a network that can promote welfare development in communities affected by the Lake Chad crisis. To achieve this, we will support an autochthonous framework for social and cultural pedagogy, using a dance-based system known as Pas en Avant, created by social artist Taigue Ahmed, Director of Association Ndam Se Na (NSN). More specifically, this network project will:  -Host three week-long dance workshops, one in the community of Baga Sola (UNCHR camp), one in the host community of M&#xE9;t&#xE9;rin&#xE9;, and one in the lake island of Kinasserom, thus expanding NSN&apos;s coverage to the Lake Chad area;   -Host community forums in all three local communities, to encourage debate between refugees and hosts;  -Run a two-month training scheme for four new NSN trainees, involving a week-long intensive camp in N&apos;Djamena and its collaborators (Tchado-Stars, SIA Projects, Refugees on the Move), followed by practice-led sessions conducted during the community workshops;  -Organise and document a cultural end-of-project event to celebrate and showcase the work of social artists, trainees, refugees and host communities in N&apos;Djamena.  These activities will:  -Enable us to conduct an impact evaluation designed to identify how NSN pedagogy impacts refugee and host community experience (This will be the first time that the data acquired by NSN over the last ten years is collated, evaluated and made available to researchers and stakeholders);   -Help identify successful and transferable pedagogical interventions with a view to facilitating the sharing and adoption of good practice by similar organisations;  -Enable comparisons across other dance-based pedagogies such as Refugees on the Move (Congo) and SAI Projects (Nigeria), in order to establish the relative merits of alternative approaches;  This workflow will ultimately lead to:  -Publication of a high-impact journal article that will make PeA available and accessible as a novel dance methodology in refugee camps for researchers and practitioners working in and with Africa;   -Publication of project report, feeding back to strategy and decision makers at UNCHR about where to focus activity and resources for enhancing non-formal education in IDP camps."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">38658.94</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">75.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">75.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">75.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">152.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">16670.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
