<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007877_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the name of the father: Otino Onywalo Ilum - docu-dance theatre and children born of war</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the Name of the Father develops and extends the artistic, cultural, societal and wellbeing impact activities of the AHRC network &quot;Children Born of War - Past, Present and Future&quot; (2011-14). This network brought together researchers and practitioners exploring the life courses of children born of war (CBOW) with particular emphasis on children fathered during and after World War II and children fathered during the LRA War in Northern Uganda since the mid 1980s. This research was designed to respond to a need, frequently-expressed by NGOs, policy-makers and CBOWs themselves, for an enhanced understanding of the challenges of CBOW; we followed an inclusive participatory approach that involved the study population alongside a range of partners, including NGOs, charities and policy-makers.  The key insights, including the enhanced understanding of the challenges faced by CBOW in different contexts, and the related insights into best approaches to improving their wellbeing and quality of life have inspired innovative, unexpected impact activities. These are based on the additional research outcome, namely that empowerment and capacity-building driven by an inclusive cross-sectoral research and impact design are key to optimising individual and societal outcomes. As a result, some of the initial network members, through sustained engagement with CBOW and an intensive academic-artistic partnership with a choreographer, Darrel Toulon, and his production company, the alpha group, are developing a programme of policy-relevant performance-oriented projects of empowerment for and with the CBOW.  Engaging with three specific groups of CBOW in Norway, Bosnia and Uganda, the project aims at capacity-building and empowerment through: - transgenerational and international dialogue - exploring creative alternative avenues of awareness raising - amplifying the effectiveness of advocacy of CBOW through confidence building for engagement with media, policy-makers, service providers and politicians - building strength through awareness of historical and political contextualisation of the CBOW experiences - building capacity for CBOW to determine the direction of further engagement through networking opportunities and through supported, yet independent engagement with stakeholders.  This impact will be achieved through the development of a multi-chapter docu-dance theatre: In the Name of the Father, an academic-artistic endeavour led by the University of Birmingham and the alpha group (https://www.the-alpha-group.org/) linking CBOW from World War II and Bosnian children conceived of conflict-related rape in former Yugoslavia with children of abducted and forcibly enslaved women in Northern Uganda, through the creation of the Ugandan chapter of a dance performance based on testimony collected in a four-week workshop with CBOW in Aboke, Lango, Uganda.  The project is divided into three interlinked strands: 1) artistic-creative - historically and culturally contextualised narratives of CBOW form the basis of a theatre-dance production that, supported by professional actors, will be performed by the CBOW themselves. 2) transnational-transgenerational - through Skype-facilitated workshop sessions, CBOW of the three wars (former Yugoslavia, World War II and Uganda will work together in the artistic-creative activities and in developing advocacy activities in Acholi and Lango. 3) social-inclusion - inspired by the life-story narrative approach that forms the basis not only for the docu-dance theatre, through inclusion of cultural and faith leaders, the aim is to engage local communities, schools and cultural and faith groups  public with the subject of the performance: fully inclusive post-conflict reconciliation and reconstruction.  The launch of the project is extremely timely as UN Security Council Resolution 2467 (2019) has recently highlighted the need to support social, economic and emotional wellbeing of CBOW globally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-12-16"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="UG" type="UGANDA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">87887.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="In the Name of the Father is comprised of a series of impact and engagement activities which together work towards the following objectives:  1. To exploit fully the unanticipated pathways to impact emerging from the AHRC-funded network Children Born of War - Past and Present that developed as a result of later unplanned engagement with third-sector partners.  2. To respond to a need expressed by non-academic partners for increased collaboration and exchange between research and different forms of artistic practice on the use of public engagement and advocacy.  3. To respond to a need expressed by non-academic partners for increased academic input into artistic practice to support the translation of academic findings into art, policy and the interactions between the two.  4. To bring to Birmingham the collaborative docu-dance theatre In the Name of the Father and disseminate the innovative method showcased in the production by performing the multi-chapter performance at the UoB Green Heart Festival (Spring Season: theme Hope) and, concurrently, alongside activities to mark the commemorations around the 25th anniversary of the Srebrenica massacre.  5. To pilot the methodologies initiated in an intersectoral international workshop Exploring the Borderlands (between academic and artistic practice) bringing together academics, performance artists, choreographers, film producers, and children born of war through a writing/rehearsal workshop in Uganda leading to a chapter in the production of In the Name of the Father.  6. To increase public knowledge and understanding of the challenges of children born of war in post-conflict societies, particularly in societal contexts where this topic remains a taboo. This will be achieved through active engagement with cultural and religious leaders in Uganda to reach as wide an in-country audience as possible, and by including the film and photo capture of the Ugandan chapter into the broader transnational docu-dance (https://www.the-alpha-group.org/current-production/).  7. To promote intergenerational and transnational exchange on the topic of children born of war through post-performance panel discussions and an intersectoral workshop.  8. To foster the academic-artistic development of all participants with focus on capacity building among Ugandan children born of war and a local research assistant with the aim of creating in-country capacity for regional and national follow-on performances.  9. To contribute to the University of Birmingham Green Heart Festival&apos;s core aim to showcase innovative and impactful research to a broad audience."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">87887.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007877_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
