<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_P014186_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Digital threads: Towards personalised craft production in Malay cottage industries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Digital Threads project addresses the challenge of poverty for rural Malay women and its risk for the cultural heritage of traditional weaving practices. Cottage industries across the entire region of South Asia are considered beneficial both for economic growth and as accessible means to alleviate rural poverty. The Malay Government has invested significantly over recent decades to revitalise weaving practices such as songket textiles. However, there has been limited success since these initiatives have adopted a traditional product-centric business model and made limited use of digital technologies.  In this project we will engage in ground-breaking interdisciplinary research to promote sustainable economic development and welfare in Malaysia by radically changing the business models of cottage industries. The project will explore more sustainable and innovative business models flexible to integrate cutting-edge technologies that place customers at the centre of personalised production. We propose the design of digital applications which could be built upon distributed ledger technology for the management of the demand chain. These in turn will be able to support the hand-making of unique individual artefacts rather than mass-production commodities.  The Digital Threads project has the potential for significant economic and social contributions. We draw expertise from HCI, computer science, and information management to deliver:  (i) new knowledge about the cottage industries and their decentralised handmade modes of production; (ii) innovative customer-centric business models for the management of the demand chain; and  (iii) novel designs of digital technologies for shaping these business models through fresh approaches to designing for provenance. Such approaches will enable the transparency of the hand-making process, the maker&apos;s experience, and the value of cultural heritage embedded in it.   These outcomes have the potential to bring the Malay cottage industries into the 21st century and its worldwide Digital Economy whilst honouring and leveraging their cultural heritage. They will also leverage the less explored potential of blockchain technologies for social impact and for addressing the global challenge of poverty.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Research Vision: Towards economic development and welfare of rural Malaysia  This project will drive original interdisciplinary work which will seek to radically change the business models of Malay cottage industries in particular and those for entrepreneurship for the world&apos;s poorest people in general. It will lay the foundation for the development of more sustainable and innovative business models to be coupled with cutting-edge technologies in order to place customers at the centre of the production process and support distributed personalised production.  &quot;Every product has a story. A journey of people, places and raw materials. This story of design and making is often missing when we buy a product. The story of ownership is often unknown when we inherit one. This talk looks at how we might start to embed physical objects with meaning by joining them with their digital story&quot; Jessi Baker, CEO of Provenance, ThingsCon, Berlin 2014.  We propose the design of digital tools which could be built upon distributed ledger technology to support the management of the demand chain. This will leverage the strength of cottage industries of creating unique individual artefacts rather than mass-production commodities, with the added-value of: (i) personalising the products to be co-designed by their maker and prospective buyer; (ii) capturing and delivering digital stories which will make transparent the cultural heritage of the making practice, while (iii) ensuring makers&apos; online presence and relationship with their potential customers, without the need of a distributer middlemen.  The aim is to support economic development and welfare of women weavers in rural Malaysia through an innovative approach to the demand chain management which could be integrated with mobile and blockchain technologies, while preserving the endangered cultural heritage of their weaving crafts, i.e. songket textiles and baskets.   In order to achieve this aim we will focus on the following objectives:  (i) To explore the practices of weaving along the supply and demand chains to understand their challenges and opportunities for innovation;  (ii) To identify the required changes to these practices, that the integration of distributed ledger technology with demand change management requires;   (iii) To design user-centred platform and applications compliant with the blockchain technologies for meeting these requirements;  (iv) To evaluate our prototypes and business models with rural women weavers.  (v) To develop long-term relationship between the UK and Malaysian partners through networking and dissemination which will strengthen future collaborative research of high international standard.  (vi) To position project partners as international leaders in integrating innovative digital technologies and business model for economic development and welfare in developing context</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-03">17069.29</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-03">68415.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-03">35244.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
