<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_P013821_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diet, physical activity and cardiometabolic health in Malaysian adolescents: from epidemiology to intervention</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Malaysia the prevalence of obesity among adolescents is increasing and non-communicable diseases, like type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease, account for two out of three deaths. While research in European and US-based populations has found that particular lifestyle factors might cause adolescents to be fatter and less fit we do not have a complete picture of what causes these problems in Malaysia. In this study we are going to look at how different lifestyle factors, like foods eaten, timing or frequency of eating, physical activity, sedentary behaviours and their timing or location, combine together to create an overall behavioural pattern score that indicates whether adolescents have good health.  We&apos;ve previously found that a combination of factors is more important for health compared with single factors alone. Initial analysis of health outcomes will focus on obesity, blood pressure, and how much LDL cholesterol, fats and glucose are in blood samples. We also plan to use a new, reproducible laboratory technique, known as metabolomics, to measure 233 different components of blood that indicate a range of metabolic processes. This will help us find out in much more detail than ever before how behaviour leads to better cardiovascular health via metabolic pathways. When we know more about the pathway that leads from lifestyle to disease we will be better able to predict who will stay healthy and who will not. In this study, one of our aims is to find the main behaviours related to keeping a healthy metabolism and reducing the risk of cardiovascular disease in the future. We&apos;ll then work out how these behaviours can changed by an intervention. This research is possible because of a large study of over 1361 adolescents, called MyHeARTs. The aim of MyHeARTs was to identify which factors best predict health to enable the early detection and prevention of type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease. MyHeARTs started in 2012, collecting information on the behaviour and health of 1361 adolescents from 15 urban and rural schools in 3 regions of Malaysia and has just completed a third follow-up in 2016. The participants have provided detailed reports of their diet, activity, and other health behaviours as well as measurements of body composition, physical fitness and blood samples at age 13, 15 and 17, which we will use for this study. We are interested to see whether combinations of lifestyle behaviours can accurately predict changes in the blood chemical profile of participants as they progress through adolescence before they develop clear symptoms of cardiovascular disease or diabetes. Finally, within this project we lay the foundations for improving adolescents&apos; metabolic health. We will talk to adolescents and school staff about how they could adopt the behaviours we found were important for health in MyHeART. We will then use their views paired with known methods of behaviour change to encourage a healthy lifestyle and prevent disease that will work in countries, like Malaysia, where resources are limited.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of the project is to identify behavioural intervention targets to develop and pilot a school-based strategy to improve cardiometabolic health in Malaysian adolescents. The Malaysian Health and Adolescents longitudinal Research Team study (MyHeARTs) is a prospective cohort of 1361 Malaysian schoolchildren followed from age 13-17yrs. We aim to combine state of the art epidemiology with rigorous intervention development, based on the MRC framework, to achieve 5 interlinked research objectives: 1. Identify behavioural patterns and examine their associations with clinical cardiometabolic risk factors 2. Systematic reviews of observational and trial evidence for the behavioural prevention of cardiometabolic disease in Malaysian adolescents 3. Generate data in-depth metabolite profiles from stored MyHeARTs serum samples and examine associations with behavioural patterns and clinical cardiometabolic risk factors 4. Design a behaviour change intervention based on high-risk behaviours (from 1 &amp; 2) and formative work with Malaysian students &amp; staff 5. Pilot test and evaluate a behaviour change programme in Malaysian adolescents We will characterise behavioural patterns using a data-driven technique called reduced rank regression (RRR), which has been applied in nutrition to identify combinations of foods, (dietary patterns) that explain variation in specific intermediate variables on the hypothesised pathway from diet to disease. For example, we have previously shown that a combination of foods explaining overall dietary energy density, fat and fibre intakes is robustly associated with the development of obesity in the Avon Longitudinal Study of Parents and Children. We propose to apply RRR to diets in Malaysia and expand its application to broader behavioural patterns. For example, to find a pattern of types of physical activity explaining overall physical activity level and cardiorespiratory fitness simultaneously. Patterns will be prospectively associated with obesity, fasting blood glucose, LDL cholesterol, triglycerides and blood pressure using MyHeARTs. Combining epidemiological and systematic review results, the most promising physical activity and dietary behaviours will be taken forward as targets for intervention development. Metabolomics is the comprehensive assessment of metabolites in human tissue and emerging evidence suggests specific metabolites can indicate future risk of disease, before the onset of clinical symptoms. We will retrieve stored serum samples collected in MyHeARTs at age 15 and 17 years and analyse them using an automated high-throughput serum nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) metabolomics platform. This end-to-end platform provides quantitative molecular information for 233 metabolites, including the lipid concentrations and composition of 14 lipoprotein subclasses, various fatty acids, a-1 acid glycoprotein, amino acids, glycolysis related measures and ketone bodies. This will enable a deeper understanding of the impact of behavioural patterns on cardiometabolic health and strengthen the evidence for potential targets of interventions. Using the MRC framework for the development and evaluation of complex interventions we will develop a feasible strategy applicable to Malaysian adolescents. We will conduct qualitative research with key stakeholders, including adolescents and school staff, to explore acceptable approaches to adopting the behaviours. We will use intervention mapping and the views of stakeholders to find effective behaviour change techniques. A pilot evaluation of the intervention, with pre- and post-measures of diet, physical activity and cardiometabolic risk, as well as process evaluation, will be conducted. The findings of the proposed research will provide novel insights into the mechanisms linking behaviour to cardiometabolic disease and also create an intervention ready for a phase III trial that could promote cardiometabolic health among Malaysian adolescents</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-07">29092.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-07">116606.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-07">29328.42</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
