<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Can dual apprenticeships create better and more equitable social and economic outcomes for young people? A comparative study of India and Mexico</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this proposal is to support more effective implementation of dual apprenticeship in India and Mexico and to strengthen the capacity of project partners to evaluate their apprenticeships in the medium to long term. Dual apprenticeships combine a strong component of school-based education with highly regulated work-based training in integrated learning plans leading to a formal qualification and have proven successful in Germanic countries. They are being introduced by the federal governments of India and Mexico to raise the quality of current provision of skills, to improve the labour market conditions for young people, and to increase the productivity levels of the workforce. However, policy transfer across different political, economic and social contexts raise important academic, policy and practice questions: Why and how dual apprenticeships are adopted and re-contextualized by national governments? And, how and under what contextual and institutional circumstances do dual apprenticeships create better and more equitable social and economic outcomes for young people?  To answer these questions, our study develops a comprehensive research approach that scrutinizes the different, but mutually constitutive stages of policy transfer, from the adoption and re-contextualization of dual apprenticeships in national programmes to their implementation and impact on social inequalities in multiple local contexts. A robust comparative and multi-level methodological strategy that combines quantitative and qualitative methods will contribute to advancing such an innovative approach. First, we will synthesise international evidence on the adoption, implementation and impact of dual apprenticeships in low and middle income countries through a realist literature review. Second, we will analyse the drivers of the adoption and re-contextualization of dual apprenticeships in India and Mexico through the analysis of policy documents and in-depth interviews with key policy stakeholders. Third, we will evaluate the implementation and impact of dual apprenticeships on inequalities of access, learning and labour market outcomes among young people through a mixed methods realist evaluation that will combine a national survey of apprentices in India and Mexico with in-depth interviews to apprentices, teachers/trainers and employers. Finally, we will provide evidence-based policy recommendations to inform current design and implementation of dual apprenticeships at the same time that will strengthen the capacity of project partners to evaluate their apprenticeships through innovative methodologies. The two middle income countries selected for the comparison, India and Mexico, face important educational and socioeconomic developmental challenges that justify the interest in the impact of their dual apprenticeship programmes. India and Mexico present high percentage of young people out of school in upper secondary education (48%, 42%), high occurrence of informal employment (92%, 60%) and large inequalities of income as measured by the GINI index (35, 48). From a policy transfer perspective, they present similarities and differences in the adoption of dual apprenticeships that make the comparison particularly interesting. Both countries share the strong national ownership of the reform and its wide systemic scope, which has already led to significant legislative changes in both countries.  On the other hand, while the adoption of dual apprenticeships in India represents an upgrade of its current model of apprenticeships, in the case of Mexico it implies the creation of the first apprenticeship experience in a country where the whole TVET provision was delivered in schools. Given the different TVET traditions and political economies in these two federal countries, it is expected that the factors driving and mediating the adoption, implementation and impact of their dual apprenticeship programmes will differ between them and at local level.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">79685.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">319387.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">321974.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The policy transfer of dual apprenticeships in India and Mexico raises two main general research questions for this study. First, why and how dual apprenticeships are adopted and re-contextualized by national governments? Second, how and under what contextual and institutional circumstances do dual apprenticeships create better and more equitable social and economic outcomes for young people? The aim of this study is to support more effective implementation of dual apprenticeship in India and Mexico and to strengthen the capacity of project partners to evaluate their apprenticeships in the medium to long term. This general aim is sub-divided into four specific research objectives:  1. Synthesise international evidence on how dual apprenticeships have been adopted, implemented and how they have impacted inequalities of access, learning and labour market outcomes in low and middle income countries.  To synthesise this international evidence, a realist literature review on dual apprenticeships in low and middle income countries will be conducted. We will extract information from existing studies in relation to the factors driving the adoption of dual apprenticeships in low and middle income countries, the &apos;theory of change&apos; behind these interventions and the context-mechanisms-outcomes configurations that explain the successes and failures of dual apprenticeships in low and middle income countries.  2. Analyse the material and ideational drivers of the adoption and re-contextualization of dual apprenticeships into different regulatory frameworks and policy interventions at national and local level in India and Mexico.  The analysis of the policy adoption of dual apprenticeships in India and Mexico will entail a stakeholder analysis that corresponds with interviews to key informants (e.g. German cooperation agencies, ministries of education, chambers of commerce, state governments, civil society) and document analysis (archives work, legal texts, policy reports, media news). We will investigate how different material conditions and discourses define the social problems that dual apprenticeships should tackle, the processes that led to their selection as feasible and adequate policy solutions to these problems, and the governance technologies put in place to implement these programmes.    3. Investigate the way apprentices, employers and trainers interpret and enact dual apprenticeship programmes within concrete training and learning practices, and elucidate the mechanisms that explain the different impact of dual apprenticeships on inequalities of access, learning and labour market outcomes among young people in different local contexts.   The analysis of policy enactment and impact will combine data from an apprentices&apos; survey and from in-depth interviews with apprentices, employers and trainers. We will elucidate how these actors interpret and react to the introduction of dual apprenticeships, how social inequalities affect their capability to benefit from these learning opportunities and the mechanisms that explain the different impact of the programmes on diverse populations and contexts.  4. Provide evidence-based policy recommendations to inform current implementation of apprenticeships in India and Mexico and strengthen the capacity of project partners to evaluate their apprenticeship programmes through innovative methodologies.  The project will involve research users in the evaluation process by co-constructing the goals, the scope and the methods of the evaluation. We have designed training activities to develop the capacity of early career researchers to evaluate apprenticeship programmes and knowledge exchange events in Delhi and Mexico City to disseminate our findings among policy stakeholders and wider audiences."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">79685.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">79685.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">79685.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">79685.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">80331.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">80331.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">80331.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">80331.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S004297_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
