<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_V003046_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Cascading Climate Risks Assessment Network (ACCRAN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">How can a drought in Russia cause social unrest and protests in Zambia? Or an emergent virus in China cause the collapse of the tourism industry in Kenya? These and many other situations are the result of systemic risks, where a crisis in one sector sets off a chain reaction of crises that &apos;cascade&apos; into other sectors and/or distant locations. Cascading risks are the result of the interconnectedness of systems, such as climate, agriculture, public health, economics, migration, and more. Ongoing stresses and shocks from climate change increase the frequency of cascading risks and highlight the urgency of developing ways to understand and respond to unexpected crises. 
 
Kenya is particularly vulnerable to cascading climate risks. More than half the population depends on climate and ecosystem services for their livelihoods through smallholder agriculture. Many more also live below the poverty line with limited access to safety nets like insurance or affordable health care. Kenya also serves as a regional hub for trade and transport, and is highly dependent on foreign direct investment and overseas development assistance. Despite the vulnerabilities of Kenyan society to climate-driven external cascading risk, there is practically no experience in Kenya, or in most countries in fact, to predict cascading risks.
 
Methods for forecasting cascading risks are poorly developed and have not been adapted to specific decisions that policy makers and development partners face. ACCRAN will form a multi-stakeholder network of scientists, policy makers, development practitioners, and humanitarian aid agencies to develop new approaches to predicting cascading climate risks. The network will also aim to increase the capacity of policy makers and organizations operating in Kenya to address cascading risks from climate change and other triggers. Together,the network will map how sectors are interconnected and how risks spread, analyse how decisions and policies on risk mitigation are made, and survey and test available methods for understanding and monitoring cascading risks. The network will apply these approaches to a case study from Kenya to evaluate and compare the performance of various methodological approaches. Through the project we will adopt a &quot;human-centered design&quot; approach, where the people who will use the research outputs (e.g. policy makers and development partners) are involved in all stages of the research from discovery, to ideation, to developing prototype guidelines. By involving these end-users in the research process, we can accelerate the impact from research by being sure it addresses stakeholder needs from the very beginning. 
 
Through a series of participatory workshops and analyses, ACCRAN will develop a set of outputs that lay the foundation for changing how cascading risks from climate change are predicted and how countries can respond. This begins with developing a deep understanding of the context and constraints that policy makers and program developers face when making decisions, such as the types of information needed, when they need it, and the obstacles they face in cross sectoral planning. ACCRAN will use this knowledge to develop decision-appropriate methods using transdisciplinary approaches that draw on computer science, econometrics, integrated assessment models, climate science, and scenario planning amongst other techniques. We will specifically evaluate each methods&apos; performance when applied to the real world case of decisions in Kenya. ACCRAN&apos;s network generates new connections and information to integrate, iterate and improve science-policy-practice risk assessment so it becomes practical for use in decision making in lower-income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The African Cascading Climate Risk Assessment Network project has three key objectives:
 
1) Build a network of researchers, policy makers and development and humanitarian aid practitioners from diverse sectors to increase our understanding and cross-institutional capacities for preparation and response to cascading risks in Kenya.
 
2) Develop methods for the analysis of cascading climate risks and risk transmission by drawing from diverse disciplines such as climate science, computer science, sociology, public health, economics, and business analytics. Such methods could include, but are not limited to, Integrated Assessment Methods, Bayesian Networks, Complex Systems, and participatory scenario building. 
 
3) Create a set of guidelines for national/regional analyses of cascading climate risks appropriate for decision and data context in Sub-Saharan Africa,working with stakeholders across policy, humanitarian, and scientific domains to evaluate and implement these guidelines to a case study for Kenya. 
 
Scaling out lessons learned from these three objectives to other countries and contexts in sub-Saharan Africa will form the basis of a larger collaborative research proposal for Nexus Phase II.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">193534.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to World Agroforestry Centre</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/V003046/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Agroforestry Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FV003046%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
