<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006175_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Peace babies&apos; - the unintended consequences of United Nations peacekeeping (HN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As of March 2016, a total of 104,773 uniformed personnel from 123 countries were serving in 16 peacekeeping operations around the world. Where foreign soldiers - during war, occupation or peacekeeping operations - are on foreign soil, military-civilian relations develop, including those between soldiers and local women. Peacekeepers have increasingly been associated with sexual exploitation and abuse of the vulnerable populations they had been mandated to protect. Many of the intimate relations between peacekeeping personnel and local women, of both voluntary and exploitative nature, have led to pregnancies and to children being born. These so-called &apos;peace babies&apos; and their mothers face particular challenges in volatile post-conflict communities, reportedly including childhood adversities as well as stigmatization, discrimination and disproportionate economic and social hardships. The network connects two strands of inquiry around &apos;peace babies&apos; - from the academic world and from within the development sector - in a spirit of conversation and collaboration, to examine challenges of humanitarian intervention in a transnational historical context. Building on the firm belief that history&apos;s focus on causality and long-term processes of change is indispensable for appreciating the complex dynamics of socio-cultural change, the network contributes a deeper understanding of development and aims to affect practice. It provides an historical complement to the wealth of available analyses - internal and external - of the contemporary humanitarian environment.  Specifically, the network proposes an in-depth-study of the situation of &apos;peace babies&apos; by exploring the children conceived by personnel from or associated with the United Nations Stabilization Mission in Haiti (MINUSTAH). MINUSTAH is among the missions that have been associated with allegations of a range of abuses, not least related to sexual and gender-based violence and consequently the unintended legacy of children fathered by UN personnel. The UN has recently acknowledged that &apos;peacekeeper babies&apos; exist. Yet, an evidence base relating to the welfare of children fathered by UN peacekeepers (globally or in Haiti) is virtually non-existent, and it is clear that the existing UN policies and support programs are inadequate. This multidisciplinary collaboration between scholars from Queen&apos;s University, the University of Birmingham, the Centre of International and Defence Policy, and Haitian-based Enstiti Travay Sosyal ak Syans Sosyal (ETS), along with civil society organisations, the Institute for Justice and Democracy in Haiti and Haitian-based Bureau des Avocats Internationaux, will address this knowledge gap and enhance our historically-informed understanding of the challenges faced by peace babies and their families as well as the obstacles to accessing support. Beyond the core UK-Canada-Haiti partnership, the network will include a further four ODA-recipient countries (Cambodia, Bosnia, Liberia and the DRC) and will apply insights from Haiti to PSOs more generally in discourse with academic and non-academic participants from those countries with extensive PSO experience. The network is structured around three network meetings (two workshops and a network conference, the latter supplemented by an early-career research workshop) which will create a sustainable partnership that focuses on co-creation of knowledge as well as a collaborative mobilisation of this knowledge to inform academic and non-academic stakeholders interested in peacekeepers&apos; children. The findings of the workshops and the final conference will inform both academic outputs and - going forward - the development of an intersectoral research agenda; furthermore they will frame a special journal edition on &apos;Peace Babies&apos; and will be at the core of the network&apos;s activities beyond the funding period, both as a platform for continued transnational and intersectoral conversation and of collaborative research</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using Haiti as a case study, this project will address fundamental questions related to the difficulties &apos;peace babies&apos; face as a result of their biological origins and resulting life circumstances, as well as the legal and administrative processes in place to support them and the challenges they and their mothers face in accessing support.  In a second step, the network will link the insights drawn from the Haitian case to engage other countries with large peace support operations (PSO) and significant numbers of &apos;peace babies&apos; (Cambodia, Liberia, Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), Bosnia-Herzegovina) The network&apos;s objectives are: 1) Engaging with current debates regarding accountability of United Nations (UN) peacekeepers, and indeed of the UN, for acts committed by their personnel while deployed in PSOs, the project will recalibrate the discourse on &apos;peace babies&apos;. While the current debates focus largely on criminal actions, particularly gender-based violence (GBV), this work will use a human rights-based approach to understand accountability. This approach allows for a focus on the children and mothers and their fundamental rights to access a court and a remedy. Our approach will apply a victim-centred lens to examine the accountability of both peacekeeping personnel and of the UN in relation to &apos;peace babies&apos;. 2) Using the case study of the United Nations Stabilization Mission in Haiti (MINUSTAH), the network will engage in dialogue about circumstances of conception in consensual, exploitative and coercive relations; discuss the geographic mapping of where cases have occurred in relation to UN peacekeeping camps; exchange knowledge about the home countries of the alleged fathers and the impact of their provenance on their children. It will further consider the life experiences of women raising children fathered by UN peacekeepers including the children&apos;s identity, perceived stigma and discrimination, local understanding of rights and justice, identified needs and barriers to accessing services. 3) Methodologically, the network will consider the suitability of a range of approaches, quantitative, qualitative and mixed methods as well as participatory and non-participatory. In particular, it will explore those approaches  in view of  i) language-neutrality and cultural sensitivity of instruments  ii) potential for and value of participatory elements for the research and   iii) potential of capacity building by engaging local researchers and exploiting cross-fertilising potential  4) Engaging Haitian and in a second step other ODA-recipient country stakeholders in advocacy planning and policy-making, this multidisciplinary collaboration between scholars from Queen&apos;s University, the University of Birmingham, the Centre of International and Defence Policy, and Haitian-based Enstiti Travay Sosyal ak Syans Sosyal (ETS), along with civil society organisations, the Institute for Justice and Democracy in Haiti and Haitian-based Bureau des Avocats Internationaux, will address four specific objectives:  i) interdisciplinary research to co-create knowledge on life courses of &apos;peace babies&apos; and their mothers in Haiti with a view of identifying determinants of outcomes in terms of social, economic, and psychological well-being,  ii) training the next generation of research leaders including research mentorship and development of professional skills;  iii) mobilization of research findings through planned engagement with academic and non-academic stakeholders including the UN, the Haitian government, non-governmental aid organizations, national militaries, human and women&apos;s rights civil society organizations and the general public iv) amplifying this impact by investigating which local insights have greater applicability through widening the network in the second part of the programme to include four additional ODA-recipient countries with different geopolitical and security environments but similar challenges of PSOs</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="HT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Haiti</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1031" percentage="100" vocabulary="CARIBBEAN, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-20">41692.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">41692.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006175_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">5977.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006175_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
