<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_M028801_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">14CONFAP Application of quantitative proteomics to accelerate vaccine development against Schistosomiasis, a neglected tropical disease.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Brazilian researcher will learn advanced protein quantitation in The Centre for Proteome Research, Liverpool. These techniques will then be applied to a specific protein extract from the disease- causing parasitic worm to quantify key target proteins, first in Liverpool and then migrated to Ouro Preto in a comparative analysis. New data will be acquired by transcript sequencing in York to extend the protein candidate list, and to extend the quantification analyses to additional proteins, as a joint venture in Liverpool and Ouro Preto.  In addition to specific training visits relating to quantitative proteomics workflows, the Liverpool group will deliver a workshop in Proteomics for Brazilian scientists, to be held in Ouro Preto. This will maximize the transfer of skills not only to Ouro Preto group, but to a wider audience in the small but growing Brazilian Proteomics community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Schistosomiasis a neglected tropical disease caused by persistent blood-dwelling parasitic worms, is the focus of this application and remains an important public health problem in Brazil. Treatment with the one available drug does not prevent reinfection so an effective vaccine would enhance control. Sequencing of the worm&apos;s transcriptome (2003) and genome (2009) has facilitated post-genomic initiatives. Brazilian science would greatly benefit from an injection of cutting-edge proteomic technologies from UK experts to better orientate the search for novel vaccine candidates. As stated above previous collaborations between the proposed partners have led to publications in high impact journals, which in turn have informed the research of vaccinologists in Brazil and worldwide. Proteomics is a young subject, expanding into a very sophisticated technology with enormous potential to illuminate many of the disease problems we face in the developed and developing world alike.  The group in Ouro Preto is also in the growth phase.  The proposed project could serve as the springboard to establish a longer-lasting collaboration with a leading group of UK researchers at the cutting edge of Proteomics. The impact that this would have on infectious tropical disease research in Brazil cannot be underestimated. The new collaboration will inject advanced proteomic techniques to underpin and consolidate the inventory of novel proteins we expect to identify and quantitate. We anticipate that the collaboration will kick-start a new round of vaccine testing. In this programme, we will apply technologies developed at Liverpool to the analysis of potential vaccine candidates. In particular, Liverpool will host scientists and trainees from Ouro Preto, giving them access the super facilities that are located there. In addition, scientists from Liverpool will visit Ouro Preto to provide advanced training and to deliver a formal training course that will be open to other Brazilian scientists.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-18">10426</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-18">31277.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-18">583855.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Small Grants Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_M028801_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FM028801%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
