<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008466_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Local Heritage and Sustainability: promote reflection and sharing within and across communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research network has been designed to create a solid, long lasting and mutually relevant partnership among five universities (Bournemouth University, University of Leicester, Universidad Federal de Rio de Janeiro, University of Malaysia Sarawak, and Universidade Lurio), one ministry office (Autoridade Reguladora das Comunica&#xE7;&#xF5;es de Mo&#xE7;ambique) and nine local organisations in three LMIC countries (Mozambique, Malaysia and Brazil) and in the United Kingdom. This network will explore how rural and urban communities can strengthen their resilience, promote their sustainability, and protect their local heritage through the use of creative and digital tools. The network will be focusing on three emblematic contexts: a rural community (Bario) in Malaysia, an historical town (Ilha de Mo&#xE7;ambique) in Mozambique, and three shantytowns (Rio de Janeiro) in Brazil. These are three very diverse settings, but they are all affected by global flows of migration and tourism, and their related challenges and opportunities. This network is scaffolded around local heritage, be it natural, cultural, or historical, as a focal point of shared concern, and how communities can leverage the creative and storytelling potential of digital media to reflect and share on past, present and future sustainable practices. Faced with increasing global mobilities, the challenges of migration and tourism flows, the communities in the network, and specifically women and girls, will benefit from shared reflection on the value of heritage and from practical support in the usage of heritage for sustainable development.  By working with the communities on three areas (sustainability, local heritage and identities) in the light of contemporary global flows, the project has been designed to tackle the following objectives:  1. to promote the reflection on heritage and sustainability, in order to co-create strategies to shape the communities&apos; future; 2. to employ digital media, in particular interactive mapping tools to be used to raise awareness among local as well as global audiences on the complex interplay between heritage and sustainability; 3. to identify similarities and peculiarities of this process in each case study, in order to promote a Global South dialogue among communities affected by similar challenges and opportunities.  The network will produce the following outputs, for the local communities ad development practitioners: 1. A multimedia archive on the process and content of each event, to be hosted on the project website 2. Three curated digital stories in the form of interactive locative maps developed with &quot;Storyplaces&quot; to be accessed via mobile 3. Three web versions of the same stories to be hosted on the project website and developed with a storymapping tool.  4. A methodological toolkit for practitioners to explore how digital and creative technologies can be used to unpack sustainability, local heritage and identities and promote reflection among rural and urban disadvantaged communities. 5. A practitioner report to document similarities and differences, challenges and successful strategies of the three case communities.  In its 12 months of activities the network will organise three events: - Networking Event #1 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (MONTH 3). Organiser: Dr. Camila Moraes, UNIRIO. - Networking Event #2 in Bario, Malaysia (MONTH 6). Organiser: Prof. Narayanan Kulathuramaiyer, UNIMAS. - Networking Event #3 in Ilha de Mo&#xE7;ambique, Mozambique (MONTH 9). Organiser: Milton Novela, UNILURIO.  Furthermore, three national dissemination events in the involved LMIC, in which the network outputs will be presented to local stakeholders and communities affected by the same opportunities and challenges and a dissemination event in the UK will be organised. The UK event will be coupled with a virtual connection with the academic partnership in LMIC and, where possible, local organisations a involved communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-14">41068.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-14">13452.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The aim of the project is to investigate how rural and urban communities can strengthen their resilience, promote their sustainability, and protect and foster their local heritage through the use of creative and digital tools. By working with the communities on three areas (sustainability, local heritage and identities) in the light of contemporary global flows, the project has been designed to tackle the following objectives:  1. to promote the reflection on heritage and sustainability, in order to co-create strategies to shape the communities&apos; future; 2. to employ digital media, in particular interactive mapping tools can be used to raise awareness among local as well as global audiences on the complex interplay between heritage and sustainability; 3. to identify similarities and peculiarities of this process in each case study, in order to promote a Global South dialogue among communities affected by similar challenges and opportunities.   These objectives will be reached by engaging in community-based participatory workshop events leveraging the creative and storytelling potential of digital media to capture culture-specific community experiences. Core network partners, local organisations, and community members will collaboratively work on the production of local stories reporting on opportunities and challenges related to the three interconnected areas of the network: local heritage, global flows, and sustainability. These stories will shape the outpus and dissemination strategy of the network."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">41068.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008466_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bournemouth University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">-27616.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008466_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bournemouth University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
