<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015066_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting the National Action Plan on AMR in Tanzania (SNAP-AMR)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) is recognised as a global threat to human and animal health, productivity and prosperity. AMR is widespread in both resource-rich nations such as the UK and in low and middle income countries (LMICs). The United Republic of Tanzania is one such LMIC, and in response to a call to action from the World Health Organisation, it has created a National Action Plan (NAP) to combat AMR.   The NAP is an ambitious plan outlining five strategic routes for tackling AMR: i) improved awareness and understanding; ii) enhanced surveillance and research; iii) better sanitation, hygiene and infection prevention; iv) optimized use of antibiotics; and v) sustainable investment in alternatives. In common with many LMICs, the challenge posed by AMR is exacerbated by widespread or unregulated use in both humans and livestock, whilst successful implementation of the NAP is threatened by lack of human and financial resources. Prioritisation of activities and targeting of interventions is therefore an essential component of an effective and efficient campaign to control AMR.  Our research will provide new evidence to support this prioritisation and targeting, taking an approach that recognises that behavioural change is a complex phenomenon depending not just on policy, regulation or knowledge provision but also on cultural background and social norms. Our team of UK and Tanzania-based researchers and policy experts will take an interdisciplinary approach to provide novel insights into the biological, social and cultural drivers influencing antibiotic use in the community and health care system; the spread of AMR between the humans and animals in the community and health care settings; knowledge about AMR; and how to change behaviours to reduce antibiotic use and the spread AMR.  We will contrast doctor prescribing practices in different health care settings (referral hospitals, district hospitals, health centres, dispensaries), as well as investigating community access and attitudes to antibiotics among householders, community &apos;drug&apos; shops and unregulated sources such as roadside traders. We will use focus groups to examine factors that influence prescribing and usage, e.g. availability of antibiotic drugs, diagnostic facilities, patient demands, medical training and knowledge, coupled with choice-based experiments to establish how best to create change in prescribing behaviour or use. We will also use choice-based experiments to examine use in livestock by individuals with different levels of knowledge about AMR, e.g. district vets, community livestock officers and livestock holders. In parallel, bacterial isolates from people or livestock in hospital and community settings will be DNA-sequenced and examined used genomic tools to establish whether resistant commensal bacteria found in faecal samples in the community are those responsible for illness (respiratory infections, diarrhoea, sepsis and urinary tract infections) in hospitalised children.  The final component will be to assess the knowledge and sources of knowledge held by the public, health care and veterinary workers, policy makers and educators; to design interlinked targeted media campaigns that reflect educational, professional and cultural differences; and to assess the uptake of these materials and their impact on attitudes and approaches to antibiotic drugs and resistance.  The outcomes of our research will help priority setting and targeting in the NAP by identifying the settings (health care system or community) where most effective change can be achieved; showing how to create change in antibiotic usage (e.g. via improved training or education, diagnostic facilities or a social-norm based &apos;nudge&apos;) and identifying the individuals to target to create the most effective change; and by designing and delivering a mass media campaign to create awareness and behavioural change that will help Tanzania to combat the threat posed to its future by AMR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="TANZANIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-02">50129.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Our aim is to provide novel insights into the biological, social and cultural drivers of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) that will support the Tanzanian (TZ) government in implementation of its National Action Plan (NAP) against AMR by prioritising the use of limited human and financial resources via targeted, evidence-based interventions. Our objectives, which will be delivered by activities across four work packages (WP), tackle key knowledge gaps in behavioural drivers of antimicrobial usage (AMU) in communities and health systems; the spread of AMR between human and animal reservoirs in communities and health systems; and in how to promote AMR awareness and create behavioural change.   Objective 1 addresses key knowledge gaps surrounding behavioural drivers of AMU to identify &quot;best bet&quot; interventions to reduce AMR spread from human and veterinary usage. To capture the multiple contexts for AMU in TZ, we will consider community use (WP1) and health systems (WP2). WP1 will investigate human usage within households, via formal providers (community &apos;drug&apos; shops) and informal providers (roadside traders), as well as veterinary usage by district veterinary officers, livestock officers and farmers. WP2 will examine prescribing practices in dispensaries, health centres, district hospitals and tertiary hospitals. Key informant interviews, focus groups and surveys will provide a rich baseline understanding of the context and constraints on AMU, that will inform the design of choice experiments to identify trade-offs individuals make when making choices about antibiotic use. The outcomes will reveal potential interventions such as better information, or a behavioural nudge (i.e. social norm effect) that influence choices to buy, take or administer antibiotics, and let us identify individuals that may be targeted to bring about the greatest change in antibiotic use.  Objective 2 addresses key knowledge gaps surrounding the clinical relevance of AMR in the community. Human and livestock bacteria exhibit high prevalence of AMR but it is not known whether they are important reservoirs for human clinical disease. Extended spectrum beta lactamases (ESBL) are resistance determinants of global concern, present in hospital- and community-derived Escherichia coli from TZ, but with little known about spread between settings. Using genome sequencing of selected isolates, WP3 will use identification of resistance genes and niche indicators, phylogenetic and diversity analyses and plasmid reconstruction to compare ESBL E. coli isolates from hospital patients with those from an extensive existing collection (&gt;70,000) of E. coli from farming communities in northern TZ to determine whether AMR flows from animals to humans in the community and subsequently into the hospital. The outcomes will provide evidence to support the appropriate context (human or veterinary) and setting (hospital or community) for &quot;best bet&quot; interventions.  Objective 3 addresses key gaps in how to promote AMR awareness and create behavioural change. Priority action 1 of the TZ-NAP is to raise awareness and understanding of AMR through effective information, education and communication. WP4 will establish a series of inter-linked public media, information or education campaigns and associated materials, underpinned by a One Health Approach, and targeting different audiences in human and animal health and agriculture with context specific messages, tone (e.g. rational or emotional) and delivery model. Prioritization of audiences and messages will initially be aligned with priorities from the NAP and refined in response to outputs from Objectives 1 and 2. The desired outcome of these campaigns is improved knowledge and awareness of AMR and its risks, and promotion of responsible use of medicines in the human and livestock sectors. This will contribute to a reduced risk of AMR, and help to avert the threat it poses to lives and livelihoods in Tanzania and other LMIC."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">50129.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015066_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">25829.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015066_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
