<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015719_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Between a rock and a wet place: exploring historical trajectories of exposure, governance and tenure to build resilience to multiple hazards in SIDS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience building requires integrated approaches to disaster risk management (DRM) to identify overlaps and leverage political support for measures that improve early warning systems, encourage adaptations and improve recovery from a range of hazardous events within the context of sustainable development. As our climate changes, accelerating such integration is paramount to improve responses to intensifying and multiple shocks and risks. The need is even more acute for Small Island Developing States, where isolation, limited land availability, a complex range of environmental hazards and limited resource base further intensify their exposure to risk. In this proposal we suggest that &apos;all hazards&apos; approaches to building resilience are needed and test the thesis that these will be more effective if placed within the particular historical and cultural contexts through which land use patterns were established in individual SIDS, in order to assess how risk is created and disaster risk management responses evolve. We test this on two islands in the Pacific and the Caribbean by focussing particularly on exposure and physical vulnerability to multiple hazards, and analysing historical factors that have shaped tenure and governance processes in order to explore how these may have contributed to increased exposure of populations and physical vulnerability to hazards as well as detrimental political and cultural responses. We are particularly interested in the interactions between differing hazards and the implicit competing pressures on resources and tenure, both on- and offshore. We are taking an &apos;all-hazards&apos; approach to this analysis, to identify strategies and investments that can relieve these pressures and encourage long-term resilience to multiple land and marine-based hazards. We refer to these measures as DRM investments with &apos;co-benefits&apos;, meaning that one action, originally intended for a particular type of hazard, can be adapted and used to produce joint, multiple and/or simultaneous benefits in terms of reducing risk. We will identify measures that have the potential to reduce risk to multiple hazards through the development of future scenarios and an approach to modelling impacts that tests the benefits (in terms of loss avoidance) of different DRM investments. The two islands selected to trial this holistic approach are exposed to a range of environmental hazards, and have colonial and imperial histories and sets of institutions to address risk with some similarities but also differences. Drawing insights across these settings will allow us to better understand the potential for applying this approach to other SIDS around the world, including in the Indian Ocean.  This research will also have implications for implementation of the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction 2015-2030 (SFDRR), linking it more closely with resilience targets in the Sustainable Development Goals and the Paris Climate Change Agreement by enhancing knowledge of the links between past and future hazard exposure and development, and identifying options for overcoming resource constraints in SIDS and building resilience to multiple shocks and stresses.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research has 4 key objectives: 1. Build understanding of integrated disaster risk management by taking an &apos;all hazards&apos; approach to the assessment of risk in Small Island Developing States (SIDS). Historical analysis of hazards, impacts of disaster, tenure patterns, governance and disaster risk management (DRM) in two countries will be conducted to: (a) assess direct, indirect, interacting and cascading impacts from &apos;reef to ridge&apos;; (b) understand current DRM approaches (to different hazards) and how these have been affected by historical governance processes;  (c) incorporate historical and DRM information into modelling of future disaster impacts and scenarios; and, (d)  facilitate the development of strategies that can provide &apos;co-benefits&apos; in terms of reducing risk to multiple hazards faced by SIDS.  2. Assess the underlying historical factors and cultural influences driving exposure and physical vulnerability to hazards. To better explain and understand land use patterns, access issues and building practices in relation to hazardous processes, and how these are governed and managed, by investigating the influence of historical experiences drawing on the available written record - both short term and longer term. The research takes a novel and interdisciplinary approach to risk assessment, to understand more fully how these experiences shape the contemporary political and governance landscapes of SIDS, vulnerability to hazards, DRM strategies and resilience to sudden and sustained shocks and stresses.  3. Identify DRM investments that offer co-benefits for reducing exposure and physical vulnerability to multiple hazards, including protective infrastructure measures, building techniques, land and coastal planning, improved networks and road access for evacuations. These measures will be assessed under different scenarios based on the historical analysis of disaster impacts, governance, tenure and previous DRM investments, as well as modelling of future disaster impacts. Initial results will be discussed with planners and emergency managers. 4. Integrate novel findings from (1), (2) and (3) to draw conclusions on how to build resilience to multiple hazards in vulnerable SIDS. By bringing together a holistic &apos;all hazards&apos; assessment, with a deeper understanding of disaster impacts and historical trajectories that influence exposure and physical vulnerability, the project will identify DRM investments with multiple benefits and pathways for supporting more effective DRM. Through engagement across disciplines and with local and regional stakeholders, this work will inform a research agenda that can be rolled out to other SIDS- enabling comparisons between regions with different colonial and/or imperial histories and forging potential collaborative policies.   This research will realise changes with policy impacts, ensuring the dissemination of our most relevant results in the countries specific to this proposal, and addressing the Call&apos;s aims for foundational activities and building new communities of practice in the UK and overseas. This work will have implications for the lives of those most exposed to environmental risks in the settings where we will work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overseas Development Institute ODI</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-02" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-25">107185.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-25">53592.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-25">160778.334</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to Overseas Development Institute ODI</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015719_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overseas Development Institute ODI</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FP015719%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
