<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T006293_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harvesting the sun twice: Enhancing livelihoods in East African agricultural communities through innovations in solar energy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Access to energy is a widespread problem across East Africa, where 73% of the population still do not have reliable electricity. Proving secure and affordable energy infrastructure is crucial to promoting inclusive development of rural communities in this region, and solar power is a sustainable way of achieving this. However, ground mounted arrays of solar panels also remove land from food production at a time when crop yields are threatened by a changing climate and increasing populations, insecure ownership and land &quot;grabbing&quot; are putting pressure on land resources. In practice, economic growth linked to conventional solar arrays may be outweighed by reduced income from crop production and greater food insecurity. Renewable energy technologies which resolve energy, climate and land security conflicts are urgently needed. So called agrivoltiac (AV) systems permit the delivery of solar electricity, crop production, and rainwater harvesting on the same land area. Instead of being ground mounted, arrays are several meters high, enabling crops to be grown underneath. In locations with high light intensity, high temperature, and low rainfall, such as many places in East Africa, the productivity of crops grown beneath these elevated solar arrays can be significantly improved because shade from the panels creates a more favourable growing environment with reduced heat stress and water loss. This more favourable environment for plants means the range of crops can be extended to higher-value ones, which can improve farmer incomes in disadvantaged rural communities. Crops may also be grown in locations previously unsuitable, further increasing food supplies and revenue sources. Working with African solar developers and a Kenyan agribusiness company, as well as non-governmental organisations, regional political organisations and local communities, we have identified case study sites in Kenya and Uganda where solar arrays are being installed and our interdisciplinary research can be conducted. The project aims to provide a real test case for the application and adaptation of AV systems to the needs of communities in Eastern Africa by: a) Identifying areas in Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania that are most physically suitable (e.g. climate, existing land use, lack of energy access) for realising the benefits of AV systems and their uptake by communities. b) Field testing of AV systems in communities in Kenya &amp; Uganda to provide data on resulting livelihood enhancement (increasing crop yield and farmer income, access to sustainable energy) as well as perceptions and attitudes of rural communities to AV systems. c) Using the data collected to develop a decision support tool for regional and national governments and NGOs to deliver AV systems effectively and in line with community needs. The findings from this project will reveal the potential this technology to lead to livelihood improved access to energy and increased incomes through production of higher-value crops, as well as the barriers within local communities to the uptake of AV systems. It will also show which economic, social, cultural and political factors help or hinder the expansion of AV systems in this region. We will assess how AV technology can best be co-designed with the users and seek input from national and regional policymakers to inform the potential rollout of AV systems across East Africa and potentially beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-30">304070.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-30">394727.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-30">394727.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-30">197363.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Energy access and security challenges are widespread across East Africa, where 73% of the population lack reliable and affordable supplies of energy. Improved energy infrastructure is crucial to promoting inclusive development and making progress towards the UN Sustainable Development Goals in this region.   The overarching aim of this project aims to significantly improve livelihood opportunities associated with increased access to renewable energy in East Africa, through an interdisciplinary programme of shared knowledge which addresses the intersections between sustainable technology, land and other natural resources, and agricultural development in rural communities.  We will achieve this by:  - Evaluating renewable energy land-use governance challenges  - Co-designing, testing and optimising innovative energy systems - Providing participatory technology assessment tools and datasets to facilitate just and efficient energy planning outcomes - Mapping socio-techno-economic and policy scenarios for technology up-scaling and deployment This collective research activity centres upon the assessment and implementation of agrivoltaic (AV) technologies - innovative socio-technical systems that combine solar energy, food production, and improved ecosystem services simultaneously within the same land footprint. Despite improving rural electricity access, the land footprint of renewables (particularly solar voltaics) can exacerbate socio-environmental conflicts over alternative land uses (primarily food production, biodiversity conservation or other ecosystem services). Integrated land-use systems which deliver sustainable energy, food production, livelihood and biodiversity goals simultaneously are urgently needed and it is this energy governance priority this project addresses. We have three key objectives: 1. Generate empirical evidence of the potential benefits of AV systems by assessing: land use governance for renewables deployment; the livelihood enhancement and economic development achievable by developing innovative integrated energy and food systems; assess perceptions and attitudes of rural communities towards these AV systems to facilitate their just development. Through an equitable partnership with local agencies, we will collect and analyse multiple sources of political and socio-techno-economic field data across three East African states in order to: assess land-use governance; optimise outputs from AV systems; model the potential for the expansion of AV on a regional scale. 2. Identify areas that have the highest potential for implementation of AV, based on social, physical, economic, and political dimensions and create an evidence-based decision-support framework to inform and facilitate inclusive and just AV expansion across East Africa. This will inform regional and national policy makers, the energy industry, and community leaders on where the greatest benefits from AV development will be achieved across East Africa. 3. Develop and evaluate capacity building approaches to facilitate the just expansion of co-designed AV innovations. Our multidisciplinary and cross-sectoral team has expertise spanning the energy-food-water nexus, and includes Global North and South research organisations, the energy industry, regional political organisations, and local communities. Our partner organisations specialise in capacity building and translating research into policy-relevant outputs, thus enabling us to have broad-reaching impacts across national and regional energy and agricultural policy networks, and affected rural communities."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">106707.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T006293_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">98681.78</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T006293_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
