<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N018095_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bilateral BBSRC-Embrapa: Using disease risk forecasting, NGS and HIGS to explore and control Fusarium Head Blight disease in wheat fields</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This is a highly innovative and truly ground breaking research project devised by scientists based at Embrapa Wheat, Soybean, Genetic Resources and Biotechnology and Bioinformatics in Brazil and Rothamsted Research in the UK. The problem to be addressed is the control of a fungal disease called Fusarium head blight (FHB) which is one of the most serious and hazardous crop diseases worldwide. The main consequence of FHB is that trichothecene mycotoxins, such as deoxynivalenol (DON), accumulate in the grain, presenting a health risk to humans and animals.  In Southern Brazil, where 90% of Brazilian wheat is grown, severe FHB epidemic years occur at a minimum of every 4 or 5 years. Legal limits have been set on the DON levels permitted in harvested grain used for different purposes.  However, even moderate FHB years are highly problematic causing the lack of available safe grain for use either on farms or for sale into the market. For low income Brazilian farmers, FHB disease reduces the standards of living of farmer&apos;s families and that of their local communities. There is a pressing need to develop novel and effective FHB control options. In this project, we intend to take a novel whole fungal genome and disease modelling guided approach to develop a pipeline of genetically modified wheat genotypes harbouring T-DNA constructs, which can silence Fusarium genes critical for wheat infection via host-induced gene silencing (HIGS). We also intend to determine the plant and fungal mechanisms that control the HIGS phenomenon. HIGS could be used to control multiple pathogens. This project has six main research steps. 1. To explore using next generation sequencing the genomes of the five FHB causing species in Southern Brazil. Define the core and species-specific proteome of the FHB species complex (FGSC) for the development of molecular diagnostic tools and the selection of HIGS targets. Monitor for possible genome alterations over 3 years. 2. To enhance FHB disease risk forecasting, by establishing a spore sampler network that can detect and quantify Fusarium species. Devise and use diagnostic assays to identify and monitor FGSC diversity. Sample atmospheric Fusarium spores to identify potential inoculum sources and population structure. Incorporate data on the dynamics of airborne Fusarium spore populations into the existing regional FHB risk model.   3. To develop various T-DNA based constructs to silence Fusarium gene expression by HIGS, thereby controlling Fusarium infections. Evaluate single gene HIGS constructs using a novel cut wheat tillers (transient assay) and via stable transformation into Arabidopsis or lettuce. Two lead HIGS constructs targeting multiple Fusarium genes will be transform into a moderately FHB resistance Brazilian wheat cultivar. In the resulting transgenic plant populations, FHB severity and DON levels will be quantified.  4. To explore the underlying mechanisms of HIGS three cutting edge experiments will be completed. We will establish if long or short RNA molecules move between fungal and wheat cells, determine if the gene silencing phenomena once initiated operates systemically and investigate if transported RNA molecules are cargoed using vesicular transport to the plant cell surface for delivery into fungal cells. 5. To perform two years of GM wheat trial in two locations in Brazil using the four best HIGS lines and three appropriate control lines. Assess in-field FHB symptoms, airborne inoculum, grain quality, DON contamination and fungal spore production. To collect Fusarium isolates able to cause any disease on the HIGS lines and complete a full genome analyse. 6. The research team will engage with farmers, farmer co-operatives, grain purchasers, plant breeders in Brazil and the UK and academics globally to explain the project, the research findings and discuss ways to implement the new modelling/forecasting technologies, to use the novel GM trait and further understand the HIGS phenomenon.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-31">97702.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-31">130593.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-31">130240.36</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="To effectively control Fusarium Head Blight disease (FHB) disease in Southern Brazil a new multifaceted approach is required. A project with five main research objectives has been devised.   Objective 1: Fusarium genomes  Five Fusarium species will be investigated, namely, F. graminearum, F. meridionale, F. cortaderiae, F. austroamericanum and F. asiaticum.  Objective 1A. Gain an in depth knowledge at the full genome level for the entire Fusarium species complex present in wheat crops in Southern Brazil.   Objective 1B. Define the core and species-specific proteome of the FHB species complex.  Objective 1C. Select suitable Fusarium targets for gene silencing  Objective 2 Fusarium population dynamics in Southern Brazil: Developing a regional survey A ground based network of fungal spore traps, associated weather stations and crop development data as well as unmanned aerial vehicles will be used to achieved this objective.    Objective 2A. Improve accuracy, increase the data types and data sets included in the disease risk forecasting model.  Objective 2B. Develop new molecular diagnostic tools to monitor and track population diversity shifts.   Objective 2C. Implement a regional Fusarium complex survey and disease risk forecasting system.  Objective 3 HIGS target evaluation in wheat, Arabidopsis and lettuce To design and test new approaches to control FHB based on trans-kingdom gene silencing.   Objective 3A. Evaluate single gene HIGS constructs using anovel cut wheat tiller (transient assay) and via stable transformation into Arabidopsis or lettuce. These experiments will use wild-type and GM Fusarium graminearum isolates.  Objective 3B. Select up to 5 lead Fusarium genes, make 2 HIGS constructs targeting different 2 or 3 Fusarium gene combinations and stably transform these into a moderately FHB resistant Brazilian wheat cultivar.  Objective 3C. Test the two populations of GM wheat lines generated in the pump priming year and select the four best lines for field evaluation.    Objective 4 Understand the mechanisms underlying HIGS in Fusarium To increase knowledge of the underlying plant and fungal gene silencing mechanisms and thereby reveal new strategies to further enhance the levels of FHB control.  Objective 4A. Establish if long or short RNA molecules move between fungal and wheat cells using wild-type, double dicer and double argonaute Fusarium mutants.   Objective 4B. Determine if the gene silencing phenomena once initiated operates systemically throughout the entire plant, using Arabidopsis and reciprocal grafting.  Objective 4C. Investigate if transported RNA molecules are cargoed using vesicular transport to the plant cell surface for delivery into fungal cells using Arabidopsis and lettuce.  Objective 5 Field evaluation of HIGS  To test the GM wheat lines to control the natural Fusarium species complex in Southern Brazil.  Objective 5A Test the efficacy of the best four GM wheat lines harbouring different multi-target HIGS constructs to control FHB disease under Brazilian field conditions at two locations and in 2 years. Within these replicated trials, three appropriate control wheat lines will be include and evaluated.  Objective 5B Monitor for any Fusarium population shifts within the field trial occurring on the GM wheat HIGS plants.      Hypotheses to be tested  1) The Fusarium graminearum species complex in Southern Brazil is globally unique (WP1) 2) New species-specific molecular diagnostic tools can be used to improve the tracking of FHB population dynamic and to enhance disease risk and mycotoxin forecasting (WP2) 3) HIGS can be used to control FHB at the individual plant and field scales (WP3+5) 4) Distinct plant and fungal mechanisms regulate HIGS (WP4)"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
