<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T009918_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urgent Appeals: Data and Shared Learning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Context: The working conditions for today&apos;s typical garment worker are poor. The majority of production is located in the global south, mainly in parts of Asia, and ODA countries feature prominently as locations for production.  With low associational power and limited access to remedy, workers need international allies in order to get their voices heard. The Clean Clothes Campaign (CCC) has campaigned for the accountability of brands and lobbied policy makers for some 30 years. One of its core mechanisms for interacting with human rights defenders (HRDs) and other civil society actors is its Urgent Appeal (UA) system.  Through the UA system workers and their organisations can contact CCC for support. Examples of UAs taken up by CCC include large scale disasters such as the Tazreen fire in Bangladesh in 2012, which killed over 100 workers, the Ali Enterprises Fire in Pakistan in 2012 where 265 people died, and the Rana Plaza building collapse in 2013 which killed over 1,000 workers and injured 2,000 more. In addition to health and safety, UAs may also relate to workers&apos; rights such as freedom of association, wage theft or in relation to intimidation and harassment of HRDs. Each UA case file is a repository of information which, if organised, coded, analysed and fully utilised, could provide support for advocacy and campaigning at both international and local level.  In 2018 researchers at Cardiff University were awarded funding under the IAA NGO data fund, with the aim of constructing a user-friendly dataset of UA data that could be used by CCC in strategising campaigns, identifying tactics that have worked in specific contexts and providing a strong evidential base for targeted lobbying and advocacy. The project concluded in March 2019 with its limited objectives met, but having highlighted the need for further work to improve the accuracy and consistency of the data across cases and undertake more detailed analysis of relationships between variables in UA case histories.   Aims and objectives: The overarching aim of the proposed project is to maximise the use of UA data that CCC holds but has not hitherto fully utilised. Such data has significant potential as an evidential base for decision making, strategic planning and targeting of tactics in campaigning and advocacy. Two key objectives sit at the centre of the current application:   Research Objective 1: To further review and evaluate the UA IAA database in collaboration with CCC colleagues, with three aims:  a) to address issues highlighted to CCC in March 2019 around incomplete or inaccurate data, thereby improving its comprehensiveness and accuracy;  b) to undertake a comprehensive needs analysis and assess the functional capacity of the UA database for future usage in the light of sectoral trends;  c) to make recommendations for the maintenance and utilisation of the dataset within CCC.  Research Objective 2: To analyse the UA database in greater detail and embed it in the CCC network as a strategic tool with direct application to advocacy and campaigning.  Such analysis would involve, for example, the tracking and mapping of violations, identification of successful campaigning strategies and exploring relationships between violations according to country characteristics and national / institutional variations.    Potential application and benefits: The project will provide CCC with more easily accessible data and an evidence base for campaigning and advocacy at the international level as well as acting as an operational tool for Urgent Appeals Coordinators (UACs) who need to access information in conditions of extreme complexity. Ease of access to data analysis provides potential for identification of effective tactics to assist campaigning in conditions of limited resource. It also offers potential for shared learning beyond the life of the Urgent Appeal, with benefits accruing to workers and civil society stakeholders in ODA countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">53473.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">107379.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overarching aim of the proposed project is to maximise the exploitation of data on its Urgent Appeals work that the Clean Clothes Campaign (CCC) holds but has not hitherto fully utilised. Such data has significant potential as an evidential base for decision making, strategic planning and targeting of tactics in campaigning and advocacy. It is also a powerful bank of knowledge that could and should be more fully shared throughout the CCC network. The data&apos;s potential has been identified within CCC but in conditions of limited resource it had proved impossible to devote the necessary time to organising and coding information contained in the records of UA cases in a way that will support detailed analysis of patterns and themes. The IAA NGO Data project (October 2018-March 2019) provided the funding that began the task of establishing a dataset that would act as a user friendly analytical tool for the CCC Network. The IAA project achieved its limited objectives, but having begun working with the data it was apparent that far more could be done. The challenge is to provide CCC with a dataset that allows access to the information embedded in each Urgent Appeal and thereby provides an accurate and reliable evidential base for campaigning and advocacy. We therefore wish to build on the work done under the terms of the IAA NGO Data funding and further review and improve the dataset we developed (referred to here as the IAA dataset) as a long-term source of shared learning and strategic decision making.  Two key objectives sit at the centre of the current application:   Research Objective 1: To further review and evaluate the UA IAA database in collaboration with CCC colleagues, with three aims:     a. to address issues highlighted to CCC in March 2019 around incomplete or inaccurate data, thereby improving the comprehensiveness and accuracy of the database;     b. to undertake a comprehensive needs analysis and assess the functional capacity of the IAA database for future usage in the light of sectoral trends;     c. to make recommendations for the maintenance and utilisation of the dataset within CCC.  Research Objective 2: To analyse the UA database in greater detail and embed it in the CCC network as a strategic tool with direct application to advocacy and campaigning.  Such analysis would involve, for example, the tracking and mapping of violations, identification of successful campaigning strategies and exploring relationships between violations according to country characteristics and national / institutional variations.    Realisation of these objectives will aid the CCC International Office in disseminating learning across the network, establishing a sound evidential base developed from their own internal data and strategizing their campaigning and advocacy. It will also give Urgent Appeals Coordinators (UACs) easier access to information on brand behaviour, trends in violations and successful campaigning tactics in specific contexts. This sort of access to information is crucial for CCC and for UACs operating in highly complex contexts, where a large amount of information needs to be evaluated under extreme pressures. Provision of high quality data analysis in real time should improve UAC effectiveness in real time as well as providing a knowledge base that the CCC network will cascade down to human rights defenders on the ground, to the wider benefit of the struggle for decent work and human rights in ODA countries."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">26736.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T009918_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">26736.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T009918_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">26736.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T009918_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">26736.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T009918_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">26953.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T009918_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiff University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
