<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004215_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Centre of Excellence for Inequality Research: Partnerships and Capacity Building for Economic Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inequality has emerged as the social challenge of the decade. Empirically, a series of influential studies of the available evidence suggest that global inequality has been falling in the last quarter century. This encouraging trend appears to have been driven entirely by convergence in GDP per capita across nations &amp; the consequent decline in inequality between countries, with the average inequality within countries remaining constant until about 2000 but increasing thereafter.  Within Africa inequality is more complex &amp; often obscured by problems with unreliable &amp; non-comparable data, both over time &amp; across countries. The most careful African data analysis suggests that African inequality is very high: it is the most unequal continent. There is however huge variation in the magnitude, changes &amp; texture of this inequality across the continent. The high aggregate figure is driven by the fact that 7 of the 10 most unequal countries in the world are in Africa (Beegle, Cattaneo, Christiaensen, &amp; Dabalen, 2016). If Southern African countries are excluded, Africa has inequality levels comparable to developing countries in other parts of the world (Bhorat, Naidoo, &amp; Pillay, 2015). Because some African countries are world &apos;leaders&apos; in inequality, &amp; over the next 30 years, Africa&apos;s population will make up a rapidly rising share of the world&apos;s population &amp; especially in the younger age groups (Lam &amp; Leibbrandt, 2013), the primary objective of the Centre is to deepen understanding about Africa&apos;s inequality dynamics &amp; to foreground this in the international inequality literature &amp; to ensure that it is included in the international measurements.  Equally important is the need for the continent to ensure that the specifics of our societies are considered in the analysis both of the factors causing inequality &amp; the consequences of inequality. This analysis is the basis for policy interventions &amp; civil society action to turn the tide. ACEIR will directly address both the analytic &amp; measurement challenges. With DataFirst leading this, ACEIR&apos;s objective of providing frontier data scholarship with great possibilities for capacity development is attainable. The data foundations described will be used to build an ambitious &amp; important intellectual agenda on inequality in Africa. It will enable us to show how inequalities are produced &amp; their destructive consequences on individuals, communities &amp; societies. We will also contribute to a global &amp; continent-specific understanding of how inequalities can be overcome. Measuring multidimensional well-being is data intensive. Understanding how multiple dimensions of well-being interact to trap some in poverty, put others on a positive trajectory into the middle class &amp; serve to perpetuate privilege for others is analytically challenging but at the heart of well-designed policies to break persistent inequality. It is this match between frontier social science &amp; policy impact that is at the heart of ACEIR.  Summarised in its boldest form, the primary objective of ACEIR is to ensure that African researchers &amp; policy makers lead the discussions of African Inequalities &amp; their solutions on the international &amp; continental levels, &amp; especially within each country context. It requires a consolidation &amp; increase in both the knowledge &amp; skills bases on the continent. We build this strength out into broader African research networks off the platform of strong research capability &amp; infrastructure within each of ACEIR&apos;s 3 nodes. The training &amp; networking activities outlined have been designed to improve the partner institutions&apos; ability to undertake &amp; disseminate research, which will promote the welfare &amp; economic development of these developing countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seven of the world&apos;s 10 most unequal countries are located in Africa - this while the continent&apos;s population is bound to take a rapidly rising share of the world&apos;s population in the next 30 years. Understanding Africa&apos;s inequality dynamics is a key component of the international inequality puzzle. The establishment of the African Centre of Excellence for Inequality Research (ACEIR) directly addresses the analytical, empirical and data needs that are required for policy interventions and civil society action the tide against inequality. ACEIR&apos;s current partner universities are located in western, eastern and southern Africa.  The Centre&apos;s launch research programme is aimed at improving the quality and accessibility of relevant data on inequalities in Africa. Equally as important, the ownership of local knowledge production on national and continental inequalities will underline the voice and agency vested in African scholars and research institutions. ACEIR&apos;s goal is to contribute to deep, multidimensional and interdisciplinary understandings of inequality in each country context, and a continental and global understanding of how inequalities can be overcome. Our approach includes building capacity for frontier data scholarship and the interpretation of analyses for policy. Textured country-level analyses of inequality that are also anchored in historical legacies of the political economy of African development is in the process of being undertaken. ACEIR researchers will link processes related to inequality within each country to international measurements such as the Sustainable Development Goals. The initial research programme sees researchers working with the national statistical offices to: - Use census, survey and administrative data to profile and map inequality and poverty; - Analyse the dynamics of poverty and inequality by using panel data; and - Use the evidence generated by a set of tax and social expenditure benefit incidence analyses as a platform for dialogue on strategies to overcome poverty and inequality. Each of the Centre&apos;s nodes are members of the African Research Universities Alliance (ARUA). ACEIR has its hub at the University of Cape Town (UCT), which also hosts the southern African node. The western and eastern nodes are hosted by the University of Ghana, Legon; and the University of Nairobi, respectively. The hub and each node are led by researchers of stature and who are well-established in the contemporary African and broader international inequality communities. This grant will facilitate connecting the Centre into these broad networks, including their own countries&apos; statistical agencies. DataFirst, based at UCT, has over twenty years&apos; experience in the curation and dissemination of data and is the only data service on the African continent to have achieved the CoreTrustSeal certification as a trusted repository. Over the last decade DataFirst has also developed a specific competence in the assessment of data quality issues and in the harmonisation of data. DataFirst will play a central role in the Centre&apos;s data preparation, harmonisation and training activities across the three nodes initially, with a longer term view to extending support to the Centre&apos;s other partners, including the current partnership with the University of Bouak&#xE9;, C&#xF4;te d&apos;Ivoire, and partnerships in the process of being explored, with Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia, and also Kenyatta University, Kenya. The Centre&apos;s establishment is supported by an initial start-up grant from the Agence Fran&#xE7;aise de D&#xE9;veloppement (AFD) as part of the Research Facility on Inequality funded by the European Union, as well as awards from ARUA and each partner university.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">100810.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">151623.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">51224.91</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">51224.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">14024780.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004215_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT004215%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
