<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014313_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessing policy implementation and health systems impacts of Option B+ in three African countries to inform the delivery of Universal Test and Treat.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2013, the World Health Organisation (WHO) recommended initiation of lifelong antiretroviral therapy (ART) for all HIV-positive pregnant women, regardless of disease stage, in order to minimise transmission risks to their index offspring and offspring of later pregnancies. HIV-exposed infants should receive antiretroviral (ARV) prophylaxis, be tested and receive ART if HIV-positive. In 2015, WHO extended their guidance to recommend immediate ART initiation for all adults diagnosed with HIV (universal Test and Treat (UTT)), following evidence from randomised control trials demonstrating that it reduced sexual transmission and provided individual health benefits for HIV-positive adults. Although few sub-Saharan African countries have introduced UTT policies, many have rolled out Option B+, despite ongoing debates over its cost-effectiveness and health systems impacts, particularly in settings with weak infrastructure. Despite its potential to eliminate HIV in infants and improve maternal health, some argue that poor delivery could lead to resources being channelled away from adult HIV services, detrimentally affecting their quality and health outcomes. There is widespread agreement that research is needed to understand how Option B+ has been implemented in different settings and its corresponding impacts on health systems. Furthermore, there is a key window of opportunity to use the evidence generated by such research to assess how best to prepare these health systems for further expansion of ART services as UTT policies are rolled out. Our study will take place in three HIV community cohort (HCC) sites in rural Malawi, Tanzania and South Africa, representing early, mid-term and late adopters of Option B+ in 2011, 2013 and 2015 respectively, and where UTT policies were being drafted in 2016, in order to answer 4 key research questions: 1) What are the Option B+ policy implementation gaps in each setting and how do the actors, policy content, context and processes explain these gaps? 2) Have underlying economic and epidemiological assumptions in economic evaluations that demonstrated the anticipated cost-effectiveness of Option B+ been met in each site? 3) What are the health systems impacts of Option B+ in each setting? 4) What strategies can be developed with policymakers to ensure that health systems are ready for effective delivery of UTT? We will use a comparative, longitudinal approach with mixed methods that include secondary analysis of existing policy reviews, health facility survey data and routine HIV clinic data linked to HCC data. We will also collect new data through an updated review of national HIV policies, a further round of facility surveys, key informant interviews with policymakers and programmers, in-depth interviews with health workers and PMTCT service users, and costing estimates. We will draw on existing  frameworks to identify gaps in Option B+ implementation and to explore the policy processes and contexts underlying them. We will then assess whether the costs of implementing Option B+ in purposively sampled health facilities correspond with pre-implementation estimates, and whether epidemiological parameters used for economic evaluations prior to Option B+ implementation align with local estimates derived from the HCC. We will also adapt existing indicators to assess the impacts of Option B+ on governance, financing, service delivery, workforce, information, medical supplies, and use qualitative and HCC data to consider impacts on health systems processes commonly defined as those relating to access, quality and coverage. Using our findings, we will work with key stakeholders to develop tools to assess health systems readiness for UTT, and to monitor health systems impacts through its implementation.  The research questions and methods were developed in collaboration with policymakers to support the uptake of the findings into UTT policies in each country and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Several African countries are preparing to adopt Universal Test and Treat (UTT) policies for HIV despite a dearth of evidence on health systems&apos; preparedness for its implementation. Important lessons can be learned by investigating the health systems impacts of Option B+, widely viewed as the precursor to UTT.  The overall aim of the research is to assess the policy implementation and health systems impacts of Option B+ for the prevention of mother-to-child transmission (PMTCT) of HIV in Malawi, Tanzania and South Africa in order to inform the future delivery of policies for UTT.  Our longitudinal and mixed methods study will be implemented in an HIV community cohort (HCC) site in each country. It draws on a conceptual framework that incorporates elements from Walt and Gilson&apos;s &quot;policy triangle&quot; and a modified form of the WHO health systems &quot;Building Blocks&quot; model, and is informed by a &quot;systems thinking&quot; approach in order to achieve the following objectives:  1. To assess Option B+ implementation gaps in each setting, and explore how the actors, policy content, context and processes explain these gaps. We will generate and compare indicators using data from national HIV policy reviews and health facility surveys in each study site undertaken in 2013, 2015 and to be updated in 2017, to describe gaps in implementation of policies relating to PMTCT. We will conduct key informant interviews to elicit how the actors, policy content, context and processes influence implementation of these policies in each setting.  2. To assess whether the underlying economic and epidemiological assumptions used in economic evaluations that demonstrated the cost-effectiveness of Option B+ are applicable in each of the three study sites We will collect data on the costs of implementing Option B+ in purposively sampled health facilities in each HCC to assess whether they correspond with pre-implementation estimates. We will also investigate whether the epidemiological parameters used for economic evaluations prior to Option B+ implementation align with local estimates derived from the HCC datasets. 3. To longitudinally investigate the impacts of implementation of Option B+ on key health system inputs for HIV services including financing, governance, service delivery, workforce, information and medical supplies, and health systems processes (quality of care, access and coverage). Using the health facility survey data on HIV service delivery from each site over the three time points, we will investigate and compare trends in indicators pertaining  to impacts on each of the health systems inputs. We will also consider the impacts on health systems inputs and key processes (including quality of care and access) from both health provider and patient perspectives using qualitative methods. In South Africa and Malawi, we will additionally investigate the consequences on HIV service coverage using the HCC data that are anonymously linked to HIV clinic records in the study area to determine trends in the proportion of all HIV-positive pregnant women receiving lifelong ART.  4. To develop strategies for assessing and ensuring health systems readiness for effective delivery of UTT in each country. Using internationally-agreed indicators of health systems readiness to deliver HIV services that are captured through our health facility surveys, and with the findings from the qualitative data, we will devise a framework for determining readiness for UTT delivery in each site, which is likely to apply to scale up of other health services. We will work with relevant stakeholders in each country to draw out lessons concerning the health systems impacts of Option B+ implementation in order to develop tools and strategies for assessing health systems readiness and ongoing evaluation of UTT policy implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">60226.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">199851.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">178154.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">117364.87</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">555597.3644</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014313_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP014313%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
