<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V007998_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Belief in the time of Covid-19: Understanding the making of meaning and trust to maximise public health responsiveness of faith communities in DRC</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Democratic Republic of Congo(DRC), faith communities and their medical services are central to reducing contagion. They should be urgently deployed. Religious belief and traditional healing practices are part of the framework in which Congolese people understand disease and respond to it. Understanding the contextual response to Covid-19 is vital to reducing its spread.  Faith Communities support over 50% of biomedical care in North-east DRC. They are vital, trusted providers of care. They bridge community and professional sectors, providing supportive networks, medical treatment, prayers for healing. They have led medical response and social restrictions to the recent outbreaks of Ebola (2,250 dead between 2018-2020) and measles (killed 6,500 since 2019). They have knowledge of disease management and are integral to developing community-led solutions to endemic cholera, HIV, malaria, meningitis, plague. Their resilience in the face of multiple losses and repeated disease give insight into communities&apos; capacity for restoration. Yet faith-health beliefs in DRC do not always lead to positive disease control. Disease outbreaks, like Ebola, propel particular beliefs about life, death, sickness, healing, the seen and unseen that, when there is no cure or vaccine, can present appealing alternatives to physical distancing, closure of community organisations and alterations to rites of passage. We examine the application of belief in DRC where faith communities are leading the health-care response to Covid-19 and where the scientific and spiritual operate within the same conceptual framework. Recorded cases of Covid-19 are low in many African countries. This is, in part, related to a lack of diagnosis and testing. DRC had its first recorded case in Kinshasa on 10th March 2020. But until May only one institution in the country had testing capacity. Numbers have risen steadily, and been reported Ituri and Nord-Kivu. Covid-19 compounds the urgent medical and security concerns of the region. Yet Covid-19 also highlights good practice of disease management and resilience in a region that is familiar with epidemics.  We ask how Covid-19 and the public health strategies for mitigation and management are being understood, delivered, and actioned. We aim to understand, predict and mitigate adverse public reactions to civil contingency measures. A public health response using trusted communities is the best chance of reducing the death toll whilst there is no cure or vaccine. However, the measures taken in High Income Countries may not be appropriate for LMICs, and they rarely consider discourses of religious faith. The Congolese members of the project team are already investigating meaning-making discourses around Covid-19 in Ituri and Nord-Kivu. They are identifying disease management knowledge, and communal beliefs that support and critique protection and prevention practices. Findings from this in-depth examination will be used to co-create public health messages that are trusted and trustworthy and allow effective, emergency mobilisation of volunteers in faith communities.  Our study of contemporary religious belief examines the beliefs and moral capacity of faith communities and their medical services to maximise community-inspired action and ensure community ownership. It is a timely piece of work that has implications for disease prevention beyond Covid-19. It informs a debate on how to increase public health capacity in fragile states where national governments rarely support the structural transformation required.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project urgently seeks to understand faith-health beliefs in the time of Covid-19 in order to contribute to effective and immediate public health communication and action through faith communities in the regions of Ituri and Nord-Kivu, in North East Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC). It will inform civil contingency measures and engage trusted institutions to mitigate adverse public reactions to the measures. Those living in Congo have a recent history of responding to epidemics of HIV, Ebola, measles, cholera and plague with limited medical resources. We know that contextual factors influence response to disease. Most Congolese are affiliated to at least one faith community, and these communities support bio-medical, faith-healing and traditional healing practices. Medical and spiritual discourses operate within the same conceptual framework in DRC (Janzen, 2019), known here as &apos;faith-health beliefs&apos;. We do not have enough knowledge on how people in Ituri and Nord-Kivu make meaning from disease spread. This lack of contextual knowledge reduces the effectiveness of public health messages. In a pandemic this puts lives at risk.  Objective One:  Quickly to comprehend the current meaning-making discourses (stories, reports, sermons, public health advice, songs, news items) in faith-health beliefs around Covid-19. To attain the objective as a matter of urgency, we are already examining the hermeneutics of discourses in the public domain (in French, Swahili and Lingala), and conducting interviews remotely (some in local languages). We will also ask some participants to note or record the information they are receiving about the pandemic, and their responses to it.  Objective Two:  To identify trustworthy discourses and messengers (individuals and institutions) and apply this knowledge as rapidly as possible to public health messaging and the mobilisation of volunteers to combat the current pandemic. Here we respond to the World Health Organisation(WHO) research call to reduce fear and rumour and promote adherence to public health measures, by ensuring that advice &apos;speaks the language&apos; of trusted faith communities.  Objective three: To reflect on the immediate hermeneutical analysis of meaning-making of Covid-19 and trust in contingency measures to reduce its spread in order to apply the method more broadly. Our analysis of faith-health beliefs in contemporary religion will impact public health practitioners in DRC and internationally through Cellule d&apos;analyse en sciences sociale, the Health Systems Governance Collaborative, Joint learning Initiative, WHO. It will inform heath discourses in Theology and Religious Studies. The rapid spread of Covid-19 requires a fast-action first stage of the project (objectives one and two) to collect and analyse discourses and simultaneously inform public health messaging and action through organisations and networks already established in the region.  In this way the project will have an immediate impact on contingency measures necessary for disease control, through radio broadcasts, songs, public announcements and programmes for volunteers. We take a grounded approach that prioritises the daily search for well-being by ordinary citizens and health-workers in faith communities.  This initial stage will be largely be complete by October, but on-going monitoring of relevant new data will continue in response to disease spread and any shift of beliefs surrounding Covid-19. Within 12 months we will prepare articles to appear in peer reviewed journals on the context and causes of beliefs surrounding disease and developing responses to them (see academic beneficiaries). These objectives are achievable only because researchers Kangamina, Way and Baba know the context and languages, are already collecting data, and have excellent professional connections with religious and medical bodies in the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Congo (the Democratic Republic of the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1028" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-05">46528.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-05">46528.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-05">93057.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/V007998/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">23264.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V007998_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FV007998%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-11-09"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
