<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S006990_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As Good as (G)Old? Comparing Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services of Restored and Natural Mangrove Forests in the Wallacea Region (CoReNat)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mangrove forests are unique intertidal ecosystems connecting the land- and seascape. They provide habitat to terrestrial and marine species, sustain the livelihoods of millions of mostly poor people globally, and are considered as high priority habitats in climate change mitigation strategies, due to their extraordinary carbon sink capacity. Mangroves forests are degraded globally, with land use change being the single most serious threat at present.  Successful restoration/rehabilitation of diverse, functional, resource-rich and resilient mangrove forests is a major development challenge in many countries, including Indonesia. The so called Blue Revolution - the conversion of mangroves to (unsustainable) aquaculture ponds in the 80s and 90s - is one major reason why the country has lost 40% of its mangroves over the last three decades. This has caused manifold problems for people&apos;s lives. Halting and reversing Indonesia&apos;s loss of mangrove natural assets is key to improve coastal livelihoods and reduce poverty. The Indonesian government currently spends around $13 million a year for planting mangroves on degraded areas. Most planting projects in Indonesia and elsewhere in the world have failed, and it is mostly understood why. There are however numerous critical information gaps in understanding how successful the &quot;successful&quot; projects are in regards to recreating diverse and functional self-organising and self-maintaining systems.   CoReNat will investigate outcomes of established community-based mangrove restoration/ rehabilitation (R/R) projects in the heart of Wallacea - North-Sulawesi - Indonesia, to unravel whether these mangroves are &quot;As good as (G)Old?&quot;. The overall project aims are to assess whether mangrove ecosystem biodiversity, functions, resilience and service provision have been restored, and to make evidence-based recommendations for maximizing the success of future R/R efforts in Wallacea (and beyond). Combining UK and Indonesian experience, expertise and scientific excellence, CoReNat will provide evidence-based recommendations to relevant stakeholder to guide future ecological R/R efforts.  CoReNat takes a novel interdisciplinary approach to deliver a comprehensive ecosystem evaluation of established restored/rehabilitated and adjacent natural (reference) mangroves, bringing together paleoecology, geoscience, botany, zoology, environmental microbiology, ecological network analysis combined with next generation sequencing, toxicology and bioexploration.   CoReNat will  -  provide new data on the region&apos;s (mangrove-associated) biodiversity and species interactions, for conserved as well as for rehabilitated/restored mangrove forests -  apply and generate innovative new tools for the field of mangrove restoration -  provide data that will allow a better understanding of the biodiversity, functioning and services of mono-specific versus multi-specific replanted mangroves -  support the provision of solutions to mangrove conservation, restoration/ rehabilitation and management -  explore current local use of conserved and restored mangroves, as well as potential new avenues for business and innovation, to help balance Indonesia&apos;s need for conservation with economic development</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project &quot;As Good as (G)old? Comparing Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services of Restored and Natural Mangrove Forests in the Wallacea Region (CoReNat)&quot; has scientific- and impact-related objectives.   THE SCIENTIFIC OBJECTIVES ARE TO:  - Reconstruct long-term mangrove biodiversity changes, ecological thresholds and resilience as well as pre-human impact vegetation baselines using paleoecological archives. This will allow the identification of past and future ranges of environmental variability  - Quantify above and below-ground C stocks in restored and natural (R/R) mangroves, estimate their climate change mitigation, quantify surface elevation change due to sediment accretion and sub-surface changes and estimate their adaptive capacity regarding regional and global sea level rise  - Assess and compare floral, (benthic-macro) faunal and sediment microbial taxonomic and functional diversity, and community structure between sites; determine faunal-mediated carbon burial rates  - Assess and compare local use of natural and R/R mangroves   - Unravel food web interactions through an innovative approach of combined ecological network analysis (ENA) and Next Generation Sequencing; use the degree of biotic complexity identified through ENA as indicator for ecosystem functioning, complexity and robustness of the natural and R/R mangrove forests   - Investigate the tolerance and phytoremediation potential of the most abundant mangrove species in regard to heavy metals, abundant pollutants in Wallacea (and health risks)  - Explore novel potential opportunities for economic growth in Wallacea (and Indonesia) by screening mangrove associated fungi for potentially useful proteolytic enzymes and antibacterial compounds   - Develop a new rapid assessment best practice protocol for evaluating R/R projects  KEY IMPACT OBJECTIVES ARE TO:  - Generate new knowledge concerning ecosystem services provided by mangrove ecosystems when well managed and restored, for multiple stakeholders  - Engage with and influence decision-makers and practitioners; make recommendation to relevant bodies to improve the monitoring, and the effectivity and efficiency of current and future R/R practices   - Build capacity for new methods and tools in ecological restoration in Indonesia, both on the level of academia and civil society, including local communities</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edinburgh Napier University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-13">95940.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-13">217426.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-13">225746.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-13">104726.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-13">643840.03</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to Edinburgh Napier University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE/S006990/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edinburgh Napier University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FS006990%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
