<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P011543_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF - Drugs and (dis)order: Building sustainable peacetime economies in the aftermath of war</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">First, the project will engage scholars working on the political economy of conflict and war to peace transitions. This includes researchers working on issues of violence (e.g. Christopher Cramer, Stathis Kalyvas, Teo Ballve), resources, statebuilding and political settlements (e.g. Jonathan Di John, James Putzel, Philippe Le Billon, Douglass North and Mushtaq Khan), and hybrid political orders (e.g. Volker Boege, Kate Meagher). The research will contribute to this literature by providing a comparative evidence base regarding the perpetuation of criminalised economies in peacetime and the complex dilemmas and trade-offs that exist between peacebuilding, development and counter narcotics efforts to tackle illicit economies. The research will be disseminated through publication in leading development and politics journals, through engagement with existing research networks (such as the Political Settlements Research Programme) and UK and international conferences. Second, the research will benefit scholars working on drugs and other illicit economies, including Pierre-Arnaud Chouvy, Carolyn Nordstrom, Richard Snyder, Ko-Lin Chin, Francisco Thoumi. The research aims to redefine the field of drugs and development by generating an innovative, interdisciplinary framework for conceptualising the dynamics surrounding drug economies that combines political economy, livelihoods, gender, and public health analysis to understand the tensions that exist between counter-narcotics policies and concurrent efforts to address state fragility and poverty. The project is well-placed to disseminate research to audiences across different disciplines through the SOAS Violence, Conflict and Development research cluster, the new SOAS Corruption Centre, the LSE IDEAS International Drug Policy Project, the Centre for Research on Drugs and Health Behaviour (CRDHB) and The Centre for Health and Social Change (ECOHOST) (both hosted by the LSHTM). Third, the research will strengthen recent borderland studies scholarship focused on how state margins are not simply reflective of power relations at the centre, but are often constitutive of new political and economic orders (e.g. Hastings Donnan, Thomas Wilson, Benedikt Korf, Timothy Raeymaekers, Paul Nugent, James Scott and Willem van Schendel). Research will strengthen this growing body of literature by demonstrating how a borderlands perspective can address the lack of sensitivity to space in much of the literature on war to peace transitions and statebuilding, which focuses predominantly on national-level political settlements. The research will engage beneficiaries by submitting publications to targeted journals including Geoforum and Journal of Borderland Studies, and through interacting with the Asian Borderlands Research Network, the Association for Borderland Studies and the African Borderlands Research Network. Fourth, the project will provide an important contribution to the literature engaged with developing new research approaches for working in insecure terrain (e.g. Gutierrez-Sanin, Mansfield, Ko-Lin Chin). The research&apos;s integration of in-depth fieldwork, GIS spatial imagery and public health analysis will showcase methodological innovation that may then be adapted to other research initiatives in drugs and conflict-affected environments. These findings will be disseminated through the project&apos;s workshops and capacity building initiatives with UK-based and southern researchers. The project aims to strengthen the links between UK and southern researchers in Afghanistan, Colombia and Myanmar across all of these areas of knowledge by establishing an extensive  research network through the project&apos;s proposed Policy Lab and subsequent Research Consortium for Transforming Illicit Economies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching objective of this research project is to address one of the most significant challenges facing fragile states: How can war economies be transformed into peace economies in countries experiencing or recovering from armed conflict?  Finding convincing answers to this question could have a significant effect on the lives of the more than 2 billion people live in in countries where development outcomes are affected by fragility, conflict and violence (World Bank 2016). The focus of this project is Global Challenge 10 (&apos;reduce conflict and promote peace, justice and humanitarian action) because of its concern with fragility and illicit economies and how to transform war economies into peace economies. This is a global priority, as shown by Sustainable Development Goal 16 on conflict reduction and governance.  It is also a UK government priority, as reflected by the fact that the UK has committed to spending at least half of its aid budget on fragile and failing states..  The project also targets Global Challenges 1 (Secure and resilient food systems supported by sustainable agriculture), 2 (sustainable health and well-being), 6 (Sustainable livelihoods) and 11 (poverty and inequality, including gender inequalities) because of its focus on the livelihoods, health and gender dimensions of illicit drug economies in fragile and conflict-affected states.  The project will address these challenges by: First, the project will generate a robust evidence base on the relationship between illicit drug economies, state fragility and post-war transitions in borderland regions of Afghanistan, Colombia and Myanmar. Existing evidence on illicit drug economies is patchy, politicised and contested. The project will develop a strong evidence base regarding the role of illicit economies in wartime, their perpetuation in peacetime and the complex dilemmas and trade-offs that exist between peacebuilding, statebuilding and counter-narcotics efforts.  Evidence will be generated through innovative mixed methods, including the use of GIS imagery, animations and comic strips, archives, household surveys, participatory mapping and key informant interviews.  Second, the project will strengthen the capacity of research organisations in Afghanistan, Colombia and Myanmar, as well as the UK, to generate rigorous and credible evidence The project will strengthen the research and advocacy capacities of all partners through a suite of trainings, including distance learning, mentoring, peer to peer learning and collaborative events involving researchers, policy makers and affected populations from borderland regions. The project aims to support a new generation of researchers, with the capability to redefine the academic and policy debates on drugs, development and peacebuilding. Third, the project aims to be a catalyst for policy reforms, based on new understandings of the relationship between drugs, conflict and development. The policy consensus surrounding the war on drugs is fracturing.  The SDGs constitute a remarkable opportunity to reframe the debates around drugs as a development issue.  However, the SDGs have only a limited concern with drugs and illicit economies. This project&apos;s global research network is well placed, having extensive experience of and engagement with the development and drug communities, to span these two policy fields. In additional to an annual international conference, the project will target key policy fora at the local national, regional and global levels.  Fourth, the project will establish a Research Consortium for Transforming War Economies. This will provide a hub for methodological innovation, learning and sharing, policy dialogue and advocacy on policies related to drugs, and on illicit economies more broadly.  It will sustain a longer term legacy of high quality training materials, open access data platformsand a strong, dynamic and participatory set of research partnerships.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOAS University of London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-25">482228</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-25">1843140</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-25">1865916</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-25">1839651</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-25">867552.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-25">87945499.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF RCUK Award to SOAS University of London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P011543_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOAS University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP011543%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
