<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T020164_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Homegrown solutions in Viet Nam: bringing C. asiatica compounds forward as candidates to treat liver cancer</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liver cancer is a critical problem in Viet Nam, killing 25 thousand Vietnamese individuals each year - more than any other cancer. The problem is especially acute in Viet Nam because of the convergence of overlapping risk factors: hepatitis B and C are prevalent; alcohol consumption is very high; dioxins persist in the environment stemming from the use of Agent Orange during the Viet Nam War; and cultural and economic factors mean that patients frequently present for modern medicine only at a very advanced stage, relying first on traditional herbal remedies.  However, Viet Nam also presents unique opportunities. Its traditional medicine is largely empirical i.e. based on experience rather than philosophical convictions. There is therefore opportunity for the discovery of natural products with therapeutic efficacy, which could be developed as approved drugs in an informed way through chemistry and biology. Centella asiatica is a popular medicinal herb, and our Vietnamese partners have discovered that one of its natural products, madecassic acid, is active against liver cancer, with chemical derivatives showing further improved potential.  In this project we will work on a number of fronts to bring madecassic acid derivatives forward as potential new therapeutics against liver cancer, which could be produced within Viet Nam. This involves optimisation of growth conditions for maximal madecassic acid production (using analytical chemistry), improvement of chemical extraction processes, broadening the range of chemical derivatives in hand, in-depth studies using chemical biology of the cellular effects of madecassic acid, and exploration of use of polymers to control the rate of release in the body. This work will be underlined and supported by networking activities with stakeholders (doctors, industrialists, farmers, policy makers) in Viet Nam, and survey work to assess attitudes of the population to medicines which cross over the traditional-modern divide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this project is to develop drugs to treat liver cancer, a critical health problem in Viet Nam, using Vietnamese natural products, expertise, and industry. The objectives of the project are:  in order of highest immediate potential gain are: (1) Improve and scale-up chemical extraction and purification protocols of the natural product madecassic acid and related compounds from Centella Asiatica (C. asiatica) (2) Identify cellular targets of madecassic acid  using chemical biology for informed drug development (3) Strategically broaden the library of madecassic acid derivatives synthesised and examine their cellular effects, to drive optimal drug candidate selection (4) Develop polymer prodrug formulations for targeted delivery and sustained release of madecassic acid  derivatives (5) Improve yield and phytochemical content of C. asiatica grown through agricultural development in Hue province (6) Lay foundations for success by establishing a network of scientists, clinicians, and industrialists in Viet Nam and the UK to advance towards clinical trial, and by surveying the populace to discover attitudes to drugs based on C. asiatica. In terms of potential long term gain, these are ranked (6) &gt; (2) &gt; (3) &gt; (1) &gt; (5) &gt; (4), since the target is to get a liver cancer drug to the people of Viet Nam. However, (1) and (5) offer low-risk, immediate benefits to farmers in one of the poorest regions in the country since C. asiatica products already have a very large market.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Viet Nam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-10">611291.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Kent</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T020164/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">76103.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T020164_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">76103.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T020164_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT020164%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
