<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R014094_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of New Low Cost Point of Care Diagnostic Technologies for Diabetic Retinopathy in China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The prevalence of diabetes is increasing rapidly worldwide, but more especially in China (a Development Assistance Committee &apos;Upper Middle Income Country&apos;), because of genetic predisposition and lifestyle changes associated with increasing affluence. Over 110 million people in China live with diabetes and this number is expected to increase to 150 million by 2040. Diabetic retinopathy (DR) is becoming the leading cause of blindness in China. DR does not cause any symptoms in its early and moderate stages. Blindness can only be prevented by early detection and prompt treatment of sight threatening DR. The UK National Screening Programmes are world leading and provide clear evidence for the effectiveness of screening in reducing blindness. However there are hurdles to be overcome in order to make DR screening viable in China. The fundus cameras that are conventionally used for screening are not fit for purpose. There are insufficient trained graders and it is impractical and cost-prohibitive for China to train and maintain such a large number of technicians. Also the international definition of screen positive is inappropriate for China as patients would have to pay for unnecessary hospital visits and there are insufficient eye doctors for UK style hospital monitoring. China has to embrace some leap-frog technologies involving innovative engineering, imaging, machine and human learning. Aim The overarching aim of this project is to develop a novel integrated diagnostic and educational solution to screening for sight threatening DR which specifically addresses this complex large-scale challenge in China. Objectives 1. To develop a new low-cost retinal imaging camera, incorporating a scanning laser ophthalmoscope and optical coherence tomography (OCT), that is capable of taking images of sufficient quality for DR grading 2. To produce a novel DR grading solution suitable for China by seamlessly combining machine learning and human learning in a self-reinforcing loop which:    i). enhances specificity and sensitivity of machine learning with new deep learning algorithms,     ii). develops and exploits human skill in making judgements about DR through human ranking of retinal images supported by a computer-based assessment technique, Adaptive Comparative Judgement (ACJ), underpinned by new developments in statistical techniques    iii) is suitable for combined retinal photography and OCT 3. To evaluate the new engineering and delivery technologies in China and estimate cost-effectiveness The end points of the project are (1) a validated new integrated diagnostic solution for the detection of DR in China by non-expert health care workers; (2) a generalised comparative system that allows image grading with novice graders and that is accompanied with flexible monitoring metrics; (3) a new training method to train health workers in China; (4) evidence of cost-effectiveness of the developed solutions to support scale-up in China and potentially other Low Middle Income Countries (LMICs). Although an ambitious project, we are satisfied that our multidisciplinary research team forged from the strong partnership between the UK and China researchers can deliver on all objectives. The project objective is well aligned with the EPSRC GCRF funding strategy to develop new diagnostic imaging technologies tailored to solve health challenges in China with potential for other LMICs and indirectly contribute economically to UK PLC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will develop novel, low-cost, diagnostic technologies for the detection of a blinding condition called diabetic retinopathy (DR) in China. These technologies will enable cost-effective, large-scale detection of sight-threatening disease to be performed by non-expert health care workers at the time and place of patient care in China. Over 110 million people in China live with diabetes and this number is expected to increase to 150m by 2040. Diabetes causes visual loss through damage to blood vessels of the retina at the back of the eye. Treatments are effective (and increasingly affordable in China) but only if the disease is detected early enough. Improving early diagnosis and treatment of DR is one of the principal objectives of the Chinese Government&apos;s 5-Year National Plan of Eye Health (2016-2020). Current methods of detecting DR rely on costly imaging equipment and many skilled personnel to take and interpret retinal images. China has very few health workers with these skills.  Case detection strategies which are cost-effective in Western Europe cannot possibly be replicated at the scale necessary for China. Building on an existing collaboration between the University of Liverpool, Peking University and the Chinese Medical Association (CMA), our joint research team from Liverpool and China of engineers, statisticians, education specialists, eye doctors and health economists are well placed to develop a new diagnostic imaging solution tailored to local needs.   Our objectives for this project are: 1. To develop a novel, low-cost, robust imaging device for detection of DR 2. To develop new automated computer algorithms to rate images of the retina for sight-threatening disease 3. To develop a novel comparative judgement method to refine the DR severity grading from automated computer algorithms 4. To validate the new technologies in the UK and test them in China to ensure maximum cost-effectiveness We will develop a new low-cost, camera designed specifically for the needs of China. This device will produce both high-quality colour images and optical coherence tomography (OCT) images of the retina. OCT is widely available but current commercial systems are very expensive.  Our new device will be based on our novel patent-pending technology and will be first tested on human donor tissue.  We will develop and evaluate new, automated image analysis techniques allowing computers to learn to analyse both colour and OCT images of the retina. We aim to produce systems capable of differentiating between patients with and without DR and between those with mild/moderate and severe disease at the time and place of patient care. In order to achieve a high level of diagnostic accuracy (over and above automated image analysis), we will develop and evaluate a new human learning system. This system will harness the collective judgements of Chinese health workers to rank images in terms of DR severity. We will create a self-sustaining network of activity where novices and experts support each other in making effective clinical judgements. We will develop new statistical methods to underpin the system and to evaluate both diagnostic accuracy and performance of the health workers. Our imaging and diagnostic system will be validated in 241 patients with diabetes in the UK. Our project team in China will then undertake a pilot study of 461 patients and a costing exercise. The diagnostic accuracy of the system and its cost-effectiveness will be investigated. We will engage policy makers through our Chinese team who occupy leading roles in the CMA. Detection and treatment of sight threatening DR will prevent disability with benefit to Chinese society and China&apos;s economy. Our systems will upskill health care workers, strengthen existing health systems and build research capacity in China. Dissemination of our techniques through open-sourcesoftware will maximise benefits for other low and middle-income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-21">92355.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-21">370158.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-21">377580.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-21">310355.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-02-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-02-21">11504500.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R014094_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FR014094%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
