<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021972_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The mechanisms underlying the production of natural mosquito repellents by human beings</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives  Our overall hypothesis is that the identification of genes that control the production of natural repellents by the human body could lead to the discovery of new ways to protect against mosquito biting. This research will also provide fundamental insights into how humans produce natural repellents, which may be a form of natural protection and the first arm of the body&apos;s innate immune system against mosquito-borne diseases, or a way in which mosquitoes avoid unsuitable hosts. There are 3 overarching objectives examining the chemistry and genomics associated with the production of natural repellents by the human body. Objective 1. Identify human volatiles that attract or repel mosquitoes in UK study subjects. We will correlate mosquito attractiveness of participants to their body odour chemistry in sets of twins using established laboratory behavioural studies, volatile collection techniques and analytical chemistry. We have selected twins since they have been genotyped as part of the Twins UK database. Although we have already demonstrated that chemistry is associated with differential attractiveness in a pilot study, we need to increase the sample size to directly correlate genetic studies with the level of attractiveness to mosquitoes and specifically associated chemistry.  In doing this we will: a. Determine the relative attractiveness of identical and non-identical twin pairs in the UK to Anopheles gambiae mosquitoes by testing the odours from 100 sets of twins from Twins UK database in a behavioural wind tunnel; b. Collect volatile body odours using nylon socks, as Anopheles mosquitoes are known to be highly attracted to foot odour, and air entrainment of whole bodies for chemical analysis;  c. Analyse volatile samples collected from participants in (b) using gas chromatography (GC), GC-electroantennography and GC-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) to confirm that the already known repellent compounds are associated with attractiveness and identify new associated chemistry. Objective 2. Test the genetic basis of attraction and repellency to mosquitoes using, for the first time, a natural host-vector-parasite system. Evolutionary theory may suggest that people who repel mosquitoes will have a survival advantage against mosquito-borne diseases such as malaria, conferring a survival advantage for &apos;repellent&apos; individuals. It might follow that a genetic effect would be stronger in indigenous Africans compared with Europeans. Here, we will determine the relative level of attractiveness of 100 pairs of identical and non-identical Gambian twins, repeating (a), (b) and (c) above. We hypothesise that, if attractiveness or repellency has a genetic basis, the variation in attractiveness between twins will be greater in non-identical twins than identical twins. We will also test whether the presence of malaria parasites in our study population affects the level of attractiveness to mosquitoes. This will allow us to investigate a natural, long-established host-vector-parasite system. Objective 3. Identify genes involved in the production of mosquito repellents We will use existing genome-wide single nucleotide polymorphism data to perform a staged association analysis of attractiveness in twins tested in Objectives 1 and 2 to identify genetic variants associated with differential attractiveness to malaria mosquitoes, and the production of natural repellents.  a. Analyse participant samples to investigate HLA and CYP11A1 as specific functional candidate loci which we suggest is likely to be involved in the oxidative production of the repellents identified so far. b. Investigate broader groups of candidate genes through RNA-Seq to determine correlations in the transcriptome associated with the repellent production. This will allow direct identification of candidate biosynthesis genes which should also provide opportunities for further identification of candidate regulatory genes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Some human beings are bitten more than others by mosquitoes. From an evolutionary perspective this is fundamentally important since those that get bitten less often are less likely to die from lethal mosquito-borne diseases like malaria. Thus there is likely to be a selective advantage for being less attractive to malaria mosquitoes. Whether or not this is due to natural selection in humans, or because mosquitoes are simply avoiding unsuitable hosts is unknown, but our previous studies show that human differential attractiveness to mosquitoes is due to the natural production of key repellent chemicals given off by individuals who rarely get bitten. Essentially this could be thought of as the first line of defence related to the immune system. In a recent pilot study we showed that for Europeans how attractive you are to mosquitoes is controlled by your genes. We intend to extend this line of research and carry out a similar study amongst an indigenous African population that has traditionally been under intense selective pressure from malaria. Here we would anticipate finding genes for new repellent molecules that are under selection. The natural repellent chemicals that we have identified from our study of Europeans are effective repellents when applied to the skin, but what remains unknown is how the body produces these chemicals and which genes control this process. Preliminary studies show that some of the repellents can be produced by skin cells and there are likely candidate genes as potential targets. In this study we aim to compare identical and non-identical twins using chemical ecology and molecular genetic techniques to identify how the chemicals are produced and which genes are involved in production and regulation. This will give an understanding of how the body provides an important component of natural resistance to mosquitoes and provide a new potential treatment which stimulates production of these repellent chemicals in susceptible human beings. This could allow us to develop a more persistent application and eventually an oral treatment in the form of a pill which enhances the production of natural repellents to protect against mosquito bites, minimising the need for repeated skin-applied volatile repellents. This research has the potential to find new mosquito repellents that could be produced systemically, and elucidate one of the least understood innate immunity mechanisms: how we use chemical warfare to hide from vectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gambia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">111007.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">222915.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">224720.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">112813.55</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-16">671457.234</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021972_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP021972%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
