<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R025525_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cellular immunity and resistance to schistosomiasis in the Philippines</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Schistosomiasis, also known as bilharzia or snailfever, is a parasitic worm infection currently infecting more than 200 million people worldwide. Infection remains a major health risk in the Philippines, with an estimated 2 million Filipinos infected and 12 million of the population at risk of infection. Humans are infected though contact with fresh water, such as rice paddies and streams, where the snails carrying the parasite live. Once inside the human host the adult worms produce eggs, which get stuck in the liver and other organs where they evoke inflammation and blockages. No vaccine is currently available and despite attempts to control the infection with mass drug treatment programs, low-grade chronic infections leading to anaemia, growth retardation and cognitive impairment are still prevalent. Re-infection occurs quickly even after treatment since the parasite is still widespread in water sources which people need to access.  The overall aim of this proposal is to assess the role of various types of immune cells in the development of resistance or susceptibility to schistosome reinfection, with a long term goal to support vaccine development. Previous studies have shown that individuals that have high levels of a particular type of antibody (IgE) in their blood are more resistant to becoming reinfected with schistosomiasis after drug treatment, whilst individuals with a different type of antibody (IgG4) are more susceptible to becoming reinfected. However, what is not known is what type of immune cells and mediators are involved in controlling what kind of antibodies are generated in different people. In order to develop effective vaccines against schistosomiasis, we need to have a better understanding of how protective, as well as non-protective immune responses are generated in naturally infected humans. This proposal aim to address this gap in knowledge by analysing immune function correlates of protection and susceptibility in individuals living in a schistosome endemic area of the Philippines. Antibodies are produced by B cells but various types of T cells are important in instructing the B cells in what kind of antibodies they should produce. We are particularly interested two specific types of T cells, known as follicular T helper cells (Tfh) and follicular T regulatory cells (Tfr), as well as the mediators they produce, in order to determine whether these particular cells are responsible for influencing the antibody classes produced during infection. We hypothesise that an individual&apos;s Tfh and Tfr numbers and phenotypes are crucial in determining if they become resistant or susceptible to reinfection. No previous studies have investigated the interaction between Tfh, Tfr and B cells in schistosomiasis and the new information gathered from this study will be of great importance for the ability to develop the vaccine needed to combat this debilitating disease in the Philippines and other parts of the world. Schistosomiasis is a major public health problem and a barrier to social and economic development in the resource poor areas of the Philippines. Our application will promote advancement in biotechnology and health sciences that will impact public health in the Philippines and globally. Our proposal also has the added benefit of potentiating both the international mobility of Filipino researchers and the establishment of sustainable global scientific partnerships. Collectively, these advances in scientific understanding and in capacity building will provide a framework for tackling barriers to development and for nurturing progress, with Filipino investigators being key drivers in change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of the current proposal is to identify the protective immunological phenotype of individuals resistant to reinfection with S.japonicum in the Philippines.   We hypothesise that: (i) Cytokines produced by Tfh cells upon schistosome antigen stimulation influence the antibody isotype produced by B cells in infected individuals. (ii) Immunomodulation by chronic schistosomiasis infection, possibly mediated by IL-10-producing Tfr cells or B regulatory cells, limits antibody production. (iii) Biomarkers of Tfh activity in human serum will act as predictors of resistance or susceptibility to reinfection.  Objectives: 1. To determine the phenotypes and activation status of T and B cell subsets in peripheral blood and to correlate this with parasite-specific IgE and IgG4 levels in serum, collected pre- and post-treatment, to seek out associations between the cellular phenotypes, cytokines, antibody types and reinfection rates 12 months after treatment.  2. To identify serum biomarkers that will serve as identifiers of individuals at high risk of reinfection. 3. To improve the sensitivity and accuracy of diagnosis in low-intensity settings, and thereby increase the precision of our analysis of immune correlates of resistance and susceptibility in this setting.  Finally, we will also promote capacity building, through technology transfer, training and exchange of researchers between the UK and Philippines. In particular, Filipino scientists will be trained with use of a multiparameter flow cytometry - the work horse of cellular immunology experiments for which an investment is being made by RITM - and other immunological assays.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133903" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines (the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">57567.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">135815.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">126685.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">48273.94</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">368342.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Newton Fund Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/R025525/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR025525%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
