<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_R010625_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">School, territory and post-conflict: grounding a local peace culture in Tolima, Colombia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project seeks to contribute to peacebuilding in South Tolima, by working with school, teachers and community leaders from four municipalities (Ataco, Chaparral, Planadas and Rioblanco) in the design and development of a pedagogical strategy for the construction of a local culture of peace that can be developed through schools.  Using action-research, the project seeks to make visible the experiences that children, teenagers, teachers, parents and community leaders have had with the armed conflict and, from there, to generate with them proposals for peacebuilding in schools. This pedagogical strategy will be designed and developed jointly with the local actor University of Ibague through the Peace and Region Programme and Eureka Educativa, working with teachers and leaders in two central themes: a) school life and armed conflict and, b) territory, natural resources and post-conflict. The project makes two innovative contributions. First, it uses a collaborative research approach between scholars and community members, developed by the actors themselves (children, teenagers, teachers, parents and leaders) as a fundamental element to bottom-up peacebuilding efforts. This perspective implies a change in the traditional way in which research projects are structured, by transforming the role of both professional researchers and local participants in the research process. The coordinating team will have, fundamentally, a role in training, mediating and accompanying teachers, students and leaders, while the latter will actively participate in research and develop proposals that are rooted in a local perspective of conflict transformation. Second, the research will use media, arts and literature as a way of eliciting dialogue among collaborators and local actors during and after the research process. This way of carrying out research and applying the results to the interests of the education sector and the community ultimately seeks to achieve a social appropriation of the knowledge produced in the project so that it can have a long-lasting effect on the construction of a local peace culture in Tolima. The project is organized into four components: a) research, b) capacity-building for teachers, students and community leaders, c) appropriation and dialogue of knowledge between the educational community, community organizations and regional institutions, and d) the production of physical and virtual outputs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-05-14"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="CO" type="COLOMBIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">117915.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">170236.99</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">32995.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="General Objective:  To contribute to the sustainability of peace in the south of the Department of Tolima through: (1) The generation and social appropriation of knowledge derived from the realization of a research project on the impact of the conflict on educational institutions and in particular, in the consolidation of a culture of peace and reconciliation in the Territory, and (2) The implementation of pedagogical strategy aimed at the construction of a culture of local peace for southern Tolima to be driven by the schools as a result of the research process.   Specific objectives:  - To jointly develop with community organizations, teachers and students from rural and urban schools in Southern Tolima a research process on how the different forms of conflict (armed, social, socio-environmental) and the post-conflict period has affected life in schools, the community and the relationship with the environment and territory. - To jointly design a model for the construction of peace in schools and the municipalities of South Tolima that is rooted in memories of the armed conflict, cultural and environmental heritage, and visions of a desired future. - To propose education strategies for the construction of a local culture of peace in schools that can help to strengthen local development and a sense of reconnection to the territory and place in Tolima."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
