<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S014152_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International - Untangling the origin and movement of ghost nets in the Indian Ocean to aid management and mitigation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Modern fishing nets are made to last. In contrast to other plastic marine pollution, fishing nets are also explicitly designed to entrap marine life. When lost or discarded these durable nylon, polypropylene or polyethylene nets remain intact and afloat for decades. Consequently, they continue to &apos;ghost fish&apos; valuable fish stocks and damage critical coastal resources like coral reefs essential for sustaining artisanal fisheries and tourism-dependent communities. The now familiar image of lost or discarded fishing nets entangled with decomposing turtles, fish, seabirds and other creatures, attest to the deadly nature of this marine pollution. Less well recognised is the threat these &apos;ghost nets&apos; pose to the food security and sustainable economic development of developing coastal nations. In 2015 the Global Ghost Gear Initiative (GGGI), a cross-sectorial alliance of stakeholders from the fishing industry, the private sector, NGOs, governments and intergovenmental organisations was launched to drive solutions to the problem of lost and abandoned fishing gear worldwide within the UN Global Partnership on Marine Litter. The GGGI has three strategic approaches; build evidence, define best practices and inform policies, and catalyse mitigation solutions. For the Indian Ocean the major local NGO stakeholder is the Olive Ridley Project (ORP; http://oliveridleyproject.org/), the CEO of which is a previous chair of the GGGI &apos;Build Evidence&apos; Working Group. Our Innovation Project &quot;Untangling the origin and movement of ghost nets in the Indian Ocean to aid management and mitigation&quot; has been co-developed with both ORP and GGGI. The Maldives are particularly vulnerable to this type of marine debris. Over 700 conglomerates of multiple individual nets and other fishing gear were recovered by Maldivian ORP citizen science volunteers between 2013-2017. These numbers represent only the tip of the iceberg in this vast remote region. Nets are not officially used in Maldivian fisheries, indicating that this local environmental crisis has come from far afield in the Indian Ocean, crossing international borders and turtle migration pathways. Clearly the problem needs addressing at the point of origin, but this is very difficult to pinpoint; the Indian Ocean contains a large number of low-income countries and is an extremely active region for international commercial fishing, as well as illegal and unreported fishing activities. Evidence is required to identify which regional fishing grounds are responsible for the ghost gear. It would also be invaluable for both mitigation and conservation efforts to demonstrate the journey ghost nets take, and areas of accumulation, as they drift across the ocean with the currents. In this project we propose to combine state-of-the-art ocean dispersal modelling and visualisation tools developed at Bristol University using one of the fastest and most advance supercomputing facilities in the UK, with data on recovered ghost nets from citizen science projects run by ORP in Thailand, Pakistan, India, Oman and the Maldives to backtrack their likely source within the Indian Ocean. We will modify our modelling capabilities, originally developed to identify the pathways coral larvae take from one reef to another across thousands of miles, applying this powerful tool to instead simulate the oceanic transport of nets. Visualisation tools developed during a NERC ERIIP funded project to map the probability of jellyfish blooms being transported to coastal power plants will be translated here to communicate the statistical likelihood of ghost gear originating from specific regional-scale fishing grounds stranding in the Maldives and other problem areas. The outcome of our collaboration will be strategic targeting of education and outreach efforts at the responsible sector and region by the ORP based on strong scientific evidence that will also be used by the GGGI to support transboundary decision-making and policy change actions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our primary aim is to demonstrate which international fishing grounds are responsible for abandoned, lost or otherwise discarded fishing nets arriving in the Maldives. This knowledge will allow the UK-based Project Partner and the Olive Ridley Project (ORP; registered UK charity no. 1165905) to strategically target their community-level education and mitigation efforts to decrease the volume of ghost fishing gear entering the Indian Ocean. Whereas, the Project Partner Global Ghost Gear Initiative (GGGI) will use this scientific evidence to drive change within the fishing industry sectors responsible, identify where solutions to the problem of lost and abandoned fishing gear and improved practice are required, and to support evidenced-based policy development at regional and international scales. The outcome will be a reduction in the deadly impact and damage of this marine pollution on the Maldives, and improved sustainability of coastal communities across the Indian Ocean.   Our project will result in the following outputs as tools for project partner decision-making and knowledge transfer: Output 1: Gridded maps of the probability of ghost nets arriving at the Maldives from fishing grounds across the Indian Ocean. These will be used by the project partners to target their actions. Output 2: Maps highlighting hotspots for ghost net accumulation and stranding across the Indian Ocean. These will be used by the project partners to identify where high densities of nets overlap with migratory species of conservation priority, and which coastlines and coral reefs are most impacted by this form of marine debris in order to target conservation efforts such as direct recovery.  In order to achieve these outputs we will complete the following objectives: Objective 1: Simulate the potential journeys of fishing gear that are discarded or lost from individual Indian Ocean fishing grounds to identify where they would accumulate and strand, using a method developed during a NERC funded project to simulate larval dispersal between global coral reefs (Wood et al., 2014). Objective 2: Using the modelling output, &apos;backtrack&apos; the likely source locations (to a local level) of nets recovered from monitored sites in the Maldives, Pakistan, Oman, Thailand and India (ORP citizen science dataset) and compare these with evidence of regional source from ORP ghost net data collections. Objective 3: Develop appropriate graphics and visualisations of the project output for presentation to various relevant stakeholders, in collaboration with ORP, building on a NERC ERIIP funded project to develop an early warning system of jellyfish ingress at UK coastal power stations.  The critical milestone is the IUCN Congress to be held in Marseilles, France (June 2020) where GGGI will be contributing evidence to assist transboundary environmental decision-making by actively interacting with leaders from government, civil society, indigenous peoples&apos; organisations, business and academia to address this pressing environmental and development challenge to sustainable coastal Indian Ocean communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MV" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Maldives</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-30">106216.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Innovation Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE/S014152/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">18912.3</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S014152_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">27413.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S014152_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">27413.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S014152_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FS014152%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
