<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T013613_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Law of Protracted Conflict: Overcoming the Humanitarian-Development Divide</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Contemporary armed conflicts have become protracted, complex and urbanised with far-reaching socio-economic consequences, such as severe damage to infrastructure, disruption of services, and protracted displacement. The dire socio-economic dimensions of protracted conflicts, as well as the link between poverty and fragility, render the traditional divide between humanitarian and development assistance unfeasible to address the short- and long-term needs of affected communities. The proposed project will provide a comprehensive analysis of the institutional and substantive legal frameworks within which humanitarian and development assistance are delivered. Its aim is to investigate the extent to which international law enables integrated, sustainable and accountable humanitarian and development assistance in contexts of protracted conflicts. The project will deliver on its aim through three closely connected work packages (WP) that focus on institutions, legal regimes and accountability, respectively. WP 1 charts the multitude of humanitarian and development actors operating in contexts of protracted conflicts and examines whether their mandates, principles, legal relations, and institutional structures are amenable to the creation of a humanitarian-development nexus. WP 2 focuses on the interactions between legal regimes applicable to protracted conflicts, with a view to evaluating whether international law contributes to the creation of the divide between the two sectors or can in fact provide legal common grounds to overcome the divide between them. Lastly, WP 3 assesses the need for new standards and mechanisms to ensure the inclusion of and accountability to affected communities in light of the expanding and interconnected nature of humanitarian and development responses. The project will be the first to approach the divide between humanitarian and development assistance comprehensively from an international law perspective. Moreover, it will clarify the laws that pertain to the underexplored, socio-economic dimensions of protracted conflicts. Therefore, the project will make fundamental advances in the field of international law, as well as the multidisciplinary fields of humanitarianism, development, transitional justice, and peacebuilding. More broadly, the research findings of the project will contribute to some of the fundamental debates in international law, for example, on the evolution of international (humanitarian) law in face of the changing characteristics of armed conflicts, regime interactions and fragmentation of international law, and the expanding role and authority of non-state actors, particularly international organisations, in global governance. Beyond its contributions to scholarship, the project will develop legal and policy recommendations for the interpretation and design of international law and thus engage in knowledge transfer for international cooperation towards the operationalisation of the humanitarian-development nexus.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main aims of the project are to clarify the legal frameworks applicable to socio-economic dimensions of protracted conflicts and to examine the legal drivers of the humanitarian-development divide. The objectives of the project relating to these aims are to: 1) identify the legal challenges and modalities for the integration of development and humanitarian sectors at the institutional and systemic levels; 2) examine the interactions between various legal regimes relevant to the socio-economic dimensions of protracted conflicts; 3) assess the body of accountability standards and mechanisms present in humanitarian and development sectors in order to understand how they can be adjusted to ensure both the effectiveness and the accountability of international action under the conditions of protracted conflict; 4) develop, as an overarching aim of the project, legal and policy recommendations for the interpretation and design of international legal rules that facilitate sustainable humanitarian and development assistance in building resilience and peace. Pursuing these aims and objectives, the project will make fundamental advances in the field of international law, most notably by examining how the socio-economic dimensions of protracted armed conflicts can be addressed by the applicable legal frameworks and how an integrated and sustainable humanitarian and development response can be anchored in and promoted by international law. More broadly, the research findings of the project will contribute to some of the fundamental debates in international law, for example, on regime interaction and the fragmentation of international law, the expanding role of international organisations in global governance, and the evolution of international (humanitarian) law in face of the changing characteristics of armed conflicts. Beyond international law, the project will make substantial contributions to the multidisciplinary fields of humanitarianism, development, and peacebuilding. The research findings of the project are conducive to practical application and knowledge transfer; they will contribute to the international cooperation towards the operationalisation of the humanitarian-development nexus in the pursuit of sustainable peace. The ambition of the project in this regard directly aligns with the DFG&apos;s funding principle of supporting knowledge transfer and AHRC&apos;s 2016-2020 International Collaboration, Global Challenges and Development Goals, particularly in the area of &quot;Conflict, Humanitarian Aid and Human Rights&quot;. The project will also facilitate the realisation of the commitments of Germany and the UK to the Sustaining Peace agenda and to the operationalisation of the humanitarian-development nexus, as well as the post-Brexit cooperation between the two countries in these fields.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic Republic of the Congo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-20">94537.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-20">78990.25</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-20">63443.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-20">315960.976</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T013613_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT013613%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
