<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007958_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementation Action Team: Cultural Heritage Promoting Quality of Life and Sustainable Development in the At-Risk Megacity Periphery of Kolkata</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The areas targeted by the Implementation Action Team (IAT) are cities on the banks of Hugli River in West Bengal, India. The origins of the unique value of much of their built heritage can be traced back to European trading and fortification (the French in Chandannagar from the 1670s, the Danes urbanizing Serampore from the 1750s and Barrackpore being developed by the British in the 1770s). During the nineteenth century, Indian merchants and traders who enriched themselves supplying the Europeans had grand residences built in a highly original hybrid style: their Palladian facades mirrored the public buildings built by the Europeans, but their cloistered inner courtyards were geared to the climate, multiple family occupancy and to Hindu devotional practice. The importance of this wealth of built heritage and the hybrid cultural heritage that has sprung from it in terms of food cultures, musical traditions, language variation etc, led the UK historian of heritage conservation Philip Davies to comment in 2015 that the Hugli &apos;is not just an Indian river but belongs to the world&apos;. The state of West Bengal lies below the median in terms of many of the standard development markers when compared against other Indian states and the state of the heritage and tourism sectors reflect this. For example, the first hotel for overseas visitors opened in Serampore only in 2018. The economic liberalization of India starting in 1991, however, has led to  the Hugli Corridor being subjected to overwhelming and accelerating urbanization increasing the population density, but this wave of so-called development has put domestic built heritage at extreme risk. The developers&apos; imperative is that its riverine environment and excellent commuter rail links make the Hugli Corridor the ideal suburban dormitory pendant to the megacity of Kolkata (population 14.03M in the 2011 census). The Hugli Corridor&apos;s Unique Selling Point, therefore, also places it at the highest risk. In the absence of any enforceable planning law and building control, hundreds of heritage properties have been demolished and replaced by three-storey, identikit, concrete flats. IAT&apos;s partners, the West Bengal Heritage Commission and the Serampore Initiative have both done important work, listing and renovating seven public buildings, but the IAT&apos;s blended mix of wealth-creation, renovation, education, well-being and documentary film pathways will show the West Bengal state government a diverse toolkit of ways to invest resources to preserve and develop the region&apos;s cultural and built heritage before it is too late. Crucially, the IAT will do this through the people and organisations that its predecessor project, the Hugli River of Cultures Project (HRCP), won and up-skilled for the cause of heritage. The predecessor AHRC-ICHR funded Hugli River of Cultures Project documented heritage assets and sensitized large numbers of people into how the river connects them, but the IAT&apos;s pathway activities will make selected key individuals even more active throughout 2020. Those individuals will no longer be only witnesses and co-creators of heritage knowledge, they will move up to the next level and apply the IAT&apos;s tools to built and cultural heritage and used both to create wealth and well-being for themselves in a sustainable manner. When in ends in January 2021, the Implementation Action Team (IAT) will show the new agency that West Bengalis from diverse socio-economic groups can have in creating bottom-up heritage infrastructure in their state (pop 98.8M, 2018), thus marking a radical and much-needed change of course from the overwhelming top-down, culturally elitist and (rather unfortunate) superficial efforts that have characterized official interventions to date (not WBHC). It is only with active intervention and skilled local people that effective action can be taken to address the present heritage emergency caused by urban sprawl and to prepare this low-lying region for climate change</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are seven objectives of equal priority and two &apos;partnerships for the goals&apos; with the Denmark-India Serampore Initiative and the West Bengal Heritage Commission: 1. The project aims that 10 young professionals gain official tourist guiding accreditation in a public private partnership through our Hugli Heritage Enterprise Incubator (HHEI); 2. That three large schools, of up to 1000 students each, participate with their teachers in project-based, employment-focused schools heritage activity (EF-SHA) that allows students, teachers and parents to use the Implementation Action Team&apos;s (IAT&apos;s) equipment and know-how to raise funds for preservation of the history and heritage of their school or a significant building in their locality. 3. That there are 432 places in a total of 36 seminars on both individuals&apos; sensitization and community awareness of heritage as part of a Heritage and Mental Well-Being Programme (H-MWB-P). 4. That the IAT&apos;s conservation architect and Sir James Stirling Chair of Architecture in the University of Liverpool, works with Konnagar Municipality to create a sensory garden and museum displays which recognize the key role the Tagore family riverside garden house played in the development of Indian modernist painting. This is action for community resource development in Konnagar (CRD-K), a city on the urban periphery of Kolkata (population 76,172 in 2011), where public leisure space is in extremely short supply. 5. That the first Masons&apos; and Allied Trades&apos; Centre of Excellence in the Hugli Corridor (MAT-CE) be established in Chandannagar. Here master masons from Murshidabad, outside the immediate region, and currently working with our partner the Serampore Initiative, train allied tradesmen and women in building restoration techniques in order to form local teams that can demonstrate their skills with sample demonstration micro restoration projects at five large heritage dwellings identified according to need. 6, the work of the MAT-CE and the two best-in-region heritage precinct restorations in Barrackpore Park and Serampore (as well as an impact audit thereof) will then all be the subjects of two 30 and one 10-minute films. These are to be produced by the Heritage Education Film Unit (HEF-U), a direct spin off of the film work of the predecessor Hugli River of Cultures Project (HRCP). 7. a UK expert environmental assessor will use drone captured images  to create a single map of the stretch of the Hugli corridor from Chandannagar to Konnagar that will allow different groups of town and transport infrastructure planners to better connect heritage assets with transport nodes at different points in the day, allowing main and subsidiary heritage precincts to be identified. The Implementation Action Team&apos;s partnership for the goals with the Denmark-India Serampore Initiative is zero cost and in-kind; it will allow the IAT to have the benefits of the Initiative&apos;s contacts, work plans and, above all, practical expertise of heritage renovation in West Bengal. The Serampore Initiative started started in 2008, but is reaching the end of its life cycle. This partnership with the Serampore Initiative will be supported in terms of personnel by the Hugli Chapter of the Indian National Trust for Arts and Cultural Heritage, that is to be formed in January 2020 as one of the outputs and lasting legacies of the predecessor Hugli River of Cultures Project (HRCP). The partnership and the additional support will further the ultimate aim of allowing the IAT to continue some or all of its seven pathway activities beyond January 2021, after the end of the twelve-month funding period. This ultimate aim of continuity will be facilitated and funded by the West Bengal Heritage Commission, an official state body that has offered us an accreditation partnership. Full details of these project partnerships can be found in the form of Letters of Support in the Attachments section.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-30">80363.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">80363.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007958_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
