<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P004253_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China&apos;s International Financial Integration - Impact on Financial Development and Stability</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the most important macroeconomic developments in the coming decades will be China&apos;s rapid financial integration into the world economy.  Together as a group, emerging economies&apos; GDP has risen from 20% to over 80% of advanced economies&apos; GDP in the last two decades, and constitute 50% of world GDP. Global dynamics will increasingly be characterized by an advanced bloc and an emerging bloc, in which China plays a central role. There are important economic differences between the two sets of countries that can be crucial for determining the global equilibrium - perhaps most notably in financial development. In China&apos;s case its financial markets and macroeconomic conditions differ significantly from those of other emerging economies, suggesting caution when drawing historical parallels or lessons for globalization.  As the world&apos;s second largest economy, China&apos;s full integration into global financial markets will invariably impact the world economy. At the same time, the ramifications on the Chinese economy - given the particular characteristics of its financial development - are still largely unknown, as a result of the dearth of frameworks to analyze heterogeneous economies in a global setting. Our aim is to study the impact of its financial liberalization for China and the rest of the world-from a positive and a normative perspective.   Our research agenda focuses on developing hitherto non-existing frameworks for integrating China&apos;s particular financial market conditions in an open-economy macroeconomic setting. Typically, the existing literature focuses on the effects associated with particular financial frictions - such as collateral constraints, and limited enforcement in repayment. While these frictions may also be important for China, they are unlikely to be the most prominent. China&apos;s financial market distortions have certain distinct features: 1) financial repression; 2) a two-sector economy where the state sector is significantly less credit-constrained than the private sector; and 3) the prominence of banks in financial markets, among others.  The research projects intend to explore the impact of a country with these financial frictions and the process of financial integration. Important questions that deserve a thorough investigation include: given the described frictions, what is the impact of financial globalization on capital flows, exchange rate dynamics, and growth? Under what conditions would financial crises occur, and are they more or less costly than the crises that would have occurred in a closed-economy?  From a normative perspective, should financial development and financial liberalization happen sequentially or simultaneously? Would liberalization induce faster financial development? Are these policy goals potentially conflicting and/or self-defeating?  How are global financial shocks transmitted to China, and conversely how are China&apos;s shocks transmitted to the rest of the world?   China also differs from other emerging economies in its macroeconomic conditions. It is a net saver, and runs a significant current account surplus. Traditionally, emerging market financial crises have come from within: financial dollarisation, excessive deregulation, allocation inefficiencies due to high level of state ownership, etc. In the global financial crisis a negative shock from advanced economies was transmitted to emerging economies heavily financed through foreign investment, with domestic credit constraints amplifying these shocks.  This research aims to fill a gap in the literature and directly address China&apos;s particular problems.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective is to investigate the domestic and international impact of China&apos;s financial integration into the world. China financial development has distinct features, with important domestic distortions that may interact with financial liberalization. So far, there is no framework suitable to analyze China in a global economy setting.   The objective is to fill in the gap by developing frameworks that incorporate China as a &apos;large open economy&apos; impacting the rest of the world and with its unique financial and macroeconomic characteristics. Emerging market financial development is usually captured by credit constraints limiting the amount it can borrow internationally. However, China&apos;s financial conditions are primarily characterized by: (1) financial repression (policies that regulate interest rates and mandatorily allocate resources); (2) a two-sector economy with the state sector significantly less credit-constrained than the private sector; (3) banking sector dominance; and (4) a dearth of `liquid assets&apos;. So far, none of these distortions have been introduced in a global setting with two large open economies.   The proposed framework is very much needed to evaluate the impact of financial liberalization of economies with slow internal financial development. We would be the first to incorporate firm dynamics, financial distortions, and aggregate uncertainty in a two-country setup. With the discipline of a general equilibrium model, we can estimate the model via Bayesian methods and assess to what extent it can capture the macroeconomic dynamics of the Chinese economy observed in the past two decades.   Such a model would help us answer a host of questions such as: Do firms choose riskier projects after financial liberalization when domestic financial distortions are removed? What&apos;s the welfare gain from removing each type of financial distortion? What&apos;s the implied GDP growth with perfect domestic financial markets and financial liberalization? Will Chinese economy respond more or less to international shocks (in particular financial shocks) after financial liberalization with or without domestic distortions?    With this framework, one can then conduct a normative analysis, and answer important policy questions such as: should China&apos;s domestic financial development and financial liberalization happen sequentially or simultaneously? Or would liberalization induce faster financial development? Are these policy goals potentially conflicting and self-defeating?   Substantial empirical analysis is necessary alongside the theoretical work. Apart from the ones described in the research proposal, the endeavor also involves collecting relevant financial and macroeconomic data, including credit, cross-border assets and liabilities, domestic bank assets and liabilities. These variables help us understand the build-up of financial fragility before the Great Recession and the Eurozone crises, but are also of critical importance for China. Only once the country balance sheet has been systematically constructed and evaluated can the economy&apos;s financial vulnerability be consistently monitored.  In sum, the main objective is to help understand how China&apos;s financial integration with its particular financial frictions would affect China and the rest of the world, and what approach it should take to liberalize its financial markets - so as to maintain its growth prospects and alleviate, not accentuate its own domestic distortions, potentially causing global financial instability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China (People&apos;s Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-16">28284.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-16">113365.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-16">108189.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-16">45300.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
