<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005099_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Youth engagement and skills acquisition within Africa&apos;s transport sector: promoting a gender agenda towards transitions into meaningful work</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. The main project objective is to help disadvantaged girls and young women improve their skills in engaging with Africa&apos;s transport sector (whether as users or workers/employees) and thus expand their opportunities for accessing meaningful work.  The proposal is set within the specific context of Africa&apos;s highly gendered transport and travel arena.  Development strategies emphasise the importance of recruiting young women as active labour force participants, requiring them to be increasingly spatially mobile.  However, women are discriminated against, both regarding access and use of transport (which affects their access to education, skills acquisition and employment in all sectors) and with reference to employment within the transport sector itself.  Women need to start acquiring relevant skills  at a young age, if they are to break through such barriers and contribute to reformulating policy prescriptions through pressures &apos;from below&apos;.  Through research in peripheral areas of three diverse African cities, Abuja, Cape Town and Tunis, where girls&apos;/women&apos;s experiences in the transport sector have often been profoundly discouraging, we seek to understand the nature and scale of gender inequalities shaped by transport sector practices and the implications for young women&apos;s skills acquisition and employment prospects (within and beyond the transport sector). We will then pilot sets of interventions that address them.  2. This requires a cross-cutting, 3-strand interdisciplinary approach: a) The Employment strand, comprising research into learning how to improve young women&apos;s access to skills (e.g. commercial driving, vehicle repair/maintenance) that can  enable them to obtain meaningful employment in the transport sector.   b) The User Strand, comprising research into improving girls&apos;/young women&apos;s use of transport for travel to access training programmes/employment.  It will explore how young women&apos;s physical access to meaningful work and associated skills building is shaped by their travel potential and access to transport (especially re travel safety and security in low income areas) and what key skills they need to travel safely to work/training opportunities (whether as pedestrians, as cyclists, or when negotiating public transport).  It will then explore how appropriate safe travel skills training can best be provided.     c) The Action Research Strand will build on User and Employment Strands findings.  With NGO support it will pilot transport-related skills training activities for women relevant to each of those strands, to improve their access to employment [both directly, through transport-employment skills, and indirectly, through travel safety skills that will enable them to travel to diverse employment opportunities].  3.  Intensive, sustained engagement with communities, local and central government (transport, labour, education, women&apos;s affairs), transport unions, NGOs, private sector (transport and mobile phone network providers), is essential to aid understanding of wider political, economic and social constraints and opportunities in Nigeria, S.African and Tunisia.  Country Consultative Groups, set up with representatives of these diverse interests, will meet 6-monthly to promote engagement with the research design and aid analysis, intervention and dissemination activities.   4. Participatory approaches employed throughout, to ensure young people&apos;s voices are heard/acted upon. A small group of young women in each country will be trained as community co-investigators to help establish key research questions through peer interviews (Porter 2016).  Other participatory work includes in-depth (including mobile) interviews and participant photography.    5. Academic capacity building through mentoring of an early career researcher by a senior academic in each country.  6. Wide dissemination of findings at local, national and international level (to government, private sector, NGOs, academia)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acknowledging the importance of mobilising Africa&apos;s young women into the labour-force, this research addresses the specific impediments presented by a highly gendered transport and travel arena and the implications this has for girls&apos; and women&apos;s current/future access to meaningful work.  Women of all ages are discriminated against, both with regard to access and use of transport (which affects their access to skills acquisition and employment across all sectors) and with reference to their employment within the transport sector itself.  Relevant skills acquisition at an early age, for safely navigating transport and more equitably seeking employment is essential if  they are to break through such barriers.    We aim to understand and address these challenges through in-depth participatory research with young women of low socio-economic status in peripheral locations of Nigeria, South Africa and Tunisia (one city-region per country), including piloting of skills-based interventions.    The research has three, interlinked strands:  a)The User Strand comprises research into improving young women&apos;s use of transport to access training programmes and employment, built around the following questions:  -What are the economic, social and infrastructural determinants of the transport ecology in which young  women are located and how does it impact on their transport experiences and behaviours? -How is young women&apos;s physical access to meaningful work and associated skills building shaped by their travel potential and access to transport (i.e. especially travel safety and security for women resident in low income areas)?    -What key skills do young women need if they are to travel safely to work and training opportunities (whether as pedestrians, as cyclists, or when negotiating public transport)?  -How can appropriate safe travel skills training be provided?    -What wider interventions are needed to support a safe travel skills programme [e.g. from government, transport unions, NGOs, private sector] i.e. with reference to the multiple layers of political, economic and socio-cultural decision-making processes? b)The Employment Strand comprises research into improving women&apos;s access to skills (e.g. commercial driving, vehicle repair/ maintenance) to enable them to obtain more meaningful employment within the transport sector, built around the following questions:    - How have historical, social, political and economic legacies of planning and policy processes impacted on opportunities for women&apos;s employment in the transport sector?    -How can young women&apos;s aspirations to work in this sector be expanded and enhanced?  -What do young women perceive as the main barriers to skills acquisition and subsequent employment in the sector?  -What skills training can be provided to enable young women to play a more prominent role in the sector?  -What wider interventions are needed to support training programmes to improve women&apos;s employment in this sector [e.g. from government, unions, NGOs, the private sector] c)The Action Research Strand builds on User and Employment Strand findings.  It will pilot transport-related skills training for young women, to improve their access to employment [both directly, through employment in the transport sector and indirectly, through travel safety skills to enable them to travel to diverse employment opportunities].  Ihere will be small pilot action research projects in each country:  -One to assist women build skills as transport users [and thus access diverse employment opportunities within and beyond the transport sector]  -Up to 3 to assist women build skills towards employment in the transport sector. Intensive monitoring and evaluation of this strand throughout its life will ensure key lessons are learned.  Through this work we will produce gender-sensitive transport/travel skills guidance for govt, private sector, NGOs + academia at local, national + international levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">86182.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">345429.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">261346.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">779840.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to Durham University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005099_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FS005099%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-12-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
