<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S007059_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unlocking the potential of Seasonal Forests to underpin Wallacea&apos;s green economy</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives of this project are to: 1. explore the plant biodiversity of the understudied Seasonal Forests of Wallacea in East and West Nusa Tenggara Provinces, specifically on the islands of Sumbawa, Sumba and Flores.  2. investigate their response to environmental change, creating tools and resources to help land managers and local communities to understand their natural capital assets and use them to develop a sustainable natural resource-based economy.  3. produce a Natural Capital Asset Register of the region&apos;s plants (species, populations, communities, landscapes) through delivery of species checklist, maps, habitat and landscape mapping, species modelling, and ethnobotanical surveys.  5. undertake a programme of exploration generating plot and soil data and provide standing biomass and soil fertility data to understand ecosystem functions. 6. model responses of these landscapes and habitats to climate change  7. map areas of high ecological risk anthropogenic activities such as mining and infrastructure development, and red-list species to assess the resilience of biodiversity to environmental change.  8. determine which natural capital assets can be sustainably enhanced, working at both the species level, by identifying plant resources with further potential for economic exploitation for material and non-material benefits, and habitat level, by exploring the potential cultural services provided by forest-based eco-tourism.  9. to run a programme of capacity building to develop regional scientific capacity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will investigate the understudied Seasonal Forests of Wallacea in East and West Nusa Tenggara Provinces of Indonesia, specifically the islands of Sumbawa, Sumba and Flores, to assess how they will be affected by imminent environmental change and to evaluate their present and future economic potential. The forests of Indonesia are some of the most biodiverse but unexplored in the world with huge potential to be effectively managed to support economic development. To allow local communities to develop a stable green economy based on the region&apos;s natural capital assets, we must fully understand the forests&apos; diversity and distribution.  To address this need, we will first produce a Natural Capital Asset Register of the region&apos;s plant diversity consisting of species checklist, forest atlas derived from satellite imagery, ecoregion definition, and ethnobotany database. A structured programme of exploration across the three islands, generating plot and soil data, will give us an understanding of the standing biomass and soil fertility to understand ecosystem function. We will then compare these data to climatic variables to model the response of the Seasonal Forests of Wallacea to climate change and map anthropogenic risks, such as development for mining and infrastructure. We will carry out conservation red-listing to assess the resilience of the region&apos;s biodiversity to these environmental changes. Finally, we will determine which natural capital assets of the Seasonal Forests can be developed, working at both the species level, identifying plant resources that have further potential for economic exploitation and habitat level, exploring the potential for and risks of forest-based eco-tourism.  We will initiate a programme of capacity building to develop regional scientific capacity to deliver these aims. We have assembled a group of experts from the Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew, and Surya University, Herbarium Bogoriense, and the University of Nusa Cendana in Indonesia to undertake the programme of exploration, mapping, seed-banking, training, and analysis to inform the development of Wallacea&apos;s green economy.  The proposed research will have three Work Packages: 1. Documenting the plant diversity of Wallacea&apos;s Seasonal Forests and how it is distributed: building an inventory of the region&apos;s natural capital. 2. Asessing the resilience of Seasonal Forests in Wallacea to climatic and anthropogenic changes 3. Evaluating the potential of Wallacea&apos;s natural capital to underpin its green economy: building in-country capacity around a green economy. The overall goal of this project is to produce new biodiversity data from the Wallacea region, to determine the distribution of, and threats to, selected species, better characterise regional biodiversity associations though ecoregion definition, and understand the resilience at the species and habitat level to future environmental change in Wallacea. These data will be interpreted and made easily available for use by local communities and other stakeholders, enabling them to exploit and manage the biodiversity more effectively, whilst conserving the habitats and endemic, endangered and economic species.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Botanic Gardens Kew</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">52584.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">225885.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">181205.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">60488.66</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">24280382.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to Royal Botanic Gardens Kew</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S007059_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Botanic Gardens Kew</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FS007059%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
