<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P004121_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unravelling the impact of El Ni&#xF1;o on waterborne diseases in South America</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vibrio species are a diverse genus of Gram-negative bacteria found in marine habitats. In addition to playing a critical ecological role in many marine ecosystems, this genus also includes key pathogens of humans. V. cholerae and V. parahaemolyticus, are amongst the most significant human pathogenic bacteria originating from the marine environment. Cholera alone affects an estimated 3-5 million people worldwide; V. parahaemolyticus is the leading cause of seafood borne bacterial gastroenteritis in the world. Infections caused by Vibrio cholerae and V. parahaemolyticus have shown a steady expansion over the last decades associated with the emergence of pandemic clones. The seventh cholera pandemic began in Indonesia in 1961 and was confined to Asia until 1970 when it reached Africa and Europe. After a long time without any new evidence of dissemination, it re-emerged in northern Peru in 1991 causing more than 1,000,000 cases of cholera in just three years. Likewise, V. parahaemolyticus infections were almost confined to Asia until the emergence of cases associated with a single clone in Calcutta in 1996. We report the first incursion of this clone outside Asia in 1997 causing infections along the coast of Peru. The advent of V. cholerae and V. parahaemolyticus infections on the West coast of South America in 1991 and 1997 represented the two only reported evidences of an eastward drift of Asian variants of these pathogens and both processes were concurrent with the arrival of warm equatorial waters displaced by El Ni&#xF1;o.   El Ni&#xF1;o is a climate pattern that describes the unusual warming of surface waters along the tropical west coast of South America causing a notable impact on the ocean and weather at global scale. El Ni&#xF1;o events occur irregularly and are not strictly predictable and one of the most major manifestations is the zonal displacement of the Indo-Pacific Warm Pool, a body of water which holds the warmest oceanic seawaters in the world. This body of water is subjected to strong east migrations to Ecuador in phase with the movement of El Ni&#xF1;o waters. In the Pacific coast of South America, the incoming of El Ni&#xF1;o equatorial waters to the American coasts originate the incursion of warm waters of lower salinity moving southward along the coast, which has been shown to transport foreign zooplankton populations into Peru and Chile.  As the survival and spread of vibrios in the marine environment under adverse conditions has been linked to the ability of these bacteria to attach to plankton, we hypothesize that zooplankton provide nutrients and protection to enable vibrios to travel across oceans.   We have been working in Peru over the last 10 years isolating and characterizing Vibrio strains obtained from environmental and clinical sources with the aim of identifying new evidence of the link between populations in Asia and the Pacific coast of South America. As result of these investigations, we have identified in environmental sources in Peru the presence of four genetic variants of Vibrio which had been uniquely previously reported in Asia and, strikingly, all of these variants emerged both in time and space with significant El Ni&#xF1;o events. According to these observations, the incursion of invasive plankton populations into the coasts of Peru trapped in the El Ni&#xF1;o waters may provide a unique source of novel pathogenic variants of Vibrio.  After more than ten years waiting for a new El Ni&#xF1;o episode, the active event provides a unique opportunity to test the hypothesis of the existence of an effective trans-Pacific transference of Vibrio populations in phase with the zonal displacement of El Ni&#xF1;o waters. All these aspects will address key aspects of the ecology of zooplankton and Vibrio, and specifically the role of zooplankton in driving the global dispersal of Vibrio through major oceanic corridors, which will be particularly useful protection of populations and prevention of future epidemics.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the collaboration of the National Institute of Health (INS, Ministry of Health) and the National Institution for Seafood Safety (SANIPES, Ministry of Fisheries), we propose to perform a rapid action in response to the current 2015-2016 El Ni&#xF1;o event to investigate the potential role of El Ni&#xF1;o water in the introduction of novel variants of pathogenic Vibrio waterborne pathogens into Peru with the potential impact on public health in the region.  The specific objective of the proposed research are:  1. To evaluate how the zonal displacement of the pacific warm pool in phase with El Ni&#xF1;o could contribute to the long-distance dispersion of planktonic species and assess the impact of the arrival of these populations on local communities of Vibrio in environmental and clinical sources. 2. To identify the novel variants of Vibrios in Peru introduced in the country in association with the incursion of El Ni&#xF1;o waters along coastal areas of Peru. 3. To determine the genetic signatures of the novel variants and infer potential phylogenetic connections between Vibrio populations identified on both sides of the Pacific Ocean using the repositories of genomic data publically available as well as the collections at the FDA and CEFAS, both with global coverage. 4. To utilise the mechanistic understanding of El Ni&#xF1;o dynamics and associated fluxes of plankton to develop models for prediction of potential risks for public health associated with the introduction of new pathogenic variants of Vibrio driven by El Ni&#xF1;o.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">167237.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-10">40623.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">41809.38</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P004121_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">40623.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P004121_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">19056.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P004121_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
