<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R014914_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iraqibacter: Exploring the Links Between War and Antimicrobial Resistance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To build the consortium for full proposal, our aims and objectives are: 1- Develop interdisciplinary research clusters, in three themes  a-History of MDRAB and microbiology of war. A comparative history of war and MDRAB, building on a history of science approach to AMR.  The focus of this cluster is the study of the historical sequence of emergence of resistant pathogens in 20th century wars, and changing responses to antibiotic resistance in military medicine from World War II to today. We will address the emergence of MDRAB, and its circumstances, in order to discern whether this pathogen is specific to war, or reflects shifts in diagnostic capability; and address the phenomenon of growing pathogenicity, suggested by increasing presence in blood and tissue cultures. We will ask whether wars, since the invention of antibiotics, seen similar evolutionary events in bacterial resistance and virulence. The longer history of antibiotic resistance in war will thereby inform our understanding of what is new or particular to 21st century Middle East conflicts.  b-Epidemiological, microbiological and environmental links between heavy metal and MDRAB in conflict. The aim of this cluster is to explore the epidemiological, microbiological, and environmental links between heavy metal exposure, MDRAB, and antibiotic resistance in zones of conflict and among wounded populations. This will be done through clinical, laboratory and environmental analysis that 1) examine the evidence of environmental contamination with heavy metals in bacteria, soil, and water; 2) describe the clinical and environmental epidemiology of MDRAB to identify risk factors relating to the mechanisms of wounding, pre-hospital care, nosocomial infection, and clinical course; 3) identify the cellular and molecular mechanisms by which Acinetobacter baumanii acquires resistance to antibiotics and/or heavy metals.  c-Anthropology of war and AMR. This cluster focuses on political economy and ethnography of AMR wound infections. Ethnographic research on surgeons; hospital administrators; medics; injured civilians, their families, and communities to elucidate lived experiences of care givers and victims who move regionally or internationally to flee violence or seek treatment. Political economy research on countries of conflict and their contemporary prescription practices to illuminate the effects on antibiotic stewardship and inform the experimental and epidemiological studies. 2- To scope and carry out feasibility assessments on the state of knowledge and methods a-Reviews and experts&apos; and informants&apos; interviews to consolidate the current state of knowledge on the topic. Working through the three main clusters, these will be the backbone for the literature review for the full submission and an opportunity to develop a number of manuscripts b-Conduct a baseline assessment of available data (patient records, preliminary laboratory analysis), in preparation for developing a database on war injuries, AMR, and heavy metals. This will serve as a platform for developing a region-wide registry to monitor and study the public health impact and burden of AMR  c-Feasibility assessments of research and capacity needs in different sites of investigation and development of appropriate methodologies that ensure the high standards required for implementing the research project in the different countries of conflict.     3- To develop critical competences for the wider program a-Identify gaps in ethical framework and guidelines for the wider program, taking into account the complexities of conducting research in conflict settings.  b-Establish platforms for communication and data management between the different researchers, collaborators and other stakeholders including patients and policymakers.  c-Identify junior scholars and researchers who will be involved in surveys, laboratory analysis, ethnographic research, and other fieldwork activities during full implementation phase</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WHO and the G20 have identified the growing threats of Anti-Microbial resistance (AMR) as a major concern that will define the future of global health. Despite these urgent calls, the emergence of AMR in settings of war and distress migration has not been systematically explored. Case reports from Syria, Iraq, Libya, Yemen, and Afghanistan have shown the proliferation of AMR in combatants and civilians injured in these protracted conflicts. With regional conflicts spreading across state borders as well as one of the largest global refugee crises in decades, AMR in the context of conflict has come to pose a serious threat both regionally and internationally. So began penicillin in the Second World War: antibiotics arose in war. Today, in the context of long-running military conflicts we see harbingers of the end of antibiotics. The core question underpinning this proposal is how war, particularly weapons and the industrialised, urbanised context of contemporary conflicts, drives antibiotic resistance by contaminating the environment and the human and non-human organisms that live there. So far, there has been no systematic or holistic consideration of the environmental health impacts of contemporary conflicts conducted in cities.  Our program draws together scholars working in the fields of medicine, anthropology, history of science, ethics, epidemiology, microbiology, molecular biology, and environmental sciences to examine the specific intersection of antibiotic resistance and war. Rather than focus on antibiotic resistance as a universal problem afflicting modern societies in general, we focus first on the impact of global conflict on antibiotic resistance more holistically, and second on the case of multi-drug resistant Acinetobacer baumanii (MDRAB), initially reported by American military surgeons under the moniker Iraqibacter, and that has been identified recently by the WHO as a &quot;critical pathogen&quot; for research and the development of new antibiotics. We will focus on a number of specific countries - Iraq, Syria, Palestine, Yemen, and Lebanon-places with history of protracted conflicts and with different, yet overlapping, ecologies of war.  The potential global health significance of conflict-related heavy metal mediated antimicrobial resistance is enormous and warrants further study. It will contribute to the field of environmental pathways for antimicrobial resistance more broadly as well as informing the specific intersection of war and antibiotic resistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-02">47714.28</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">47714.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R014914_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">1990.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R014914_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
