<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S003304_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Popular performance for new urban audiences: reconnecting M50 creative cluster with Shanghai All-Female Yue Opera</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To engage new urban audiences with traditional Chinese opera through the digital mediation of performance into a heritage site in Shanghai, focusing on Shanghai All-Female Yue Opera. In doing so, to re-present Shanghai Yue Opera as a contemporary, participatory cultural offering in Shanghai&apos;s distinctive contemporary arts area.  2. To revive for these audiences and a wider public Shanghai Yue Opera&apos;s historical connection to the site of the Shanghai M50 contemporary arts creative cluster.   3. Through these processes to form collaborations between academics, arts and performing arts institutions and creative industry small and medium sized enterprises, who have not worked jointly in the past, to formulate a creative industry chain in which the private and public sectors work reciprocally to identify specific consumer groups and develop local markets. In this case, the creative industry chain will be embedded in relationships between music business, design merchandise, and the reinterpretation of traditional performing arts. This creative industry chain is intended to outlive the duration of the research project and contribute to the diversity and sustainability of the creative economy development in Shanghai.  4. To publish conclusions from the project that offer a model relevant to the sustainable development of other traditional opera forms across China, of which there are up to 300 nationwide. These conclusions will be disseminated firstly through the project documentary video, which will act as an animated tool kit to inform and inspire new arts business collaboration across China in relation to traditional performing arts. This model will also be elaborated in the report to the Shanghai Municipal Government and other outcomes published on the project website.  5. To apply this analysis of the creative industry chain more generally to broader questions of the development of the &apos;Creative City&apos;, in which diversity and sustainability are key elements. To disseminate this research through a co-edited volume on &quot;Creative City and Creative Industry Chain through Shanghai Traditional Opera&quot; to be published in Chinese and English and through commissioned reports in Chinese to the Shanghai Municipal Government and in English to the Arts Council of Wales.   6. To catalyze new UK-China creative economy collaborations via the two public symposia and external party engagement with the project and its collaborations. The first symposium will be in Shanghai in month 18 at the Shanghai Theatre Academy and M50, to which UK and China artists, producers and funders with an interest in UK-China collaborations will be invited. The Symposium will include the workshopping of elements of the project installation and performance material; an international forum and discussion of papers engaging with the project&apos;s research questions, including contributions from project participants, stakeholders, and Chinese and international speakers; and a practice forum intended to directly facilitate new UK-China creative industry collaborations. A culminating symposium in month 36 in Cardiff will provide an end-point and report back on emergent collaborations and new activities in relation to the project and beyond.  7. To compile and widely disseminate, via data published on the project website, book and article publications, and a documentary video, project research outcomes relating to the contemporary production, distribution and exhibition of Shanghai Yue Opera in Shanghai. These research outcomes will target a range of end-users: academics, creative industry professionals in China and the UK, and organizations linked to the Shanghai Yue Opera development, as well as an informed public with an interest in traditional Chinese opera and contemporary arts and performance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will engage new urban audiences with traditional Chinese opera through the digital mediation of performance into a heritage site in Shanghai, focusing on Shanghai All-Female Yue Opera and reviving its historical connection to the Shanghai M50 contemporary arts creative cluster. The project will explore how this kind of engagement with traditional forms may provide opportunities to enhance small and medium enterprise business development in partnership with the public sector, establishing a &apos;creative chain&apos; that will enhance the diversity and sustainability of Shanghai&apos;s urban creative economy.   Yue Opera first entered Shanghai from the rural countryside of Zhejiang province following the influx of Zhejiang female workers to the expanding Shanghai textile industry in the early 20th century, where it evolved into an urban popular cultural form identified with female performers and audience in Shanghai. In the 1990s, nationwide state enterprise reform, textile factory closures and worker redundancies cut off the traditional audience as well as state patronage. The M50 creative cluster was established at the site of one such textile factory and has since developed into a world-renowned creative cluster. It currently houses more than 140 artists&apos; studios, galleries and other creative companies, from over 20 countries and regions, presenting international contemporary art. It is today the symbol of China&apos;s transitional economy - from &apos;made in China&apos; to &apos;created in China&apos;. However, despite its historical association with Yue Opera, at M50 there is no presence associated with traditional Chinese opera and no tourism or other literature providing this link or history for visitors. This project will reconnect M50 to its historical association with Yue Opera, and re-present Yue Opera for a contemporary urban audience as an art form of constant evolution; and do so at a site now renowned for contemporary art, including media and digital work.   The project will result in a series of public site-specific installations at M50 developed through archival, historical and contemporary audience research and collaboration with local businesses and stakeholders. The installations will use digital media to re-present aspects of Yue Opera, and its historical links to M50, to a broad public. This will include the use of iPads by visitors acting as hand-held guides, large-scale projected installations of performance, the site-specific screening on monitors of contextual and other material, as well as the facilitation of visitor participation and the embedding of media into interactive objects of historical or contemporary relevance. The project will also result in a documentary video, a co-edited book, and a report to the Shanghai Municipal Government, to ensure the widest possible dissemination. The project will include two public symposia that will bring interested parties from the UK and China to contribute to and debate the implications of the project as it develops and in its culmination.    Our case study aims to demonstrate how by engaging new urban audiences for Yue Opera a creative industry chain may be built in collaborations between public and private sectors. In this creative industry chain, the private and public sectors work together to identify specific consumer groups and develop local markets: in this case in relationships between music business, design merchandise, and the reinterpretation of traditional performing arts. This creative industry chain is intended to outlive the duration of the research project and contribute to the diversity and sustainability of the creative economy development in Shanghai. In these ways, the project will contribute to Shanghai&apos;s ambitions to build a global cultural city of diversity, creativity and sustainability. The project will also offer a model relevant to the sustainable development of other traditional opera forms across China, of which there are up to 300 nationwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-07">33092.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-07">66452.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-07">66990.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-07">33630.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-07">200165.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/S003304/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FS003304%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
