<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S019553_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;SPIICA&apos; - the Sao Paulo-Imperial College Immune Correlates in Arbovirus Infection Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Aedes egypti mosquito can spread a number of different viruses. In regions of Brazil, these include the different types of Dengue virus, as well as Zika virus, Yellow fever virus and Chikungunya virus. Of these, perhaps the least is understood about Chikungunya. It is believed to be rather underdiagnosed. The symptoms can include headache, fever and rash. However, the key concern is that a proportion of patients will go on to develop a devastating arthritis-like, chronic disease which can continue for years. In some cases, disease is fatal. This is thus a disease which causes great misery to those infected and also, a great financial healthcare burden in caring for chronic disease.  There is an urgent need to unravel why it is that some people experience mild disease, while others develop severe, chronic disease. It is believed that the chronic, joint disease is mediated not by the virus itself, but by the immune response to it. For this reason, there is an urgent need to understand the detailed aspects of protective host immunity, so reducing the risk that any future vaccines may inadvertently induce rather than prevent joint disease.  To address this question, we here propose to build a joint centre of leading immunologists in England and Brazil. We have called the joint centre &apos;SPIICA&apos;, an astronomical allusion to two separate stars that appear as one. We will work closely together, including joint workshops and staff training. Central to the plan is to recruit a Chikungunya patient cohort, 90 patients in each of four groups, across three seasons at 6 clinical centres in Brazil. Each patient will be carefully evaluated clinically for Chikungunya symptoms and followed longitudinally, giving periodic blood samples. These blood samples will be evaluated using a large array of state-of-the art technologies, allowing correlations to be drawn between the immune response and the disease features.  The approaches include characterisation of the antibody response to the virus, of the response by subsets of white blood cells including T lymphocytes and natural killer cells, and of immune mediators in the blood termed cytokines.  Our aim is that, by the end of this study, we will have a much-improved rationale to explain the different outcomes following infection. This should help explain how to build vaccines that can promote protection without causing harm and also, how to predict who might be the patients who will develop the chronic disease, treating them before symptoms develop.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">209918.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">177828.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">179268.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Our objectives during this programme of work, in order, are as follows:  1. To build a successful, bi-national network of researchers and clinicians, generating the most substantial ever grouping of researchers targeting understanding of the immune correlates of outcome after arbovirus exposure, with particular emphasis on Chikungunya (CHIKV) - &apos;SPIICA&apos; - the Sao Paulo-Imperial College Immune Correlates in Arbovirus Infection Network. In so doing, we seek to build sustainable links between leading immunologists in the two countries, based on close interaction, joints workshops and staff exchange visits. 2. To build capacity through a consortium of collaboration in cross-disciplinary areas to understand the complexity of CHIKV immunology and immunopathology.  3. To establish a broader understanding of CHIKV as a chronic disease. 4. To publish high-impact joint publications on CHIKV susceptibility and immunity. 5. To put in place a detailed, rationale for the immune correlates of differential outcomes after CHIKV exposure, from acute disease and convalescence to chronic disease with polyarthraligia or death. 6. To recruit a substantial CHIKV human clinical diseases cohort across 6 centres, stratified into acute infection, chronic infection with evidence of polyarthralgia, recovered/convalescent and matched, uninfected controls. 7. To understand the correlates of disease in the above groups at the level of viral seroreactivity, in terms of antigen specificity and antibody isotype, as well as generation of exemplar human, neutralizing monoclonal antibodies for detailed characterization and definition of neutralizing epitopes. 8. To use multi-parameter flow cytometry of peripheral blood mononuclear cells to define the immune phenotypic correlates of disease outcome. 9. To assess the immune phenotypic correlates of disease outcome at the level of serum cytokines and transcriptomic biosignature, analysed by RNAseq. 10. To define the immune correlates of disease at the level of T cell antigen and epitope recognition, including elucidation of responses associated with protection relative to those associated with pathogenesis. 11. To define the metabolic perturbations induced in host cells by CHIKV infection. 12. To supplement biopharma applications in terms of diagnostic and treatment improvements.  13. To improve the clinical protocols and basic care for chronic CHIKV infection.   14. To improve the Brazilian System of Health (SUS) to offer specialized, personalised care for the populations suffering from this infection"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
