<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N00888X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Two Centuries of Indian Print: pilot project on Bengali Books</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project objectives: 1. An estimated 200,000 pages from 1000 early print Bengali books from British Library and SOAS collections digitised and preserved in the British Library&apos;s Digital Library System (DLS) and made available online through the British Library&apos;s website (www.bl.uk)  2. 2000 enhanced catalogue records discoverable through the British Library&apos;s main catalogue Explore (http://explore.bl.uk) for printed books 3. Three workshops, in India, for training and capacity building in digital scholarship and digitisation 4. One academic workshop in India to be developed and organised by the project curators 5. A project blog and social media account detailing progress on digitisation, capacity-building and research strands of the project 6. A dedicated space on the British Library&apos;s website (www.bl.uk) presenting the Two Centuries of Print pilot, featuring articles that provide historical context to the digitised material and explain the project and its research questions and outcomes 7. Datasets, subject to copyright clearance, made available under an open license via www.bl.uk and other data storage platforms where appropriate, containing the newly created page images, PDFs and bibliographic data and any other derived datasets created through the course of the project The digitised collection of Bengali texts will serve as the foundation for the research strand of the project, to investigate ways in which the digital outputs might be enhanced to enable large scale data analysis as is undertaken in the Digital Humanities (DH). Working in close collaboration with the School of Cultural Texts and Records (SCTR) of Jadavpur University, the South Asia Institute at SOAS, as well as with the National Library of India, the BL will develop the foundations for a digitised Bengali Print corpus suited to the needs of the modern scholar. Alongside the digitisation and research strands of the project, the team will work with Indian partners to deliver a series of three workshops and training sessions to build digital capacity in Indian institutions, for students and professionals in the arts &amp; humanities, and library and information science.  These workshops will focus on digital workflows, digital preservation of cultural heritage, and the application of digital scholarship methodologies to research in South Asian studies.  There will also be four opportunities for placements at the British Library, which will enable a more extended engagement and skills-development opportunity. The placements and workshops will draw on the experience and expertise of the British Library and Jadavpur University in this area, and be tailored to the particular priorities and challenges faced by Indian cultural institutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The British Library (BL) holds extensive collections of South Asian printed material encompassing the many languages of the Subcontinent - the most important outside the region.  In order to make these collections more readily accessible to researchers in India and around the world, we are working towards a major project to catalogue and digitise all the South-Asian-language printed books published before 1914 - an estimated total of 11m pages, or 140,000 titles, in more than 22 languages. In order to begin this project, and prepare plans for later phases, this pilot phase will focus on early printed Bengali books. These are a particular strength among the pre-1914 South Asian-language printed books held by the British Library, and many are unavailable in other library collections, or are extremely difficult to locate and access. This pilot project will catalogue and digitise 200,000 pages of early printed Bengali books, making them accessible to researchers everywhere. It will also use the catalogue information about, and the digitised images of, these books to undertake new research using digital humanities tools and techniques. Complementing the digitisation and research elements of the project will be a programme of skills-sharing and capacity-building, working with Indian institutions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Library</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-02">698325.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-02">252105.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-03-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-02">20909487.632</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Newton Fund Award to British Library</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N00888X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">British Library</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FN00888X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-03-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
