<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S003347_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">[Malaysia] Integrated Modelling of Landslides due to Hydrometeorological Impacts in Langat Basin, Peninsular Malaysia (iModelLandslides)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In recent years, Malaysia has experienced a number of landslide disasters resulting from extreme tropical rainfall. Landslides have occurred in several parts of Malaysia, such as Paya Terubong (Penang), Highland Towers (Kuala Lumpur), Hulu Langat and Pos Dipang (Perak). These landslides cost millions of pounds of property loss and hundreds of lives. On 21 October 2017, 11 workers were killed in a landslide at a construction site on Malaysia&apos;s Penang Island.  The October 2002 landslide in Kuala Lumpur which completely destroyed several houses and killed six members of a family and the 2011 Hulu Langat landslide, where 15 children and a caretaker in an orphanage were killed are still in the public&apos;s memory. Population increase and subsequent urbanization have demanded the development of new residential and areas and roads in mountainous areas where there is an increased risk of slope failures. Malaysia&apos;s population is projected to rise to 41.5 million by 2040, up from 28.6 million in 2010. This proposal will produce a qualitative hazard map delineating areas prone to landslides in the Langat River Basin, Peninsular Malaysia. The hazard map will identify landslide-prone areas, including expected changes in landslide susceptibility as a result of climate change.  Langat River Basin is most urbanized river basin in Malaysia. Important conurbations include towns such as Cheras, Kajang, Bangi and Putrajaya (the administrative capital of Malaysia). The basin has an area of about 2350 km2. The area has been experiencing numerous landslides disasters and has been identified by the Malaysia Public Work Department in its National Slope Master Plan Study as landslide-prone area.  The proposal will involve close collaboration with the Public Works Department and the National Disaster Management Agency in Malaysia and several industrial partners to ensure the adaptation of the proposed map in practice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this research is to improve the social understanding of the impacts of the landslides hazards. The main objectives of this project are: 1. To carry out field monitoring and numerical simulations of selected slopes at Langat River Basin in order to understand the relationship between rainfall and landslides using a coupled hydro-mechanical framework. Future climate scenarios will be implemented in the numerical analysis to understand the impact of climate change. 2. To carry out Statistical Multivariate Analysis using Artificial Neural Network (ANN) integrated with Geographic Information System (GIS) model to produce the landslide susceptibility map. 3. To develop a social vulnerability index for landslides in Langat River Basin. 4. To produce an integrated disaster risk map using the landslide susceptibility map and the social vulnerability map.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-14">23016.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-14">129230.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-14">138151.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-14">32766.84</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-14">6219185.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to Durham University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S003347_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FS003347%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
