<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R030294_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">TERSE: Techno-Economic framework for Resilient and Sustainable Electrification</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rural electrification is fundamental for the social and economic development and well-being of developing countries, as it supports the development of vital critical infrastructures (e.g. communication and transportation) and it provides energy to critical services to peoples&apos; quality of everyday life, such as home appliances, health and water supply. The lack or limited and highly unreliable access to electricity still remains one of the key challenges that rural and remote communities face in these countries. In order though for the electrification to go beyond lightning, it is critical to develop energy networks that are sustainable, cost-effective, and scalable, as well as resilient, particularly in areas that are frequently exposed to natural hazards, such as floods, monsoons, etc.       In this context, the ambition of this project is to develop a novel holistic techno-economic framework for supporting and enabling the decision, policy and regulatory making towards the design of transformative energy networks in developing countries. This holistic framework will be supported by the development of an options portfolio for sustainable electrification, including a mixture of infrastructure solutions (e.g. building new or upgrading existing infrastructure) and emerging low-carbon distributed energy resources that will focus on the development of sustainable microgrids (both grid-connected and off-grid). Further, integrated system simulation models will be developed to analyse the vulnerability and quantify the risk and resilience profile of these energy solutions to natural hazards and extreme weather. This is is highly timely given the latest evidence of the impact of such events worldwide and also highly critical if the rural communities are to withstand and quickly recover from such catastrophic events. Following these analyses, stochastic optimization planning techniques will be developed to support the optimal design of these energy networks, considering transformative energy technologies, to maximize the impact on the well-being of local communities. Building on this last point, the research team has developed a well-structured user-engagement strategy, bridging to wider socio-economic aspects of communities facing electrification challenges. The aims of this strategy are to get an in-depth understanding of the electricity needs of rural communities in the partner countries (China and Malaysia), enable their active role in the project and provide briefing and training sessions on the use of the new energy technologies to be applied in these communities. The UK and overseas research teams will jointly work with the local industrial partners to facilitate this active involvement of remote villages, communities and their local authorities.  This project will aim to complement and further strengthen the current electrification plans of the partner countries, i.e. Malaysia and China. The research team will work closely with Sarawak Energy and other authorities in Malaysia to review and improve its Rural Power Supply Scheme that was formulated in 2015, as well as evaluate and improve the design, operability and maintenance planning of existing microgrids in Zhoushan islands, China, which also serve as excellent testbeds for validating the simulation models developed by the project. Within this context, this project will also aim to develop recommendations for changes and improvements in standards, regulatory and policy-making frameworks. We will aim to make the key findings and recommendations of this work of generic applicability and validity to accommodate its international development importance. This would also be of UK national importance, where building sustainable energy networks for reducing its carbon footprint, while being resilient to extreme weather (e.g., the storms of 1987, 2007 and 2015 which resulted in major power outages) is key for safeguarding the social and economic well-being of the country.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Overall Aim, and key novelty of the proposed work, is to develop an innovative, integrated techno-economic framework for supporting decision-making and planning of sustainable, cost-effective and resilient energy infrastructure in LMICs and beyond. In particular, our Ambitions of this project are to: - Develop a quantitative understanding of the role of novel DER in providing hybrid energy network sustainability as well as resilience to natural hazards, particularly in rural and isolated regions in developing countries, considering also their ease of deployment and scalability. - Be able to identify optimum solutions for off-grid-to-grid transitions by comparing benefits and challenges of novel DER options (e.g., through microgrids and community-based energy systems) and traditional infrastructure solutions, based on cost, sustainability and resilience multi-criteria analysis, e.g., based on &quot;hybrid&quot; energy networks. - Propose technical solutions and make policy recommendations for energy network planning and operation which, based on engineering and socio-economic considerations and local user-engagement strategies, ensure that the newly designed energy networks meet the users&apos; needs and maximize the role of and benefits to the local communities. To achieve these ambitions, maximizing the benefits to the social and economic well-being of rural communities, the following Objectives have been identified: - Study current electrification practices and gaps in LMICs and work closely with local authorities and communities in China and Malaysia to understand the challenges and limitations in planning and operation of energy networks in fairly isolated areas, including the consequences of adverse environmental conditions on networks and communities. - Develop specific simulation models of DER options, such as based on grid-connected and off-grid microgrids and community-based energy systems, with application to wider network planning (including hybrid network infrastructure-DER solutions) in rural regions of LMICs. - Develop numerical simulation models of natural hazards that will be tailored for asset vulnerability and infrastructure impact studies, including the identification of critical assets and their impact modelling on the resilience and response of the energy network, which can be validated based on data available from real experiences in Malaysia and China. - Develop innovative stochastic optimization models for network and DER portfolio planning and adaptation based on cost, sustainability and resilience multi-criteria analysis, and considering large scale uncertainties such as frequency and severity of natural (e.g., climate change-driven) hazards, local resources availability, DER options, demand growth, etc.  - Provide engineering and policy recommendations for network planning, design, operation and maintenance practices and standards based on both technical and socio-economic factors that consider the LMIC partner needs.  - Develop effective user-engagement strategies (by &quot;user&quot; we refer here, e.g., to local electricity authorities, local communities, etc.) and dissemination activities to maximise societal impact and enable active role, participation and engagement of a wide range of users in the decision-making of optimal sustainable and resilient electrification solutions</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-19">332133.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-19">361579.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-19">248304.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-19">10247856.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R030294_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FR030294%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
