<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004118_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Supporting Oral Language Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Children with a small vocabulary are at a disadvantage for all aspects of learning. Unless there is targeted support, children who start slow will continue to fall behind their language-rich peers.  A powerful way to ensure all children are ready for learning, particularly in school, is to offer high quality oral language education early in a child&apos;s life.  The power of early language intervention is supported by a large body of evidence showing a combined foundation of strong spoken language and listening comprehension cascading to reading and writing skills.  However, little is known about the efficacy of oral language interventions in low- and middle-income countries where communities are often multilingual.  We aim to address this gap in the literature through a mixed-methods study with children ages of 3-to-6 living in India and the Philippines.  The study will examine oral language development under the particular complexities of multilingual urban poor settings.  Research in these settings is of importance as there is reason to believe resources that spontaneously support children&apos;s language development may be under strain for the urban poor (e.g. reduced social networks, a new school language), making them a particularly vulnerable group for school failure.  A co-developed project  The proposed project was co-developed by multiple agencies.  Government partners shared that a pressing systemic concern was the low literacy rates in primary schools.  Community partners stressed the need for evidence on quality programs that will work in local schools and university partners echoed the need for a comprehensive program of research.  We therefore propose to understand children&apos;s language development in-context and will test an intervention that could potentially better prepare children for primary school.  The research sites will be Udupi district in India and Quezon City in the Philippines.  Defining characteristics of these sites include the multiple languages around the child and a policy commitment to either mother-tongue or multilingual education.  Hence, these contexts offer an opportunity to research a topic that is understudied in not just DAC countries but also internationally: children&apos;s oral language development and oral language intervention in a multilingual setting.  Objectives and Outputs  The primary objective of this research is to provide descriptive and causal evidence on quality (in early childhood development and pre-primary education) and readiness (for primary education) through three studies that aim to a) map opportunities and barriers to oral language development, b) validate assessments to track children&apos;s developing oral language and c) examine a targeted intervention delivered by teachers one year before entry into primary school.  We will map opportunities and barriers by following thirty children over one day to record their language experiences, examining language knowledge of their conversation partners, and conducting an ethnographic inquiry of classes they attend.  We will finetune fifteen assessments by analyzing 3000 data points on each test and, in a study with 800 children, evaluate a language intervention designed with teachers that draws upon folk tales and local narratives.  This inter-disciplinary project will provide an approach to reach the Sustainable Development Goal of effective learning outcomes for all children by focusing on the language bedrock of early childhood learning.  Outputs include evidence briefs for policy makers and open access toolkits for educators. Multiple bodies of data for the research community will expand the evidence-base in these contexts.  These include a word bank, an archive of child language, a rich description of talk in the classroom, performance data and outcomes data.  Taken together, the proposed research could potentially act as a catalyst for informed early childhood education in India, the Philippines, and other DAC countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Target 4.2 of the UN&apos;s Sustainable Development Goals (SDG) calls for a smooth entry into school education for all children: &apos;By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys have access to quality early childhood development, care and pre-primary education so that they are ready for primary education.&apos;  The primary objective of the proposed research is to provide descriptive and causal evidence about two key ideas implied by this goal: quality (in early childhood development and pre-primary education) and readiness (for primary education).  Both are complex and layered constructs; our aim is to bring a fresh perspective by examining their interpretation within the domain of children&apos;s oral language development.  The proposed research will be conducted in India and the Philippines.  In both countries, annual surveys show a high proportion of primary school children not learning to read and write to their grade level. In both countries, limited access to a quality early childhood program is a forerunner to the unfolding learning crisis and a review has been initiated by the governments to address the challenge. It is therefore timely to launch a program of research to inform the review.  The focus of the proposed inter-disciplinary research will be on urban poor 3-to-6-year-old children in multilingual settings.  To contextualize the research, we will map children&apos;s oral language environment at home and in the classroom.  To follow children&apos;s language development, we will develop assessment tools in oral language skills and emergent literacy.  Since a language program can provide the foundation for children to engage with &apos;organized learning&apos; before entry into primary school (SDG 4.2.2), we will develop an oral language intervention and gather evidence for this component of the early childhood curriculum.  Another objective of the project is to ensure user engagement and knowledge exchange.  Teachers and cultural actors in the community will be actively engaged in the development of the oral language intervention to source indigenous oral narratives and design lessons that are responsive to needs of educators and children.  Representatives of the wider community of interested stakeholders will be consulted to produce the final outputs.     A third objective is to synthesize prior knowledge and findings from this innovative research for societal use.  For this, outputs from the project will be made suitable and accessible through a tiered strategy.  For practitioners, three outputs will be a teacher toolkit which will provide indicators of children&apos;s progress in language learning, a guided 27-week supplementary oral language program and a 10-day teacher training course.  For policy makers, evidence will be provided on what needs focus in the provision of early childhood care and education, and what works as a supplementary intervention one year before entry into school.  The evidence briefs will describe how policy priorities in each country can align with the evidence. For academia, multiple databases will be created under the open science framework to allow researchers to trace what we did, replicate our studies and run other studies using our databases.  The databases include a corpus of words found in children&apos;s literature, archives of child language, research diaries of classroom processes, and datasets from the study to validate the assessment tool and examine feasibility of the intervention.    Our broader goal is to provide a platform for local and international academics, civil society partners and governments interested in supporting children&apos;s oral language in early childhood in low- and middle-income countries, especially in the ASEAN, SEAMEO and SAARC region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">152387.99</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">617369.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">225938.55</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">857706.88</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">152387.99</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004118_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">154030.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004118_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">154030.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004118_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">154030.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004118_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
