<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00357X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Caribbean Resilience and Recovery Knowledge Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In a region beset by serial disasters, effective recovery from hazardous events is not just a worthy goal it is an imperative.  The Caribbean Resilience and Recovery Knowledge Network will support a transformational approach towards post-disaster recovery in the Caribbean,particularly as it responds to the impacts of the 2017 hurricane season that caused $130 billion of losses in the region. A community of researchers, practitioners and policymakers is emerging, but at the moment their response is ad hoc and driven by divergent research or short-term aid goals. This generates locally useful outcomes, that alleviate the worst symptoms from the disasters, however they are collectively less effective at encouraging long term resilience to future events, strengthening ecosystems or reducing long-term vulnerabilities in poor or remote communities. The Caribbean Knowledge Network seeks to remedy this by  creating a new culture for responding to and preparing for hazardous events. This is our principle aim. We will do this  by joining together diverse researchers, and engaging with practitioners and policymakers from the outset. These groups are all motivated to come together and transform how we approach post-disaster recovery. The researchers (in the Caribbean and the UK)  work on wide-ranging topics relevant to long term hazard resilience, connected by their desire to improve recovery from disasters. The practitioners bear responsibility for ensuring the best possible outcomes for communities at risk and  face increasing challenges associated with climate change and environmental degradation in the region. The attention of donors and policymakers has been focussed by the recent systemic destruction from the 2017 hurricanes. Thus, the Network is both timely and needed. We have structured a series of mutually beneficial activities to help us achieve our overall aim, and associated objectives. The first of these will be a forensic workshop where we will bring our multiple perspectives to bear to understand what drove and hindered recovery following three key events (the 2017 hurricanes, the Haiti earthquake and long-term recovery following Hurricane Ivan). To reflect the multiple perspectives were are calling these forensic analyses, and this will be a great vehicle for learning from each others expertise and perspectives. This will run in the same location and just before the Annual Caribbean Disaster Management conference, which will provide further immediate feed-in to our conclusions.  After that we will create some scenarios to help test, design and evaluate existing response and recovery plans for multiple types of hazard. We will visit several Caribbean countries to do this, and they will be co-designed with different social groups to ensure relevancy. These will be used to create new principles and strategies in each setting.  While we are doing this we will run a series of webinars to discuss challenges hilighted by these two activities. We will make these freely accessible to participants throughout the Caribbean and further afield. The outcomes from all of this work will create our new community who will co-create a manifesto for research to transform recovery and use that to secure further funding. Importantly, however along the way we will also have created some tangible benefits which will ensure the longevity of the grouping and maximise its benefit. These are: (1) forensic analyses on several important disaster events, identifying priority actions and sets of principles; (2)   flexible, tailored scenario exercises for local disaster practitioners so they can develop their own new strategies in response to these on four islands (3) the time and momentum to consider how to &apos;join up&apos; strategies across the islands, critically in collaboration with regional and international agencies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-06-02"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="JM" type="JAMAICA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CARIBBEAN, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1031</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">36534.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">73364.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">36830.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall aim of the Caribbean Knowledge Network is to create a new culture for responding to and preparing for hazardous events; one that promotes sustainable and equitable recovery and resilient development pathways in Caribbean islands. The following objectives will help us achieve this.    1.Facilitate greater engagement and collaboration between academic and non-academic stakeholders to address complex recovery challenges and promote lesson learning 2. Enhance uptake of research and evidence in the design and development of new regional and national recovery initiatives 3.Initiate a new planning process in Caribbean states: the development of national recovery plans 4. Provide substantial input and support to the implementation of the Regional Comprehensive Disaster Management (CDM) Strategy (2014-2024) 5. Identify critical research problems, in collaboration with non-academics and establish partnerships towards the creation of a research agenda for the Caribbean on transforming post-disaster recovery  This will be done via a number of structured activities that will create this community but also produce tangible outputs. Three key activities will all happen in the region: forensic workshops, scenario roadshows and a interdisciplinary webinar series.  New knowledge will be co-produced between the research, practitioner and policymaker communities. This will take the form of policy briefs, scenario exercises, new (bespoke) principles and strategies for disaster recovery and  new research manifestos and proposals."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">18267.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00357X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">18267.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00357X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">18267.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00357X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">18267.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00357X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">18415.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00357X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
