<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014527_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Feasibility of a cluster randomised trial of a nutritional intervention to improve outcomes after cancer surgery in low-income countries</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">OVERARCHING OBJECTIVE To perform a global cluster randomised controlled trial of a nutritional intervention in malnourished patients undergoing cancer surgery in low-resource settings. CONTEXT The importance of optimising patients prior to surgery is well recognised. It is estimated that two-thirds of patients undergoing cancer surgery in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) are malnourished. Small, single-centre studies in high income settings suggest that administering an oral nutritional supplement can improve outcomes in malnourished patients undergoing cancer surgery, such as reducing surgical site or chest infections. Despite this, no large, high-quality studies have been performed or are registered in any setting.  We run a large international research collaboration in surgery and have now established focused Surgical Research Hubs within LMICs. Our prospective observational cohort study is currently recruiting patients undergoing surgery for breast, gastric and colon cancer in 100 countries (NCT03471494; http://globalsurg.org/gs3). This study will characterise hospital infrastructure (such as availability of imaging and pathology services for diagnosis), processes (such as neoadjuvant/adjuvant chemotherapy/radiotherapy being available and given as per international guidelines), and outcomes (such as death, major complications and surgical site infection). This study will provide important data on the relationships between nutritional status and outcomes after surgery. We want to take these data and design a cluster randomised controlled study of a nutritional intervention in malnourished patients undergoing cancer surgery.    SPECIFIC PUMP-PRIMING GRANT OBJECTIVES Work package 1. Identify and validate a nutritional screening tool for patients in LMICs undergoing surgery for cancer. 1. A systematic review of nutritional assessment prior to surgery;  2. Review of the quality and accuracy in an LMIC setting of the tools identified;  3. Guided focus groups of patients and clinical teams in partner countries to determine relevance, feasibility, and acceptability;  4. Trial data collection and validation using the selected tool. Work package 2. Identify a low cost sustainable nutritional intervention for patients in LMICs undergoing surgery for cancer. 1. A systematic review of nutritional interventions used for patients prior to surgery;  2. Consultation with local manufacturers of ready-to-use therapeutic food/nutritional interventions;  3. Semi-structured interviews with patients and healthcare professionals on proposed nutritional intervention. Work package 3. Establish the feasibility of a cluster randomised trial of a sustainable nutritional intervention for patients in LMICs undergoing surgery for cancer. 1. Identify and verify the wider network of hospitals to deliver trial; 2. Administer a centre feasibility questionnaire to Hub hospitals and their Spokes; 3. Trial patient identification, recruitment, and administration of intervention; 4. Trial outcome assessment and data collection instruments acceptability; 5. Establish feasibility of longer-term follow-up; 6. Determine final study design, analysis plan and power;  7. Design resource use and health economic plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">THE PROBLEM: For many types of cancer, high quality surgery is the only cure. This is particularly true in low-income countries where treatments such as chemotherapy or radiotherapy may not be available. It is important that surgery goes well. When complications occur, longer term outcomes are worse, and some patients will die. It is increasingly recognised that boosting the health of patients before surgery can greatly improve the chances of success. Of course, a balance must be struck between the urgency to operate and remove the cancer and a desire to take time and improve a patient&apos;s health. Cancer often causes extreme weight loss and, in many countries, this occurs on top of pre-existing malnutrition.  THE QUESTION: Would it be of benefit to intensively treat patients with nutritional supplements prior to surgery? Studies from high income countries suggest it could be, and the benefit may be even greater in low-income countries. THE TEAM: We are a well-established team working to improve surgical care worldwide. Surgeons from low- and middle-income countries are supported in Research Hubs and set their own research agenda. Nutrition in cancer surgery has been identified as an area of high priority. Our team has the broad set of skills required to make this work.  OUR CURRENT WORK: We are gathering data on patients undergoing cancer surgery worldwide. It is the largest study of its kind and is taking place in 100 countries. This information will allow us to work out the relationship between malnutrition and the results of surgery in a way that hasn&apos;t been possible before. But what we really want to do is come up with a solution. This grant application is for funding to bridge the gap between our current observational study and a trial to treat patients prior to surgery. We have broad experience and are currently launching the FALCON trial, looking at steps to reduce wound infection after surgery in low-income countries.  FUTURE PROPOSED TRIAL: We want to perform a large study in low- and middle-income countries giving a nutritional supplement (sometimes called ready-to-use therapeutic food) to patients undergoing cancer surgery. We will then measure whether it results in fewer complications and better outcomes after surgery. Before we can do that, we need to do three things.  NEED FOR THIS PUMP PRIMING GRANT: First, we need to find a good way of screening patients for malnutrition in low-income countries. This is to identify those who may benefit most from a treatment. One would have thought that this would be easy and well-established, but it is not. Simple but accurate screening methods for malnutrition, which can be used by a nurse or a doctor for patients undergoing surgery, need to be developed or adapted. Second, we need to find an appropriate product. This needs to fulfil specific nutritional requirements but must be inexpensive, sustainable and ideally locally sourced. We will work with companies, experts, patients, and clinicians to find what is best. Third, we then need to make sure that a trial can actually be run. We will ask pragmatic questions such as, will there be a sufficient number of patients in our partner hospitals who can take part? Will they be able to take the nutritional supplement? Is the hospital in contact with patients after discharge to ensure we know what happens to them etc.? Determining the practicalities and planning for any problems identified is essential in ensuring the success of a study such as this. THE BENEFIT: We propose to perform this preliminary work in a small area of our network (Ghana, Zambia, Pakistan and the Philippines), but the research promises great benefits beyond this. Focusing on fitness prior to surgery and issues such as malnutrition will be essential in improving the outcomes of cancer surgery worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">54624.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">101101.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">46477.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-09">202203.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S014527_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FS014527%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
