<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biopesticides for Africa: A model system</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">African agriculture is impacted by a range of stresses leading to losses in yield, of which insect crop pests are a major problem. It has been estimated that agricultural crop pests account for around a 30% loss of crops grown globally. Conventional chemical pesticides are highly effective at protecting such crops, but are generally expensive and in Tanzania, for example, more than 70% of farmers cannot afford them. It is a similar story throughout most of sub-Saharan Africa. In addition to the problems with cost, those farmers who can afford them risk exposing themselves to harmful chemicals due to a lack of appropriate safety gear. Moreover, many chemical pesticides harm beneficial insects such as pollinators, livestock and the wider environment; in Europe this has resulted in a drastic reduction in the number of chemical products allowed in crop protection over the last two decades.   Both globally and across Africa in particular, there is a pressing need to develop cheaper, environment-friendly alternatives to chemical pesticides, and this is the focus of our project. Biological pesticides used to protect agricultural crops are derived from plants and microorganisms, such as fungi, bacteria, and viruses. They are often much cheaper to develop than new chemicals and, currently, global sales of biopesticides are estimated to be worth $2.3 billion, around 5% of the overall pesticides market and growing at around 16% per annum.  The long-term goal of our proposed study is to develop a novel, cheap, effective and locally-produced biopesticide in Tanzania (known as SpexNPV) to combat the one of the most infamous insect pests in sub-Saharan Africa. This pest is the caterpillar stage of the African armyworm moth (Spodoptera exempta). The product will be derived from a naturally-occurring virus, which is ever-present in natural populations of the armyworm in small amounts. Whilst our proposal necessarily addresses issues that are specific to the armyworm-SpexNPV system, this can better be viewed as a model system for understanding generic technical and production issues associated with the mass-production, mass-application and formulation of novel biopesticides, especially in Africa.  The overall objective of the proposed study is to use a specific host-biopesticide system (African armyworm-SpexNPV baculovirus) as a model for exploring some of the key issues associated with developing and deploying a new biopesticide in Africa. We will do so by better understanding the process of developing and applying the biopesticide. Specifically, we will test to see what impact application of the biopesticide has upon the target insect (e.g. will it develop resistance to the pesticide over time?), its gut microbial community (e.g. does this protect or harm its host?) and the effectiveness of the biopesticide itself (does it evolve undesirable traits over time?), and the potential to utilise this knowledge to develop novel biocontrol strategies (e.g. can we design novel combinations of viruses and bacteria to make the biopesticide more effective and cheaper?).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The armyworm-SpexNPV host-biopesticide system provides an ideal model for exploring some of the key issues associated with developing and deploying a new biopesticide in Africa, by better understanding the consequences of its mass production and application, such as selection on the biological properties (including resistance) of the target host species, its microbiome and the biopesticide itself.  Specifically, we will address the following questions:  1) Does continual &apos;field production&apos; of SpexNPV biopesticide lead to selection for undesirable biopesticide traits - do we get out what we put in? Specifically, does the genetic and phenotypic profile of the biopesticide change following host selection. We will test this using both field trials in Africa and laboratory bioassays in the UK, in which the genetic and phenotypic profile of the virus is quantified pre- and post-challenge.   2) Does mass inundation of SpexNPV biopesticide against African armyworms select for a more vigorous host population? Speciically, by controlling the pest population with SpexNPV, will we inadvertently select for resistant insects. We will again test this using both field trials in Africa and laboratory bioassays in the UK, in which the genetic and phenotypic profiles of the insects are quantified pre-and post-challenge. In both cases, we will also determine whether there has been a change in the microbial community.   3) Does the gut microbiota of the host influence susceptibility to SpexNPV? Specifically, are there any resident microbes, other than the Wolbachia bacterium, that influence host susceptibility to disease? Inferences to this can be made from (2), but we will also conduct transplant trials in which the microbiota is transferred between the guts of susceptible and resistant hosts . We will also explore the more general possibility that specific gut bacteria modulate host susceptibility to baculoviruses by conducting a series of laboratory bioassays in which insects are challenged with SpexNPV in combination with a range of different bacteria. If successful, this could provide a novel &apos;combination strategy&apos; for the control of armyworms and other crop pests.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tanzania</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-21">199666.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-21">201283.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-21">50728.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">99833.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">49916.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">49916.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">50320.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">50320.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">50320.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">50320.93</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">50728.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P023444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
