<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S003282_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">[Indonesia] Mitigating hydro meteorological hazard impacts through transboundary river management in the Ciliwong River basin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In recent decades the Jakarta Metropolitan Area has undergone widespread development and led Indonesia&apos;s impressive economic growth. But this development and associated urban sprawl has contributed to undesirable water-resource issues, such as pollution, groundwater extraction, and increased flooding. For example, the major floods in 2002, 2007, 2013, and 2014 have caused billions of dollars of direct and indirect economic damage, the destruction of houses and livelihoods, widespread displacement, and loss of life. The Ciliwung River Basin (CRB) has been a major source of flooding in recent years. With an area encompassing 347km2, the CRB starts upstream at Tugu Puncak located between Bogor and Cianjur Regencies, and runs downstream into the Jakarta Bay area. There has been rapid development within the CRB due to the increasing rate of population in Jakarta, Bogor, Tanggerang and Bekasi City. The floods are of both fluvial and coastal origin, and are worsening due to a large number of drivers, including land subsidence, low drainage or storage capacity in Jakarta&apos;s rivers and canals, changes to the climate increasing the frequency and severity of extreme weather events. They are also the result of a rapidly growing population, and land use change causing a growth in economic assets located in potentially flood-prone areas.  Traditional flood control is focused on structural flood protection measures through physical intervention. Modern flood management also considers prevention and addresses institutional and social aspects. It also extends from upstream to downstream areas to cover the whole river basin. However, the Indonesian context is challenging. Indonesia began a process of rapid government decentralisation in 1999 from a formerly strong centralised government structure. Prior to 1999, the state could enforce flood mitigation measures. Decentralisation has shifted authority to the local level, creating fragmentation among institutions at different levels, and making coordination more complex. This study will consider different aspects of current transboundary river management that could positively or negatively influence the functioning of flood management in the CRB. These will include legal frameworks, roles and responsibility-sharing, modelling, data and information sharing in support of flood forecasting and early warning, dialogue and coordination mechanisms, and stakeholder participation. The project draws upon a range of disciplinary expertise, including hydrological processes, disaster risk reduction, urban planning, public policy, disaster resilience, flood modelling and fluid mechanics, hydraulic engineering, and behavioural science. The team will combine analytical methods (e.g., modelling of key physical flood variables, urban risk flood modelling) with empirical methods that are based on the analysis of observed or potential consequences through the use of interviews, questionnaires and focus groups. The project has the support of and will involve several government institutions at national, regional and local levels in Indonesia.  It will also use a community participatory approach that will raise awareness among communities at risk, and also encourage them to hold accountable those actors who are responsible for disaster risk reduction and river basin management. Through these approaches, the results and recommendations from the study will have been co-created, increasing the likelihood of uptake.  The fieldwork and model development will deliver a better understanding of how and why the current transboundary river management arrangements are mitigating or exacerbating flood hazard impacts in the CRB. The recommendations will contribute to improved governance and institutional arrangements in the CRB, and can inform improved models for governance of transboundary river basins elsewhere.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ID" type="INDONESIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">82690.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">159091.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">144149.1</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">67673.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This jointly developed proposal is led by an Indonesian-UK research team and tackles two key challenges set out in the call for proposals: (challenge 3) Understanding how governance and institutional arrangements contribute to (flood) risks from hydrometerological hazards; and, (challenge 1) Developing models of future flood hazard in the Ciliwung River Basin (CRB).  This project will examine how and why the current transboundary river management arrangements are mitigating or exacerbating flood hazard impacts in urban and peri-urban areas of the CRB, in light of key physical flood variables and any future changes to statistically significant future flood variables. The study will tackle transboundary management arrangements on the CRB, which crosses two provinces (West Java and the Special Region of Jakarta), and four municipal boundaries (Bogor City, Bogor Regency, Depok City, and Jakarta Provincial City). An interdisciplinary approach will be adopted that addresses the problem from environmental, physical, governance and social vulnerability perspectives. Using a state of the art theoretical framework, it will consider different aspects of current transboundary river management that could positively or negatively influence the functioning of flood management in the CRB. These will include legal frameworks, roles and responsibility-sharing, modelling, data and information sharing in support of flood forecasting and early warning, dialogue and coordination mechanisms, and stakeholder participation. The guiding research questions (with equal priority) for the study are: 1. What is the response of Ciiliwung catchment to extreme rainfall during tropical storms and cyclones? 2. What are the key flood drivers and the impact of climate change on their future variability? 3. What are the downstream hydrodynamic conditions that contribute to flooding in Jakarta? 4. How do river flooding, local rain/intensity and local drainage system contribute to urban flooding? 5. What are the roles and responsibilities for integrated river basin management in the CRB? 6. Is there strong linkage between upstream and downstream cities/regencies? 7. What are the mechanisms used to enable wider stakeholder engagement, including communities, civil society and business organisations?  8. What non-water related policies and regulatory regimes impact on the CRB?  9. What are the incentives and barriers to uptake of effective integrated river basin management in the CRB? 10. What sharing and exchange of data and information is required for more effective decision making, forecasting, early warning, basin-wide planning, evaluation and monitoring? 11. What modelling is required to improve transboundary understanding and communication among stakeholders? The team will combine analytical methods (e.g., modelling of key physical flood variables, urban flood risk modelling) with empirical methods that are based on the analysis of observed or potential consequences through the use of interviews, questionnaires and focus groups. The results of the study will identify the environmental, socio-economic, political and organisational landscape that contribute to, and link with flood risk. By working closely with river basin stakeholders throughout the lifetime of the project, the results will be used to inform improved transboundary management arrangements for the CRB. The project will also result in a model for improved transboundary river management to tackle flood risk, that can inform governance of river basins in urban and peri-urban areas."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
