<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_P008437_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RCUK-TUBITAK: Understanding volcanic risk in Turkey for improved emergency response and disaster risk reduction</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Geological and historical records of the ten active volcanoes in Turkey indicate potential in several of them for major explosive eruptions. Over 4 million people live within 30 km of an active volcano and over 15 million live within 100 km. Several major cities have high exposure to volcanic risk including Kayseri and Diyarbaki. In an assessment of the global distribution of volcanic risk Turkey ranked at 14th in overall volcanic threat out of 95 volcanically active countries, reflecting high population exposure. The last major volcanic disaster in Turkey occurred in 1840 from Mount Ararat, when an estimated 1900 people lost their lives. However, there is a 70% chance of a major eruption in this century based on global statistics and preliminary analysis of Turkish eruption records. Turkey is vulnerable to volcanic hazards due to the large exposed population, lack of experience of public officials and communities with volcanic emergencies, very limited volcano monitoring, and lack of knowledge on volcanic hazards and risk. This project seeks to increase resilience in Turkey by contributing to development of appropriate volcanic emergency management plans and disaster risk reduction. The project will enable partners in Turkey to learn from those with direct experience of volcanic emergencies in order to build preparedness. This project therefore brings together the General Directorate of Mineral Research and Exploration (MTA), the authority in Turkey charged with investigating and handling geophysical hazards, the School of Earth Sciences at the University of Bristol and the Montserrat Volcano Observatory. This project will also draw from expertise across the global volcanological community through the Global Volcano Model network, co-chaired by University of Bristol. Improved collaborations fostered through this project will enable knowledge transfer via exchange visits designed to share experiences gained in volcanically active situations. The aim is to facilitate learning and tool development to increase the ability within Turkey to respond to future volcanic unrest and eruption.  The eruptive histories of volcanoes in Turkey are very poorly understood. A key issue and first step to be addressed is to improve understanding of past activity, through literature studies, historical records, field studies and sampling, and radiometric dating. Scenarios for future eruptions of high-risk volcanoes will developed to inform planning for emergencies. Access in Eastern Turkey is limited due to the security situation. This, however, generates a need to create an innovative solution to developing studies at remote or inaccessible volcanoes, which will involve remote sensing using various tools such as satellite and aerial imagery and InSAR and identifying analogue systems. These tools developed in Turkey can be applied to other countries with volcanoes made inaccessible by security issues or limited resources.  We will identify high-risk volcanoes and communities, through development of new methods for identifying vulnerable populations and population exposure, with identification of critical infrastructure. This will enable the focussing of the project at high-risk sites. We will increase monitoring capacity in Turkey through purchase and installation of crucial monitoring equipment at a high-risk volcano to significantly enhance the ability to give early warning. Training in monitoring techniques, interpretation of the monitoring signals and InSAR data will be provided. The project will also build resilience through the education of the local communities, scientists, authorities and emergency managers. Engagement with these groups will be facilitated by MTA and includes making educational communication tools about volcanic hazards and risk. A simulation exercise will be run to test emergency plans with relevant authorities, and lessons learned will be delivered to the Prime Ministry Disaster and Emergency Management Authority (AFAD).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project aims to make major improvements in Turkey&apos;s preparedness for future volcanic emergencies, thereby increasing societal resilience. The project includes novel elements of hazard and risk assessment at volcanoes with limited prior information that can be applied in other countries. Key objectives are: 1) Improving knowledge of Turkey&apos;s volcanoes and their activity Eruptive histories for the ten active volcanoes in Turkey will be developed using available information on historical eruptions, geochronology and geology extracted from databases, published and grey literature, discussion with key researchers with local knowledge. Analysis of this information, together with field studies and remote sensing, will enable us to rank volcanoes according to the potential threat to populations and to identify high-threat volcanoes that will be prioritised in the project. This analysis will enable us to evaluate eruption frequency, and to identify the most likely eruptive style, magnitude, and hazards at each volcano and to test hypotheses about tectonic triggering of eruptions.  2) Hazard assessment and scenario development Basic hazard assessments will be carried out for all of Turkey&apos;s active volcanoes based on existing information, including that gathered in objective 1. Development of most likely and maximum credible eruption scenarios will be prioritised on high-risk volcanoes to inform emergency management plans and preparedness. Scenarios will include probable chronologies from unrest through to impact, and the creation of hazard &apos;footprints&apos; that outline the expected distribution of eruptive products and their magnitude and intensity. Critical knowledge gaps will be identified and filled if straightforward and prioritised for future research if not. Hazard maps informed by the scenarios will developed for every active volcano in Turkey, even those where data availability and quality are very limited. A key component of developing hazard maps will be to recognise major knowledge gaps and to establish (and communicate) the uncertainty with any hazard estimates. 3) Monitoring capacity for early warning and volcanic emergency management Monitoring of active volcanoes is limited; monitoring capacity will be increased through:  - Purchase and installation of critical monitoring equipment at the priority volcano.  - Training in installation and maintenance of monitoring equipment. - Capacity building to increase knowledge in interpretation of monitoring signals.  - Training in InSAR data acquisition and analysis to detect deformation at volcanoes. - Knowledge transfer between MVO, Bristol and MTA staff.   4) Identification of potential consequences Eruption scenarios and hazard footprints established in objective 2 will be coupled with detailed population and infrastructure exposure assessments to evaluate the potential consequences of future eruptions. Methods for evaluating and mapping critical infrastructure remotely will be investigated and ground-truthed to assess their feasibility in enabling assessment at remote volcanoes, and overcome security concerns at some volcanoes. Identifying potential future eruption consequences will inform emergency management planning and preparedness.  5) Develop a volcanic hazards and risk communication and education strategy The project will build resilience through the education of communities, scientists, authorities and emergency managers. Work will include: - Education tools will be created to deliver basic volcanic hazard and risk, management and mitigation information, including posters, websites and films. - A volcanic crisis simulation exercise will be carried out with the relevant authorities in Turkey, to test command chains, communication chains and emergency response.  - A project report will provide an assessment of volcanic risk with recommendations for research priorities and actions required for planning for volcanic emergencies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Turkey</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="89" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-07">60902.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-07">81697.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-07">64889.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-07">3438.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-07">3585766.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_P008437_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FP008437%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
