<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T014954_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Africa Research Universities Alliance, Centre of Excellence for Non-Communicable Diseases</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Context. The rise in non-communicable diseases (NCDs) threatens to roll back the progress that has been made in health and development of Africa. Globally, the World Health Organisation (WHO) estimates that in 2008, there were 36 million deaths from NCDs, projected to rise to 50 million by 2050.  In 2008, these deaths were mainly from cardiovascular diseases (48%), cancers (21%), chronic respiratory diseases (12%) and diabetes (3.5%), with 80% of all the deaths occurring in low- and middle-income countries.  In Sub-Saharan Africa, WHO estimates that 23% of all deaths are from NCDs, and projected to grow to 27% by 2020.  What is however not clear, due to lack of data from the continent, is the distribution of among the key NCDs.  The rise in NCDs in Africa places a tremendous social and economic burden on communities through increased absenteeism, job loss, unaffordable medical costs, increased responsibilities from family members for care-giving, or complete loss of income from death of the breadwinner.  The loss of income (partial or complete) pushes low income households further into the poverty trap.  On a broader scale, the combined effect of decreased labour outputs, lower return on human capital investments, increased healthcare costs, and loss of economic activity, leads to increasing inequalities not only within populations, but between countries. The four common NCDs - cardiovascular diseases, cancers, chronic respiratory diseases and diabetes - have four shared behavioural risk factors: tobacco use, unhealthy diet, physical inactivity and harmful alcohol use.  These are in conjunction with other conditions including mental disorders, disabilities (including blindness and deafness), violence and injuries.  To achieve a reduction in the levels of NCDs, there must be a concerted effort to bring about behaviour change through evidence-based approaches by conducting localised research and training.   Aims and Objectives. The ARUA Centre of Excellence on NCDs (ACE-NCDs) provides a platform for the creation of a long-term strategic network of researchers in African Universities through a hub and spoke model to strengthen intra-African collaboration, and collaboration between the network and the rest of the world. The ACE-NCD will build on the strengths of the core university members, University of Nairobi (Kenya and the Hub), University of Ghana, University of Ibadan (Nigeria), Makerere University (Uganda) and the University of the Witwatersrand (S. Africa).  At its inception, the ACE-NCD has also partnered with the University of Leicester and University of Glasgow who shall support its development. In addition, the ACE-NCD will bring on board relevant stakeholders involved in prevention, control and management of NCDs within their regions including medical research institutions, relevant professionals, policy-makers, civil society to ensure co-design and co-production of high impact research output that shall be support policy-making, interventions, and commercialisable intellectual property. Continental and regional teams will be supported to develop grant proposals around the ACE-NCD thematic areas, thus ensuring sustainability and growth of ACE-NCD beyond the current grant.  Potential Application and Benefits. ACE-NCDs seeks to build capacity in holistic NCD research through training of Masters and PhD students (while ensuring co-supervision across member universities), targetted short courses in need-identified areas, staff and student exchanges, among other interventions. Dissemination of research output will be through journal and conference articles and book chapters targeting researchers and practitioners, policy-briefs, workshops and seminars aimed at policy-makers, stakeholders and civil society.  The envisioned outcome as a result of this capacity building funding is a vibrant, sustainable ACE-NCD at the forefront of NCD research, capacity-building and policymaking support in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project seeks to develop a strong collaborative research and training platform, the ARUA Centre of Excellence on Non-Communicable Diseases (ACE-NCD), anchored at five ARUA member universities: Nairobi, Makerere, Ibadan, Ghana and Witwatersrand - working closely with other universities on the continent and UK universities. Specifically, ACE-NCD shall seek to  1. Form a strong network of researchers broadly addressing the problem of NCDs in Africa. Researchers will be drawn from ACE-NCD universities, University of Glasgow and University of Leicester, as well as regional and international universities.  Research teams&apos; activities will revolve around six initial thematic areas: Prevention, mechanics of disease, multi-morbidity, bio-banking/biomarkers, models of care, and big data.   2. Bring on board other ARUA and non-ARUA African Universities, especially those that are less-research intensive. Each ACE-NCD spoke university will serve as a regional hub, actively engaging universities within their countries and regions: Ghana and Ibadan targetting West Africa, Nairobi and Makerere focussing on Eastern and Central Africa, and Witwatersrand on Southern Africa. Once on-board, these additional universities will actively collaborate with all members institutions across the continent and indeed the world. This approach will ensure the organic structured growth of the network leading to intra-Africa research capacity-building in NCDs.  3. Provide training and capacity-building in support of NCD research through Masters and PhD programmes (where students will be co-supervised by faculty drawn from the network) and post-doctoral training attached to existing and new research projects.  4. Develop and mount targeted short courses and capacity-building workshops and seminars offered both face-to-face and through e-learning.    5. Develop strong research collaborations with other global networks, initially with the World Universities Network where NCDs is one of its four key pillars and in which Nairobi and Ghana are active members with existing related research projects.  6. Build strong collaborations with African governments, policy-makers, non-university, research institutions, professionals, private sector players, and civil society through the regional hub approach for co-design and co-production to ensure relevance, usefulness, high quality of the research outputs.   7. Develop a vibrant research culture across the network, breaking down traditional silos within and across the member universities to form multi-institutional, multi-disciplinary research teams working to develop fundable high-impact research projects that address the challenges within the identified research themes. These projects will also build upon and strengthen on-going related research activities in member institutions. Supporting activities will include identification, dissemination and exploitation of funding opportunities, training on writing winning grant proposals, support in proposal preparation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-30">614772.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/T014954/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">50405</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T014954_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">50405</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T014954_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">50405</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T014954_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nairobi</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FT014954%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
