<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007589_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">21st Century Filipina Nature Writing for Sustainable Development and Environmental Justice</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To work in close partnership with and support ongoing efforts by two local NGOs towards the sustainable development of the Philippines. These include the Centre for Environmental Concerns (CEC), which is a Philippines-based environmental organization that works directly with under-resourced and marginalised communities around the country; and the National Coalition of Rural Women (PKKK for its Filipino acronym), which advocates for the rights, security, and political participation of rural Filipina women.  2. To shed light on the most pressing environmental issues of the Southeast Asia region, as identified &apos;on the ground&apos; and directly relayed by those with first-hand experience 3. To generate compelling evidence and illustrative personal accounts in support of claims by a growing number of organisations and civil society groups in the Philippines and other parts of the developing world, that socio-economic inequality is the single greatest threat to global environmental security and sustainability 4. To bolster critiques of capitalist conservation by fostering greater understanding of the communities it disempowers as well as the local environmental values and traditions it undermines 5. To highlight equitable and sustainable alternatives to capitalist conservation, and to inform environmental practices and policies at multiple scales by giving voice to the unique knowledges and practices of rural Filipina women - and then translating such insights into concrete policy recommendations for presentation to national and international policymakers 6. To honour, engage with, and help shape the future direction of nature writing by working to diversify, contextualise and modernise the art form. a. We aim to diversify nature writing by bringing in historically underrepresented voices, specifically those of rural communities, women, people of colour, and residents of the developing world b. We aim to contextualise nature writing within contemporary society by showcasing it as a locally-based tradition shaped by an increasingly globalised world - one that must grapple with the interconnectivity between environmental crises and social inequalities c. We aim to drive the modernisation and continued relevance of nature writing by expanding its already diverse array of forms and formats to include digital media, and in particular the &quot;video essay&quot;7. To address gender inequality in the fields of both nature writing and conservation by focusing on the female experience, and by celebrating women as authors and engaged environmental citizens</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research explores the potential of 21st century nature writing to empower disadvantaged communities, restore environmental rights at risk, and transform the global conservation agenda. Nature writing, which entails personal reflection and creative expression through language to record experiences of the natural world, encompasses many different formats: from poems, short stories, fables, essays, and journal entries, to annotated drawings, short skits, lyrical compositions, and - in the modern era - visual and spoken word performance through various digital media. While the art form has historically been associated with white, Western, upper-middle-class men, and has thus tended to reinforce social segregation and inequity even while inspiring responsible stewardship of the natural world, we re-envision it here in the hands of Filipina women as an instrument of sustainable development and environmental justice. Underpinning the research is a critique of the currently dominant neoliberal framework for global conservation, which involves monetising the natural world and incorporating its various components into the global economy as commodities. Of particular importance are problems identified by a growing number of local communities, environmental NGOs and social movements in the developing world, including Philippines-based advocacy organisations such as Ibon International and the Center for Environmental Concerns. As laid out in an open letter to the United Nations, authored by a coalition of civil society organizations led by Ibon International, more than a thousand signatories contend that capitalist conservation reinforces corporate rather than local control over natural resources, thus endangering livelihoods, threatening the sovereignty of vulnerable communities, and devaluing place-based knowledge. They further describe that the economisation of nature exacerbates rather than addresses existing social inequalities, which in turn fuel further resource exploitation and environmental degradation. The letter&apos;s authors instead call for environmental decision-makers to support a range of alternative knowledges and ecological practices as the &apos;building blocks&apos; of genuine people-centered sustainable development. Our research responds directly to this call by conducting a practice-based inquiry in the form of a nature writing workshop, delivered in partnership with local writers and community leaders, and under the guidance of two local advocacy organisations who work in the areas of environmental protection and women&apos;s empowerment, respectively. The workshop examines nature writing as tradition, identity, practice, communication, advocacy, and legacy - all while working towards the compilation of a 21st Century Filipina Nature Writing Anthology. It further engages participants in the digital humanities to produce a distinctly contemporary piece of nature writing - the video essay - which will be disseminated through social media. Ultimately, the project translates the environmental values, unique perspectives and future ambitions of rural Filipina women into specific and concrete policy recommendations, which will be presented to key national and international decision-makers, including the Philippine Commission on Women, in writing (in the form of a &quot;policy pack&quot;) as well as through live performance. A showcase event held in the final month of the project will be attended by community members, conservationists, invited local representatives and key national policy actors. It will feature vivid and compelling nature writing compositions, written and read by the participants themselves, towards the aim of educating audience members, informing local as well as national environmental governance and policy, and moving decision-makers at all scales to immediate action in line with the stories revealed and insights gained over the course of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-19">60482.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-19">20160.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-19">80643.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to University of Leicester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007589_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FP007589%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
