<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S013598_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cocoa; future yields across West Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seventy percent of the world cocoa production is produced by small holders in West Africa. However, yields are low and at risk from climate change, pests and diseases and many cocoa farming families live around or below the international poverty line. Major changes are needed to develop a sustainable supply chain.  Being able to accurately predict cocoa yields and production will be one such change. Currently,  accurate production forecasts are only available to a handful of large multinational cocoa companies and brokers, who run their proprietary forecasting programmes, based on physical monitoring of hundreds of cocoa farms. All other actors in the cocoa industry lack a reliable source of information about the expected harvest. However, such forecasts are essential to support planning and adaptation across the supply chain. They are also essential to price formation, which is determined in futures markets, which rely on participants&apos; expectations of future harvests. Currently, information is asymmetrical in the market, favouring the few big players.  Here we propose to use a demonstrated technology to generate accurate forecasting models at a fraction of the cost of the proprietary systems, making them affordable for a broad audience in the cocoa industry and hence contributing to the democratisation of the cocoa sector.  We combine a range of data sources now available over long periods (20-40 years) with machine learning and models to generate a robust forecast tool. We now have time series mapping of critical determinants of yield, including rainfall, leaf area index, surface soil moisture, soil physical properties. We also have regional and national yield data. There is strong evidence of climate (soil moisture) impacts on yield, but little information on the critical thresholds in drought stress effects. Here we use process modelling to link plant production to soil moisture through the rooting zone. We calibrate our model at site scale to couple plant-soil processes, and then calibrate the model at regional and national scale to couple yield to plant-soil indicators. The outcome is a robust tool for generating forecasts of yield through the year, with clear confidence intervals. This information provides the novel input for the cocoa value chain. The output from this research will form the scientific basis on which commercial providers can offer products and services to end-users in the cocoa industry, as demonstrated by two project partners. Once proven for cocoa, the approach can be replicated in a range of other crops, from grains to tropical commodities to vegetable oils.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The primary objective of this project activity is to launch a technology-based product for forecasting cocoa production and yields across the West African cocoa belt.  The project is divided into two components that support each other - a commercial development plan and a technical development plan. The objectives of the technical development plan are to: 1. Data collation and organisation. We will collate yield, production area, climate, soil, vegetation and land cover data across W Africa into a consistent database. 2. Data harmonisation and scaling. We will generate regional weather fields, and historic maps of cocoa growing area based on climate, verified against land cover maps. 3. Machine learning and simulation. We will calibrate our yield model at farm scale, and then produce regional gridded simulations of cocoa production and soil moisture.  4. Yield forecasting. We will use machine learning to generate a forecasting tool using time  series of yield data across the cocoa region, based on inputs from (3). 5. Demonstrate that this technology can produce yield forecast and production estimates of the same or higher accuracy as expensive pod-counting programmes The objectives of the commercial development plan are to: 1. Develop intelligent forecasting tools and techniques that to a stage where they can be packaged into commercial applications  2. Demonstrate the viability of the technology to key actors and prospective buyers in the cocoa industry in West Africa and Europe 3. Create a blue print for model-product integration that can be replicated across other agricultural commodities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-22">131084.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Innovation Award to University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE/S013598/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">43577.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S013598_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">21788.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S013598_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">21788.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S013598_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FS013598%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-11-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
