<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004498_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominica as a Centre of Excellence for the Preservation &amp; Celebration of the Creole Culture through Language, the Arts and its indigenous Kalinagos</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The kweyol language surfaced in Dominica and elsewhere in the Caribbean during slavery from the 1600s and became the first language among the natives.  About the middle of the last century this changed with the colonised mother tongue, English, moving into the main stream gradually replacing the creole tradition. That decline continued particularly among the youth, in the urban areas and spread into some rural regions. For many decades use of the indigenous Kweyol language was forbidden in the homes of the upper and middle class since it was then perceived as a practice among the lower class and rural population. Moreover, families who migrated and settled in the UK for the most part abandoned the creole culture.  As such, except in rare cases an identity gulf was created between Black-British descendants and their Creole heritage. However in the last 30 years there have been efforts on a national scale to expand its usage into non-traditional domains by cultural icons and advocates, the media, through tourism signage, internet and Parliament.  This involved a concerted drive towards &apos;creole brand recognition&apos; as a valued national heritage for its rich assets of a distinct language and an instrument for advancing creative cultural industries in the arts and among marginalised communities and the diaspora. Yet still today kweyol remains largely conceived as part of the cultural tradition celebrated in popular music, storytelling, dance and informal conversations, but generally this is limited mainly to Creole month activities.  Hence, there have been recent efforts by KEK and other advocates to raise the profile of the language and its accompanying creole art forms among the populace and within the cultural tourism market. Nevertheless, marked by significant limitations and challenges of a small island and an LMIC efforts have not been fully realised.  Accordingly, there is urgent need for an evidenced based approach to advance the work of KEK as a core driver to the national Creole cultural agenda of the island and in the wider Caribbean region. Thus the DoBeC network aims to explore, through public debate and research, ways in which the creole heritage can be preserved and further developed to ensure sustainability of the way of life, language, unique fashion and artforms. DoBeC seeks to celebrate innovative forms of its representation on the national tourism platform in the short term and future sustained growth at the level of World Heritage Status. In seeking in-depth contextual understanding through social constructivism and engaging activity theory the network will adopt a series of qualitative inquiry measures over a two-year period as follows:  1   Initial online scoping and planning meeting among lead investigators, 2017 2   Development of online presence via social media to initiate public awareness and promote the project, 2017 3   Public engagement workshop at the Dominica High Commission (UK), 2017 4   Creative Industries Expert Public Forum - University of Bedfordshire, 2017 5   A series of out-district workshops &amp; focus groups in key cultural hubs in Dominica       (Grand Bay, St. Joseph, Kalinago Territory, Petite Soufriere Area, Laplaine, Cottage/Portsmouth/Vielle Case), 2018 -2019 6   Youth symposium &amp; focus groups, Dominica State College 2018, 2019 7   Youth symposium &amp; focus groups UK, Dominica High Commission, April 2018, 2019  8   Expert video interviews with cultural experts, elders and icons on the island, 2018-2019 9   An International creole symposium in the Dominica during creole month October 2018 10 Academic conference - University of Bedfordshire, Summer 2019 11. Creation of Documentary, 2019  The data collected will serve to advance the research network specific objectives in the short and form a platform for advancing the broader mid to long term goals for KEK as a Centre of Excellence in Creole heritage and cultural preservation in the Caribbean region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The primary aim of DoBeC is to establish a research network between the University of Bedfordshire and the Kommite Pou Etid Kweyol (KEK), a Commonwealth of Dominica NGO an affiliate of The National Cultural Council, Cultural Division of Dominica to establish and develop advocacy for advancement of the Creole heritage and culture through the arts and humanities. The core focus of building this network with the LMIC The Commonwealth of Dominica, is for advancement of the Creole heritage and culture employing a multidisciplinary approach through the unique indigenous Kweyol language, arts (storytelling, song and dance), tourism and its indigenous Kalinago people.  In that regard, the networking activities aim to establish and sustain long term engagement and partnership between key actors and stakeholders in the LMIC Dominica and academics at the University of Bedfordshire so as to ensure collaboration which extends beyond participation in initial networking events. Importantly, the network aims to develop and advance policy proposal to establish the Commonwealth of Dominica via KEK and the National Cultural Council as a Centre of Excellence of the Creole Heritage &amp; Culture in the short to medium term, with prospects for seeking World Heritage status in the long term. DoBeC desires to strengthen links with other key regional and international organisations and actors in advancing marginalised indigenous Creole cultures in general and specifically in the wider Caribbean region among other Creole speaking communities namely, St Lucia &amp; Haiti (two LMICs).   DoBeC seeks to develop medium to long term international significance through creating further awareness and building stronger links with the international experts in the field in UK and beyond.  This will be facilitated through a discussion forum for stimulating debate on creative and innovative perspectives by which marginalised indigenous communities can be engaged and supported in bridging the gap across cultural borders and mixed identities.  As such, a pivotal short-term goal of the network is to employ a series of workshops and public engagement fora to advance a white paper for promotion of national policy on establishing (a pilot project) for KEK as a Centre Excellence, and driver of a national creole curriculum and related teacher training programmes. In this regard the specific objectives of the network are to: 1 Develop a platform for collaboration that aims at advancing the creole heritage and culture (language, food, arts, dance and fashion). 2 Instigate the development of a knowledge base regarding the creole heritage and culture and aimed at supporting advocacy, teaching and information dissemination. 3 Investigate and document core principles and best practices for advancing policy on preservation and promotion of the creole heritage and culture in pursuit of advancing KEK as a Centre of Excellence in Creole heritage and          cultural preservation in the Caribbean region and beyond. 4 To advance links through established and new international organisations that could help further the agenda of the network (example, International Federation of Art Council and Culture Agencies; Folk Research Centre, St. Lucia;           La Francophonie, Waitukubuli Culture and Tourism Initiative, UK among others) in the medium to long term. Evidence based research is needed to determine current attitudes, ascertain support for further institutionalising the creole culture and to document critical aspects of the heritage for sustainable development of all its dimensions.  Currently, in some genres much of the knowledge and history remains undocumented practices handed down (Taylor 2006) and in the minds of a few cultural elders and icons. As such it is critical that research is employed to first capture such valuable national information, and then to document and archiveit for sustainability of the creole culture, heritage and its art forms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bedfordshire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="DM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dominica</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="389" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-30">33899.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-30">4999</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-30">14528.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-11-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-11-30">53426.806</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to University of Bedfordshire</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004498_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bedfordshire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FR004498%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
