<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_P014577_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessing human impacts on the Red River system, Vietnam, to enable sustainable management</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Red River in Vietnam is located in a rapidly developing area of the world&apos;s 13th most populous country. The area, which supports 20 million inhabitants, includes a major rice-growing region, the mega-city of Hanoi and a range of industries each of which have expanded in recent decades. The Red River Delta (RRD) delta area of the river which discharges water into the Bay of Tonkin provides crucial ecosystem services including the retention and removal of nutrients and pollutants for groundwater (drinking water) and marine resource protection, carbon processing, flood protection which is heavily managed through a series of agricultural dikes and sediment transport which governs erosion and deposition at the vulnerable coastal zones. However, hydropower dam installation, increasing agricultural fertilizer use, increases in urban wastewater and use of a range of toxic contaminants threaten these ecosystem services and the health and wellbeing of the people who live in this region. The delta region is a complex and highly modified hydrological network which is difficult to model using calibrations developed on more straightforward river basins from temperate regions. Therefore, this proposal aims to improve modelling capabilities through the application of the alternative approach of Materials Flow Analysis which is more suited to complex systems. The project focuses on filling in knowledge gaps in understanding on relationships between hydrology, nutrients, carbon and pollutants in the RRD region for improved model calibration using a combination of stable isotope and organic geochemistry techniques which have rarely been applied in this area. The first part of the project will use stable isotopes of oxygen and hydrogen to quantify precipitation-surface water- groundwater interactions and estimate the extent of saline intrusions upstream from the coastal zone. The second work package will focus on understanding how dam installation alters nutrient and carbon sequestration and removal from the downstream river in order to better inform reservoir management. The third work package will aim to better constrain nutrient cycling in the delta (including carbon, nitrogen, phosphorus and silicon) through the use of stable isotope techniques. The work will be supported by a PhD student project using more recently developed techniques of dual nitrogen isotope analysis (analysing N and O atoms in nitrates) and the application of Silicon-30 which can provide important information on silica cycling, shown to be important in rice paddy areas. The final work package will focus on providing an updated assessment of toxic contaminants from this region because systematic monitoring has not been conducted recently. A broad suite of persistent organic pollutants and heavy metals will be analysed, with a focus on some problem chemicals in this region such as the pesticide DDT and its derivatives which was banned in 1995 but has increased after that time indicating illegal usage, and the dioxin herbicide defoliant &quot;Agent Orange&quot; which was used extensively in the Vietnam War. For the first time we will measure pharmaceutical residues in river sediments and suspended particulates in order to evaluate the distribution and trends of these compounds across the delta. The project will also install facilities for &quot;Microtox&quot; analysis in Vietnam, allowing rapid screening for toxic pollutants in order to pilot the use of this technique for environmental monitoring agencies. The outputs from this project will deliver improved capabilities for MFA modelling of nutrients and hydrology, the carbon budget, the first measures of emerging pollutants (pharmaceuticals), updated measures of legacy and persistent contaminants and a newly establish national capability for toxic pollutant screening.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal aims to provide an updated, detailed and process-based overview of macronutrient fluxes and pollutant distribution, to fill in knowledge gaps of C, N, P and Si processing and produce an improved model using Materials Flow Analysis for scenario planning in the Red River Delta (RRD), Vietnam.   The objectives of the proposal are therefore to: 1. Improve the spatial scale and techniques of hydrological monitoring using stable isotopes of oxygen and hydrogen to:  a. quantify how seasonal differences in rainfall influence the relative sources of water into the RRD (including groundwater)  b. identify the extent of saline intrusion from the coastal zone 2. Understand the functioning of reservoir impoundments upstream of the RRD to optimise management of suspended solids, nutrients, carbon and toxins delivery into the delta. 3. Improve the calibration of nutrient and materials flow analysis (MFA) models by increasing the spatial and temporal resolution of macronutrient (C, N, P and Si) monitoring  4. Use novel stable isotope techniques including analysis of Si-30 and dual nitrogen isotope analysis to understand how macronutrient processing differs in urban and agricultural areas of the RRD for better model calibrations.  5. Apply Materials Flow Analysis to develop scenarios for C, N, P and Si fluxes across the RRD. 6. Provide the first comprehensive carbon budgets for the RRD, including estimates of autochthonous versus allochthonous production to understand the consequences of watershed management for greenhouse gas exchange. 7. Estimate how toxic pollutant contamination including persistent organic pollutants, banned pesticides, legacy contaminants (including &quot;Agent Orange&quot;) and pharmaceutical derivatives are distributed throughout the RRD.  8. To understand how toxic contaminants vary with wet and dry seasons and how recent pollution compares with that in recent decades. 9. To establish toxin screening (&quot;Microtox&quot;) techniques in Vietnam for the first time with the aim of improving environmental monitoring capabilities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Viet Nam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-03">123840.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-03">124843.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-03">125855.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
