<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N000013_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Augmented urbanity and smart technologies: how &quot;smart&quot; are our cities becoming?</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We intend to work in two interconnected research areas - smart technologies and smart cities -, both important to understand the enormous urban transformations in the past two or three decades. These areas are grounded on our experiences as researchers, reflected in books, peer-reviewed publications, and conferences. The expected outcomes of this research will be of three main types: (a) Institutional cooperation: the construction of a permanent link between the four universities for the exchanging of students, future studies and joint research projects; (b) Joint publication: we expect that, at least, the main investigators will be able to produce one written outcome of this experience and, probably, 2 articles to be published in journals of relevance to the field of urban studies. (c) Students&apos; interchange: postgraduate students will strongly benefit from this experience of thematic and methodological exchange, and this is expected to reflect on a better quality of their dissertations and further publications.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-01-06"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-19">49513.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The idea of smart cities is based on the assumption that a substantial use of information and communication technologies (ICTs) in the management of urban functions can make cities work more efficiently and effectively. The objectives are three fold: 1. To critically explore forms of increasing interaction in the fields of augmented urbanities and smart urbanism, between scholars and students of the two Brazilian (PUCPR and UFBA) and British (Durham and Plymouth) universities, through a program of academic mobility. 2. To stimulate the debate and capacity for research about the use of ICTs for promoting spatial augmentation and smarter cities, and analyse the relationships with contemporary social and economic urban transformations. 3. To understand how the construction of meaningful spaces in the city as a sociotechnical process that involves an overlapping of different physical, cultural and technological layers, can augment our urban experience and wider developmental priorities."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
