<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005268_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using Digital Tools to Challenge Xenophobia and Support International Development in South Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) To work with groups of young people across the Gauteng province of South Africa to challenge the rising tide of xenophobia to be found in the country today, supporting the work of the international development NGO The Bishop Simeon Trust (BST) and the 20 Community Based Organisations (CBOs) it services in the region. 2) To realize the full impact potential of our original research, which sought to test current trends in the literature on digital engagement with heritage against the specific needs of museum and heritage professionals. Working with one of our original partners, the Johannesburg Holocaust and Genocide Centre (JHGC), this follow-on project will significantly amplify the project&apos;s original impact (which was largely focused on making a policy intervention) by supporting heritage professionals involved in the original project to develop new skills and enhance existing expertise in digital engagement. 3) To maximize the potential of the original research for the international development sector, providing an innovative model of how digital tools can draw out synergies between the heritage sector and CBO&apos;s working with communities that do not traditionally engage with organisations such as JHGC, in order to challenge discrimination, enhance inclusive decision making and community resilience. 4) Working with JHGC and peer educators from the Youth Committees of the CBOs supported by BST, the project will co-produce a set of digital educational resources. This material will draw on the JHGC&apos;s newly opened permanent exhibition on the history of the Holocaust and the Rwandan genocide, its current visiting exhibition on the global relevance of the Holocaust, the active community of survivors from both the Holocaust and Rwanda it works with, as well as the centre&apos;s wider archive. The material produced will explore the contemporary relevance of these moments in history for the lives of the young people the CBOs work with, and in particular the lessons that can be learnt for the current rise in xenophobic attacks facing the country. The specific nature of these resources will be agreed through the co-production process, but it is envisaged that they will include, for example, short films, photographic and video essays, interviews with survivors, digital exhibitions curating objects drawn from the centre&apos;s archive, family histories and creative writing, all of which will be presented in such a way as to raise questions, draw comparisons with, and prompt discussion about the current rise of contemporary xenophobic violence in South Africa.  5) To use the digital resources produced as part of a sustainable education programme to be rolled out across all 20 of BST&apos;s CBO and embedded within their on-going activities. 6) To incorporate all the digital resources generated into the online offering of the JHGC. These are to be freely available to all as an educational resource and will be publically disseminated beyond the project team via &apos;celebration&apos; events towards the end of the project. 7) To use a selection of the resources generated as part of a digital installation that will be exhibited at the JHGC. 8) To provide a career-development opportunity for a project RA to gain experience in partnership working between university researchers, the heritage and international development sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project will work with groups of young people across the Gauteng province of South Africa to challenge the rising tide of xenophobia to be found in the country today, supporting the work of the international development NGO The Bishop Simeon Trust (BST) and the 20 Community Based Organisations (CBOs) it services in the region.   Working in partnership with BST and the Johannesburg Holocaust &amp; Genocide Centre (JHGC), the project will use the exhibitions, archive and other resources of JHGC to create a set of digital educational materials that will explore the lessons that can be learnt for South Africa today from the ethnic violence of the Holocaust and the Rwandan Genocide.  The project will draw on the research findings of Cooke&apos;s AHRC project &apos;Experiencing the Digital World: the Cultural Value of Digital Engagement with Heritage&apos; on the ways in which the co-production of digital heritage assets can, when time and resources permit, genuinely connect grassroots communities with heritage institutions, effecting a fundamental shift in the relationship between the two. Over the course of the project, the group will work together to make a range of digital resources, the precise nature of which will be decided via a process of knowledge exchange and co-produduction. It is envisaged that the project will produce short films, video and photographic essays, curate small digital exhibitions, research family histories or produce creative writing, all of which will be presented in such a way as to raise questions, draw comparisons with, and prompt discussion about the rise of contemporary xenophobic violence in South Africa. These resources will then be used as part of an educational programme to be rolled out across, and embedded within, the wider educational activities of all the CBOs.  In so doing, the project will give BST the opportunity to further strengthen the CBOs, as well as explore new means of building the confidence and resilience of the children and young people supported. It will provide a safe space for the exploration of the highly sensitive issues around xenophobia and empower young people to consider root causes, consequences and means of resolution within their own communities. This will have the impact of helping to challenge prejudice at community level, leading to greater prioritization of xenophobia by community leaders and help identify long term and sustainable community-led solutions. The project will also give JHGC the opportunity to undertake a sustained period of work with CBOs that have a far more diverse demographic than the visitors they have worked with hitherto. It will develop the digital skill-base of colleagues working at the centre, allowing them to undertake future digital co-production projects, exploring how digital tools can provide new and better ways to deliver its broader mission &apos;to use the history of the Holocaust and Rwandan genocide to intervene directly in contemporary debates on human rights abuses, xenophobia, racism and bigotry&apos;. The material produced will be incorporated into the centre&apos;s online offering and will be freely available to all. A selection of the materials will also be exhibited as a digital installation at the centre itself.  Thus, the project responds to the &apos;Highlight Notice for International Development&apos;. It will &apos;catalyse knowledge exchange, shared learning and capability development&apos; between cultural organisations and diverse community groups and &apos;explore ways that arts and humanities research can inform approaches to inclusive participatory decision-making, community engagement, co-production, social innovation and user-led service design in an ODA recipient country&apos;, in order to make &apos;a significant contribution to the UN&apos;s 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development&apos;, specifically, Goal 16 to &apos;promote just, peaceful and inclusive societies&apos;, by &apos;challenging discrimination&apos; and supporting &apos;participatory and representative decision-making at all levels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-22">53750.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-22">26875.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-22">80626.348</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P005268_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FP005268%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
