<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R008086_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CLOSER GCRF Senior Research Associate Post</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UK is world leading in the collection, curation, storage and analysis of complex social data, and UCL is one of a small number of UK Research Organisations with broad ranging capability in this area. This post seeks to harness and expand UK expertise through working in partnership with other Research Councils, in-country organisations (e.g. research organisations, UK Department for International Development, policy actors, communities and charities), international organisations (e.g. Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development, the United Nations, World Bank, US National Institute of Aging) and existing investments (e.g. MRC&apos;s existing units, the Wellcome Trust and NIA&apos;s existing cohort studies in developing countries) to build capacity for data collection, research and analysis within and between countries and regions to enable better targeted development initiatives. There are three key elements to this post:  1. To develop a strategic understanding of the issues and opportunities offered by this research, and help plan and execute appropriate subsequent activities to strengthen capacity in this area.  2. To play an active role in CLOSER&apos;s UK activities through, for example, research activity, communication and impact or assistance with training and capacity building. 3. To carry out high-quality research based on quantitative analysis of longitudinal studies in a development context. The post holder and their GCRF work will be guided by, and report to, a small steering group of senior academics. They will be a member of the CLOSER team based at UCL&apos;s Institute of Education and will managed by CLOSER&apos;s Director, Professor Alison Park. Some overseas travel will be expected as part of the role.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This application is for funding from ESRC for a period of three years to fund a post at UCL that supports the development and delivery of plans to position the UK&apos;s longitudinal studies to best engage with GCRF opportunities and partners. The post will support cutting-edge research that addresses the challenges faced by developing countries.  There are three key elements to this post:  1) To develop a strategic understanding of the issues and opportunities offered by this research, and help plan and execute appropriate subsequent activities to strengthen capacity in this area.  2) To play an active role in CLOSER&apos;s UK activities through, for example, research activity, communication and impact or assistance with training and capacity building. 3) To carry out high-quality research based on quantitative analysis of longitudinal studies in a development context. The post holder and their GCRF work will be guided by, and report to, a small steering group of senior academics. They will be a member of the CLOSER team based at UCL&apos;s Institute of Education and will managed by CLOSER&apos;s Director, Professor Alison Park.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-16" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-24">75607.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-24">101422.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-24">51019.07</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-24">304886.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R008086_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FR008086%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-07-16"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
