<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003731_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ARUA Water Centre of Excellence Development: &quot;Water for African SDGs&quot;</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Where: SDGs (Sustainable Development Goals), U (university), CoE (Centre of Excellence), CSES(Complex Social-Ecological System) &amp; landscape/catchment/watershed: synonymous.  The &quot;Water for African SDGs&quot; project will establish &amp; develop the ARUA Water CoE as an effective, high-performance, hub &amp; network of 8 African Universities&apos; researchers &amp; post graduate students. CoE research development will be based on understanding humans living on earth as the intricate coupling of society with the natural world - CSESs. We will forefront community engagement &amp; knowledge sharing for sustainability. We will use research to catalyse change towards social and ecological justice and sustainability, paying attention to African community water and sanitation needs.       The Water CoE has developed a systemic image of the SDGs as a planning, practice &amp; evaluation tool. The image has SDG 6, Clean water &amp; sanitation, at the centre, linking two primary water cycles: i) Water in a Catchment (rainfall, run-off, ground water recharge, evapo-transpiration, evaporation); &amp;  ii) Water Services - supply &amp; sanitation (raw water from the natural resource, often in dams, pipes &amp; pumps to water treatment works, treated potable water to households, waste water to treatment works &amp; discharge into the natural resource).        Several nodes place their water research in a climate change context (SDG 13), and acknowledge that water is integral to SDG 15 (life on land), 11 (sustainable cities &amp; communities), &amp; 12 (responsible consumption &amp; production), Effective water resource management, supply and sanitation requires good water governance by strong institutions (SDG 16). The Water CoE itself embodies SDGs 17 (partnerships to reach goals), 4 (quality education) &amp; 5 (gender equality).       Each CoE node has strengths in different parts of these cycles. This project brings together strengths, so nodes can flexibly link &amp; respond innovatively to research funding calls, &amp; effectively apply research. Capacity-building, exchanges and mentorship will mainly be addressed through the development &amp; delivery of a 3-day course by each node, to 14 participants from 3-5 other nodes. Participants will be doctoral students, early-, mid-career &amp; established researchers. Nodes will host a course on their primary strength, nodes will co-develop courses out of secondary strengths.        In Year 1, the hub (Rhodes U), will deliver a core foundation course to 3 delegates from each node (total 21), on Adaptive Integrated Water Resources Management (A-IWRM), including the CSES concept, transdisciplinarity and water governance. Node courses will run over Years 1 &amp; 2, and an early identification of course areas is: Landscape restoration &amp; catchment water use (Addis Ababa U, Ethiopia), hydrology, geohydrology &amp; hydraulic regimes for IWRM (U Dar es Salaam, Tanzania), optimising benefit from dams (Cheikh Anta Dio U, Senegal), biodiversity, natural resource management, water-energy-food nexus  (U Rwanda), urban water pollution (U Lagos, Nigeria), urban water quality design (U Cape Town, South Africa), &amp; water in future cities (Makarere U, Uganda). Course days will include time to work on research proposals. In Year 3, activities will focus on grant applications and a Water CoE delegation attending a relevant international conference to present the outcomes of the whole project.       Over the 3-year period, each node will have one opportunity to invite/visit an international specialist, &amp; by the end of year 3 at least 3 collaborative research projects will be running, each progressing an SDG challenge-area. Spin-off companies in water &amp; sanitation could be emerging, and each node will have community-based water and/or sanitation impact successes. At least 24 early career researchers and 24 doctoral students will be mentored through the CoE. We will demonstrate the clear emergence of an African water research cohort, addressing water-related SDGs, with positive outcomes and impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-09-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">105635.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">202086.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">50725.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-03">255270.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="1.  To establish &amp; develop the ARUA Water CoE as an effective, high-performance, research hub &amp;nodes (spokes) network of African researchers &amp; post graduate students. The CoE will develop strong interlinking relationships through co-learning and capability development across the research strengths of hydrology, environmental water quality (pollution), aquatic ecological infrastructure (ecosystems), and water in landscapes and cities. The CoE will use a transdisciplinary and systemic approach to discipline-integration,in addressing African water -related Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).  2. To establish a common intellectual grounding &amp; post graduate supervision capabilities in complex social ecological systems and transdisciplinarity, resulting in a confident praxis within sustainability &amp; resilience science. The CoE Hub will offer a 4-day core course attended by 3 delegates from each node, to establish a common integrating philosophy and methodology. Follow-up support will use distance learning technologies. 3. To recognise the primary and secondary research strength/sat each node, and to ensure that each node has:  i) identified established, mid- and at least 2 early career researchers, ii) fostered mentorship of early career researchers &amp; co-supervision of at least 3 post-graduate students. 4.  To locate the primary and secondary research strengths in relation to the SDGs; and to identify and agree on co-learning collaborations best suited to build research capacity across the CoE. Primary research strengths are: adaptive integrated water resources management (IWRM), including transdisciplinarity and water governance (Rhodes U, South Africa). Landscape restoration &amp; catchment water use (Addis Ababa U, Ethiopia), hydrology for IWRM (U Dar es Salaam, Tanzania), ecological infrastructure &amp;ecosystem services (Cheikh Anta Dio U, Senegal), irrigated agriculture (U Rwanda, Rwanda), urban water pollution (U Lagos, Nigeria), urban water quality design (U Cape Town, South Africa), &amp; water in future cities (Makarere U, Uganda). Therefore, for example, Dar es Salaam U has primary research strength in Hydrology, and at least Rhodes U and Makarere U have hydrology as secondary strengths. These three nodes (and any other that identify hydrology as a secondary strength) will co-develop CoE research excellence, capacity and productivity in hydrology - and will collaborate in transdisciplinary activities.  5. To use the development of primary-strength courses as the core mechanism for knowledge sharing and research capability building.  Each node will prepare and deliver a 4-day course in their primary area to 15 delegates from 2-5 other nodes.    6.  To enable each node to invite/visit a relevant international specialist to engage with knowledge and skills transfer and the co-development of research grant proposals.    7. To use the co-development of knowledge among the nodes during and between courses to submit at least 3 research grant proposals over the 3 years.      8.  To ensure each post graduate student presents published work at one local conference, and each node to have published at least 3 papers.    9. To have the whole CoE prepare, motivate and participate in a session at an international conference. (All nodes with at least one researcher and two post-graduate student delegates). A full session on CoE work demonstrating disciplinary excellence, and transdisciplinary integration to address SDG water-related challenges, will be a clear demonstration of capacity development. The CoE will be established internationally as a network of water-related research strength.  10. To develop a cohort of African water researchers working to address complex water-related problems. Meeting this objective will be demonstrated at the international conference, through publications and post-graduate readiness for graduation."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">50317.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003731_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">55317.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003731_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">50317.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003731_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">50317.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003731_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">50725.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T003731_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
