<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R007810_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Monitoring Object and Visitor Environments (MOVE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Museums are repositories for our cultural heritage and are responsible for the care of precious collections for the benefit of present and future generations. Key to this stewardship role is the management of indoor conditions to prevent deterioration of vulnerable objects. Preventive control measures are required to keep the indoor climate within conservation limits by maintaining environmental conditions within certain parameters and by minimising environmental fluctuations. Visitors and staff also demand excellent thermal comfort, access to natural light and good air quality to enable them to access these collections. Conflicting environmental requirements often require a degree of compromise, and managing these environmental demands will become ever more challenging for museums as the impact of climate change leads to more frequent extreme weather conditions. Where environmental control and management systems in museums fail to respond to adverse and unstable climatic conditions vulnerable artefacts will inevitably deteriorate, and the need to accurately monitor microclimatic variations over time is fundamental to good museum practice.   The safe preservation of cultural heritage is an essential mission of Egyptian museums where some of the world&apos;s most ancient and valuable artefacts are conserved (Ingo et al, 2015). The lack of environmental control programmes in the region is generally attributed to resource limitations and skills shortages, which often result in compromised indoor environmental quality leading to the accelerated deterioration of vulnerable objects. These risks can be mitigated with adequate knowledge of the indoor environmental parameters required for collections care and with robust and accurate monitoring programmes. New user-friendly methods of monitoring using cutting-edge technology are needed if Egyptian museums are to take action in response to changing external conditions and reduce the threat of damage to artefacts from extreme weather patterns.   Our research project proposes to develop a visual live environmental dashboard of digital data that is aimed at assisting museum curators in achieving stable and controlled indoor conditions to address seasonal variations and unpredictable weather patterns. The project will contribute a new application for the use of real-time environmental data as a means of supporting actions to reduce risks to artefacts and improve comfort in visitor areas. A key principle of the digital platform will be its ease of use. One case study museum in Salford, UK and two in Cairo, Egypt, will provide the basis for prototyping the dashboard. Internal environmental parameters recorded at each site will be used to assess the performance of the case studies against relevant conservation requirements, comfort standards and energy benchmarks, and to develop a user-friendly prototype sensor management live dashboard that can be replicated in other museums across Egypt. The proposed dashboard will provide accurate measurements of a range of criteria including exposure and illumination in natural and artificial light, pollution levels (CO2 and dust particles), relative humidity, solar ultraviolet radiation, internal operative and air temperature, external temperature, and energy use figures. In-situ detailed live monitoring of this environmental data will inform decision-makers and staff on curation, exhibition design and safe storage environments while optimising consumption of resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of the MOVE project is to respond to the challenges of climate change and its implications for the care of collections and for energy management in museums in Egypt by providing an advanced tool for environmental monitoring. At present, internationally important collections in Egyptian museums are at risk from poor environmental controls and unstable and inappropriate conditions, which are leading to the deterioration of vulnerable artefacts.   We will deliver on this aim through achievement of the following objectives:  - We will address the lack of available standards appropriate to this region by building on existing environmental standards for museums in the UK and elsewhere to develop a set of criteria for collections care and visitor comfort which is accurate and appropriate to Egyptian contexts.   - These criteria will form a basis for establishing an integrated monitoring regime for a range of relevant environmental parameters, including light, temperature, humidity and pollutant particles.  This monitoring will encompass museum storage areas housing different artefact types including organic and inorganic materials as well as exhibition spaces where visitor comfort is a key consideration.   - The platform we will create for live monitoring of these complex environmental parameters represents an alternative to traditional more cumbersome manual methods of data collection. This will support a more sophisticated approach to managing museum environments in response to challenging and changing climatic conditions. It will facilitate enhanced environmental management for three key applications: collections care, visitor comfort, and energy efficiency.   - Designs for a dashboard will initially be developed in the UK combining existing best practice in this area with pilot studies at Salford Museum to create test models. These models will be tested and refined in Egyptian contexts to address a range of usability criteria and ensure the dashboard responds to local needs, including the display and visualisation of data, technical performance, maintenance, language etc. The final dashboard design will present relevant data in an accurate and easily accessible visual format and be straightforward for museum staff to understand and implement.   - To address skills shortages in this area training will be provided to museum staff and trainee graduates to build capacity and widen the impact of the project with a view to improving the long-term care of Egyptian cultural heritage.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Salford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-20">36394.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-20">83903.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-20">68199.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-20">188498.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Large Grants Award to University of Salford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/R007810/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Salford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FR007810%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
