<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N024028_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RCUK-CONICYT Mucosal health and microbiota during sea lice parasitism: effect of oral delivery of immunomodulants</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The mucosal surfaces (skin, intestine and gills) of fish are constantly interacting with a wide range of pathogens and, in concert with the resident mucosal microbiota, are the first line of host defence. Several immune factors have been described in fish mucus and their presence and abundance can be affected by pathogen infection. As a consequence, the mucosa-associated microbiota can be affected and this may lead to dysbiosis, a microbial imbalance on or inside the body, which reduces the beneficial role of microbiota on the innate immune system and may lead to secondary infections by opportunistic microbes. Sea lice (Lepeophtheirus salmonis and Caligus spp.) infections are the most economically important causative agents of disease in marine-farmed salmonids worldwide. Caligus rogercresseyi is the main ectoparasite affecting the Chilean salmon industry with estimated costs of up to $120 million annually. This parasite damages external surfaces of the integument providing portal of entry for secondary infectious pathogens, and infected fish also become stressed which leads to immunosuppression with consequent increased susceptibility to the secondary infections. Other Caligid parasites (Caligus rogercresseyi and other Caligus spp.) have detrimental impacts on mariculture  operations in both developing and developed parts of the world which causes economic losses of US$ 100&apos;s millions annually. The development of novel methods to prevent or reduce sea lice infection is therefore a high priority for the industry. An essential prerequisite for improved treatments strategies is a better understanding of relationship between host-microbiome-parasite at the epidermal interface. Therefore, the aim of this research programme is to evaluate the influence of sea lice parasitism on mucosal health, including aspects of the immune response and host microbiota. We will evaluate the effect of immunomodulants on susceptibility to sea lice infection, and on gut and mucus quality by determining epidermal mucus proteomic responses, microbiota changes and mucosal transcriptomic changes. We will correlate the responses of the host and the sea lice during the early stages of parasitism in order to develop new strategies (i.e. identify antigens for vaccines, targets for RNAi, probiotics, prebiotics, immunomodulants) for sea ice control.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The mucosal surfaces (skin, intestine) constitute the first line of defence against pathogen invasion and simultaneously carrying out other critical physiological processes (nutrient absorption; osmoregulation). Caligus rogercresseyi has recently become a significant parasite of concern on salmon farms in Chile, causing very important economic losses every year. This ectoparasite feeds on host mucus, epidermal tissue and blood. Understanding both how mucosal health is impacted by parasites and how dietary additives can enhance mucosal barriers is essential to improve the management of farmed salmon and to develop new strategies to reduce diseases (microbiota manipulation, prebiotics, probiotics, dietary additives, therapies), which is very important for aquaculture as a global industry. The general aim of this proposal is to evaluate the influence of sea lice parasitism (C. rogercresseyi) on Atlantic salmon mucosal health, including aspects of immune responses, mucus barrier and microbiota. To address this aim, we will begin by identifying mucus-associated microbiome in healthy salmonids. Then, we will evaluate the effect of C. rogercresseyi parasitism on both skin and gut mucus-associated microbiome (Specific obj.1). At this stage, we will be able to identify bacterial OTUs that might be involved in determining host protection or host susceptibility. Subsequently, we will focus on the host response to parasitism. We will study and characterize the response of Atlantic salmon to sea lice parasitism using transcriptomic and proteomic approaches (Specific obj.2). Differentially expressed genes will be examined by RNAseq, and biological function pathway analysis, will be performed in order to identify expression modules for key functions for fish that are infested with low and high parasite loads compared to uninfected controls. Proteomic profiling and quantitative proteomic analysis of salmon epidermal mucus will be conducted to further characterize the host response and to ascertain which proteins correlate with susceptibility to parasitism. Simultaneously, we will focus on Caligid transcriptomic responses (Specific obj.3). Caligids from low and high level infested fish will be compared to explore variance in response to the different levels of host susceptibility. Caligus samples will be also collected to investigate the response of the parasite to the potentially immunomodulated salmon (Specific obj.4). In the next stage, we will determine the efficacy dietary immunomodulants in modulating host immunity, microbiota and resistance to Caligus infestation in lab scale experiments (Specific obj.4). The effects of the feed additives on salmon skin immunological responses, epidermal mucus proteomics and skin microbiome will be determined to understand their possible modes of action. After dietary treatment, immunomodulated salmon will be challenged with Caligus to evaluate dietary effects on sea lice load. This will allow us to identify dietary treatments that can (or cannot) improve resistance to Caligus infestation. Our last stage will be the validation of our findings at farming scale (Specific obj.5). The focus will be determine genes/proteins/bacterial genera that have been identified to correlate with parasitism, that occur consistently across laboratory and farm settings, in order to help inform future treatment strategies. Specific aims: 1] To evaluate the effect of sea lice parasitism on gut and skin mucus associated microbiota; 2] To characterize the response of Atlantic salmon to sea lice parasitism using transcriptomic and proteomic approaches; 3] To identify differentially regulated genes of sea lice during parasitism; 4] To evaluate the effect of immunomodulants on gut and skin mucus associated microbiota and host susceptibility to sea lice infection; 5] To identify suitable approaches for future treatment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Plymouth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-29">26492.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-29">138691.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-29">70825.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-29">262717.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Plymouth</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/N024028/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Plymouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FN024028%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
