<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029005_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Digital Diagnostics for Africa Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Preventable and treatable diseases cause a huge amount of illness and a huge number of deaths in Africa. Infectious diseases, like malaria, are some of the biggest killers. Not only do these diseases cause major health problems for those infected, they are also a major financial burden to individuals and communities, and they hinder economic and societal development for whole countries. The poorest and most marginalized communities are usually the worst affected, and so these diseases exacerbate inequalities associated with geography, gender and ethnicity.  Current strategies to tackle infectious diseases in the poorest settings rely on rudimentary approaches to diagnosis and treatment, such as reliance on a few clinical features (like fever, difficulty breathing or pallor) and very few simple tests to decide the treatment someone should receive. This approach is necessary because there are rarely diagnostic laboratories nearby to provide comprehensive testing, and even if there are, their services are often too expensive. Unfortunately, the simple methods of diagnosis often result in incorrect diagnosis, and provide little data from which to learn how to improve. A wrong diagnosis can mean the wrong treatment is given, resulting in prolonged illness or death, whilst at the same time encouraging overuse of some treatments like antibiotics or anti-malaria drugs, which can drive resistance to these drugs. A revolutionary solution to this problem is to develop a new generation of digital diagnostic tests which can be used at the point-of-care in even the hardest-to-reach communities. These diagnostic tests are not only more accurate and faster than current alternatives but potentially cost saving. Digital diagnostics have the potential to transform the situation by linking the precision typical of an advanced laboratory with the portability, connectivity, analysis and support that can be provided through a modern smart phone. This means tests can be administered anywhere and anytime by a wide range of healthcare workers with minimal training. For example, a drop of blood collected from the tip of the finger of child by a health worker in their community, could be applied to a tiny microchip powered by a mobile phone battery, and within 15-20 minutes a result could be available to make a diagnosis. The results are transmitted from the microchip to a smartphone via Bluetooth so no internet connection is required. If &quot;Malaria&quot; is detected, the device can notify the healthcare worker of the type of malaria and the correct treatment. The smartphone could also send the result and location data via the mobile network to a remote computer system, which could determine whether there is an unusually high level of malaria in that area and, if so, notify the national Malaria control program that extra resources are required to tackle an outbreak before it gets worse. Thus the child benefits from the right treatment, the community benefits from the intervention, and the health authorities benefit from being able to allocate the resources available to where they are most needed or will work best. The real-time data also allows international organizations to make more effective policies to tackle malaria and allocate funding. In our proposal we are developing a network of scientists with diverse skills and expertise, joining them together with commercial companies that manufacture diagnostics, and organizations who work directly in African countries putting new disease control tools and strategies into practice. This network will plan how best to develop new digital diagnostic devices to tackle health problems in Africa. The network will test its strategies by specifically planning the development of a new digital diagnostic test device for malaria and drawing out a roadmap to its implementation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of the project is to develop a Network for the development of digital diagnostics for Africa. The Network will bring together appropriate expertise to conceive, plan and implement a development strategy for innovative digital diagnostics that address urgent health needs specific to the African continent. Our objectives for the one-year Network grant are focused on a Pathfinder project, building the necessary community of experts to help develop an innovative point-of-care digital molecular diagnostic and disease surveillance platform called Lacewing, with a particularly focus on the application of Lacewing to malaria in the first instance. Specific objectives of the Pathfinder project are: 1. Establish a network partnership to plan, enable, and evaluate the development of a novel digital diagnostic platform for malaria diagnosis, surveillance and control in Africa; 2. Describe a generalizable framework for Africa-led development and evaluation of digital molecular diagnostic platforms, and to broadly define target product profiles for these digital diagnostics; and 3. Identify efficient capacity building activities which are needed to enable innovation, development and evaluation of locally-prioritized digital diagnostics for other infectious and non-infectious diseases in Africa. Our Network of stakeholders, with a diversity of skills and expertise, will help design the roadmap required to develop a new diagnostic device from conception to implementation, ultimately improving the health of some of the poorest communities in the world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">135412.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">8937220.512</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to Imperial College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029005_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT029005%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
