<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004084_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-State Education and Ethnic Conflict in Myanmar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aim 1 - Networking and knowledge creation:  To connect an international network of scholars, researchers and practitioners in order to analyse the politics of non-state education and ethnonational conflict in Myanmar.  Our objectives are: a) to connect London-based scholars working on education, knowledge and conflict with researchers and practitioners from non-state ethnic nationalities-based education regimes in Myanmar through organising three workshops; b) to develop a shared understanding of the main challenges faced by non-state ethnic nationalities-based education in Myanmar on the basis of our initial framework as well as participatory methodology focusing on participants&apos; auto-ethnographic observations;  c) to analyse the similarities and differences between these experiences and perceptions to feed into subsequent academic and policy publications. Aim 2 - Networking and impact:  To facilitate knowledge sharing amongst education researchers and practitioners from different ethnic minorities in Myanmar together with other civil society actors and strengthen their voice in the national education reform process as well as with the international donor community.  Our objectives are:  a) to support knowledge and experience sharing amongst education practitioners and researchers from different ethnic minorities in Myanmar;  b) to support learning and knowledge sharing between education practitioner researchers from different ethnic minorities in Myanmar and UK-based researchers with expertise on education in ethnonationalist conflicts in other contexts;  c) to support the networking and learning between non-state education practitioners and researchers and broader civil society; d) to facilitate non-state education practitioner researchers ability to inform international donors and development agencies engaged in Myanmar&apos;s education reform. Aim 3 - Outputs and Impact:  To produce impactful scholarly, media and policy outputs on the politics of non-state education and ethnonational conflict in Myanmar.  Our objectives are: a) to produce at least two co-authored, peer-reviewed article on different non-state ethnic nationalities-based education as a window into the identity politics of conflict in Myanmar; b) to facilitate a conversation between non-state education researchers and practitioners on a Southeast Asia politics blog;  c) to produce a policy report, including recommendations, on the politics of non-state ethnic nationalities-based education and its potential for conflict transformation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This network aims to bring together London-based scholars working on education, knowledge and ethnonational conflict with education researchers and practitioners in Myanmar. Its main aim is to analyse the role of non-state education in Myanmar&apos;s competing nation-building projects and ethnic conflict. In doing so to it aims to a) generate academic and policy-relevant knowledge on the extensive landscape of non-state ethnic minority-based education regimes in Myanmar&apos;s conflict zones, to b) aid capacity building of education practitioners and researchers in Myanmar&apos;s ethnic minority communities, and to c) to inform the country&apos;s education reform, including international donors engaged in the reform process.  This is important as education has long served as a main vehicle for Myanmar&apos;s violent nation-building, including the forced assimilation of its ethnic minorities. At the same time, competing non-state education regimes have emerged as one of the means of resistance amongst the numerous revolutionary movements recruited from ethnic minorities. In order to analyse the politics of these non-state education regimes the network will use participatory research methods, including auto-ethnographic approaches that draw on the extensive experience of its local participants: education researchers who are themselves involved in non-state education provision. This will help to address the main paradoxes that ethnic-minority education providers are confronted with: 1) the tension between their aspiration to modernity and their need to create and preserve identities, ancestry and heritage and 2) the tension between resistance against an ethnocratic state oppression and the need to homogenise and solidify fluid and diverse ethnic minority identities into salient ethnic categories under the banner of an alternative nationalism. The network aims to address these challenges in three workshops (two in Myanmar and one in London). The workshops will provide the platform to connect the network, generate empirical and conceptual knowledge about non-state education in Myanmar, provide a platform for knowledge and experience sharing between participants, and inform Myanmar&apos;s education reform and international donors by incorporating seminars for a policy audience. The network will also disseminate its findings through academic, media and policy publications.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goldsmiths College</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">37133.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">268.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">16214.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-07">53616.528</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to Goldsmiths College</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004084_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Goldsmiths College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FS004084%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
