<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N017528_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Metabolic adaptation and nutrient acquisition of Paracoccidioides spp. during host interactions: Search for targets and new therapeutic approaches</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Paracoccidioides spp. is the etiological agent of Paracoccidioidomycosis, a human systemic mycosis, with high prevalence in Brazil. It forms a complex of at least four phylogenetic species that can cause chronic or severe acute systemic mycoses. Paracoccidioidomycosis mainly affects rural workers, which require, when diagnosed positive for an infection, ongoing treatment for 2 to 3 years.  Investigations have been initiated to study the molecular mechanisms of metabolic adaptation of Paracoccidioides, since this response is relevant for manifestation and progression of disease within the host. Initial transcriptional and proteomic studies suggest that within the Paracoccidioides genus the preferred metabolic routes not only depend on the morphotype, and the direct interaction with the host, but also the phylogenetic subspecies. Therefore the major objectives of this project are:  - To characterise the four virulent Paracoccidioides subspecies for differences in their metabolic physiology under the transition into the yeast morphology, which is the morphology found in infected tissues.  - To heterologously express enzymes of key metabolic pathways as targets for inhibitor screenings. Here, natural and semi-synthetic compounds will be tested for their in vitro and subsequently in vivo efficacy to block Paracoccidioides spp metabolism.  - To generate bioluminescent reporter strains that are suitable to assess the expression of certain genes under changing environmental conditions and, more importantly, will allow to follow disease progression and therapy efficacy under in vivo conditions in infection models.  - To generate bioluminescent knock down mutants that will elucidate and verify the importance of specific metabolic pathways under in vivo conditions in infection models. By using the bioluminescence imaging approach, niche specific colonisation in dependence of the metabploc physiology will be determined.  - To analyse metabolic knock down mutants for general changes and adaptations of the metabolic profile. This will provide insights into the plasticity of Paracoccidioides spp. metabolism.  - To identify inhibitors of Paracoccidioides metabolism that might provide sources for new antifungal agents. The spectrum of fungi targeted as well as cytotoxicity will be determined. Compounds with lhigh antifungal efficacy will be patented and selected for future therapy studies in model systems.  We assume that this research proposal can promote long-term sustainable growth and economic development by broadening the knowledge of the metabolic prerequisites of Paracoccidioides spp during infection, by refining infection models for Paracoccidiodomycosis, elucidating virulence mechanisms and by exploring new therapeutic targets.  This proposal will also increase the skills and knowledge by adding new technologies that support the development of the research infrastructure. In this way, the improvement of human skills will counteract poverty and promote economic growth in Brazil.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The number of life-threatening fungal infections is steadily increasing. Due to limited diagnostic and therapeutic opportunities invasive fungal infections may cause lethality rates of more than 50%. Paracoccidioides brasiliensis is an ubiquitous fungus in Latin America. This fungus has a dimorphic life-style with a filamentous growth morphology at lower and a yeast morphology at elevated temperatures. In soil the filamentous form is the prevalent morphology and asexual conidia are formed from hyphae. These conidia are easily inhaled by farm workers. After inhalation condia may germinate and form persisting yeast cells in the lung. It has been assumed that in Latin America -and especially in Brazil- approximately 10 million people carry a latent infection with Paracoccidioides spp.  and in 1 - 2% of cases the fungus is no longer controlled by the immune system, which leads to acute infections that, when untreated, are life-threatening.  In order to persist and proliferate within host tissues the acquisition and utilisation of host-provided nutrients is indispensable for all pathogenic organisms. In terms of P. brasiliensis, previous studies have shown that regulation of metabolism and metabolic physiology among hyphae and yeasts substantially differs. Even more, at least four virulent P. brasiliensis subspecies (S1, PS2, PS3 and 01-like) have been described and first preliminary analyses indicate that these subspecies differ in their metabolic preferences when entering the yeast form. However, the impact on virulence, fungal proliferation and therapeutic options has not been studied yet.  Therefore, this projects deals on the identification and characterisation of the metabolic physiology of the different P. brasiliensis subspecies to gain a deeper understanding on the impact and interplay of metabolic pathways during the infection process. Identification of essential metabolic processes provides new targets for antifungal therapies that may not only be suitable for combating P. brasiliensis, but also other invasive life threatening fungal infections.  By an generating bioluminescence imaging system for Paracoccidioides species, it will be possible to establish an in vivo imaging approach that allows the real-time visualisation of disease progression in temporal and spatial resolution using murine model systems of Paracoccidiomycosis. This system will be of high value to investigate the niche-specific metabolic capacity of Paracoccidioides spp. that is required proliferate within the host.     To assess the impact of distinct metabolic pathways key enzymes will be silenced by gene knock down approaches, which will be performed in combination with bioluminescence reporter expression. The resulting mutants will be tested in alternative and murine infection models to investigate the fungal proliferation rate and dissemination.  To identify new compounds targeting key metabolic pathways, a library of natural products available at the Brazilian partners will be screened. This includes the direct inhibition of purified enzymes as well as inhibition analyses of fungal growth under in vitro conditions. Interesting candidates will subsequently become analysed for potential cytotoxic effects on cell lines and eventually in murine models.  By performing these complex analyses the project not only aims in broadening the understanding of metabolic adaptations during the infection process, but also tries to refine the understanding of Paracoccidioides spp infection process and will identify new compounds that target essential metabolic pathways and could be suitable to prevent and cure invasive fungal infections.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-29" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">29795.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">111284.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">79489.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">27588.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">261952.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N017528/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN017528%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-29"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
