<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007915_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The use of creative arts to engage Nepali schools with antimicrobial-resistance and create positive behaviour change on health-seeking behaviours.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Building on research findings from AH/R005869/1, the UoL, HERDi and Nepali community stakeholders will collaboratively develop a pedagogically sound and robustly evaluated school-based education programme to engage children in Nepal, with the topic of antimicrobial resistance (AMR).    2.This education programme will use community engagement and participatory arts methodologies to encourage exploration and behaviour change around health-seeking behaviours including the unregulated purchasing, and misuse, of antimicrobial drugs by children aged 9-11.  This group were realised to be key actors in the purchase of antimicrobial medicines in the initial research project and hence all partners are keen to expand our research to focus on this audience.   3.The UoL and HERDi will train participants of the AH/R005869/1 project to become Community AMR Champions in their local areas.  This will develop AMR-specific knowledge gained by participants during the previous project while also building a transferable skillset for health communication.      3a. The newly trained Community AMR Champions will assist in the training of school stakeholders in the same programme.     3b. All newly trained facilitators will co-design and facilitate the education programme with support from HERDi.  4.UoL and HERDi will co-produce two delivery manuals to allow both the training process and education programme to be scaled and repeated in other global, national or local contexts.  This will accompany the existing (AH/R005869/1) project manual and will be freely available as a hard and online copy with translation options.      4a.Our long-term objective is for this education programme to be rolled out to all schools in the ward where we will be working during this project.  Our training and manuals will allow this process to be entirely sustainable without Global North intervention.   5.Children participating in the education programme will produce outputs to suggest behavioural changes around the AMR issues they face in their lives.      a.Outputs will become key resources to raise awareness of, and encourage behaviour change around, AMR within participants&apos; local communities.     b.Outputs will be used as evidence for the role of children in AMR-related behaviours and presented to Ministry of Health officials with the aim of influencing Nepali policy on AMR.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will apply the methodology and learnings from AH/R005869/1 to a new audience, children aged 9-11 in Nepali schools.  This group emerged as key actors within health seeking behaviours including the purchasing of non-prescription antimicrobials in our original project, hence all partners wish to modify the initial project to reach this group.  This will involve community co-production of an education programme based upon existing community engagement methodology which allowed Nepali communities to explore their relationship with the issue of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) through participatory filmmaking.  AMR is a major One Health threat, particularly acute in developing countries such as Nepal due to growing populations, limited health infrastructure and the accessibility of antimicrobials without medical advice or prescription.   While the previous project engaged adult participants, our original research project highlighted the key role that Children in Nepal play in AMR-related health-seeking behaviour. They are frequently the member of the family sent to purchase non-prescription antimicrobials.  The misuse of these drugs exacerbates AMR, but public understanding of this risk is low.  Children especially have limited AMR knowledge or empowerment to change harmful behaviours because conversations regarding AMR are mainly held at Ministerial level and the risks of AMR are not currently taught in schools.  Our co-produced education programme will use participatory arts to encourage children to share how their behaviours interact with AMR.  This will significantly extend the community-level reach of the previous project, allowing children in Nepal to develop knowledge and confidence to facilitate changes in their own AMR behaviour, and spread this message through their communities.    In preparation for this education programme, the project will invest heavily in training community volunteers as facilitators.  This will involve the re-engagement of AH/R005869/1 participants and the use of their original outputs (participatory films), both are integral to the community engagement aspect of our educational programme. They maximise the value of existing community resources, ensure Global-South ownership of the project, and provide local-contextualisation to help young people understand this complex &apos;One Health&apos; issue.  Existing AH/R005869/1 films will be used as educational resources and AH/R005869/1 participants will be trained as Community AMR Champions to facilitate the educational programme.  Training will enhance their AMR knowledge and confidence whilst at the same time developing their skills in public speaking, working with children (including safeguarding and unconscious bias) and their understanding of participatory arts methodology.  The training programme will then reach out to schools engaging head teachers, school nurses and subject specific teachers with the same training programme.  Supported by Community AMR Champions, these participants will then co-produce the final content of the AMR education programme to be delivered in their school.    This project is designed to be scalable.  Regular debriefing sessions with participants, robust evaluations of the both the education programme and facilitator training package will provide a rich dataset to assess the impact of community engagement and participatory arts methodology for creating behaviour change with regard to AMR.  This will allow the creation of best-practice resources (manuals), allowing other practitioners to repeat this intervention. It will, moreover, allow the original research team to continue to engage the Nepali Ministry of Health and Population as it develops its national AMR action plan.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-15" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-14" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NP" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nepal</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">93503.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">93503.508</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007915_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT007915%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
