<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R013748_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Embodied Performance Practices in Processes of Reconciliation, Construction of Memory and Peace in Choco and Medio Pacifico, Colombia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives of the proposed research project are: To research, document, archive, and disseminate the embodied artistic practices that performance practitioners and post-armed conflict Colombian communities are doing together in order to work through their memories of trauma and conflict thereby enabling reconciliation; To interview vulnerable members of the communities affected by the armed conflict, and the performance artists working with them; to then collect material (film footage, oral histories, memorabilia) for a digital archive that we will co-create together and make available to academic and non-academic audiences; To organize workshops and events in Colombia alongside our project partner, Corp-Oraloteca, with performance artists, vulnerable community members, and Colombian academics in Colombia; To organize events in the UK that reconsider memory, trauma, and knowledge production among vulnerable communities affected by armed conflict through embodied practices; To produce a range of outputs, including two journal articles (in Spanish and English), a special topics issue for e-journal Conversations Across the Field of Dance Studies, conferences panels and papers, a digital archive. Project Outputs: a) ethnographic research, pedagogical exchanges which will lead to co-creation of  a digital archive with the communities, sharing the diverse artistic initiatives implemented within the communities. This will be done through ethnographic interviews and dialogues with (either video or audio) of artists, practitioners and community members. It will feature footage from workshop events, practices, interviews with stakeholders, Colombian academics, community arts practitioners. i)Overview of Field: Collation and establishment of preliminary archive of artist and community-led initiatives of embodied practices of great visibility in the last 5 years with the expertise brought to the project of Corp-Oraloteca, our project partner ii) fieldwork with the assistance and participation of Corp-Oraloteca: 4 municipalities, 2 visits to each, 10 days duration per visit, total of 80 days of ethnographic fieldwork b) host two events in Colombia: i) one at Universidad de Antioquia, Colombia where members of the affected communities can gather, attend, and help co-produce the archive in relation to the workshops on memory;  ii) one at Corp-Oraloteca, Quibd&#xF3;, Colombia where members of the four communities would be in attendance for dialogic exchanges. c) host 5 workshop sessions on memory at Universidad de Antioquia to share and disseminate ideas, pedagogies, and best practice procedures. The topics would be developed in conjunction with the on-going project and stakeholders&apos; interest and input and then contribute to, and inform the events above in section b). d) host two events at Royal Holloway, University of London, UK i) a showcase of the project for wider participation among scholars of dance, theatre and performance studies, Latin American studies, visual culture, digital humanities, cultural geography ii) a symposium on comparative post-conflict approaches featuring artist-scholars that work on post-conflict  e) curate and present a panel/roundtable at the Dance Studies Association 2019, Rutgers University based around research project; show archives in progress; invite 3 of our community arts workers from Colombia to attend/present/share f) journal articles in Spanish by Colombian PI and Co-I for Latin American Studies journal, then an English version/translation submitted g) Proposed UK PI, Dr Blanco Borelli, is incoming Editor of the journal of Dance Studies Association (DSA), Conversations Across the Field of Dance Studies. We will create dedicated special issue on topic of Dance, Memory, Trauma and Reconciliation that will feature extensive details about the project as well as invite submissions related tothis theme from a transcultural, comparative perspective.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project examines the role that embodied performance practices have on post conflict memories in order to aid the processes of reconciliation and peace-building among the majority Afro-Colombian communities affected by the armed conflict in four municipalities in Choc&#xF3; and el Pacifico Medio. Its main objective is to co-create a digital archive with the vulnerable communities most affected by the armed conflict that features a collection of their oral testimonies, memorabilia, video footage of workshops and discussions, and embodied performance work. This project asks the following research questions: 1. What is the impact of embodied artistic practices in the discourses of post-war reconciliation in Colombian context?  2. How do the communities and the performance artists co-create memories together through embodied practices?  3. What role do these practices have for the vulnerable communities affected by the armed conflict? 4. How will these archived practices intervene in established discourses around memory, trauma, and practices of reconciliation? This investigation into the embodied practices led by Colombian arts and performance makers in these four municipalities considers the impact that hearing and learning about one another&apos;s memories and experiences via the digital archives will have. It seeks to facilitate a space for critical reflection and reconciliation among the marginalized vulnerable stakeholders while also proposing innovative collaborative models for community building and of co-creating an archive with vulnerable stakeholders. This can enrich the field of dance, theatre and performance studies by showcasing embodied work done by communities normally kept out of official disciplinary and archival frameworks.  By working with our key project partner, Corp-Oraloteca (a research, documentation and dissemination center of the Technological University of Choc&#xF3;, which seeks to identify, make visible, valorize, and safeguard the oral, sonic and embodied expressions and knowledges of the peoples of the Colombian Pacific), as well as other artists, teachers, community arts workers, dancers, and members of these affected communities, this project will create digital archives about the embodied practices, the arts workers, and the communities affected by the armed conflict. It will then disseminate these archives through a variety of events: community events in the affected areas in Colombia, an event at the headquarters of Corp-Oraloteca in Quibd&#xF3;, workshops at Universidad de Antioquia, and university talks and lectures in both Colombia, UK and the US. The goal of this research project is to generate spaces (virtual and actual) so that the communities affected by the conflict can use their shared experiences in order to help develop their own community awareness projects, and generate interest in and pursuit of embodied methodologies that can help with the complex processes of reconciliation, reparations, and the construction of peace.  Memory functions as a mobilizing factor for experiences, sensibilities, cultural expression, and everyday practices within these communities. In other words, how did citizens not only experience the armed conflict, but how do they remember and memorialize it now? Additionally, to recuperate or reconstruct postwar memories implies the evocation, creation and materialisation of ideas that these communities have about what their culture is and what is important to remember.  By working alongside artists already engaged in embodied practices in/with the affected communities, this research project facilitates a way for members of the affected communities to make sense of their present historical moment through embodied engagements with their respective memories. Through the digital archive and community events produced through this project, we anticipate the creation of spaces for dialogic and embodied exchanges in pursuit of peace and reconciliation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-13">64108.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-13">138063.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-13">34585.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-13">8529875.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton RCUK Award to Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R013748_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FR013748%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-07-11"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
