<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N009908_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NEXUS: Governing the nexus in Southern Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building on extensive collaboration between IDS/STEPS, PLAAS and ACTS over 20 years, this partnership grant will help develop new research and policy influencing activities around the governance of the land-water-environment nexus in southern Africa.   As questions of land and water access rise up the policy agenda in southern Africa, a critical social science perspective is crucial to ask questions about how the nexus is governed. A focus on the politics of access will illuminate how different state, market and civil society actions can contribute to more effective access for the widest number of people.   This is a crucial question for development, making this proposal firmly &apos;ODA compliant&apos;. Resource scarcities can act to exclude certain groups - including the poor, women and others - from vital resources for livelihoods. Conflicts over resources may emerge when more powerful groups grab land and water in the pursuit of the commercialisation of agriculture, energy or environmental services. Thus understanding the relationships between changing capitalist relations in the context of development and resources is essential if pro-poor, development oriented orientations for environmental sustainability are to emerge in policy.     In this project, we will examine the politics of access around the large-scale commercialisation of agriculture, water projects, including hydropower dams, and biodiversity conservation and forest carbon projects, where market offset mechanisms are applied. In each case our studies will examine the nexus between sectors, examining how relations between land, water and environment are negotiated in different governance frameworks.    The partnership will be facilitated through a combination of staff and student exchanges, joint scoping activities and project proposal development, a small grants programme for students, and an international conference that will bring together academics, policymakers and activists working on &apos;nexus&apos; themes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-11-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ZA" type="SOUTH AFRICA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1029</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-10">27050.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-10">54305.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-10">53754.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-10">14089.33</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This partnership will:  - Promote regional lesson learning on the pro-poor governance of land, water and environment in southern Africa. - Foster partnerships between IDS/STEPS Centre at Sussex and PLAAS in South Africa, involving other regional collaborators, including the African Centre for Technology Studies - Offer small grants to support fieldwork for PhD and MA students and so build a network of researchers working on the &apos;Governance of the Nexus in southern Africa&apos;. - Commission scoping studies that develop ideas for new cross-disciplinary research studies on the governance of the nexus, focusing on the intersections of poverty reduction and sustainability at the nexus. - Support staff and student exchanges between the UK and southern Africa, including visiting fellowships and attendance at the annual STEPS Summer School. - Host a workshop on the politics of land, water and environment in southern Africa to consolidate the network, and launch new, joint research activities."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
