<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007510_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A trial of low-cost, technology-assisted, integrated care delivery programme to prevent serious cardiovascular events in disadvantaged populations.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cardiovascular diseases (CVD) have become a major cause of disease burden in low- and middle-income countries (LMIC). More worryingly, within these countries, those in the lower socioeconomic classes are less likely to be utilising evidence-based therapies and they tend to be disproportionately affected by CVD. There are several barriers to more widespread and equitable implementation of evidence-based care and these barriers can be found at different levels of the healthcare systems.    It has been suggested that innovative solutions that incorporate the whole care delivery system and use new digital technologies that assist with high-quality delivery of recurrent tasks may be more successful in increasing the capacity of rural healthcare systems in the delivery of effective and affordable medical care for disadvantaged populations than the prevailing doctor and hospital-centred models of care.    In this large-scale collaborative project between the George Institute for Global Health, the Non-Communicable Disease Research Center at the University of Tehran and several other partners, we will implement and evaluate the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of a multifaceted intervention that targets at least three components of the health system (health workforce, health information and communication, medical technologies). After adaptation of this previously tested intervention into the existing rural healthcare system in Iran, we will conduct a large-scale cluster randomised study of 306 rural communities to rigorously measure the effect of the intervention on clinically important cardiovascular outcomes.    A number of enabling features of the Iranian healthcare system allow implementation and reliable evaluation of such disruptive solutions today at lower trial costs but with the potential of transforming CVD management worldwide. These include: a well-functioning and large network of community health workers in Iran who have prescribing authority for essential drugs and who have sufficient time to help with rapid screening and recruitment of patients into the trial; reliable access to affordable drugs at the intervention sites only with only a low risk of treatment contamination; a validated cause-specific national death register, well-established hospitalisations records, and free village landline telephones for efficient patient follow-up with almost no attrition; reliable communication infrastructure such as mobile networks for remote and near real-time study site monitoring; and government policies which stress the need for extending the role of community health workers in better and affordable management of non-communicable diseases for disadvantaged populations.   After about 5 years, we expect the outcome of the study, which includes process and economic evaluation, to lead to the formulation of locally relevant policy recommendations with the potential to positively impact on the healthcare of millions in Iran on a daily basis, with wider applicability for other LMICs.    The research team in this collaboration provides broad skills and a unique and substantial track record in rigorous large-scale clinical trials, statistics, engineering and computer programming, qualitative methods and health economics that are required for effective and efficient implementation of the research programme.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this study is to investigate the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of an innovative, low-cost and community-based healthcare intervention in reducing the risk of serious cardiovascular events (fatal or non-fatal stroke, or non-fatal myocardial infarction or coronary death) among high-risk individuals in disadvantaged communities.    More specifically the objectives include:    1. To refine our previously developed community-based and technology-assisted intervention for its seamless integration into rural Iran. The intervention will target three major components of the health system (health workforce, affordable health technologies and health information), which will be integrated into receptive national and local governance environments.    2. To implement the intervention in a two-armed large-scale cluster randomised trial of 306 rural health centres (about 450 community health workers, 55,000 patients with complete CVD screening and 30,000 high-risk individuals) and to measure its impact on serious cardiovascular events in the high-risk group over the 5-year study period.     3. To conduct detailed process, context and economic evaluations to better understand and measure the influence of factors that might influence scalability, affordability and sustainability beyond the trial setting (including other low- and middle-income countries).</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iran</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="MIDDLE EAST, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-08-21">108615.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
