<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting inclusion in decent work for Ugandan young people: will reducing violence help?</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2018, the Time&apos;s Up Movement declared &quot;the clock has run out on sexual assault, harassment and inequality in the workplace&quot;. These demands also resonate with the world&apos;s major development goals: decent work and economic growth (SDG 8) and gender equality (SDG 5), and influence financial security and good health and well-being (SDGs 1 and 3). Intersections between violence, harassment and labour outcomes are particularly relevant for adolescents, because substantial proportions enter full-time work during adolescence and early adulthood; and global estimates indicate that abuse is prevalent before age 18, with 1 billion children and adolescents aged 18 and under reporting past year violence.  However, there is little empirical evidence either globally or in Uganda on how experiences of violence in childhood and adolescence affect a) participation in skills programmes, entry into work, and decent employment; and b) about the extent and nature of physical, sexual and emotional violence experienced by young people in their workplaces. In this project, we will explore whether experiences of violence in childhood and adolescence lead to: inequalities in age at entry into work, retention in work, whether work is hazardous or non-hazardous; and the potential for these inequalities to be mitigated by skills training programmes and education. We will also explore the nature of workplace violence experienced by young people in employment. Our focus will be on Uganda but we will also use international data where relevant. To do this, we will conduct analyses of existing data and a new qualitative study, with input from a new network of stakeholders we will convene.  We will map the current geographical coverage of skills training provision in Uganda, and describe how inclusive current skills programs are by sex, age, socio-economic status, disability status; how many existing programs address histories of violence in participants; and how many existing programmes contain any components to address workplace violence. We will conduct a systematic review of international longitudinal studies to explore links between childhood violence and employment outcomes. We will analyse data from 2 international datasets, the Violence against Children Surveys (VACS) from 8 countries, and the International Organization for Migration Trafficked Migrants Assistant Database for Uganda (TMAD). These analyses will tell us about whether and how experiences of violence are associated with working during childhood, and unaccompanied labour migration.  We will use data from the Contexts of Violence in Adolescence Cohort (CoVAC) Study in Luwero District, Uganda, which follows adolescents over time. These unique data will provide information on whether previous experience of physical, sexual and emotional violence affect i) age at entry into the labour force, ii) retention in work, and iii) whether hazardous or non-hazardous work is undertaken.  We will also document the prevalence of participation in skills programs, and whether this is related to the likelihood of hazardous work, and the prevalence of physical, sexual and emotional workplace violence. All of these analyses will inform questions for our new qualitative study.  This study will examine people&apos;s experiences of being recruited into skills and employment programmes in Uganda, how programme recruitment mechanisms might in the exclusion of vulnerable young people, particularly those experiencing violence and/or child labour, and young people&apos;s views on the provision of violence prevention strategies within skills training programmes. Results from all of these analyses will inform network members about how best to make their skills programs more inclusive and relevant for people with histories of violence, and about how to use skills programmes as a platform to reduce workplace violence against Ugandan young people.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our aim is to develop an evidence base and platform for action around how violence in childhood and adolescence affects child labour, participation in skills programmes and employment outcomes in Uganda. As part of our impact plan, we intend to create a network, which will help shape specific research questions and maximise uptake of results. Our specific research objectives are to: 1) Describe the current geographical coverage of skills training provision in Uganda, and how inclusive current skills programmes are by sex, age, socio-economic status, disability status; how many existing programmes address histories of violence in participants; and how many existing programmes contain any components to address workplace violence; 2) Explore how violence in childhood and adolescence relates to child labour and other work outcomes internationally, and whether there are any common or unique risk factors, mediators, or moderators of these associations across countries; 3) Explore experiences of violence among trafficked adolescents in Uganda; 4) In Luwero District, Uganda,: a) explore whether gendered experiences of violence in childhood and adolescence lead to: younger age at entry into work, hazardous child labour, and other poor employment outcomes; b) Describe the prevalence of participation in skills programmes in adolescents; c) Explore whether participation in skills programmes is associated with violence, age at entry into work, hazardous labour in childhood and other poor work outcomes; d) Describe experiences of workplace violence among young people in employment 5) Understand young people&apos;s experience of participation in skills training programmes, their experience of workplace violence and views on how to make skills programmes more effective in Uganda</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-01">39872.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-01">159811.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-01">127193.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">39872.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">39872.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">39872.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">39872.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">40195.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">40195.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">28921.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">28921.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S005196_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
