<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006267_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impacts of Demand Side financing Instruments on the Continuum of Care for Maternal and Child Health in India and Bangladesh</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Having one of the highest global rates of premature deaths and poor health among pregnant women and their newborn, India and Bangladesh remain as key nations to reduce global rates of unfavourable health outcomes among women and children. Key to reducing these rates is to encourage improved coverage of health care services. Among the number of strategies used by policy-makers in both these countries - drawing on international experiences - are interventions that aim to influence women and children - particularly those from poorer households or other socially vulnerable communities - to use key health services by providing them with direct or indirect financial incentives. In this project, we aim to investigate to what extent these incentives, either involving directly paying cash amounts or providing free services in private health facilities, are successful in improving some of the most important indicators related to improved health care services directed at pregnant women and young children. In addition, we will study the barriers impeding improved access to health services, including factors such as availability of and accessibility to health facilities; we will also consider quality of care in the health services as a potentially strong determinant of whether people choose to use the health services that are offered. The results will help us to determine how these different barriers can be reduced so that the optimum potential of these financial incentives could be attained in these two countries. Ultimately, the data gathered will allow us to identify what likely modifications in the design of these financial incentive are required, in conjunction with supportive, positive improvements in quality of care, in order to attain improved health goals for women and children.   The project builds on the collective, multidisciplinary expertise of experienced researchers brought together by a rich collaboration of Universities and research Institutes from the UK, India and Bangladesh. The research we propose involves extensive use of available household survey data and fresh data collected through primary surveys in three Indian states (Bihar, Gujarat and Karnataka) and two divisions in Bangladesh. The surveys will cover the three most important schemes regarding financial incentives in the two countries - the Janani Suraksha Yojana (Maternity Security Scheme) and Chiranjeevi (or the Long-Life Scheme) schemes in India and the Maternal Health Voucher Scheme (MHVS) in Bangladesh. Key decision-makers in the Health Ministries in both the countries have shown a great interest in the proposed project, and intend to use the evidence generated to strengthen or review the existing interventions. By using robust, scientific approaches combined with micro-level insights from the target population, the project results will be of crucial influence in the decision-making toolkit for the health policy-makers in both India and Bangladesh.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ultimate aim of this research project is to generate robust empirical evidence leading to the design of a model financing mechanism to incentivise healthy behaviours and outcomes for women and children. The design will reflect contextual and health system variations in India and Bangladesh. While such mechanisms have been operational at different scales in these countries, their impact to date has been found to be limited to those outcomes that are directly incentivised such as institutional childbirth. It is less clear whether there has been any reduction of inequity in access and coverage of health services. This project, aligns its focus with the current programmatic discourse on effective health system responses to improve health outcomes and aims to provide much-needed empirical evidence on how existing demand side financing DSF interventions could be further strengthened to encourage equitable outcomes across the wider continuum of Reproductive, Maternal, Neonatal and Child Health (RMNCH) services. Additionally, the project aims to contribute to an improved understanding of the key determinants of successful health interventions. In particular, we aim to illustrate the instrumental role of quality of care for the health services being offered, in order to ensure sustainability in the demand for, and coverage of, essential RMCH services. The main output of the project will be a model which could be a crucial strategic pivot for the health system in the two countries to ensure better and equitable outcomes reflected in a wider set of maternal and child health outcome indicators.   Accordingly, the specific project objectives are:  a) To measure the impact  of selected DSF instruments on the RMNCH continuum of care, by comparing outcome variations both within a specific intervention, and between the different interventions;   b) To explain the variations arising from programme-specific features, health system characteristics and individual socioeconomic attributes, allowing for relevant interactions in the empirical models;  c) To assess the pathways of programme impacts, and identify to what extent the observed shortfalls from the continuum of health service coverage for the key RMNCH indicators are accounted for by equity and quality of care barriers, and their interaction processes; and   d) Informed by the evidence, to ascertain and suggest possible &apos;best-buy&apos; DSF designs that combine successful components of existing schemes and incorporate systematic corrections in the identified</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-08" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-02">126697.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-02">182652.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-02">45750.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-02">12676.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-02">16901.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-02">16901.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
