<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008547_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda&apos;s past, Ugandan futures: debates over equality and inclusion in 1979-80</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will show why the past matters to Uganda&apos;s future. Designed around a focused study of a key moment - the months following Idi Amin&apos;s fall from power in 1979 - it will create an interdisciplinary team that works together to improve understanding of the past and disseminate that knowledge to multiple audiences in Uganda to inform contemporary debates about persistent inequality and exclusion . Through this process of research and dissemination, the project will contribute to SDGs 4, 5 and 10. A series of workshops will bring early-career researchers together with more experienced colleagues. In a context where early-career Ugandan scholars face severe challenges in securing research experience and mentoring, the project will make possible a programme of archival and interview research that allows early-career scholars to develop their research skills and to enrich the team through their distinctive perspectives and insights,  and will enable the sharing of ideas on analysis and dissemination. Through the involvement of media (newspaper and local radio) and a civil society partner whose work focuses on promoting gender equality, the project will co-produce outputs that present research results to non-academic audiences, demonstrating the ability of research in the humanities to speak to contemporary challenges, showcasing the importance of scholarship that is sometimes undervalued, and consistently underfunded, in contemporary Uganda. Amin&apos;s fall opened a moment of possibility. Seventeen years after independence - years that had seen the abrogation of the constitution, the introduction of one-party rule, a military coup and a prolonged period of destabilising and terrifying violence - Ugandans had the opportunity to start again. The next year and a half saw active, multi-vocal debates over the future. In newspapers, on the radio, in urban streets and in villages, Ugandans pondered and argued - and took action -  in pursuit of multiple visions of a Ugandan future. The unhappy end to those turbulent months - the rigged elections of December 1980 that brought former president Milton Obote back to power - has meant that the period has been largely ignored in scholarship, remembered simply as a time of the creeping spread of Obote&apos;s influence. The project will challenge that presentation, and resurrect this as a time of hope, and of a contest over the future. This actively engaged an elite but also spread far more widely to a public that was - for the first time in many years - able to ask critical questions about what it might mean to be Ugandan, and about who should hold authority. The questions of the time were pressing, and multiple, for colonial and post-colonial states had created new kinds of inequality and exclusion, disadvantaging women and marginalizing whole regions of the country: what form should political representation take? How could inequality be overcome? What would it mean to be a good citizen of a new Uganda?  Those questions remain pressing today. The project will look back to the debates of those few hectic months - captured in newspapers and radio broadcasts of the time, and still live in the memories of those who took part - to recover a history of popular, as well as elite, debate over the nature of government and citizenship. It will produce an edited collection for academic audiences; and a series of media outputs - from newspaper articles to blog posts to radio talkshows - for wider audiences. Working with partners from civil society, the project will develop a model for using research-based knowledge of the past in contemporary policy and grassroots debates. Through research and co-production of outputs the project will create a team, involving early-career Ugandan scholars, that can bid successfully for further funding; and will show public and policy-makers  how useful and important the study of the past can be.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="UG" type="UGANDA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">38971.625</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">12990.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall project objectives are: 1. To draw on the experience and skills of researchers at different career stages - including an advisory board drawn from Uganda and the US - to build capacity in Uganda. The project will create an academic team whose members work together to research and analyse the past through interdisciplinary techniques and using multiple sources; through the project they will develop a shared experience in presenting research-based knowledge on the past to academic and non-academic  audiences.  2. Through an innovative collaboration with non-academic partners, to enhance the potential for research on Uganda&apos;s past to speak to contemporary issues of inequality and exclusion through co-produced outputs using multiple media.  In pursuit of those objectives, the project will: a. hold a sequence of four workshops, each involving the same group of nine researchers (seven Ugandan, one British, one French; two established scholars, seven early-career scholars) in two universities in northern and western Uganda. Through the workshops, the team will develop nine distinct strands of research - each of which has already been identified and agreed -  all on the same overall topic and informed by the same core questions about political representation, inequality and citizenship in Uganda. The team brings together historians, a political scientist, and early career scholars with background in education and business studies:  interdisciplinary in composition and approach it will draw on the experience and skills of all involved. In between the workshops, the project will provide funds to allow documentary and oral historical research by the Ugandan members of the team to gather data; the workshops will allow the team to share experience in analysing this data. b. (in the second and third workshops) bring the research team together with media practitioners working in newspaper and FM radio to  consider how best the research can speak contemporary questions, and to devise radio programmes and newspaper articles that draw on the research findings; and then to work with those media practitioners to gauge the impact of these programmes and articles c. (in the second and third workshops) bring the research team together with civil society activists to inform the course of the research itself by ensuring that it speaks to contemporary issues, and to devise means to incorporate research findings in civic education and advocacy work around governance and inequality; and then to work with civil society practitioners to gauge the impact of this pilot d. (in the third and fourth workshops) provide advice and mentoring for early-career members of the team in preparing academic publications and public presentations  e. hold a mini-conference that presents key research findings to academic and non-academic audiences in Kampala, and that offers members of the team experience in presenting their research to  diverse audiences f. produce a series of twelve blog posts aimed at non-academic audiences for a project blog; each post will speak to a particular aspect of the research and every member of the team will lead on at least one blog post g. produce a collection of nine academic articles aimed at an academic audience, with an introductory essay that sets the research in the context of existing analyses of Ugandan history, as well as comparative and theoretical work on contests over authority and the persistence of inequality in post-colonial Africa. Each member of the team will take the lead on an article on their own strand of the research; the more senior members of the team will co-write the introduction, and will support and mentor the early-career participants in writing their articles.   h. (in the fourth workshop) draft  a set of research questions and a methodology for a follow-on application for external funds for further research"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">38971.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008547_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">12990.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T008547_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
