<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005923_2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnership to ensure the sustainability of a public health palliative care project in Bangladesh through community theatre</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Palliative care is essentially care for the dying. While access to palliative care has recently been acknowledged as a human right, providing palliative care has also been recognized as a global health challenge.  Almost eighty per cent of adults who could benefit from palliative care are currently living in low and middle-income countries and do not have access to the levels of palliative care provision expected in most developed countries. In this context of global disparity in the framing and practice of palliative care, the authors argue that the quest for a global health system offering universal health coverage should include palliative care as a fundamental goal. Public health palliative care - the idea that care for terminally ill people should be returned to communities - has gained global interest. The community development model which we intend to initiate is based on the traditions and practice of community-based theatre.   The current map of world palliative care development shows Bangladesh as being in category 3a, which means that isolated palliative care services and training provision exist. A recent situation analysis revealed that although Bangladesh has approximately 600,000 incurable patients at any point in time, the country only has comprehensive palliative care programs, all of which are based in the capital city of Dhaka. These programmes served less than 1500 patients in 2013. In the urban slums of Bangladesh, poverty makes the impact of life-limiting conditions devastating to family and community members. Inspired by other community-driven, public health approaches to palliative care, the Centre for Palliative Care (CPC) of the BSM Medical University (BSMMU) initiated a pilot project in 2015 to provide palliative care in urban slums in Dhaka. A recent evaluation of the slum based community palliative care project found that although the patients receiving palliative care are satisfied with the project activities, the involvement of the broader slum community with the project is very limited. This was identified as a major threat to the sustainability of the slum project. Community participation in public health is crucial in order to ensure mobilization of greater resources, and greater empowerment of the community.   We aim to develop an innovative boundary-crossing interdisciplinary partnership to provide support to the sustainability of the urban slum palliative care project in Bangladesh, by developing a culturally appropriate and scientifically sound strategy for enhancing public engagement through &apos;Community theatre&apos;. Community theatre is recognised as an effective way of engaging community members in continuous reflective activities and aesthetic practices to help address and reflect upon community concerns. A script will be developed for a community theatre, based on an ethnographic exploration of local social and cultural understandings of death, dying and end of life care practices. The script will be performed by members of the slum community, facilitated by the Community Theatre Unit of BRAC, the largest Non-Government Development Organization in Bangladesh. We will then appraise the performances. The processes involved in this pilot activity will be documented and filmed, and these recordings will later be used to assess the learning outcomes as well as to develop a community engagement strategy in public health palliative care through art.    Establishing this partnership will provide a unique opportunity to researchers and practitioners of medicine, humanities, art and development, who otherwise do not work together in Bangladesh, to interact and generate new insight on public health palliative care as well as develop interdisciplinary research capacity. This experience of partnership will form the basis for subsequent funding applications to generate evidence on robust and culturally-sensitive public health palliative care for resource-poor settings in Bangladesh and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to develop an innovative boundary-crossing interdisciplinary partnership to ensure the sustainability of a public health palliative care project in an urban slum in Bangladesh. We wish to develop a culturally appropriate and scientifically sound community engagement strategy for public health palliative care, and our intention is to do this through the use of community theatre. To do this we would like to extend our existing partnership and add to the disciplinary breadth of our existing team, bringing together expertise from the fields of performing arts, anthropology, palliative medicine and community development. Though this enhanced partnership we aim to generate new insight and interdisciplinary research capacity among UK and Bangladeshi colleagues, laying the foundations of a new academic network which will address the emerging global health challenge of palliative care in resource-poor settings. The detailed objectives of the partnership:   a) To explore the interface between art, palliative care, public health, anthropology and, community development to ensure community engagement and the sustainability of this specific public health palliative care project. This will be achieved through extensive knowledge sharing workshops and Skype meetings across a team involving researchers, academics, public engagement and NGO personnel from the UK and Bangladesh.    b) To explore local contexts, indigenous knowledge, cultural practices, values and languages of death, dying and end of life care in the specific urban slum of Bangladesh. A focused ethnographic research conducted by a local researcher will be done to achieve this objective.   c) To pilot a community theatre performance to engage the slum community in the palliative care project. This objective will be achieved through a community theatre performed by the slum community members themselves, facilitated by the community theatre unit of BRAC, the largest NGO in Bangladesh with inputs from UK researcher. An on-going process documentation of the piloting activities will be created, detailing the execution of the performance from start to finish. A video of the performance will also be produced.   d) To assess the community response of the community theatre performance. This will be achieved through a rapid appraisal of the experience and opinion of the slum community about the performance using mini survey and community discussion.   e) To develop a community engagement strategy for public health palliative care in     resource-poor settings incorporating interdisciplinary approach particularly through        performing art. This objective will be achieved through a final workshop to assess the learning of this community theatre performance, using the results of ethnography, process documentation report, results of rapid appraisal and the recorded video.    f) To disseminate the outcomes of the project. This objective will be achieved through organizing public engagement events where we will disseminate the video of the community theatre performance and the strategy for public engagement through community theatre to relevant stakeholders in the UK and Bangladesh. This will also be presented in dissemination seminars at The University of Glasgow to relevant researchers. The video will be shared via the University of Glasgow website.   These primary activities will be supplemented by monthly Skype conference between the partners, and quarterly visits by the Principle Investigator to Bangladesh for progress reviews. This formative experience of partnership will form the basis for subsequent funding applications to generate evidence on art interventions for culturally-sensitive public health palliative care for Bangladesh, as well as for other existing partners of the Glasgow End of Life Studies Group who are doing similar work in resource-poor settings in India.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-16">33408.07</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-16">131062.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-16">164470.47</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Sussex</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/R005923/2" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">133632.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005923_2" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">30838.18</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005923_2" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FR005923%2F2">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
