<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_R004684_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Fund: A High Efficiency, Low Cost and Building Integratable Solar Photovoltaic/Thermal System for Space Heating, Hot Water and Power Supply</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Through a close collaboration between the leading UK/Chinese universities and the top Chinese/UK companies, the proposed UK-China collaborative R&amp;I project will develop a novel building integrate-able solar PV/T system for space heating, hot water and power supply. The universities have specific knowledge of the most advanced PV/T and loop heat pipe technologies and also expertise in China-oriented business strategy. The companies have strong R&amp;D and manufacturing capacity in solar PV, thermal, PV/T and heat storage/exchangers. The new PV/T system will achieve around 30% higher overall solar efficiency and 20% cost saving compared to the existing equivalent PV/T systems and will be flexible in component selection to meet different needs in buildings. The innovative technologies include (1) a novel loop-heat-pipe (LHP); (2) a novel PV/T panel; (3) a highly efficient heat storage/exchanger, and (4) an internet-based intelligent monitoring and control system. In terms of tasks, the project involves development of (1) a computerised design and optimisation model; (2) an experimental prototype and associated test rig; (3) a pre-production solar PV/T system for real building use; and (4) the economic, environmental and market performance reports and business model specifically tailored for the PV/T system.  University of Hull (UHULL), as the Coordinator of the project and lead partner of the UK team, will be responsible for management of all project activities, play a key role in development of the experimental prototype PV/T system and associated computer simulation models, assist in economic and environmental analyses and other project tasks. From technical point of view, UHULL has the established expertise in PV/micro-channel-thermal panels and loop heat pipe (LHP). During the project progress, UHULL will bring together the two successful innovations to develop a next-generation, high efficiency and low cost PV/T panels and associated passive, zero-power heat flow transportation system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-02">225547.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-02">121401.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall aim of the UK-China collaborative R&amp;I project is to develop a novel building integrate-able solar PV/T system for space heating, hot water and power supply, which has around 30% higher overall solar efficiency and 20% lower cost compared to the existing equivalent PV/T systems. From technical point of view, the project has four specific objectives, as below: (1) Development of computer models for the individual technologies and integrated system, leading to a fully-integrated, computerised PV/T system design and optimisation model; (2) Construction/testing of a 5kW rated experimental PV/T system, leading to an experimental prototype PV/T system and associated test rig; (3) Field testing/demonstration of a 20kW rated PV/T system at FIVE-STAR, leading to a pre-production solar PV/T heat and power system installed in a real building; (4) Investigation of the economic and environmental performance, market analysis and business modelling of the PV/T system, leading to the economic, environmental and market analyses reports and business model specifically tailored for the PV/T system.  Furthermore, the project has a non-technical objective which is to carry out a series of planned exploitation and dissemination activities to facilitate future marketing of the technology and promote academic advancement in this area. University of Hull (UHULL), as the Coordinator of the project and lead partner of the UK team, will be responsible for management of all project activities, play a key role in development of the experimental prototype PV/T system and associated computer simulation models, and assist in economic &amp; environmental analyses and other project tasks. The specific objectives of the UHULL&apos;s works are:  (1) To ensure successful completion of the project with satisfactory deliverables and scientific &amp; technological outcomes, through a dedicated R&amp;D management strategy; (2) To create the potential for converting the scientific and technological innovations into real world businesses, through a dedicated exploitation strategy and action plan; (3) To maximise the impact of the research, through a dedicated dissemination and communication strategy and action plan; (4) To implement the innovative LHP technology into a PV/T system, through the combined computer simulation and experimental testing approach; (5) To integrate the innovative micro-channel-thermal panels with PV modules by using the dedicated thermal-assisted lamination technique, thus forming the upgraded, high efficiency, low cost and building integrate-able PV/T panels; (6) To develop dedicated computerised optimisation and design models for the LHP and integrated PV/T system, by applying the latest micro-scale heat and mass transfer theory, solar to thermal and power energy conversion theory and advanced finite-element-based computer numerical method; (7) To construct and test a 5kW rated experimental prototype PV/T system at laboratory, by utilizing the existing mechanical and electrical equipment and skilled technicians; (8) To assist in economic and environmental performance analyses of the proposed PV/T system. (9) To assist in development and demonstration of the pre-production PV/T system.  The whole project will be coordinated by Prof. X. Zhao of UHULL. The management/reporting lines will be: &apos;Individual Partners&apos; - to - &apos;Task Leaders&apos; - to - &apos;WP leaders&apos; - to - &apos;Project Steering Committee&apos; (chaired by Prof. Zhao and comprising the PIs of the five partners)) - to - &apos;Innovate-UK&apos; (by the UK leader - UHULL) and &apos;MOST&apos; (by the China leader - USTC). All partners will meet at quarterly intervals (kick-off/12-month meetings in the UK, final meeting in China, remaining meetings at their own countries with the overseas partners participating by Skype) to review the project progress, identify any discrepancies between the scheduled and actual achievements and develop associated contingency plans."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
