<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003766_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Slavery Free Communities Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Modern slavery and human trafficking is estimated to affect more than 40 million people worldwide, yet despite widespread adoption of anti-trafficking legislation, sub-national policy responses are frequently fragmented and poorly implemented.  &apos;Place-based&apos; approaches to coordinating anti-slavery action, which focus on distinct geographical communities, towns and cities, offer the possibility of connecting law enforcement, governance, voluntary and faith responses to modern slavery in a more effective and coherent way.  Although examples of this type of initiative have started to emerge, models of place-based anti-slavery action have generally been developing organically and in isolation without the benefit of wider knowledge-exchange.    This proposal addresses this challenge by establishing the first global &apos;slavery-free cities&apos; network.  Starting with a core group of four cities spanning four different continents, we aim to establish network infrastructure by building collaboration agreements and knowledge sharing platforms, designing tools and indices for comparison, and collating thematic reports on core aspects of the local anti-slavery response, including prevention, discovery, recovery and the maintenance of sustainable freedom.  The academics we are working with in Brazil, Nottingham, Bangkok and Maputo have expertise in labour exploitation and supply chains, child labour and forced marriage and sexual exploitation, amongst other topics, and this project will enable us to examine the value of a place-based approach to addressing these diverse and challenging manifestations of exploitation.  This will also be the first attempt to explore in a systemic way how the concept of a slavery-free community could be developed and implemented across diverse social and economic contexts.  The network will be open to further self-funding members, and outputs and virtual participation will be made widely available, through the internet  without charge.  We will use powerful connections with UNU-CPR and Delta 8.7 to connect our core network to anti-slavery practitioners and virtual communities worldwide.  We anticipate that the network will benefit policy and practice in participating cities and states through strengthening in-country inter-agency work to address slavery.  We also see huge potential for stimulating learning across different international contexts, whilst also developing knowledge and networks to inspire future research and collaboration opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-07-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-17" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">37792.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">75891.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-04">38099</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This project will underpin global sustainable development by creating the first global slavery-free cities network.  The objectives of this project are:  - To create a two-year programme of knowledge-exchange connecting academic partners, law enforcement, local government, NGOs and faith organisations working at city level, with the aim of building and improving place-based anti-slavery interventions. - To establish the infrastructure for a wider global slavery-free cities network. - To develop and test a slavery-free communities audit tool, which will assist in reviewing and comparing resilience against slavery on a locality basis. - To build an interactive online platform, that will facilitate the sharing of information, policy and practice between local policymakers and practitioners in the network.  - To review local policy and practice in at least four participating cities, with the aim of promoting the prevention of slavery, facilitating discovery of victims, improving opportunities for respite and recovery, and creating strategies to promote long-term resilience. - To improve capacity for engaging communities as co-producers of slavery-free cities, through action-research and improved use of social media (working alongside Freedom United).    - To work with UN University&apos;s Centre for Policy Research (UNU-CPR) to explore how learning from the network can contribute towards the development of a slavery-free communities index, to measure place-based resilience against slavery. - To share knowledge gained through the network in the form of thematic reports, websites and social media, and short films and documentaries. - To develop proposals for future research and wider network-development to underpin the concept and practice of slavery-free communities as a lever for sustainable development and improving personal and community security."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">18896.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003766_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pontifical Catholic Uni Rio de Janeiro</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">18896.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003766_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pontifical Catholic Uni Rio de Janeiro</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">18896.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003766_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pontifical Catholic Uni Rio de Janeiro</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">18896.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003766_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pontifical Catholic Uni Rio de Janeiro</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">19049.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003766_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pontifical Catholic Uni Rio de Janeiro</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
