<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T00424X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL: Supporting government and partners in strengthening health systems for better mental health of Syrian refugees and host communities in Lebanon</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Aim: to support government and partners in strengthening the ability of health systems to meet the mental health needs of refugee and host communities affected by protracted displacement, focusing on Lebanon.  Objectives:  The project has the following five interconnected objectives and related work packages (WPs):  1. To explore barriers and facilitators to strengthening health system governance for supporting access to culturally appropriate mental health care for Syrian refugees and host populations in Lebanon. 2. To strengthen mental health service user participation in health system governance in Lebanon. 3. To identify sustainable financing mechanisms that can strengthen health system responses for mental health services for Syrian refugees and host communities in Lebanon. 4. To strengthen capacity on governance and health financing to support a resilient and sustainable health system addressing the mental health needs of Syrian refugees and host populations in Lebanon. 5. To maximise the value of the project findings and methods for other protracted displacement settings in ODA countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GOAL focuses on the challenge of supporting health systems providing for the mental health needs of people affected by protracted displacement, focusing on Lebanon. Poor mental health causes long-term suffering and disability, is a barrier to realising full potential of individuals and society, and impedes progress in achieving the SDGs. Poor mental health is often more common among protracted refugee populations than non-crisis affected populations. Effective mental health services exist, but there are major gaps in access to them, especially among refugee populations. The challenge is how to best deliver such services, including the design of health systems required to support this delivery. This is particularly challenging in protracted displacement settings which can place substantial additional pressure on already strained health systems and where an influx of international aid and actors can risk weakening national government-led responses.  GOAL is a partnership between universities, the National Mental Health Programme at the Ministry of Public Health and civil society organisations in Lebanon. It addresses the following questions in the UKRI-GCRF Protracted Displacement call: (i) what should governments at every level do in order to anticipate and efficiently manage protracted stays, reduce refugees&apos; dependence on humanitarian aid and implement systems that facilitate refugee /IDP integration, inclusion and social wellbeing? (ii) How can health care systems for the displaced be expanded to cover areas that are usually neglected in refugee/IDP settings such as (though not limited to) treatment of chronic illnesses, disability and mental health? (iii) How does gendered access to services, economic and cultural opportunities and levels of power influence differently the experiences, opportunities and limitations of men and women? The overall aim of GOAL to support government and partners in strengthening the ability of health systems to meet the mental health needs of refugee and host communities affected by protracted displacement, focusing on Lebanon as it is home to over one million Syrian refugees. It addresses two health system topics, governance and financing, identified as priority areas by key stakeholders in Lebanon and by external independent experts. GOAL&apos;s research is framed by the use of Transition Theory and gender is addressed as a cross-cutting issue informing all aspects of the project research. It follow a co-production approach, working closely with key stakeholders - particularly mental health service users. Quantitative and qualitative methods will be used and interdisciplinarity fostered. We also work with mental health service users to produce innovative materials (e.g. animations and augmented reality digital images) communicating the benefits of participation from people with lived experience of mental disorders in research and policy-making processes, and for advocacy and teaching.  GOAL has capacity strengthening activities to provide technical training to project partners and key stakeholders, and to support institutional capacity and individual career progression.  The main immediate beneficiary will be the National Mental Health Programme at the Ministry of Public Health in Lebanon. Other beneficiaries will include key stakeholders including mental health service users, NGOs, and UN agencies, both in Lebanon and other countries responding to protracted displacement situations. The proposal responds to SDG 3 (good health and well-being) and DFID&apos;s strategic objectives of strengthening resilience and response to crises, and tackling extreme poverty and helping the world&apos;s most vulnerable.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-20">126112.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-20">431933.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-20">286304.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-20">273378.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-20">1691702.644</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T00424X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT00424X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
