<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_T004940_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HOLY LANDS: SCOPING THE NEXUS BETWEEN HERITAGE, PILGRIMAGE AND DIASPORA IN INDIA</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">HOLY LANDS: SCOPING THE NEXUS BETWEEN HERITAGE, PILGRIMAGE AND DIASPORA IN INDIA  AIM   Our aim is to develop a network that will scope, co-design and co-produce a shared toolkit to pilot the identification of the economic and social benefits of diaspora communities on heritage sites at a sample of selected pilgrimage sites across India. This will provide a framework with which to identify both positive and negative impacts of diaspora pilgrimage at heritage sites within select geographical examples within India. The development of an interdisciplinary network that includes site managers, heritage practitioners, religious communities, residents and stakeholders, will for the first time begin to identify the social and economic impacts of diaspora communities at heritage sites as well as ensuring the continued and enhanced protection of heritage sites within India.   OBJECTIVES  Building out from the international partnerships developed through UKIERI/KEP in India and AHRC-GCRF in Nepal and SAARC-wide, our network will deliver four key objectives within the lifetime of the project:  1)  Bring together archaeologists, anthropologists, theologians, site managers, museum curators, stakeholders (including residents and religious communities) and tour operators from HEIs and GOs at a Networking and Co-design Scoping Workshop (1) to introduce the background to the broad potential socio-economic benefits and impacts of pilgrimage and tourism to heritage sites and resident communities co-develop and co-design an interdisciplinary shared toolkit for benchmarking the socio-economic benefits of diaspora pilgrimage associated with heritage sites.  2) Undertake Scoping Activities to pilot the shared toolkit for benchmarking and monitoring of the socio-economic impacts of diaspora pilgrimage at selected sample sites in Uttar Pradesh, Gujarat and Kerala, developing further methodologies for the successful implementation of the shared toolkit.  3) Promote the shared toolkit at a SAARC focused Scoping Results Workshop (2), disseminating the methodology, as well as preliminary benchmarked results with HEI and GO within India, as well as regionally through invited HEI and GO participants from across SAARC. The identified potential benefits of monitoring the socio-economic benefits of diaspora tourism pilgrimage at heritage sites will also be outlined and presented.  4) Promote and disseminate the benchmarked results and shared toolkit to academic audiences through a Dissemination Workshop Session, within a large international conference (3), a peer-reviewed journal article and edited volume, which will showcase the toolkit and case studies from within the network and its wider partners. Disseminate the results to the wider public within the UK, India and globally through the development of a temporary exhibition, which will migrate to an open web exhibition via the Durham UNESCO Chair website, which will also host document reviews of the scoping activities as well as outcomes of workshop and conference activities. The toolkit will also be shared as an online resource, with the Durham UNESCO Chair online presence providing the network with sustained legacy after the end of the grant period.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pilgrimage is recognized as one of the fastest growing motivations for travel globally, with more than 600 million &apos;spiritual voyages&apos; undertaken annually, with half of these occurring within Asia. &apos;Spiritual Voyages&apos; include local and regional pilgrimages, but also large-scale gatherings, including the Kumbh Mela, which had an estimated 120 million devotees in 2019. While tourism among diaspora communities was encouraged through the &apos;Incredible India&apos; Program (USAID 2010), diasporas occupy a complex ground between international and local tourism/pilgrimage. Indeed, in India, diasporas have yet to have their socioeconomic impact recorded or benchmarked. This is a particular challenge as diaspora communities are not recorded separately in current Indian government tourist metrics and statistics (Ministry of Tourism Report, Government of India 2018). Such assessments are critical as diaspora pilgrims/tourists are less likely to utilise the same businesses/hotels/restaurants/travel companies as international tourists (USAID 2010). They may also have distinct impacts on economies that are not yet being recognized in traditional measures. For example, it has been asserted that while diaspora may not spend as much money as foreign tourists, their expenditures are potentially more likely to go directly towards local producers and businesses, which may in turn have greater social and economic benefits for local resident communities (USAID 2010). Recording and benchmarking this impact is key as it has been identified that the benefits of large-scale infrastructure projects and initiatives to promote international pilgrimage and tourism within Asia have been restricted, and often do not reach as many resident communities associated with cultural heritage sites as originally envisaged (Coningham and Lewer 2019).    To bridge this conceptual and quantitative gap, an expert research network of academics and practitioners will develop a north-south-south partnership to identify the potential socio-economic impacts of diaspora tourism and pilgrimage for sustainable and inclusive development, as well as enhanced protection of cultural heritage. Whilst recent projects have begun to address how the collection of data on social and economic impacts of pilgrims and tourists at major pilgrimage sites can identify socio-economic benefits, the network and its shared toolkit will build on this legacy by developing a framework to scope and identify the potential impacts of diaspora communities at heritage sites. This will be based on relevant economic indicators, such as income, employment and business opportunities, and social indicators, such as education level, social cohesion, capacity strengthening, improvement of infrastructure and services. This will be achieved through the scoping of available quantitative data, such as questionnaires of diaspora visitors, local residents and local businesses including tour operators; visitor book data; site management records, as well as qualitative data, such as semi-structured interviews with site managers, community stakeholders. The network will thus scope gaps and develop a method for identifying and assessing this data, and providing a benchmark that can then be developed into long-term monitoring of the impacts of diaspora communities. Focusing on sites that are under the jurisdiction of the Archaeological Survey of India in Gujarat, Kerala and Uttar Pradesh, the team will undertake its initial scoping activities at major religious traditions of Hinduism, Buddhism, Islam, Judaism and Christianity, in addition to other religious groups and communities who utilize these sites.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-06">24151.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-06">12075.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
