<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004076_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PhotoVoice as an educational tool for intercultural learning and peacebuilding between Forcefully Displaced Populations and Host community youth</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global numbers of Forcefully Displaced Persons (FDPs) is rising, with the majority being hosted by Low and Middle-Income Countries (LMIC), which can exacerbate the economic and social challenges these countries face while compounding tensions between FDPs and the host communities as they have to share scarce resources. Efforts to reduce conflict center largely on providing humanitarian aid, vocational training, and expanding the provision of welfare services, underplaying the importance of promoting peace, dialogue and intercultural learning between the groups. This network aims to address this challenge by using photography as an educational tool and photograph artefacts as a teaching and learning resource to evaluate the potential of photovoice and visual story telling as an informal learning platform for fostering peaceful relations between the communities and easing sustainable integration of FDPs. The overarching aim is to understand how visual arts and photography training can have a redistributive effect in reducing inequalities perpetuated by intersectionality of gender, ethnicity, language, sexuality, and nationality and in mitigating tensions for peace-building through comparative research in South Africa, Turkey and Uganda. These countries host millions of FDPs.  The consortium of these countries provides an enriching multi-sited context to explore the role of photography as an educational tool and the participatory methodology as an informal learning space for establishing a culture of peace, exchange of cultural knowledge, and intercultural learning.   The participatory and bottom up programs that could foster capacity building, reconciliation and societal transformation between FDPs and host communities are often ignored for the sake of economic concerns. The central aim of the network is to bring researchers, policy makers, NGOs, local actors, photographers, practitioners, FDPs and host community members to discuss photography and arts based participatory methods in providing an informal learning education opportunity for peace that could be enhanced through policy and practice. The network assembles expertise in education, photography, conflict and forced migration. The co-applicants in each country have a track record in policy-relevant research and are well networked nationally and regionally with academic, and policy actors. The network will interact through a mix of virtual and face-to-face means.   Our hypothesis is that arts training and activities conducted in an informal setting can be used for community building, and learning to live together can make important contribution to the welfare of both FDPs and host communities. To assess whether and how such benefits may be occurring and what are the best visual arts practices of adopting such a methodology, the co-applicants first have to map existing data and literature in order to gain a much clearer picture of the dynamics of FDPs and host communities and ways of improving dialogue and participatory methodologies. The outcome will be the use of visual arts as a medium to learning to live together, understand cultural diversity, ways of preventing discrimination and inequalities. We will develop a series of collaborative bids to GCRF and other funders. The network will innovate by dialogue and photography based participatory action research and academic and practitioner networks to meet the learning needs FDPs and host communities as well as local actors who engage with them. Theoretically, the network recognizes that visual arts are a powerful tool for promoting human development, equipping people with necessary learning and capabilities to access sustainable livelihood assets that go beyond income generation. It can also include non-material aspects of education such as: well-being, support peace-building, self-development, equity, social relations based on respect and equality, and positive and negative freedoms for a life with dignity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">37845.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">16438.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This network concerns the potential for peacebuilding between FDPs and host communities through photography training and using photographs as educational artefacts to gain local and cultural knowledge.   As such it addresses two of the GCRF&apos;s thematic foci - education (informal learning &amp; cross-cultural learning) and creative and visual arts (photography). Our contributions are: first, peacebuilding and mitigating tension is significant to livelihoods of both FDPs and host communities for social and economic cohesion; second, use of photography training as an opportunity to bring FDPs and host community together to interact and build relationships across lines that divide the communities; third use of photographs as a platform for sharing and discussing how inequalities are experienced and impact on daily lives; fourth, to test the photography based participatory action methodology in order to promote intercultural dialogue and learning and train how each other lives, and  fifth to understand how these experiences around the visual arts can help the methodology going forward. Photovoice and use of photography as an educational tool is limited in terms of promoting peace, understanding inequalities and forming relations with FDPs. The network addresses this by building international, interdisciplinary capacity to investigate the extent to which such a methodology can promote social change through a dialogue across 3 most refugee hosting LMICs -South Africa, Turkey and Uganda  The network will bring together researchers, policy makers, FDPs and host community members, NGOs and other local actors like municipal/district officials, photographers and art galleries. The aim is to understand how and to what extent photography and photography training as an educational tool for intercultural dialogue/learning and co-learning process can be employed. We will achieve this through a series of linked objectives:  Conceptual &amp; methodological advancement: 1. Map existing knowledge and identify data gaps in use of visual arts with refugee communities, peacebuilding, social integration. 2. Development of innovative participatory method, photovoice, for educational use of understanding inequalities, intercultural learning, and promoting peace by engaging multiple stakeholders. 3. Refine a theoretical and methodological framework to investigate how photography can support peacebuilding processes 4. Develop co-authored papers and develop an interdisciplinary research agenda that brings together work on internal, regional and inter-continental FDs migration to explore through a comparative framework  Proposal development to grow network activity 5. Co-design a series of large, inter-disciplinary proposals to understand the role of education and arts in creating sustainable livelihoods for FDs and promoting social cohesion.  Impacts on capacity and capabilities 6. Strengthen the linkages between researchers and NGOs, policy-makers, artists or photographers, community leaders and local actors 7. Co-create processes, products and platforms that enhance knowledge on how peaceful relations arise between different groups of FDPs and host-communities, and local stakeholders through innovative participatory based visual arts methods 8. Engage the GCRF in establishing a program of research and impact around the importance of refugee crisis. 9. Outline the efficacy of a dialogue and photography based participatory action research as an educational tool for knowledge exchange and tool for intercultural learning"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">37845.66</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004076_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">16438.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004076_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">-795</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S004076_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
