<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009611_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Levelling the playing field: assessing through equity the quality of Chilean schools</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objectives of the proposed research are to:  Improve school-level secondary education -primarily in Chile and potentially in other DAC listed countries in the region such as Argentina- by delivering new insights into the quality of Chilean schools through an equity lens provided by value added models applied to assess students&apos; performance.  Provide stakeholders -including policy-makers, researchers, head-teachers and teachers- with tools and evidence-based descriptions of effective schools derived from my PhD to identify good practice in the educational system.  During the fellowship I will: Build international networks with both academic and user audiences to develop impact opportunities and inform and support the further development of my research  Collaborate with users through a placement at the Unit of Curriculum and Evaluation, Ministry of Education (MoE), Chile to help develop my professional and transferrable skills and understanding of their needs, as well as co-run seminars and co-develop practitioner materials  Conduct additional research directly linked to my PhD on stakeholders&apos; understandings of value added measures and indicators. This will serve as diagnostic work for the proposed fellowship, informing and supporting the further development of my research  Share learning gained through my fellowship with the SWDTC/P   Engage with both academic and non-academic audiences to further communicate research findings from my previous doctoral work, thus also securing additional opportunities for long-term employment in research. In addition to co-run seminars and practitioner materials noted above, dissemination will include: Use of web and social media Attending and presenting at the ICSEI 2017 international conference Development of two publications in my chosen specialisation field (school effectiveness and school improvement) Propose a special issue for a journal focusing on challenges of measuring the effectiveness of schools in unequal countries Develop a Policy briefing supported by PolicyBristol  Further improve my research and related skills training in quantitative methods through LEMMA (Learning environment for multilevel methodology and applications) https://www.cmm.bris.ac.uk/lemma/, such as &quot;Module 8: Multilevel Modelling in Practice&quot;; courses to enhance my career development (e.g. funding application training) as well as courses oriented to acquiring advanced research skills in quantitative methods, and training oriented to improve and consolidate my experience in evaluation methodology. Whilst I have been studying and working in England during the last decade, my native language is Spanish and I am culturally aware of the dynamics operating in Chile.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal builds on my PhD &quot;Searching for fairer ways of comparing Chilean secondary schools performance: a mixed methods study investigating contextual value added approaches&quot; (Mu&#xF1;oz-Chereau, 2013a). My research found that pupil intake and contextual features in Chilean secondary schools exert a very powerful influence on students&apos; performance. Therefore, accounting for prior achievement, student background and school context, provides an estimation method that seeks to correct for the extremely unequal Chilean educational playing field. Due to the fact that pupils and teachers are not distributed randomly in Chile, individual student characteristics, are considered to be potentially confounded with those associated with classes or schools groups (Raudenbush &amp; Bryk, 2002). This has proved especially true in the Chilean educational system (Manzi et al, 2011; Meckes &amp; Bascop&#xE9;, 2012). Given that value added is a technique designed to make fair comparisons between schools (OECD, 2008) by adjusting for various background factors and prior attainment by the individual child, my research challenges the routinely applied rankings implemented in Chile to assess school performance; develops value added models using Chilean secondary schools&apos; data, and uses those results to identify schools practices associated with better performance. Its dissemination will deliver new insights into the quality of Chilean schools; increase local awareness that different &apos;value added&apos; indicators are needed to assess the quality of schools, and provide methodological tools coupled with evidence-based descriptions of effective schools. The aim of the fellowship is to improve education -primarily in Chile and potentially in other ODA listed countries in the region such as Argentina- by applying an equity lens when assessing students&apos; performance using value added models. This is needed because although Chile in the last decade has reached the highest per capita average income in the Latin-American region (EEA, 2007), its wealth distribution remains one of the most unequal in the world (Zahler, 2011). Distribution of wealth and its associated inequality, vulnerability and social exclusion remain a serious concern in Chile (OECD, 2011). In this context education is a key element to stop perpetuating inequalities and support sustainable development goals, and the assessment of schools performance plays a crucial role.  During the fellowship, I will carry out activities described in detail in the work plan, including: building on the impacts of the PhD; collaborating with users; disseminating research findings and further extending my publications track record. I will also apply my research related skills, seek opportunities to improve my academic/career development; and conduct additional research directly linked to my PhD. The outcome of the proposed activities will support social cohesion and will work against educational segregation by describing a more favourable picture of schools that educate pupils coming from more disadvantaged socioeconomic backgrounds. This will help shifting the debate from type of school (public/private), to teaching and quality of school practices. Given that this is not part of the current national assessment framework, Chilean educational policies and practices oriented to tackle educational inequalities will be enhanced and supported. Moreover, recent educational reforms concerning a new evaluation system for schools (Sistema de Evaluaci&#xF3;n y Orientaci&#xF3;n del Desempe&#xF1;o de los Establecimientos y sus Sostenedores) as well as a reform for supporting public education (Sistema de Educaci&#xF3;n P&#xFA;blica) currently under discussion in Parliament, makes this proposal a timely contribution to inform and support these new developments. Finally, by combining equity and quality, Chilean educational system will be provided with information to become a fairer educational system.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">-0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009611_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
