<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015964_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Seismic Cities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over 50 capital cities of the Least Developed Countries in the world lie on top of faults in regions that are building up significant stresses within the crust. This continually growing stress will eventually lead to future earthquakes. Earthquakes are a natural hazard that are killing an increasing number of people, in part because populations are growing and densifying into urban centres. The recurrence time between earthquakes may be hundreds of years; many cities that are large today were small towns or non-existent in the past when the last big earthquake struck. There is often little social and community memory and first-hand experience of these previous events. Furthermore, urban development in the intervening years has often hidden the expressions of the active earthquake faults beneath and around a city, making them harder to identify today. In the Least Developed Countries, the impact of earthquakes on people&apos;s lives and livelihoods is much greater due to the vulnerability of buildings and communities. A major challenge has been to ensure that the mitigation of earthquake risk is a high priority in vulnerable cities, where earthquakes rarely occur but are devastating when they do. This is particularly difficult in cities in the least developed countries, where building earthquake resilience has to be balanced against other economic &amp; social pressures facing cities &amp; their development. We will develop a blueprint for the concept of &quot;Seismic Cities&quot;, which we believe will be a powerful approach for raising awareness of the devastating potential of earthquakes in cities &amp; for making them more sustainable &amp; resilient to such shocks. This will be a biennial workshop &amp; event that will bring together a range of stakeholders to target communities vulnerable to seismic hazard, and to develop more sustainable cities that can better cope with future environmental shocks from earthquakes. This will build on an existing successful concept of Cities On Volcanoes-a biennial conference and series of workshops that aims to reduce the impacts of volcanism &amp; its effects on society by understanding volcanic phenomena, recognising the hazards &amp; their impacts on people, emergency management, community education, case histories &amp; risk mitigation. In order to test the effectiveness of our methodological approaches, as well as help develop the Seismic Cities concept, we will target a large city that has recently experience major earthquakes-Santiago in Chile. We will conduct interviews &amp; focus groups with communities in the city to explore their own perceptions of risk &amp; coping strategies. We will also document these experiences through story-telling &amp; sensory mapping of the built environment, &amp; create a virtual archive of these to which the community can add. Through co-production methods such as focus groups, walking trails, mobile interviewing, live projections &amp; tours of both historic &amp; contemporary urban sites, valuable data on the effects of earthquakes &amp; their potential danger will be gathered. We will use satellite imagery to construct a 3D model of the built environment &amp; highlight active fault structures within the city, integrating this with the community resources to better communicate the findings derived from the scientific data. The strategies to best prepare &amp; protect the community can be embedded as community members become responsible for mapping &amp; curating their own lived environments. The long-term (20-year) aim is to raise resilience to earthquake hazard across the whole world to the standards of the US, New Zealand &amp; Japan. This is particularly challenging for many ODA-Recipient countries, where awareness of the threat from earthquakes may be low, &amp; where increasing resilience to earthquake hazard may be a low priority. We envisage Seismic Cities as a flagship, high-profile event that significantly raises awareness inthe host city, among both professionals &amp; the public, drawing focus &amp; resources to that city.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will address the sustainable cities &amp; communities challenge in regions prone to earthquake hazard by increasing resilience to such seismic shocks. We believe that bringing together diverse actors with a focus on a specific &quot;Seismic City&quot; is a powerful mechanism to achieve this. To develop &amp; scope this concept, we integrate a new interdisciplinary group of partners to carry out the following specific objectives: 1. Develop a blueprint for the Seismic Cities concept, building on the existing framework for Cities on Volcanoes-a successful programme promoting multi-disciplinary applied research &amp; linking physical scientists with city authorities, sociologists, psychologists, emergency managers, economists, city planners &amp; local communities. We will determine the format of a similar biennial event &amp; establish the best practice for engaging stakeholders to improve the effectiveness of research engagement &amp; uptake (Theme Call TC9). This will be based on our research findings &amp; engagement with our project partners. We will attend the 9th Cities on Volcanoes workshop Nov 2016. (Work Package WPE) 2. Conduct interviews &amp; focus groups among people in a city already by a recent earthquake. This research will be done in Santiago, Chile, which has experienced major earthquakes in 2010 (M8.8, 525 fatalities) &amp; 2015 (M8.3, 13 fatalities). Despite the very large magnitudes, the fatality rates from these past 2 events were relatively low. This will address TC6: cultural factors in building resilience, the perception of risk and coping strategies, including intercommunal engagement. WPA 3. Explore resilience through storytelling &amp; linking this to the physical environment with sensory-mapping &amp; embedding stories within an online digital media archive. We will select buildings, as identified by the community within Santiago, document them and tie stories from the local population to these structures, e.g. before &amp; after images of quake damaged buildings, as well as embedding their personal experiences of these spaces. We will also embed the imaging technologies used within the local community &amp; train citizens to continue documenting changes in their environment, contributing to an online growing archive. This addresses TC6: the cultural implications of building resilience based upon culture &amp; historical experience, as well as TC3: examine the communication of hazards to vulnerable communities. WPB 4. Construct high resolution digital elevation models &amp; imagery from satellites of the entire city of Santiago as well the San Ramon Fault on the eastern edge of city, making the topographic data openly available. This fault is relatively neglected compared to the large offshore subduction zone on which the recent major earthquakes occurred, but potentially poses a bigger hazard due to its close proximity to the city &amp; subsequent growth of suburbs over it. We will identify fault scarp offsets at the surface &amp; the encroachment onto these faults by the urban eastward expansion. This will address TC1: the underlying drivers of disaster risk - namely hidden faults beneath cities &amp; the consequences of rapid urbanisation. WPC 5. Assess the &apos;systems of provision&apos; approach to valuing resilience for earthquakes. This will address TC5: how to incentivise action &amp; measure resilience by capturing how to apply the full range of costs/benefits, choices &amp; trade-offs when the benefit of earthquake preparedness is many years away &amp; the next earthquake cannot be predicted. WPD 6. Combine the above output elements as a harmonised record of earthquake experiences, storytelling &amp; digital environment on the Pararchive Project platform Yarn, which provides an open access community storytelling &amp; digital archive. WPB 7. Establish selection criteria &amp; explore a shortlist of potential candidates for Seismic Cities V1.0, establishing the necessary networks &amp; relationships with that city to make a successful bid for future funding to hold the 1st inaugural event. WPE</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-13">55160.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-13">120315.29</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-13">175476.206</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015964_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FP015964%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-08"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
