<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024278_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Promoting sexual health and accessible HIV Prevention, Treatment, Care and Support services for women prisoners in Zimbabwe and Malawi.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) evaluation of prison based HIV Prevention, Treatment, Care &amp; Support (PTC&amp;S) services was conducted by the Principal Investigator (PI) (MCVH) and Zimbabwean co-applicants (SR &amp; RM) in 2017 and found that women&apos;s unique sexual and reproductive health (SRH) care needs were severely neglected in Zimbabwean and Malawian prisons. Despite being disproportionately affected by HIV/AIDs, women&apos;s health experiences in Zimbabwean and Malawian prisons are not routinely monitored or investigated by research institutions in either country. The partnership aims to support research capacity building on the issue through knowledge sharing and learning by bringing together and integrating the ARHC disciplines of development, gender, law, human rights and theory of performing arts into the MRC areas of public health, obstetrics and gynaecology, nursing, epidemiology and SRH. Inter-sectoral capacity building is fundamental to the partnership, with civil society organisations (CSOs) directly involved in all aspects of the work across both countries. The partnership through its research and policy outputs aims to build support for Zimbabwean and Malawian health and correctional services policy reform to ensure the special SRH needs of women in prisons are considered and in particular access to HIV PTC&amp;S services is improved. It also aims to create SRH and HIV awareness among female prisoners, and in particular, of their rights with respect to access to health care while incarcerated, and ensuring that interventions motivated by public health considerations are respectful of their rights at all times. The objectives are:  1. To establish and support a new interdisciplinary and inter sectoral partnership which will support cross cultural knowledge sharing, research skills and capacity building in investigating women prisoners&apos; SRH needs and experiences of HIV PTC&amp;S services in Zimbabwean and Malawian prisons; 2. To conduct a pilot situational assessment to improve scientific understanding of women&apos;s SRH and HIV PTC&amp;S needs for women and their children in Zimbabwean and Malawian prison settings through inter disciplinary research, local and national knowledge sharing and skills capacity building;  3. To report on international mandates, international normative guidance and the Zimbabwean and Malawian legal systems as it relates to current standards of women&apos;s healthcare and SRH/ HIV PTC&amp;S services provision in prisons in Zimbabwe and Malawi; 4. To build professional and political support for gender sensitive health and correctional services policy in Zimbabwe and Malawi to ensure that women prisoners have improved access to quality SRH/ HIV PTC&amp;S services at any time during their detention, and that the special SRH needs of women in prisons are considered and addressed; 5. To develop and pilot a series of participatory forum and image theatre workshops as HIV/AIDs education programmes for use in Zimbabwean and Malawian prisons, in order to communicate HIV messages and raise HIV/AIDS awareness, health citizenship, and critical thinking in relation to health, sexuality and HIV/AIDS; 6. To disseminate the partnership outputs locally, nationally, Pan Africa and internationally to advance local, regional and international scientific and legal understanding around gender specific needs and minimum standards of provision of healthcare for women incarcerated in both countries. 7. To work with international agencies such as UNODC, United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), the World Health Organisation (WHO) Collaborating Centre for Health in Prisons Programme, and the African HIV in Prisons Partnership Network (AHPPN) to support implementation of findings and expansion of the collaboration across Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Sub Saharan African region remains at the epicentre of the HIV epidemic, with a continuing disproportionate level of HIV infected women and girls, and concentration of HIV among inmates in prisons. HIV prevalence among women prisoners is higher due to sub-standards in hygiene, limited access to sexual and reproductive (SRH) services, and interruption of the necessary services during incarceration. Adequate health services in prisons are mandated under the Sustainable Development Goals (SDG 3, 5, and 16), as well as under the United Nations Standard Minimum Rules for the Treatment of Prisoners (Nelson Mandela Rules), the Bangkok Rules for Female Prisoners and in the SSA region, where the partnership will take place, the Southern African Development Community Minimum Standards for HIV in Prisons. The rationale for this new partnership is grounded in the recent United Nations evaluation, which reported that current provisions for women in Zimbabwean and Malawian prison systems currently fall far short of mandated equivalence care standards.  This unique partnership will challenge and address the SRH inequalities of women prisoners, who are a vulnerable HIV/AIDS population in Zimbabwe and Malawi. Both countries are compromised by a lack of robust gender sensitive monitoring systems for HIV/AIDs in prisons, and little strategic information available around women prisoner&apos;s experiences and needs. It will set the scene for a strong international collaborative effort to monitor, investigate, understand and promote women prisoner&apos;s human rights and SRH needs in Zimbabwe and Malawi. The issue of HIV/AIDS in prisons is both a human rights and public health issue, which requires a strategic approach to prevent HIV transmission and improve health for all, whilst at the same time ensuring the respect of human rights and dignity of those infected and requiring treatment.   The partnership is interdisciplinary and inter sectoral, and brings together key partners from development, law, gender and human rights, and the performing arts, in conjunction with public health and clinical disciplines. Its research, communication and policy reform activities sit within the global aim of leveraging the end of AIDS through working and collaborating in an interdisciplinary and multi-sectoral partnership (sustainable development goal, SDG 17). Understanding prison environmental cultures which shape prison staff and wardens&apos; understanding and responsiveness to female prisoners&apos; SRH needs in both countries is vital to inform policy change and improved standards for women prisoners and their children.   In partnership with CSOs, the project activities will support expert and local knowledge sharing and build national and international collaboration to generate research interest, research capacity and expertise, and develop participatory theatre programmes used to disseminated HIV/AIDS and SRH messages. Local cultures are central to design and piloting in prisons. Participatory HIV communication using forum and image theatre have never been applied to women in the prison setting. Using theatre, women prisoners are both creators and spectators. This is central to communication of HIV and SRH messages to prisoners and staff, both within the public health and human rights domains. The partnership through its activities will foster health citizenship and a sense of belonging to a community of people whose citizenship has been devalued at two levels, namely that of gender, and that of incarceration.   The partnership represents a form of international sustainable development work which will create a first step in both countries towards addressing female prisoner SRH disparity, and ensure that their views are utilized to contribute to reframing of gender sensitive and human rights based prison responses and prison health policies, and enhance their access to high-quality and stigma-free SRH and HIV prison services when needed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">170241.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF RCUK Award to Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R024278/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">85120.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">85120.825</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024278_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR024278%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
