<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N004485_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Embrapa - Exploiting new technologies to improve drought resilience in wheat</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project builds upon a previous collaboration between plant physiologists Martin Parry (RRes), Eric Ober (NIAB) and Solange Andrade (Embrapa Cerrados). New UK and Brazilian partners will ensure a multidisciplinary, innovative approach. Anthony Hall (Liverpool) brings expertise in genomic studies and Ian Dodd (Lancaster) in drought physiology. The project will develop phenotyping tools and enhance breeding outputs at Embrapa. Rothamsted Research (RRes) has extensive field, glasshouse and controlled environment facilities, and state-of-the-art core and specialist facilities, including the farm operation, metabolomics and bio-imaging laboratories, cereal transformation and virus-induced gene silencing technologies. A large array of wheat germplasm used in current experimentation includes panels of commercial cultivars and double haploid mapping populations, and a wheat TILLING population is also available. Martin Parry and Elizabete Carmo-Silva are working towards improving wheat carbon assimilation to increase grain yield. The Centre for Genomics Research (CGR), University of Liverpool, is a major collaborative academic service centre that enables access to the latest advances in DNA sequencing and array technologies, data analyses and interpretation. Within CGR, the Plant genomics group, led by Anthony Hall, includes five post-doctoral researchers working on wheat genomics and cybra-infrastructure for plant genomics. NIAB is a pioneering research and advisory organisation. Work at NIAB is guided by industry needs and farmer focussed, with strong knowledge-exchange programmes. Expertise is in breeding and genetics, farming systems development, crop physiology, agronomy, and variety evaluation. NIAB is well-equipped with machinery for field experiments and laboratories for a wide spectrum of analytical measurements. NIAB&apos;s &apos;Innovation Farm&apos; is used to communicate selected findings to the farming community. The Lancaster Environmental Centre&apos;s (LEC) offers extensive, state-of-the-art research laboratories, 15 glasshouses and 10 walk-in controlled environment rooms. Specific plant physiological equipment includes a whole-plant water use phenotyping platform and gas-exchange chamber, whole-plant pressure vessels for xylem sap collection and high throughout radioimmunossay and photoacoustic laser spectroscopy for phytohormone analysis. A field site with rainout shelters is available via a collaborative relationship with nearby Myerscough College. Embrapa Cerrados is located at Planaltina, Distrito Federal (DF), centre of Brazil. The unit has an experimental area of 2130 hectares, including 700 hectares of permanent ecological reserves. Facilities include laboratories, greenhouses, nurseries and seed processing unit. The Embrapa Cerrados team involved in this BBSRC-Embrapa project has expertise in Breeding (Julio Albrecht), Plant Physiology (Solange Andrade), Soil Science (Jo&#xE3;o Santos Jr.), Microbiology (Fabio Reis Jr.) and Water Resources (Lineu Rodrigues). The group&apos;s research aims to select high yielding wheat cultivars in Savanah areas. Embrapa Trigo is located in Passo Fundo, Rio Grande do Sul (RS), south of Brazil. The unit has researchers in various areas of expertise, with a particular focus on wheat breeding. The unit has a total area of 426 hectares, of which 284 hectares are used as experimental fields. Jorge Chagas (Co-I) and Marcio Silva (Co-I) will contribute their expertise in crop science and plant breeding, respectively. The project will be closely aligned with activities under the UK-Brazil partnership for Yield Stability and Protection in a Changing Climate (PYSP), partly funded by a Newton-fund joint centre award and jointly coordinated by RRes and Embrapa. PYSP will ensure minimal duplication and maximum engagement between groups in Brazil and UK, and provide a central focus for all RRes/Embrapa activities, strengthening links across projects and ensuring greater impact and joint research synergy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wheat is a world staple crop and provides 20% of global daily protein and calories. Over the past 20 years, average wheat productivity worldwide increased from 2.5 to 3 t ha-1, mostly as a result of breeding efforts that produced higher yielding cultivars. However, the current rate of yield increase in is too slow to meet the projected double in food demand by 2050. The need to improve food security is further compounded by climate change. Increasingly variable weather events, including variable precipitation patterns and decreased water availability, are expected to have major negative impacts on global crop productivity. Thus, it is imperative to improve the resilience of wheat yields to climate change and to minimise the yield gap - i.e., the difference between the potential yield, which is obtained under optimal management practices and in the absence of stress, and the actual farm yields. Furthermore, the improvement of wheat yields and yield resilience needs to happen in a sustainable manner that minimises impacts on the environment.  Wheat yields are currently in the range of about 2.5 t ha-1 in Brazil, slightly higher in the centre of the country at about 4.5 t ha-1, but still well below the 8 t ha-1 UK average. The aim of this research project is to develop new methodologies that will enable rapid and efficient selection of drought-resilient wheat cultivars specifically adapted for maximum yield productivity in the Brazilian Savanah. In this climatic area, temperatures are warm throughout the year and precipitation is more abundant in the summer than in the winter. Wheat is grown under irrigation in the winter and under rain-fed conditions, as a second crop, in the summer. Both wheat productivity and quality are higher in the Brazilian Savanah than the country average, yet soil acidity and low calcium availability interact with water deficit and limit plant productivity. Increasing wheat yield resilience to variable water supply will have a great impact to the agricultural sector in Brazil and benefits will be transferable to other regions of the world with similar climates, including many African countries.  In this project crop physiology will be combined with a modern molecular breeding approach to identify molecular markers and accelerate wheat breeding for drought resilience. New cultivars will be made available to other countries through the exchange of germplasm. The proposed Brazil-UK partnership has access to farm facilities and glasshouses to grow plants under diverse environmental conditions and technical capabilities that include field and glasshouse phenotyping for biomass production and water use efficiency as well as state-of-the-art genotyping technologies. The complementarity of resources and expertise will enable the evaluation and selection of cultivars that produce high yields under limited water availability. The UK partnership will enable transfer of phenotyping tools, germplasm and knowledge on genomic analyses. The project will have a strong capacity building component as both Brazilian and UK researchers will be trained in the areas of phenotyping and computational biology to promote the application of next-generation genomic approaches to wheat crop breeding.  The specific objectives of the project are to: 1. Develop a novel methodology to improve the phenotypic selection of drought-resilient wheat cultivars with high productivity in the glasshouse. 2. Validate drought tolerance and crop yield resilience of selected wheat cultivars under field conditions in Brazil and the UK. 3. Identify genetic markers associated with drought tolerance and yield resilience traits in wheat to be used in breeding programmes for selection of germplasm with improved performance in a changing climate.  The ultimate goal is to develop novel wheat germplasm with improved crop yield and yield resilience to climate change and enhance the sustainability of wheat production in Brazil and worldwide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rothamsted Research</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-20" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-19" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-25">15247.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-25">30495.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Small Grants Award to Rothamsted Research</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/N004485/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rothamsted Research</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FN004485%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-04-20"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
