<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010398_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Data, Accountability and Commercialisation. Working with NGO data to enhance downwards accountability in contexts of livelihood change.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project has four goals.   First we seek to use data held by Micaia, an NGO in Mozambique, to explore the impacts of commercialisation of natural resource products on rural livelihoods and natural resource governance. Second we examine how NGO data may be used to strengthen accountability between NGOs and the communities they serve. Third we consider how data collection can be adapted to respond to unforeseen changes that arise in the course of NGO-led development projects. Fourth we seek to integrate data we collect with publicly available datasets to make them more accessible.  In pursuit of these goals we have eight objectives.  1. Co-design with local communities and local government data collection procedures and objectives that can most effectively monitor change in rural areas brought about by Micaia&apos;s initiatives. 2. Establish protocols for integrating funder-led data requirements into these community-based data collection initiatives. 3. Integrate Micaia data into local government data collection practices in ways which respect the anonymity and ensure the safety of local residents. 4. Use locally derived measures of well-being and prosperity to understand the changes brought on by new natural resource sales.  5. Explore the relationship between these local measures with internationally recognised measures of wellbeing. 6. Examine the unforeseen consequences of changes from commercialisation and explore how data collection and management protocols can respond to them. 7. Explore practices of disseminating and communicating findings locally that respects both customary practice and responds to new trends in rural information sharing including social media. 8. Communicate our findings to national and international audiences within academia and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project has two dimensions. First it uses data held by Micaia, a development NGO that works in Mozambique, to explore the expected and unexpected consequences of commercialisation of natural resources. Micaia has been centrally involved in raising farm gate prices of natural resources (honey, baobab) and improving the management of those resources. We seek to use and expand Micaia&apos;s data better to understand how this work can be most beneficial to rural Mozambicans.  Second, it tackles a key problem facing development NGOs. These NGOs should be downwardly accountable to the people whom they exist to serve. And they have to be upwardly accountable to their funders. This tension is one of the central attributes of the development NGO sector globally.   A central component of this tension is data. The ability to know things about other people&apos;s lives is fundamental to accountability, whether with respect to project performance, changes in poverty, prosperity and wellbeing, community institutions, infrastructure and so on. Data provide power over funds, lives and organisations.  The challenge this project explores therefore is how development NGOs can collect, store and present data in ways that facilitate downwards accountability, while also meeting funders&apos; requirements. It builds on a previously funded secondary data initiative with Micaia. That project worked on data management plans and organisation to marshal previously collected data from development projects and businesses. We will work in this project on new forms and modalities of data collection that tackle the dilemmas of accountability.   Specifically this project explores four challenges. First, it will examine how data management and data collection can respond both to immediate funder needs (on how money has been spent and to what end) while also maintaining longer term monitoring and communicating key aspects of prosperity that matter most to communities. Co-ordinating and integrating these aspects of data collection is not straight forward. Yet maintaining the latter - tracking aspects of change that communities are most interested in - is central to downwards accountability. The second challenge is that these data collection systems must be robust and agile enough to respond to unforeseen changes. These can be common, particularly where projects are successful. They can present new aspects of community life and prosperity that communities and organisations will wish to track. Third, we will consider how these data might be effectively integrated with currently publicly available data in order that they can be most effectively and generally used.  We will be exploring these issues with respect to Micaia&apos;s work in natural resource management and commercialisation. Micaia has set up a baobab products company which provides substantial revenues to rural women where few revenue earning opportunities are available. It has a longer established honey company which works over a larger area. In addition it has worked on several projects on different aspects of natural resource management and institutional support. In combination these activities have driven substantial welcome change. But tracking that change and using those data to inform the appropriate entities, as well as capturing unforeseen developments - such changing gender relations within households that new revenues cause - is not straight forward. This project will take on this task. That is the fourth challenge.  The outputs of this work will be better data on the dynamics of rural villages in Mozambique where Micaia works. These will inform feedback to communities, local government and Micaia&apos;s plans and projects. In the second it will generate protocols and systems of using data to enhance downward accountability that will be useful to development NGOs more widely. Finally we will also provide insights into the consequences of commercialisation of natural resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">47822.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">130518.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">178341.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/T010398/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">47822.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010398_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">32498.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010398_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">32498.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010398_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">32761.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T010398_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FT010398%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
