<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S003207_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">New satellite observations to improve monitoring and forecasting of severe smoke pollution over SE Asia caused by Indonesian landscape burning</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outdoor air pollution is the world&apos;s greatest environmental health risk, and is contributed to greatly in the developing world by landscape burning. Smoke from landscape fires is a particularly significant contributor to the environmental health issue in parts of South East Asia. The primary objective of this project is to develop research that improves the monitoring and forecasting of air quality in South East Asia in particular Indonesia. This will be achieved through working closely with Indonesian experts at ITB and BMKG to build capacity and develop improved satellite products of aerosol, particulate matter and fire emissions that can be used to monitor particulate exposure at the surface and to assimilate into air quality forecast models.  To accomplish this, the specific objectives are:  1. to derive a set of properly representative PM emissions factors for peat, scrubland and forest burning in Indonesia, as well as from fuels such as rice straw and other agricultural residues that are frequently burned by farmers after the growing season and the subsequent harvest. 2. to improve the estimation of satellite AOD measurements which are an essential variable required to estimate atmospheric PM loadings (directly at high resolution) from satellites ad which currently use assumptions that are not applicable to the type of aerosol in the region due to a lack of knowledge on the optical pretties of aerosol generated by smouldering and intense peat fires. 3.  to combine the new PM emissions factors coming from Obj 1 with satellite-derived estimates of Indonesian fuel consumption, based on new very high temporal resolution fire radiative power (FRP) data derived from blended polar orbiting and geostationary satellite observations and converted to fuel consumptions using the new smoke plume AOD retrievals from Obj 2 in an approach akin to that of Mota and Wooster (2018).  In this way estimates of the fire radiative power (FRP) output for detected locations of landscape burning across Asia will be delivered, which directly related to the rates of biomass consumption and smoke emission of the causal fires (Wooster et al., 2005).  Himawari can be used to produce this FRP data a temporal resolution far higher than ever before 4. to incorporate these emissions estimates into a regional-scale CTM, and to work with BMKG to use this system for producing test PM concentration fields, which can then be evaluated against measurements provided by the limited in situ network operated by BMKG across the country. An assessment will be made as to the ability to use this system to provide actionable information on air quality reductions at an effective lead time. 5.  to derive PM concentrations derived directly from satellite AOD measures (made using optical properties derived as part of Obj 2), and to compare this with regional PM distributions modelled during Obj 4,  using a model based on a technique described by Van Donkelaar et al. 2006 to combine satellite measurements of AOD with meteorological fields and model information to estimate PM concentrations at the surface (which are those which represent the PM in the air breathed by the population). 6. To build capacity and connections between groups in the UK and Indonesia through joint fiield campaigns, joint research analysis and publications, visiting scientist stays, seminars,  sharing of well curated data and good communication channels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Outdoor air pollution is the world&apos;s greatest environmental health risk, and is contributed to greatly in the developing world by landscape burning. Smoke from landscape fires is a severe environmental health issue in parts of southeast Asia.. The smoke impacts are most keenly felt during dry spells in Indonesia, which hosts more than 80% of SE Asia&apos;s tropical peatlands. Over the last 50 years, deforestation and the construction of drainage canals, has increased the flammability of large areas of Indonesia&apos;s tropical peatland, during dry spells the peat can dry sufficiently to be ignitable by surface vegetation burning. The resulting fires can propagate downward into the peat and laterally, generating large areas of burning with fuel consumptions per unit area 100 times higher than other landscape fires. This releases copious amounts of particulate matter (PM) which adversely affects human health because the particles are small enough to pass into the human respiratory system causing respiratory and cardiovascular morbidity and mortality  This project teams researchers in the UK from STFC and KCL with universities ITB and BMKG to address this problem using satellite observations. In Indonesia BMKG has the remit within Indonesian to provide air quality information. However, this is based on a limited number of in situ monitoring stations across the nation, and no operational use of satellite aerosol data to complement and extend in situ coverage. Furthermore, air quality (AQ) forecast models need to be driven by accurate emissions magnitudes and timings. Unlike emissions from urban sources, those from peat burning cannot be prescribed from inventories, but must rather be based on real-time satellite observations since these fires are highly variable over space and time. Thus a reliable and timely source of fire and emissions data need to be provided, and if this is done then accurate forecasts of air pollution episodes should be possible using via an atmospheric chemical transport model (CTM) fed with these data. Such AQ forecasts alert authorities to take action (e.g. cancel outdoor activities, close schools, distribute personal protection masks). Satellite-based approaches to estimate fuel consumption are available and mature. However,   emissions factors have so far been based on laboratory combustion of just a few samples of tropical peat exhibiting significant variability. Furthermore, aerosol optical properties used in satellite retrievals of AOD (Aerosol Optical Depth) are based on measurements made in South American forests.  Neither the emission factors nor the smoke optical properties  will be fully representative of  Indonesian &apos;wildfires&apos;, and especially not the extreme combustion conditions exist during El Nino periods - such as for example intense flaming forest fires atop large areas of burning peat. Only in situ sampling of smoke from representative wildfires can deliver emissions factors and aerosol optical properties representative of such conditions.  This project has five main objectives focused on achieving a step change in the quality of AQ measurements, monitoring and forecasts over Indonesia and importantly to develop the capacity for joint Indonesian and UK research in the area through joint field campaigns and visiting scientists. The first objectives focus on obtaining a unique set of ground measurements bespoke to Indonesian scrubland, forest, peat and agricultural residue fires. The subsequent objectives will capitalize on these new pieces of information to produce new satellite aerosol optical depth (and atmospheric particulate matter) information and fire radiative power-based fire emissions products capable of being used in Indonesia in real-time to support AQ assessments and model forecasts, and finally we will assess the quality of the full set of information produced - and in particular the atmospheric PM distributions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">1137.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S003207_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">9904.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S003207_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">25466.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S003207_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">6643.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S003207_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">16712.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S003207_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">1160.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S003207_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">160595.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC GCRF STFC - ODA Award to STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST/S003207/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC - Laboratories</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FS003207%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
