<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P010873_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">G-quadruplex biology in the human malaria parasite Plasmodium falciparum</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research concerns the most important human malaria parasite, Plasmodium falciparum. Malaria is one of the world&apos;s most debilitating infectious diseases, killing over half a million people every year and affecting several hundred million. Most of the deaths occur in young children in sub-Saharan Africa, but adults can also suffer from malaria throughout their lives, reducing quality of life and retarding economic development in endemic countries. The lack of an effective vaccine and the emergence of drug-resistant parasites mean that there is now an urgent need for research leading to a better understanding of the malaria parasite, and hence to new vaccine targets and treatment strategies for this disease.  The malaria parasite causes illness via the infection of red blood cells. It multiplies inside these cells and modifies their surfaces with proteins called PfEMP1s that bind to the walls of blood vessels. This is crucial for parasite survival as it removes infected cells from the circulating blood and protects them from passing through the spleen, which might recognize and destroy them. It also contributes to disease, with severe malaria being particularly associated with the accumulation of infected cells in vessels of the brain and placenta. It is therefore of great interest to malaria biologists to understand the mechanisms that control the expression of these adhesive PfEMP1 proteins. PfEMP1s are not expressed uniformly by all malaria parasites: instead, individual parasites regularly switch between different variants. This allows them to stay ahead of the immune system and sustain a chronic infection for months or even years. The parasites have a large, variable family of &apos;var&apos; genes for different PfEMP1 proteins and they vary the expression of these genes by so-called &apos;epigenetic switching&apos;. Furthermore, var genes recombine very readily to generate new variants, so each parasite strain - of which there are many hundreds circulating in endemic areas - has a unique repertoire of possible surface proteins. This is one reason why immunity to repeated malaria infections is slow to develop in humans: every new parasite strain looks different to the immune system, so people can be re-infected repeatedly throughout their lives.  Understanding and ultimately interfering with the expression, switching and recombination of var genes, and thus the variant expression of PfEMP1 proteins, could be a key to more effective immune control of malaria. Therefore, this research focuses on a new biological mechanism that the parasite may use for switching between var genes and for generating new variants. Our recent work has showed that an unusual DNA structure called a G-quadruplex that is concentrated around var genes seems to affect both these processes. To investigate this further, we now propose to map the G-quadruplexes throughout the Plasmodium genome, both in DNA and also in the messenger molecule, RNA. We will use a range of cutting-edge genome-wide technologies to do this, and will then check whether the distribution of the structures changes when the enzymes that unwind them are removed.  These studies will lead to a better understanding of the mechanisms underlying var gene dynamics, and may ultimately inform new strategies to combat malaria, since var genes - and the adhesive proteins that they encode - are central to malarial disease. The outcomes of the research will be published in open-access scientific journals and presented at international conferences. They will be communicated to the general public via summaries on appropriate websites and via science writing in magazines and/or online. Work such as this remains vital as long as the malaria parasite continues to cause an immense burden of human disease.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research will investigate a key aspect of the biology of the malaria parasite Plasmodium falciparum. A major virulence trait in this parasite is antigenic variation: the ability to switch between different variants of PfEMP1, which is the principal surface protein expressed on infected cells. The parasite maintains and controls a large antigenic repertoire by transcriptional switching within a large family of &apos;var&apos; genes that encode PfEMP1s. Parasites can thus evade immunity and sustain chronic infections in human hosts. Furthermore, recombination of  the var gene family generates new variants at a high rate. The biological mechanisms underlying these processes, however, are not completely understood. This project will focus on G-quadruplex nucleic acid structures and the helicases that unwind these structures as a possible novel mechanism for controlling var gene transcription and recombination, as well as the stability and evolution of the parasite genome as a whole.  The two broad aims of the project are as follows:  1: To assess the locations of G4 structures and of G4-metabolising helicases in the P. falciparum genome, at the DNA level, via chromatin immunoprecipitation.  To assess the representation of G4 structures at the RNA level in the transcriptome via RNA Structure-seq.  2: To explore the relative roles of G4-metabolising proteins in P. falciparum, focussing on the two RecQ helicases PfBLM and PfWRN, plus the putative PfFANCJ helicase.  Attainment of these objectives will be marked by the following milestones:  1a: Establish the locations of G4 motifs throughout the P. falciparum genome by immunoprecipitation with motif-specific antibodies. 1b: Establish the binding sites of RecQ helicases throughout the genome by tagging of the helicases followed by chromatin immunoprecipitation (ChIP-seq). 1c: Establish the distribution of G4 motifs in the mRNA transcriptome by structure-specific sequencing (Structure-seq). 2a: Characterise a double knockout of the two Plasmodium RecQ helicases, assessing all the G4-related phenotypes that were seen in two single-knockout lines generated in our previous grant on this topic. 2b: Knock out the putative FANCJ gene - which encodes a second type of G4 helicase in P. falciparum - and characterise this mutant. 2c: Establish in all these helicase knockouts the potential contribution of replication fork instability to genomic recombination, by measuring the dynamics of DNA replication on a single-molecule level.  Achieving these objectives will significantly improve our understanding of the basic biology of the human malaria parasite and the impact of this biology on virulence, since antigenic variation is a key virulence trait for this parasite.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-29">161700.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">40425.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P010873_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">40425.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P010873_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">40425.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P010873_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">40425.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P010873_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">-12237.79</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P010873_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
