<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R018529_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MICA: BRAINTOOLS Phase 1: Optimising neurodevelopmental outcomes for global health</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Centre for Brain &amp; Cognitive Development (CBCD) at Birkbeck has a world leading reputation for the multidisciplinary study of brain and cognitive development in early childhood, including development and application of the latest methodologies for large-scale longitudinal studies and trials.  Our strategic vision is to bring this expertise to bear on LMIC mental health in early human development and developmental disorders. Whilst brain development can be altered by common risk factors from pregnancy, diagnosable symptoms of common mental health conditions often do not become apparent until mid-childhood.  Child psychiatry has traditionally focused on the development of treatments at the end point of this process, targeted towards children and adolescents with an existing diagnosis. However, post-diagnostic treatments are typically expensive and inaccessible to most patients in LMICs, who may also lack access to diagnostic services in general. To meet the needs of LMICs, we need a radical shift in our approach. Rather than focus limited resources on children already identified with a condition, we need to shift towards direct measurement of the brain systems that are affected by early risk factors in infancy, and using this information develop low-cost, scalable and preventative treatments.  To achieve this, we will build on two decades of MRC-funded work in which we have developed panels of infant brain markers that can predict childhood mental health in domains like cognition, attention and social communication. Beginning from a study based at CBCD, we have developed a UK network focused on the study of early autism and ADHD (www.basis-network.org) and extended this to two European networks (www.eurosibs.eu and www.brainview.org). This has enabled us to build large-scale replication and extension programs for our key findings, and to build the sample sizes required to assess the effects of genetic and environmental risk factors on the developing brain in Western European contexts. The logical next step for our work program is to exploit our empirical findings and organizational infrastructure to develop a toolkit of brain markers optimised for LMIC settings that can be used in large-scale risk detection and early intervention trials. While our long-term vision is for widespread dissemination of expertise, a key first step is close engagement with selected LMIC sites for bi-directional knowledge exchange and feasibility assessments. Thus, we have initially selected two LMIC partners who face contrasting challenges; MRC Gambia and Sangath India. Building on initial contacts, we will establish and consolidate a collaborative network with four short-term objectives (pump-priming projects); (1) collaboratively develop a protocol for assessing targeted features of human functional brain development in LMIC settings, (2) prepare a new Masters course in Developmental Neuroscience for Global Health, (3) develop a plan for parent education and family engagement in LMIC settings with partner SME BabyBrains, and (4) conduct a gap analysis of how to establish regional Centres of Excellence affiliated to CBCD.  Taken together, our project is designed as a cohesive package to support the Sustainable Development Goal &quot;Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages&quot;. Our toolkit is designed to enable field workers to identify early risk and test the effects of different early interventions on early brain development in low-resource settings. Further, our work on parent and family education will provide the critical human resources and community acceptance for such programmes. Combined with advanced training and the development of regional Centres of Excellence affiliated with CBCD, such advances will allow effective and cost-efficient early interventions to be validated and deployed in LMIC settings, revolutionising the life chances of millions of infants and young children.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Centre for Brain &amp; Cognitive Development (CBCD) at Birkbeck has a world leading reputation for the multidisciplinary study of psychological development and mental health in early childhood, including development and application of new methodologies for large-scale longitudinal studies and trials.  Our strategic vision is to bring this expertise in theory, study design, and technology development to bear on LMIC early mental health. Child psychiatry has traditionally focused on treating children and adolescents with a diagnosis. However, post-diagnostic treatments are typically expensive and inaccessible to most patients in LMICs (Belfer, 2008), who may also lack access to diagnostic services in general (Saxena et al., 2007). To meet the needs of LMICs, we need a radical shift in our approach. Rather than focus resources on children with a diagnosis, we need to shift towards direct measurement of the brain systems that are affected by early risk factors in infancy, and then use this information to develop low-cost, scalable and preventative treatments targeted towards those brain systems. To do this, we have planned an integrated long-term programme of research to identify the infant brain markers that predict neurodevelopmental outcomes in LMICs; to use these markers to test which common modifiable risk factors in LMICs affect key brain systems; and to identify protective factors that could represent targets for intervention to build resilience in LMIC settings. Directly assessing the effects of environmental risk factors in early childhood (rather than waiting for later neurodevelopmental outcome) enables rapid assessment of the efficacy of simple preventative interventions. Directly measuring brain development allows us to identify the most vulnerable children as early as possible, allowing limited resources to be focused on those most likely to benefit from preventative approaches. Taken together, focusing on brain development in early childhood is critical to revolutionising global mental health.  We are optimally suited to leading this challenge because of our combined expertise in developing infant neural markers of long-term mental health and our experience in deploying novel technologies to measure early childhood brain development in low-resource settings. While our long-term vision entails widespread dissemination of expertise, a key first step is close engagement with selected LMIC sites for bi-directional knowledge exchange and feasibility assessments. Thus, we have carefully selected two LMIC partners who face contrasting challenges; MRC Gambia and Sangath India. Building on initial contacts, we will establish and consolidate a collaborative network with four short-term objectives (pump-priming projects); (1) collaboratively develop a feasible protocol for assessing human functional brain development in LMIC settings, (2) prepare a Masters course in Developmental Neuroscience for Global Health, (3) develop a plan for parent education and family engagement in LMIC settings with partner SME BabyBrains, and (4) conduct a gap analysis of how to establish regional Centres of Excellence affiliated to CBCD. Taken together, our cohesive package is designed to provide the foundation for our long-term strategy to bring early childhood brain development into global mental health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gambia (the)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-01">199404.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Rapid Response Research Grants Award to Birkbeck College</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R018529/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Birkbeck College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">199404.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R018529_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Birkbeck College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">-13705.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R018529_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Birkbeck College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR018529%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
