<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004789_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Community-Centred Educational Model for developing Social Resilience (ACES): Playfulness towards an inclusive, safe and resilient society</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACES will deliver research and develop practice that will provide new insights into transformative model and practice for stimulating creative thinking, complex problem solving and social-emotional learning to tackle real-world problems in the culturally rich and multi-ethnic Malaysia, Indonesia and Vietnam towards contributing to their economic and welfare development. The objectives of ACES are: O1 -  Investigate the context of the three countries in terms of the educational model mapped against the target sustainable development goals (SDGs) related to wellbeing (SDG 3), poverty (SDG 1) and gender equality (SDG 5). This will provide a comparative analysis of the baselines, identify gaps and opportunities and articulate meaningful measures for capturing transformations enabled by inclusive and equitable quality education (SDG 4) including social and economic resilience for impacting development outcomes (e.g. economic and welfare). This objective will establish evidence-based insights into the factors that will enable transformative education (such as the 21st-century skills, environmental, economic and welfare factors) to be developed in connection with the countries&apos; development goals.  O2 - Co-develop, co-create and localise the playful ACES programme of activities with the project partners (with a focus on young people and school teachers) as the instruments to investigate an educational model that will enable social innovation in the community. The programme will afford a critical and creative culture, where disciplinary and cultural barriers will be decreased to allow young people and teachers to experiment on new techniques for facilitating creative thinking, problem-solving and social-emotional learning. This objective will deliver adaptable/adoptable ACES model blueprint and toolkits to be developed and validated, ambassadors/champions from the pilot locations to be identified and trained and, a mobile lab and an online Hub to support the communities across the countries to be developed.  O3 - Co-design and co-develop participatory studies, involving ways to onboard and engage the local, rural and indigenous communities in Malaysia, Vietnam and Indonesia, targeting young people, school teachers and wider community residents. The ACES Lab will be implemented as a research instrument for investigating the transformative role of education beyond the formal didactics for mobilising young people taking into account the impact of wellbeing, gender discriminations and poverty on education. This objective will produce the indigenous research protocol, ethical considerations, methods and instruments for the participatory studies, including practical recommendations and guidelines for the local teams.  O4 - Facilitate, capture and evaluate the experience, learning outcomes and transferability of the ACES approach, including the social and educational value of the proposed educational practice, and its ability to connect and reconnect communities into civic participation, social action and innovation towards achieving social resilience. This objective will provide insights and discussions on the relationships between transformational education and SDGs across the countries, delivered as publications and interactive media targeting the general public, policy and education stakeholders. O5 - Consolidate the outcomes and findings, and the extent to which the educational model is replicable and scalable beyond the target communities. This will include engaging with policymakers and practitioners, transferring educational research into policy and practice towards achieving development outcomes. This objective will release the final version of the adaptable and adoptable ACES model (lab, online hub and toolkits), the use cases from the three countries and the scientific, general and policy publications.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">ACES will investigate and establish a transformative educational model for bridging formal and informal educational contexts via playful and participatory methodology towards a more inclusive, safe and resilient society that will empower young people to flourish despite their social localities. ACES will investigate the role of education in mobilising young people towards achieving Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), taking into account the impact of wellbeing (SDG3), gender (SDG5) and poverty (SDG1) on education (SDG4) and vice-versa in Malaysia, Indonesia and Vietnam. ACES will focus on building resilient communities of young people in rural areas or deprived sections of urban communities through education. Young people refers to those in primary and secondary education. ACES will engage teachers and local community groups in the co-creation and ownership of the educational process, fostering an empowering and agentic practice when it comes to marginalised contexts - to motivate, ground and, most importantly, localise the intervention. The upskilling of teachers is considered as one of the most effective and direct means of achieving all of the SDG4 targets. The effects of quality education are linked to improved development outcomes. In all three countries, access to inclusive and equitable quality education is an impending issue; however, the causes, scope and severity vary from one country to another. In Indonesia, the dominance of political, corporate and bureaucratic elites affects the provision of quality education. In Vietnam, its education system struggles to provide access and quality, although since 2008, its government allocates 20% of its national budget to improve education throughout the nation. In Malaysia, access to quality education is still an issue at remote/rural areas in the country. Even though these countries report the literacy rate of over 90%, the efforts to maintain sustainable growth in their respective economies, to reach developed status, hinge on an updated system of education that is more transformative beyond literacy. While economic growth in these countries brings positive benefits and lifts people out of poverty, societies must be equipped to respond to subsequent changes related to political and social systems. Economic resilience thus depends on social resilience, agency and capabilities to respond, design, implement and support corrective and adaptive measures.  ACES will explore the use of playful and participatory methodology towards developing an inclusive, equitable and transformative educational model that will afford opportunities for young people, teachers and community groups to respond to challenges/changes in their community through creative and innovative practices. To navigate an increasingly uncertain and ambiguous world, young people will need to develop curiosity, imagination, creativity, resilience and self-regulation towards innovative economies that are more productive, resilient and adaptable. ACES will emphasise on collaborative, active and playful/creative 21st-century pedagogies, where the focus of the teaching-learning process is on active dialogue, enquiry based, media literacy and student-centred approaches. Collaborative exploration open up opportunities for social innovation, taking into account the complexity of social problems and foster solutions resilient and cost-effective enough to adapt and survive.  The project will explore social innovation through the lenses of frugal approaches to social sustainability to allow the community to thrive despite the lack of resources. ACES will investigate the impact of creative thinking, problem-solving and social-emotional learning beyond literacy afforded by playful pedagogy in these countries to conduct a comparative analysis into the complex relationships between transformational education and SDGs across the countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coventry University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">113394.57</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">227707.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">115239.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">115239.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">76820052.624</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to Coventry University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004789_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coventry University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT004789%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
