<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024682_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing Livestock-derived Antimicrobial pollution in the Nairobi River in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UN estimates that 70% of the antibiotics used globally end up in livestock (UN, 2017). And to keep up with the global demand for animal products, this use is predicted to rise by over 65% by 2030 (ibid). The figures have grave implications for the world&apos;s waterways. In the global crisis relating to antimicrobial resistance much attention has centred on stewardship. Only recently has the extent of the environmental component of the problem been recognised. Emerging research has demonstrated that many of the world&apos;s rivers are highly contaminated with antibiotic residues and antibiotic resistance genes (ARGs) in addition to resistant bacteria. Run-off and effluent from commercial and subsistence farming systems have been implicated as key sources of ARGs and antibiotic residues. We also know that antimicrobial resistance is often accelerated by other pollutants such as heavy metals, which equally are a by-product of some farming systems.  At present, the Nairobi river in Kenya has been ranked among the top ten global waterways in terms of pharmaceutical contamination. Tests undertaken to determine the presence of 6 different antibiotics revealed frequencies between 60 and 97.5%. High levels of the veterinary antibiotics such as ciprofloxacin, tetracycline and enrofloxacin have also been detected. Yet the Nairobi river basin is also home to over 4 million inhabitants, many living in informal settlements, whose lives and livelihoods are at direct risk from these toxicities. To respond to this issue, this project will leverage the findings of the following six, related research projects:   1. &apos;Supporting Evidence-Based Policy: a longitudinal study of AMR risk behaviours among livestock keeping communities in India and Kenya (SEP-AMR)&apos; (ES/P00492X/2); PI: Prof Claire Heffernan. The project explored social, behavioural and environmental drivers forging the rise in antimicrobial resistance among subsistence farming communities in Kenya and India.  2. &apos;Towards controlling antimicrobial resistance in global aquatic animal food systems by enhancing collective resilience (AMFORA)&apos; (MR/R015104/1; PI: Prof Javier Guitian, RVC).The AMFORA project used a systems-thinking approach to map aquaculture systems in Vietnam in order to identify hotspots for emergence and selection of resistance.  3.&apos;Drivers of human exposure to antibacterial resistance in the Sri Lankan environment&apos;. (MR/R014876/1; PI: Prof Alistair Boxall). The project developed a spatial framework for modelling the occurrence of antibacterial substances and antibiotic resistance genes in the environment of Sri-Lanka.  4. &apos;Global Monitoring of Pharmaceuticals Project&apos;, which tested 165 rivers in 72 countries for pharmaceuticals. In Kenya, antibiotic residues were found in over 50% of the samples, the highest concentrations were found in tributaries of the Nairobi river. 5. &apos;Low cost environmentally friendly nanomaterials and solar thermal devices for affordable clean water production&apos; (GCRF Institutional Award to City University), PI: Dr Weiping Wu. This project developed new tools for water quality improvement and pollution monitoring.  6. &apos;Safe environment and human life in Bangladesh: a low-cost water filter fabrication to purify industrial polluted water&apos; (GCRF Institutional Award to City University), PI: Dr Sumsun Naher and Professor Ken Grattan. The project produced low cost water filters using banana leaves.   Our project will work with a range of stakeholders from local communities to policy makers to identify/map sources of livestock-related effluents. We will test the feasibility, robustness and sustainability of three types of low-cost water filters to screen antibiotic residues, bacteria and heavy metals. We will undertake a range of engagement activities with the public, including school children. In this manner, we will utilise an interdisciplinary research platform to move towards the &apos;solutions space&apos; to this pressing problem.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="KE" type="KENYA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">102098.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The rise of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) in Africa has all the hallmarks of a &apos;wicked problem.&apos;  The increase in demand for livestock products coupled with low or lax regulatory frameworks and poor/limited access to livestock healthcare providers has created an explosive rise in antibiotic use. Related to this indiscriminate use, is an additional challenge: the livestock sector is a major contributor to environmental AMR via effluents and contaminated waste water and other by-products of production. Aquaculture in particular, is considered a major source of antibiotic &apos;pollution&apos; in global rivers (where such pollution includes antibiotic resistant bacteria, antibiotic residues and antibiotic resistance genes (ARG)). The UN estimates that 75% of the antibiotics used in aquaculture end up in the surrounding environment. Solving such a wicked problem belies a straightforward unpacking of the causal drivers. AMR is no exception. But by starting with the solution, rather than the challenge, it may be argued that there is a clearer pathway to change. In this case, the critical goal must be to prevent such environmental contamination in the first place.   As such, we will create a new AMR research platform to reduce livestock-sourced antimicrobial contamination of rivers. Our platform is based on the findings of six convergent research projects on AMR that range from understanding livestock-related risks at the community level (ES/P00492X/2) to mapping aquaculture systems (MR/R015104/1) to testing rivers for pharmaceutical waste (Global Monitoring of Pharmaceuticals Project) and identifying hotspots (MR/R014876/1) to developing new, low cost, sustainable water filters (GCRF Institutional Award(s), City University).   Our new work will coalesce around the Nairobi river in Kenya. The Nairobi river basin is home to over 4 million inhabitants and is one of the most polluted waterways in the world. Pollutants range from sewage from informal settlements to waste water from urban/peri-urban fish farms and commercial livestock farms to effluents from abattoirs. This toxic mix is topped-off with waste from a number of pharmaceutical companies. By combining approaches from the above projects we will begin by reducing antimicrobial pollution across a range of livestock-related sources. Our methods and approaches, however, will be relevant to all sources of antimicrobial and heavy metal contamination. We will identify the level and source of bacterial pollutants and changes over time and explore the feasibility and function of innovative, low cost water filters made from local materials. We will train farmers in the use of these filters and in reducing the drivers of AMR. Finally, we will engage the public in better understanding the scope and scale of the environmental parameters of AMR. Our platform has four broad aims:   1. To directly decrease the flow of bacteria, antibiotic residues and ARGs from livestock-related effluents and waste-water into the Nairobi river. 2. To enhance good practice with regard to antibiotic stewardship among farmers and other stakeholders.  3. To increase profitability/decrease food safety risks of livestock production with a focus on urban/peri-urban poultry and fish farmers. 4. To engage the public, particularly school children in a range of knowledge transfer activities around environmental antimicrobial contamination.   Over the course of the inception phase we will lay the groundwork for these objectives by working with stakeholder groups to identify and map sources of livestock effluents; test the use and applicability of the filters in these environments and work with urban and peri-urban farmers and policy makers to better understand uptake and adopton issues. We will also support local teachers and school children in addressing knowledge gaps around AMR in order to engage the next generation in the &apos;solutions space&apos; of this wicked challenge."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">34032.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024682_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Veterinary College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">34032.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024682_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Veterinary College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
