<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007990_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pacific Community Filmmaking and Gender, Impact and Public Engagement</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender inequality in the Pacific is a serious challenge and a sensitive issue - requiring a culturally appropriate and joined-up development approach to support and drive the necessary social changes. The prevalence of violence against women in the Pacific region is among the highest in the world, whilst women&apos;s parliamentary participation is amongst the lowest in the world. Countries across the Pacific region have put in place policy strategies, legal frameworks and a raft of initiatives, but against their own and internationally accepted indicators there has been poor progress towards gender equality, despite the development cooperation efforts of many donors over several decades.  The AHRC/GCRF Research Networking Project, Exploring Participatory Filmmaking as a Development Method to address Gender Inequality in the Pacific (2017/2018) and the SFC-GCRF Pacific Connections: Community Filmmaking and Gender Inequality in the Pacific (2018/19) projects have highlighted and brought together an emerging body of Pacific-made participatory documentary films and filmmakers. Their work opens up alternative routes to understand and influence gender inequality in the Pacific by enabling communities to tell their own stories through their own cultural terms. In their own analyses of events and actions, Pacific peoples point to the importance of differentiating gender within particular social, collective and kinship relations and of the nuances and sensitivities of promoting rights-based issues such as gender inequality and GBV within a communal society.  Significantly, these projects have brought to the fore the impact the processes of participatory production have on individuals and communities involved, and how projects can be seen as multi layered, locally embedded and culturally sensitive approaches to achieving gender based policy objectives. This proposed international community filmmaking project will enhance filmmakers&apos; and organisations&apos; capacity to work with communities around issues of gender inequality and to use this work as drivers for social change.  Based on outcomes from the AHRC/GCRF previous projects, this project will target support at training and mentoring for community filmmakers and emerging talent.  It will produce media projects on gender related themes across the Pacific that will create impact for participants and audiences during and after production. It will develop audiences through cross platform screenings &amp; events that bring together communities, funders, organisations, Government and stakeholders. Though training, production, distribution and public engagement the project will seek to visibly advocate for the validity of the emerging Pacific Filmmakers Consortium, and a sustainable and locally generated approach to contextualising and enacting change around gender equality.  The proposed project will build on the Pacific Filmmakers Consortium network, with media projects, filmmaker and public training and programmes of distribution and stakeholder, government and NGO engagement in ODA LMIC and UMC countries - PNG (including Bougainville Island), Samoa, Solomon Islands, Fiji, Tuvalu, Tonga and Vanuatu. It has the potential to also include and bring into this network practitioners and communities in Marshall Islands and Kiribati. This multi strand approach has the objective of contributing to creative development methods to support the challenge of promoting gender equality in the Pacific.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed international impact and engagement project builds on the 2018/19 AHRC/GCRF Research Networking Project, &quot;Exploring Participatory Filmmaking as a Development Method to address Gender Inequality in the Pacific&quot;  and the SFC-GCRF Pacific Connections: Community Filmmaking and Gender Inequality in the Pacific projects led by Dr. Tony Crook of University of St. Andrews. These collaborative networking projects addressed community based and participatory media production as a development methodology in tackling gender inequality and specifically gender based violence in the Pacific. The prevalence of violence against women in the Pacific region is among the highest in the world, whilst women&apos;s parliamentary participation is amongst the lowest in the world.  The proposed project seeks to consolidate and build capacity amongst a network of Pacific community based filmmakers and organisations who have come together through the above mentioned projects and whose work with communities addresses gender inequality in vernacular terms and with local participation and frames of reference.  It has become clear that while there is substantial progress and innovation being made in Pacific community media, filmmakers, organisations and institutions working with communities would benefit from targeted filmmaker support, greater visibility and communication of the methods and impact of community media to effect social change. For the filmmakers it is important to strengthen their ability to self-sustain, attract funding and articulate their methods in development contexts.  The project aims to: 1) Reduce gender inequality and gender based violence in the Pacific.  2) Build capacity amongst Pacific filmmakers to address gender inequality through participatory filmmaking practices 3) Raise the visibility and validity of the Pacific Community Filmmakers Consortium, so as to influence policy and development approaches to GBV and gender inequality.  4) Build engagement with community filmmaking participation and develop audiences across the Pacific.  In taking an innovative approach to tackling gender inequality though supporting participatory filmmaking in the Pacific as a development methodology, the project objectives are to:    1) Manage and provide training and mentoring for local filmmakers and community members in community media techniques, business support, funding application and social media.  2) Produce 13 community based filmmaking and arts projects across the Pacific, focused on gender inequality and GBV.  3) Facilitate the documentation of the 13 community film projects to further share the Consortium&apos;s approach and practice with communities, NGOs, academics and policy makers.  4) Coordinate a programme of local and regional workshops, screenings and events with public, NGO and government stakeholders. This will include pan-Pacific public screenings, events and distribution of the 13 community media projects focused on 16 Days of Activism (November - December 2020) in country and via on-line/multi platform.  5) Facilitate dialogue with regional NGO&apos;s, government, non-government and international development agencies in Port Moresby, Apia and Suva demonstrating the impact of the process of community media as development methodology.  6) Develop multi media and commercialisation routes for the community media projects via the Consortium website.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edinburgh Napier University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="889" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">93888.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">93888.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to Edinburgh Napier University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007990_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Edinburgh Napier University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT007990%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
