<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M02637X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton001 Systems Biology of Typhoid Fever</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enteric fever caused by Salmonella Typhi and Paratyphi A is wide spread throughout the world. particularly burdensome in South-East Asia, with approximately &gt;22 million new infections resulting in a 1% fatality rate annually. Control of the disease is hindered due to insufficient understanding of disease pathogenesis and immune responses to the infection, inaccurate diagnostic tests and limited efficacy of licensed vaccines. Thus understanding human host-responses to enteric infections is pivotal in developing improved diagnostic tests and vaccines. The Oxford Vaccine Group (OVG) has recently developed a human challenge model for S. Typhi and Paratyphi A. Briefly, human adult volunteers were orally infected with a pathogenic dose of S. Typhi and Paratyphi A and closely monitored the following days until treatment with antibiotics. This model was subsequently used to test vaccine efficacy by vaccinating participants prior to ingestion of the bacteria. The various samples collected provide a rich dataset consisting of clinical and immunological measurements invaluable to understand disease pathogenesis and human molecular responses to infection. Associated with such large datasets and different levels of data (molecular, serological and clinical) is the challenge of analysis and data integration, which we address through using systems biology approaches. Systems biology/vaccinology is an interdisciplinary field that combines systems-wide measurements, networks, and predictive modelling in the context of biology, vaccines and infectious disease. Computational modelling and integration of multiple levels of data (clinical, immunological, and molecular) develops a multi-facetted understanding of disease pathogenesis and biological mechanisms underlying host-responses to infections/vaccination. Particularly important in this context are regulatory mechanisms, which consist of complex networks involving multiple transcriptional and genetic components. Recently, it has become clear that long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) play a pivotal role in the regulation of biological processes by a diverse range of mechanisms. Integrative analysis of transcriptional signatures related to expression of lncRNAs allows us to identify molecular events associated with clinical and immunological outcomes. We are aiming to thoroughly integrate these different datasets to fully investigate the intricacy of human host-responses to infections. We believe that this approach is necessary in order to further shed light on the undisputed complexity of the immune system. As these samples are derived from the human host and a uniquely controlled experimental design, the results will likely elucidate important clues as to how the host reacts to enteric infections and how S. Typhi/Paratyphi A potentially modulate the host-response. By partnering with the Computational Systems Biology Lab at the University of Sao Paulo we are combining one of the largest clinical trials groups in Europe with an excellence in vaccine trials with a team of computational biologists leading in the field of systems vaccinology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-07">10060.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-07">20121.5</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The main objectives of this proposed partnership are: - Establish a long-lasting collaboration between one of the world&apos;s leading systems biology labs (CSBL) and clinical trials groups (OVG). - Facilitate academic knowledge, research and educational exchange between the University of S&#xE3;o Paulo and the University of Oxford at the highest level. - Build significant capacity in clinical trials and global health research in Brazil. - Enable innovation in complex systems biology research in order to advance the knowledge of enteric infectious diseases on a multidisciplinary level. - Perform multidisciplinary integrative analysis of highly complex datasets in order identify novel diagnostic biomarkers for typhoid fever. - Investigate the biological roles of long noncoding RNAs in typhoid fever and Salmonella infection. - Build significant capacity in the field of computational biology in the United Kingdom."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
