<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T005149_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Schools as Enabling Spaces to Improve Learning and Health-Related Quality of Life for Primary School Children in Rural Communities in South Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Globally and in South Africa inequality gaps in education and health have remained constant between urban and rural areas over the last decade. The aim of this research is to advance state-of-the-art theory and practice about how schools work effectively with families and communities in rural areas to create the optimal practices, cultures and conditions to strengthen their organisational and professional capacities and, through these, improve and sustain young children&apos;s learning, health and wellbeing in the foundation phase of their primary schooling. Despite the pivotal roles of school leadership and effective teaching in generating educational quality, especially in schools serving socioeconomically disadvantaged communities, they remain surprisingly overlooked in the evidence discourse of global sustainable development. This research will fill in this knowledge and evidence gap, and provide new understandings and innovations at the grassroots level to advance the education for sustainable development agenda. To address this, our objectives are:         - Produce a critical synthesis about the nature and effects of past and existing education and health promotion initiatives in rural primary schools and their communities in South Africa (and beyond), focusing on those that are shown to have successfully accelerated student learning and wellbeing (i.e. &apos;what works&apos; practices); and identify the range of social, cultural, economic, and policy determinants that influence the effectiveness and impact of these initiatives on children and their families, especially the disadvantaged;     - Derive and validate a conceptual map explaining schools as &apos;enabling spaces&apos; for improvement in whole-child learning, achievement and health in rural spaces, accounting for differences in leadership capabilities and teacher capacities as well as the social resources at individual, school and community levels;       - Co-construct, with local policy, community and school stakeholders, systems-oriented, multi-layered interventions to strengthen schools&apos; capacity to be(come) intellectual and social spaces of learning and development for children aged 6- 9 years - in ways that schools are strategically and systematically connected with their larger communities and that they have the organisational conditions and social resources to achieve sustained, sustainable learning and development for their teachers, and through them, their pupils;      - Evaluate the feasibility (i.e. enabling/inhibiting factors underpinning the implementation process), impact, and sustainability (including value for money) of this systems-focused intervention approach in three provinces, exploring the extent to which, and how, variation in capacities and social resources influence schools&apos; ability to improve children&apos;s academic achievement and their key objective health and wellbeing outcomes (i.e. growth status; BMI) as well as perceived subjective health-related quality of life (e.g. mobility, environmental quality, self-esteem, social relationships and connections);      - In partnership with policy, school and community leaders as well as key stakeholders from health and other related sectors, generate and disseminate new knowledge and learnings about how whole-child quality schooling can be achieved to promote learning and healthy development in rural spaces and how such learnings can be effectively translated into policy and practice to achieve wider impact in South Africa;     - Build cross-sectoral, multidisciplinary platforms and forums internationally to verify the scientific, policy and practice authority of the research findings in much wider and more diverse contexts, and through this, to advance understandings of how enabling environments can be achieved at classroom-school-community level in high needs spaces in many other countries where reducing inequalitiesin education and health has also remained a persistent challenge.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Inequalities in education and health are deeply rooted in social and economic disadvantage. In South Africa, 38% of children live in rural communities and are significantly more likely to be deprived of opportunities for quality education and health-related quality of life than those less disadvantaged. This research aims to address this persistent structural challenge and establish how schools can beat the odds and enable children to achieve and thrive despite their location in high-poverty communities.        This project is grounded in an ethic of social justice and led by a UK and South Africa interdisciplinary team from Education, Health, Psychology, Sociology, and Health Economics. This mixed methods research will establish a comprehensive, empirically grounded theory of practice - i.e. organising schools as enabling spaces for improvement in learning and health. It will focus on the Foundation Phase of primary schooling (children aged 6-9) because: i) this is a critical period of transition from early childhood to middle childhood when early interventions can make a significant impact on long-term outcomes; and ii) this is also a key transition phase when children begin developing a sense of belonging to quality schools that can provide protective environments for those who are &apos;at risk&apos; because of their dysfunctional early childhood experience.        The project will begin with a rapid evidence assessment (REA) and participatory focus group and individual interviews with purposefully selected policy officials, school and community leaders, and other stakeholders (including parents) to scope and assess the research evidence and policy reports over the last decade. The REA will identify new evidence in the key education, health and policy areas where intervention programmes have shown the potential of being most effective in enhancing children&apos;s achievement and health-related quality of life in the short, medium and long term; and the range of factors that influence these.         The results of the REA and interviews will inform the development of a systems-oriented, multi-layered intervention to strengthen the organisational and professional capacities of schools as enabling spaces for children&apos;s learning and development in socioeconomically disadvantaged rural communities. Multi-stakeholder, participatory and collaborative child (family)-school-community partnerships will be used to enhance the design and evaluation of the feasibility, applicability and sustainability of the interventions throughout the project.        A six-month pilot will be carried out in 18 rural primary schools in the province of Mpumalanga. Surveys and participatory ethnographic methods will be used with children and adults in schools and their communities to explore how variation in intervention tasks, organisational factors (especially school leadership, professional capacity of the staff, learning culture), and school and community contexts combines to create variability in outcomes (i.e. what seems to work, for whom, under what circumstance). The refined interventions will then be scaled up in an efficacy investigation in 58 rural primary schools (with 4,600+ children, 230+ teachers/school leaders) and their communities in Mpumalanga, North West and Limpopo. Similar evaluation methods will be used to assess the extent of change in schools&apos; organisational and professional capacities and how such change has impacted on children&apos;s learning and health outcomes.         By examining how schools may be(come) enabling spaces to promote whole-child quality education (SDG4), and through this, transform the health-related quality of life for children and adults (SDG3) in rural communities in South Africa, the research will make a timely contribution to understandings of how different sectors may work more effectively with schools to unlock the transformative power of education for the achievement of the other SDGs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">152425.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">306085.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">154904.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">154904.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-18">53474839.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T005149_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT005149%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
