<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N019245_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Triple-D Targets: The UK-Philippines Dengue Diagnostic and Drug Targets Research Consortium</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Dengue is the most important mosquito-borne disease of humans and is constantly spread in the Philippines, which has the 4th largest dengue disease burden of all Southeast Asian countries. Infection with dengue virus (DENV) causes a spectrum of clinical illnesses, ranging from dengue fever, a debilitating but self-limited condition to the more severe and potentially fatal dengue haemorrhagic fever. Dengue has a major impact on the health and economy of the Philippines as epidemics occur every 2-3 years. Over 500 000 confirmed cases occurred from 2008 - 2012 with &gt; 3000 deaths. Although most dengue cases could be managed at home, the lack of a diagnostic test to predict those individuals who progress from mild to severe disease forces patients and healthcare providers to seek hospital admissions for &quot;safety purposes&quot;, saturating an already overwhelmed healthcare system. The overall objective of this collaboration between academic institutes in the Philippines and the UK is to create a state-of-the-art infrastructure that that will allow better diagnosis of patients who develop severe disease after infection with DENV. In order to achieve our objective we will establish a very well characterised biobank of patient samples, collected from patients with different dengue disease outcomes as the disease progresses. We will use sophisticated methods to look at the strains of DENV that are circulating in the Philippines and also identify any changes in patient RNA or proteins which we can detect in blood that might be linked to serious disease associated with DENV infection. The methods will be both high throughput and very sensitive so that even changes in the abundance of low-level transcripts or proteins will be detected. We will also be able to detect the frequency of minor changes in the virus and investigate whether these may be linked to disease. This technology will be transferred to the Philippines so that they can monitor the virus infections, which are circulating in the country.  The results will produce large amounts of data that will be brought together using computational methods, either available or be developed by the Filipino and UK groups. The UK partners have particular experience with the bioinformatics tools needed and will provide these to their Filipino counterparts. These skills and those for detecting mutations in DENV will be transferred to the Philippines through short-term scientific exchange visits, regular real-time cyber-mentoring sessions as well as joint workshops throughout the project.  Computational analysis of the datasets will allow us to identify biomarkers in patients, which will be validated with additional samples. After validation, any biomarkers can then be used to develop diagnostic tests to predict those individuals at risk of progressing to severe disease and to monitor DENV variability and detect other infections associated with febrile disease. We will also identify cell pathways in infected patients which can be targeted with existing drugs, potentially to prevent severe disease. Overall, the project will significantly support the building of research capacity in the Philippines. Critically, the training and technology transfer provided by the UK partners will help to establish an adaptable technological framework that is also relevant to many other infectious disease areas in the Philippines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our OVERALL OBJECTIVE is to create a state-of-the-art framework and research infrastructure in the Philippines involving global, unbiased genomic and proteomic methods for the development of novel diagnostic platforms and the identification of druggable candidates to manage and prevent dengue and other diseases of concern.  To achieve our overall objective, we propose 3 parallel but closely integrated activities that are built within the collaborative framework and research infrastructure. These parallel activities will not only address a very relevant health problem in the Philippines but will also &quot;leap-frog&quot; the Philippine research capability in the field of dengue research. The core activities are: A) Research B) Training and C) Translation. Research:  Our main aim is to correlate dengue disease severity with changes in the host transcriptome and proteome, using blood and serum samples from dengue patients with well-defined clinical outcomes. We will also use novel next generation sequencing (NGS) approaches to identify viral quasi-species variations and potential co-infections that may be linked to severe dengue disease. These studies will generate rich datasets that identify candidate biomarkers for developing novel diagnostic platforms as well as druggable targets for future antiviral therapeutics. The project has 4 specific components: i. To undertake global unbiased metagenomic, transcriptomic and proteomic (&apos;omics) analysis of samples from patients with well characterised dengue  disease severities. ii. To develop a collaborative bioinformatic framework that integrates clinical and &apos;omics data. iii. To use the integrated datasets to identify candidate biomarkers for prognostic diagnosis of dengue severity and validate the biomarkers using clinical samples. iv. To use the &apos;omics analysis to define cellular pathways that are implicated in dengue pathogenesis to help identify novel drug targets.  Training: The research plan will be achieved using a series of interconnected work packages distributed between Filipino and UK researchers. The expertise of the researchers at the UoB and UoG in high-throughput &apos;omics along with any integrated bioinformatic analytical tools will be transferred to UPM through short-term scientific exchange visits, regular real-time cyber-mentoring sessions and joint workshops throughout the project. This will significantly support the Philippines&apos; research capacity enhancement program.  Critically, the training will help to establish an adaptable technological framework that is relevant to many other infectious disease areas in the Philippines. Translation:  There are 3 specific translational outcomes. First, diagnostic tests to identify early stage disease to facilitate clinical management of dengue. Second, a target enrichment method to monitor DENV variability and detect other infections associated with febrile disease.  And third, the identification of druggable cellular pathways that can be targeted to prevent dengue diseases. The outputs from our basic research will be discussed with the Research and Development offices of UPM, UoB and UoG to determine how our findings can best be exploited to benefit national health and wealth creation in the Philippines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">36451.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">144948.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">133698.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">80762.66</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-17">7521353.414</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N019245_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FN019245%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
