<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005796_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mitigating the cultural, social and organisational barriers for meeting the needs of patients with major limb loss (MLL) in Northern Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">As the world goes through one of the most turbulent periods in its recent history, the health, social &amp; economic consequences associated with &apos;post-conflict disability&apos; arising through major limb loss (MLL) has gained importance as a significant public health issue. Our preliminary observations and community engagement activities in two post-conflict societies - the Sub-Acholi Region in Northern Uganda and Northern/Eastern provinces in Sri Lanka, have demonstrated this to be an under-appreciated  complex and multi-faceted problem characterised by: a: Lack of suitable services capable of addressing the complex needs of the affected populations b:Inability of the affected population to access the existing services due to poor transport links, poverty and ignorance. c: Ad-hoc service development using non-sustainable funding sources at the time (or the immediate aftermath) of the conflict with inadequate characterisation of the needs of the local population. d: Social-cultural factors and belief systems that adversely affect the day-to-day experiences of the victims and prevent their reintegration into the society.  Influencing and engaging with future policy making in this field therefore requires an integrated approach involving multi-disciplinary teams.     This proposal aims to bring together the &apos;Humanitarian and Conflict Response Institute (HCRI)&apos; - an institution specialising in global health and &apos;In Place of War (IPOW)&apos;- an organisation with expertise in conducting cultural programmes in post conflict settings, to focus on the multi-faceted problem of disability associated with MLL in two post-conflict societies - Uganda and Sri Lanka. The project will link HCRI and IPOW with Gulu Medical Faculty (GMF)-established specifically to address the health needs of Northern Uganda, the &apos;Gulu Referral Orthopaedic Workshop (GROW)&apos; - the only centre providing prosthetic limb services in Gulu district in Northern Uganda, and &apos;Meththa Foundation UK&apos; (MF)-a charity that pioneered prosthetic services in post-war Sri Lanka using recycled components from the UK and an innovative outreach model for service delivery. The involvement of Geographical Information Scientists (GIS) from University of Manchester (UOM), surgeons/public health officials from Northern Uganda and the Uganda-UK Health Alliance (UUHA) - the official intergovernmental body with a mandate to create sustainable partnerships between the two countries, will strengthen the proposed network. Research output from this network will:  a. Evaluate the impact of arts and social theatre in challenging entrenched cultural views and bias associated with MLL b: Highlight the harm caused by ad-hoc service development in conflict environments c: Provide the forum, pilot data, policy options and critical appraisals of delivery systems in low-middle income countries to deal with the rising tide of MLL cost-effectively d: Fabricate and deliver 50 prosthetic limbs using an outreach service delivery model (successfully implemented in post-war Sri Lanka) and assess its suitability, acceptability and cost effectiveness in Northern Uganda.  The partnership will also create a quality assured environment where UK based professionals and students will be able to undertake short/long term volunteering and student placements with mutual benefits to both countries. The involvement of UUHA and Health Education England (HEE) as project partners creates a window of opportunity to champion the cause of disabled people in the region (and the UK) by influencing training, research, policy making and funding priorities. We submit that the policy documents, particularly those in relation to the feasibility/desirability of outreach prosthetic services in LMICs, will have wider applications in service planning in many other post-conflict societies in Asia, the Middle east, and Africa</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability due to major limb loss (MLL) is a complex and multi-faceted public health problem in many post conflict societies. We aim to bring together Ugandan and UK academics/health professionals/artists to address this problem, using Northern Uganda and Sri Lanka as examples of two societies emerging from major and &apos;bloody&apos; conflict.   Objectives:  A: Establish a network involving:     1. Humanitarian and Conflict Response Institute (HCRI): an academic unit at University of Manchester (UOM) with a track record in global health; 2. In place of war (IPOW): A cultural organisation at UOM involving a network of artists globally and specialising in using  creative arts and participatory theatre as vehicles for sustainable social change; 3. Gulu Medical Faculty (GMF) and Gulu Referral Orthopaedic Workshop (GROW): the only unit providing a prosthetic services in Northern Uganda; 4. &apos;Meththa Foundation&apos; (MF) UK - a charity with experience in running an outreach prosthetic service in post war Sri Lanka; 5. Public Health office in Gulu; 6. Faculty of Biology, Medicine and Health, UOM; 7. Geographical Information System (GIS) scientists from UOM and 8. Uganda-UK Health Alliance, the official inter-governmental body with a mandate to create sustainable health partnerships between Uganda and UK.     This partnership will:    B: Deliver a series of &apos;disability festivals&apos; and bespoke community focussed engagement programmes in Northern Uganda and in Kampala to raise the profile of MLL and challenge the adverse cultural attitudes to disability among the local population, health care providers, policy makers and other national/international agencies. C. Establish a high-impact &amp; quality assured professional environment where short and long term volunteering by multi-disciplinary UK professionals/ student electives may be undertaken to serve the needs of Northern Uganda and identify opportunities for future research/collaboration, particularly in areas related to low-cost prosthetic technology/materials.  D. Conduct a pilot study involving the fabrication and delivery of 50 prosthetic limbs using an outreach service model which has already been implemented successfully in Sri Lanka. The partnership will evaluate the suitability, feasibility, acceptability and sustainability of outreach prosthetic services in Northern Uganda and thereby influence policy making in this field by National and International agencies. E: Create digital maps and data sets of the entire Sub-Acholi region (7 districts) using Geographical Information Systems (GIS) and use this data to plan an outreach prosthetic service for the region with maximum coverage. The digital data will be made available through open access for other agencies/charities/research groups currently operating in the region   Deliverables and/or KPIs: 1. Qualitative surveys and stake-holder interviews evaluating the impact of art/social theatre on the attitudes towards disability among the local population and      policy makers. 2. A high impact survey determining the prevalence of MLL in Northern Uganda to aid future service planning 3. Systematic review of current prosthetic service delivery models in low and middle income countries and their sustainability.  4. Delivery of 50 prosthetic limbs using mobile out reach clinics to victims who have not had access to prosthetic services so far. 5. High impact policy documents evaluating the feasibility, acceptability and cost effectiveness of out reach prosthetic clinics in Northern Uganda. 6. Undertake a systematic health needs assessment among patients with MLL in Northern Uganda.  7. Number of UK volunteers/student placements offered through the partnership and a qualitative description of their contributions and experiences 8. Provide a temporary financial lifeline to GROW, until a more robust and sustainable service model is agreed with the Ministry Health Uganda, Health Education England and other International Donor</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-28">94128.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-28">47235.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-28">48801.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">94128.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005796_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">47235.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005796_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">48801.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005796_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">-73.1099999999997</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R005796_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
