<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S00047X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Big Picture:Adapting PhotoVoice to enhance psychological, social &amp; cultural insights into &amp; prevention &amp; treatment of youth substance use in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of the proposed research is to increase knowledge, enhance the voice of young people, and inform practice with respect to youth substance use in India. The research will be conducted in Assam, however will explore the potential transferability of our findings and methods to other Indian States. We will take a resilience approach in order to focus on, and learn from, young people&apos;s strengths. To do so we will develop an innovative form of &apos;PhotoVoice&apos;. PhotoVoice is an evolving method of inquiry which incorporates images - still and/or moving - created by the participants. We will invite participants to bring photographs/images to interview in order to help them convey their experience of risk, resilience (and recovery) with regard to substance use. We will then collaborate with them to design posters based on these photo-led interviews. An exhibition of these posters will act as inspiration for collaborative workshops with young people at risk of, or in recovery from, substance use to create short resilience-focused films. Exhibitions of the posters and films will form the basis of a public awareness and policy-directed campaign. Our overall goal is divided into three inter-related aims (what is to be accomplished) and associated objectives (tasks needed to accomplish the aims).  Aim 1 (Increase knowledge): To enhance psychological, social and cultural insights into the experience of risk, resilience and recovery with regard to youth substance use in Assam. Objective 1a: Develop an innovative adaptation of PhotoVoice for understanding risk, resilience and recovery with regard to youth substance use in Assam through active collaboration with (potential) service users and our service-delivery Partner Organisations. Objective 1b: Employ this adapted PhotoVoice method to generate insights into the experience of resilience-to-risk and resilience-for-recovery in purposely-sampled groups of young, Assamese people. Objective 1c: Explore the potential transferability of findings to other Indian States through our Partner Organisation networks and Advisory Group. Aim 2 (Enhance voice): To promote young Assamese people&apos;s voice with respect to substance use in order to reduce stigma, raise public awareness and inform mental- and public-health policy and practice. Objective 2a: Co-design and deliver - jointly with young Assamese people, our Partner Organisations and Advisory Group - a website with capacity for development providing: (a) guidance in PhotoVoice methods for research, health interventions, and awareness-raising; and (b) an aesthetically-rich, user-friendly environment to showcase PhotoVoice projects. Objective 2b: Develop and enhance understanding of research-to-policy and public awareness pathways through close engagement with policymakers, service delivery organisations, and our Advisory Group. Objective 2c: Co-design, deliver and evaluate a resilience-focused public awareness and policy-directed campaign with regard to youth substance use through close collaboration with young Assamese people, our Partner Organisations, and Advisory Group. Aim 3 (Inform practice): To learn if and how PhotoVoice can be adapted in culturally-sensitive ways to enhance local mental health services seeking to prevent and treat youth substance use in Assam. Objective 3a: Enhance local approaches to the prevention and treatment of youth substance use through establishing and maintaining dialogue with Partner Organisations to consider adaptation and utilisation of PhotoVoice. Objective 3b: Build preliminary, but sustainable, service and research capacity in the use of PhotoVoice in Partner Organisation through active collaboration. Objective 3c: Explore the potential transferability of adapted PhotoVoice methods to enhance the prevention and treatment of youth substance use in other Indian states through our Partner Organisation networks and Advisory Group.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project focuses on understanding the lived experience of young Indian people around risk, recovery and resilience in relation to substance use disorder (SUD). The goal is to increase knowledge, enhance the voice of young people, and inform practice through impacting policy and promoting public awareness. Our visual participatory method - PhotoVoice (PV) - centralises the lived experience of young people in efforts to understand, prevent and intervene - at both a service and policy level - in substance-use-related mental health difficulties in India. The research will be conducted in Assam and we will explore transferability to other Indian States. Global mental health strategies prioritise adolescents given their potential trajectory towards lifelong disadvantage. Poor mental health in young people is also a risk factor for SUD, and the Childline Foundation reports that 13% of people using substances in India are children. In the National Mental Health Survey of India 2015-16, Assam has the lowest prevalence of mental disorders so offering an opportunity to understand psychological, social and cultural resilience. Even so, in Assam stigma around mental health problems is high, the treatment gap immense, and The Assam Report of The India Survey classifies adolescent SUD as an urgent problem.  Our aims are to: -enhance psychological, social and cultural insights into the experience of risk, resilience and recovery with regard to youth substance use in Assam -promote young Assamese people&apos;s voice with respect to substance use in order to reduce stigma, raise public awareness and inform mental- and public-health policy and practice -learn if and how PV can be adapted in culturally-sensitive ways to enhance local mental health services seeking to prevent and treat youth substance use in Assam. We will conduct photo-led interviews with: (i) ~fifteen 15-18 year olds successfully refraining from substance use despite being at increased risk; and (ii) ~fifteen 19-24 year olds in successful recovery from SUD. These will be analysed using Thematic Analysis to explore protective and enabling factors around risk and recovery and will shed light on complex psychological, familial, social and cultural pathways to, and away from, SUD. Our innovation of PV is to extend it to participatory film-making. Hence, participants will be invited to make a poster of their photos to inspire ~6 short, resilience-focused films on the issues at stake and the changes they feel could best address them.  We will also explore how evidence informs mental health policy and practice in Assam. We will review key policy documents and conduct ~15 interviews with purposefully-sampled stakeholders. Material will be analysed using Framework Analysis. We will hold 3 stakeholder workshops to credibility check our assessment of conceptualisations, practices and research-policy pathways, and to help plan public awareness and policy-directed activities. In relation to potential applications and benefits we will: -launch a social media mental health photographic campaign to raise awareness and understanding of how young people manage risks around substance use in order to stay well; -strengthen research capacity through training staff in our Partner Organisations in the design, delivery and analysis of PV and support them drive implementation where it will improve services; -promote PV as a low-cost, easy-to-implement tool initially targeting prevention and treatment of SUD; -develop an ESRC-compliant, open-access, educational, and resource e-mental health website including easy-to-use, culturally sensitive guidance on how to deliver, analyse and evaluate PV mental health projects, through to flexible ways that outputs can inform service development; -engage with key decision-makers pan-India who are able to facilitate wider service and/or policy level implications of outputs and contribute to the development of an Assam State mental health policy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">92892.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">186538.42</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">188049.12</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">467480.524</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S00047X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FS00047X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
