<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_N021681_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of novel mesoporous silica nanoparticle sensing sprays for rapid field detection of foot-and-mouth disease (FMD)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Among the challenges agriculture and food production has to face in the future, is the long-term management of sustainable food production for the growing world population. A crucial factor in this respect is the control of diseases and improvement of animal health as a basis for safe, efficient, and high-quality production. The impact of disease on global animal production and thus food security are measured in the &#xA3;billions. Globalisation and climate change are driving the unprecedented increase of emerging and re-emerging animal diseases and zoonotics. Therefore improving animal health systems by providing tools to enable early detection and control of economically important global livestock diseases is the most effective response to this alarming situation. Foot-and-mouth disease (FMD) is a livestock disease of great economic importance, caused by the highly contagious foot-and-mouth disease virus (FMDV). The disease circulates in 77% of the global livestock population, costing ~between $5 -21 billion in production losses and control measures. The greatest overall economic loss by region is China totalling more than 2 billion USD, whereas the direct financial impacts as a result of production losses are greatest in Africa with an estimated loss of $815 million. Countries where FMD is endemic pose a great threat to disease free countries such as the UK for example the 2001 outbreak cost more than &#xA3;8bn to control. FMD results in these huge economic losses through production losses (producers, markets, slaughterhouses, food processors, and consumers), disease eradication losses (quarantine enforcement, euthanisation, disposal of carcases, compensation, disinfection) and trade losses (restriction of trade to FMD free countries). Routine laboratory tests are widely used for FMD diagnosis and although relatively quick, the speed of result reporting is confounded by the time delays associated with sending samples from the farm to the laboratory. These delays have direct impacts upon the quality of evidence that can be used to support immediate diagnostic decisions in the event of suspect cases of FMD. The lack of a quick test result is particularly important for suspect FMD cases in sheep and goats, since diagnosis based solely on clinical signs can be very challenging in these species.  These factors have driven the development of rapid tests which can be used in situ.  In fact, the use of such rapid diagnostic assays was recommended in major reports following the UK 2001 FMD outbreak. Simple pen-side diagnostics which can be deployed on farm to rapidly detect viral antigen have been developed in the form of lateral flow devices (LFD&apos;s) for detection of FMDV, however the sensitivity of these tests is less than that of molecular methods. Therefore, research was focused on transfering real-time rRT-PCR into the field, but with the cost of most platforms being expensive and the need for decontamination of the equipment, emphasis has shifted to alternative assays such as loop-mediated isothermal amplification (LAMP). However, at present LAMP still requires expensive reagents and equipment, multiple pipetting steps and a skilled operator to perform and interpret the test. Safe-guarding of animal health through prevention and control of animal diseases is therefore of paramount importance for sustainable food production and veterinary public health. This project will see the development and validation of the first &apos;diagnostic FMDV sensing spray&apos; which we anticipate can be applied non-invasively to the mouth, feet, nasal and teat area of animals suspected of displaying clinical signs of FMDV. Using an innovative approach a non-toxic dye which can be detected by the naked eye will be released from nanoparticles which only respond when they either come into contact with the whole FMDV virus or with enzymes released by the virus.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our overarching aim is to develop the first mesoporous silica nanoparticle (MSNs) detection platform for non-invasive, non-toxic, rapid and simple field detection of livestock pathogens. Using foot-and-mouth disease virus (FMDV) as the pathogen, we will exploit newly developed diagnostic reagents combined with next innovative MSNs, to create diagnostic platforms which can respond to the presence of target FMDV or FMDV proteases by releasing a visual sensing agent.  Objective 1: To confirm the diagnostic potential of FMDV 3Cpro and Lpro within cattle epithelial suspensions. The diagnostic potential of 3Cpro and Lpro has already been demonstrated in principle by the detection of protease activity in samples of recombinant protease and in virus infected cell lysates. The next step in developing a non-invasive diagnostic sensing system is to apply these early findings to real clinical samples and to confirm specificity of this activity. Archival cattle epithelial suspensions will be diluted and used to determine the correlation between the titre (TCID50 or PFU) of FMDV and the Lpro/3Cpro activity (measured by cleavage of recombinant firefly luciferase assay). Archival clinical samples (epithelium, nasal, saliva and milk) will then be used to define the diagnostic window, including assessment of the potential for preclinical diagnosis (milk) for which Lpro and 3Cpro can be used. In addition specificity assays will be conducted to determine any cross-reaction between proteases from related viruses such as bovine rhinitis (BRV) A and B viruses. Objective 2: To determine the diagnostic potential of modified mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) to detect FMDV. It has already been show that it is possible to create dye-loaded MSNs, which can be used as sensing systems upon contact with a specific target. This technology has however not yet been applied to creating non-invasive diagnostic solutions for rapid diagnosis of livestock diseases. Within this objective we will translate the findings of our previous research and obj. 1 and generate dye-loaded MSNs for detection of FMDV. Three innovative MSN&apos;s sensing platforms will be developed. The first and second MSN platforms will involve capping of the MSN pores (to prevent dye release) with peptide sequences representing the target sites of type O FMDV 3Cpro and Lpro respectively. In the presence of either 3Cpro or Lpro the peptide sequence will be cleaved and the dye released. The third platform will involve capping the MSN pores with Mab D9. This antibody will be linked to the MSNs by using a modified peptide (with reduced avidity) sequence representing the VP1 G-H loop as a linker attached on the nanoparticle surface. This loop forms the epitope of D9 and will be deliberately modified to have sub-optimal binding. As a result of an expected higher avidity of D9 for FMDV, the release of the MAb upon contact with the intact FMDV particles will result in the internal dye being released. Each platform will be characterised using standard techniques including dynamic light scattering-zeta potential measurements, thermogravimetric analysis and in vitro assessment of dye release.  The above analysis will determine the efficiency of capping and confirm the structure of the modified MSNs. In vitro dye release analysis will involve determining the kinetics of dose-response for naked eye result calling, sensitivity (antigen or protease conc. required for maximum dye release), specificity (cross-reactivity with related viruses-BRV A and B) and stability (temperature, pH and time) analysis. In light of this a range of dyes (including fluorophores if required) will be assessed. Results will be compared against the OIE gold standard rRT-PCR assay and also the luciferase Assay. Objective 3: To evaluation the diagnostic performance of formulated MSNs using clinical samples. The winning MSN platform will be formulated into suitable non-toxic spray and validated using the clinical samples from Obj. 1.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-05" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-04" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-05-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-12">152435.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF Standard Grant Award to The Pirbright Institute</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB/N021681/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Pirbright Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">25337.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_N021681_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Pirbright Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">25337.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_N021681_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Pirbright Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">25337.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_N021681_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Pirbright Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">25542.81</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_N021681_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Pirbright Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">23670.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_N021681_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Pirbright Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FN021681%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-09-05"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
