<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_V003755_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Fertile Land From Fertile Seas</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1 Evaluate seaweed life stage &amp; degradation status to determine if/how biomass input quality effects output product quality &amp; composition 2 Determine optimal processing parameters for effective sub-critical water processing of seaweeds 3 Test the most suitable fertiliser products through industrial plant trials 4 Identify the most suitable fertiliser fractions for formulation and the most suitable target crops 5 Determine population dynamics and best practice for commercially utilized non-invasive Macrocystis 6 Evaluate the feasibility of the process through TEA and LCA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of Mexico&apos;s most important sources of employment and revenue, and the world&apos;s second largest coral reef chain, are under threat from constant bombardment by invasive seaweed. According to the World Travel &amp; Tourism Council (WTTC), in 2018 tourism contributed 17.2% of the country&apos;s GDP (GDP 2018=$1,223B) and &gt;9 million jobs (17% of all jobs in the country). About half of Mexico&apos;s tourism income and jobs are generated in its Caribbean coast, where a record-breaking 550km-long mass of rotting Sargassum biomass is currently heading. The impact is estimated to be a 30% decrease in tourism revenue in affected areas. This project will take Sargassum and Macrocystis from Mexico&apos;s Caribbean and Pacific coastlines, respectively, and evaluate methods for subcritical water processing leading to production of liquid and solid fertiliser products which meet the requirements necessary for commercialisation. We will evaluate the economics and sustainability of producing such fertilisers from invasive and non-invasive macroalgae. The project&apos;s interdisciplinary consortium incorporates UK and Mexico biological, ecosystem management and chemical engineering expertise. Our previous Newton funded project successfully developed a microalgae-based biostimulant product, enabling more sustainable crop growth enhancement for Mexico&apos;s growing agricultural industry. This new project takes much of these learnings and expertise (product testing, optimisation and development) and applies them to solving Mexico&apos;s macroalgae (seaweed) problem. We will develop a process that removes the damaging seaweed build up and transforms a highly costly problem into a valuable and sustainable agricultural product. This will have a significant positive impact for Mexico&apos;s important tourism industry and its marine ecosystem. Furthermore, this technology will help develop Mexico&apos;s still small but established macroalgae industry and provide important information to inform industry policies and regulations. The overall aim of this project is to test the feasibility of using sub-critical water processing methods in the conversion of Mexico&apos;s problematic seaweed bloom biomass to agricultural fertiliser and assess the sustainability of production using invasive and non-invasive macroalgae. We aim to market test fertiliser products within 18 months, with full commercial deployment within 3 years.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-11-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-11-25">199759.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton UKRI Award to Plymouth Marine Laboratory</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/V003755/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Plymouth Marine Laboratory</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FV003755%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
