<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T017708_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Obesity and non-communicable disease in Malaysia: an imaging study of 6000 adults in the Malaysian Cohort Study</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Excess body fat is a major cause of diabetes, heart attacks and strokes, worldwide. Body-mass index (BMI; defined as weight in kilograms divided by height in meters squared) is the basis of the World Health Organisation&apos;s definition of overweight and obesity, with a BMI of between 25 and 30 kg/m2 classified as overweight, and over 30 kg/m2 as obese. However, there is increasing evidence that levels of body fat for a given BMI may vary between populations, raising questions regarding universally applied BMI-based guidelines for overweight and obesity. Although BMI is frequently used in Malaysia to assess excess body fat, there have been no large-scale imaging studies with direct measurements of body fat and its distribution which would allow us to understand better the relationship between body composition and disease outcomes in this population.  From 2006-2012, The Malaysia Cohort study - initiated by the Malaysian government - recruited 106,527 adults aged 35 years or over. Participants completed a lifestyle questionnaire, underwent physical measurements, provided a blood sample and are now being followed for health events. In 6000 of The Malaysia Cohort participants, we will conduct whole-body Dual-energy X-ray Absorptiometry (DXA) imaging (which provides data on body fat distribution in addition to body fat percentage) using protocols established by the UK Biobank (a large cohort study co-ordinated by the Nuffield Department of Population Health, University of Oxford). This imaging sub-study will significantly enhance this national biomedical resource. Using DXA imaging, this study will reliably assess the relationship between conventional measures for estimating body composition (including BMI, waist circumference and waist-hip ratio) with the absolute regional fat masses derived from the DXA measurements in the Malaysian population. It will then assess the relationship between these measures and risk of diabetes and cardiovascular disease, to inform public health guidance on the appropriate measure of excess body fat in this population, the ideal &apos;normal&apos; range of these measures, and whether guidance should vary for the different ethnic groups in Malaysia. DXA imaging will also significantly enhance the potential of The Malaysia Cohort to investigate the genetic and environmental determinants of obesity in Malaysia, and the biological pathways through which it causes diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Not all people who are overweight or obese suffer adverse consequence from their excess weight, in part due to differences in fat distribution. Indeed, as recently reported from The Malaysia Cohort, the prevalence of obesity (based on BMI) and type 2 diabetes is very divergent between the major ethnic groups in Malaysia (Malay, Indian and Chinese) and this is only partly explained by BMI. Therefore, a better understanding of the between-ethnic group risk, based on tissue and organ-specific fat depots, will enable more precise targeting of limited resources to those who will gain the most benefit.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project has 5 main objectives: 1. Understanding the relevance of obesity as a cause of diabetes and cardiovascular disease in Malaysia: To date, there have been no large-scale imaging studies conducted to comprehensively elucidate the importance of adiposity or body composition to non-communicable diseases (NCDs) in the Malaysian population. This study will scan 6000 participants of The Malaysia Cohort Study using Dual-energy X-ray Absorptiometry (DXA) imaging scans to directly quantify body fat and its distribution in this population. These findings will then be used to describe the relationships between body composition and risk of diabetes and cardiovascular disease, and estimate the burden of these diseases that is attributable to excess adiposity in this population. 2. Understanding ethnic differences in body composition in Malaysia: The burden of diabetes and cardiovascular in the Malaysian population differs by ethnic group, and it has been hypothesised that such differences are the result in part of intrinsic differences in body composition. However, there have been few large-scale imaging studies outside of Europe and North America. This study will describe the detailed anthropometric characteristics in the major ethnic groups in Malaysia using DXA imaging, and assess whether these differences account for differences in risk of diabetes and cardiovascular disease between these different populations. 3. Comparing the validity of conventional instruments for estimating body composition (weight, height, waist and hip circumference) with DXA-derived measurements in Malaysian populations: Previous studies of the relation between adiposity and risk of diabetes and cardiovascular disease have mostly used indirect measures of adiposity, such as body-mass index (BMI), waist circumference or waist-to-hip ratio. However, the validity of using these measures in different population around the world has not been established. Measures of body composition that directly quantify body fat and its distribution (such as DXA imaging) can be used to assess the validity (or otherwise) of conventional instruments of body composition in this population. 4. Enable comparative studies between Malaysia and the UK: Complementary analyses will be conducted in Malaysia and in two large-scale imaging studies in the UK with comparable DXA-derived measurements: the UK Biobank (which to date will have scanned about 20,000 participants with the aim of reaching 100,000 by 2022) and the Oxford Biobank (with about 6000 participants scanned). These analyses will enable comparisons between the diverse study populations, and will overall enhance the assessment in Malaysia and the generalisability of findings from both Malaysian and UK studies. 5. Establishing a shared resource and strengthening research capacity in both countries: This imaging study will significantly enhance The Malaysian Cohort Study. This cohort was initiated by the Malaysian government and will be a focal point of biomedical research and investment over the coming decade or more.  As detailed in the &apos;Academic beneficiaries&apos; section, funding would also enhance research collaboration between the UK and Malaysia, especially the training of young scientists and the development of research capacity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">22239.34</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">66898.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">22419.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">3751339.032</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T017708_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT017708%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
