<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015090_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Partnership for a cross-disciplinary approach to the ecology of antimicrobial drug resistance in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antibacterial resistance (ABR) is a significant threat to the future of effective healthcare and veterinary care.  Globally, we are dependent on antibiotics for treating common as well as severe infections, but we abuse the value of these compounds by using them irrationally.  In Kenya, as in many other countries, antibiotics are prescribed un-necessarily and without properly identifying the micro-organims being targeted, a fact that often leads to treatment failures.  In agriculture, antibiotics are often used directly by farmers, as they are readily available on the market without prescription.  Kenya is a country undergoing a demographic transition towards urbanisation, with over half the population expected to be in urban zones by the middle of this century.  Many of these people are likely to live in low income settlements (eg 60% of residents of Nairobi, the capital, live in low income settlements = slums).  Provision of high quality heath care is lacking in such sites.  Further, with more people living in towns and cities, the pressure will be on farmers to produce more food more efficiently, and a key part of this - as has been the case in more developed economies - will be to use antibiotic drugs.  These factors combine to produce a great deal of risk for highly drug resistant micro-organisms to emerge.  Essential in preventing this will be to collect high quality data in hospitals and on farms, to understand what levels of resistance are present now, and how the organisms share their genes, a process that can result in rapid spread of resistant traits. A key aspects of this is also to understand how antibacterial drugs are used in practice, how they are procured and what drives individual and collective decision making about their use.  Our programme will investigate these different aspects and work with partners in Kenya and internationally who make policy, in order to develop long term surveillance tools, plans to limit the spread of resistance and advice to the public to conserve these important drugs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will lay the foundations for an investigation of the biology, ecology, economics and sociology of antimicrobial resistance in bacteria in urbanising Kenya though an interdisciplinary approach.  The Development phase award will create an opportunity to collect pilot data and formalise a research programme with a multi-disciplinary team, bringing the best of UK and Kenyan science together.  The Consortium award will: 1) Undertake surveillance in health care settings including both longitudinal studies of patients and in care and cross sectional studies of outpatients 2) Undertake community based longitudinal monitoring of antibacterial resistance in livestock producers linked to clinical cohorts 3) Undertake ecological studies of microbiological dynamics within households keeping livestock 4) Deploy significant microbiological and whole genome sequencing capacity within a strong partnership of research and diagnostic laboratories in Kenya, as well as in both public and private sector hospitals 5) Investigate human behaviour and decision-making vis-&#xE0;-vis use and misuse of antibacterial compounds 6) Support the Government of Kenya in developing evidence based policy for controlling the development of antibacterial resistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-03">47943.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-03">86754.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R015090/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">47943.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015090_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">38811.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015090_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR015090%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
