<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006224_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A multicomponent intervention to reduce home-exposure to second-hand smoke (SHS) during pregnancy and postnatal period: a randomised controlled trial</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Asia has one of the highest numbers of male smokers anywhere in the world. As a result, over a third of pregnant women in South Asia are exposed to second-hand smoke in their homes. This has serious health consequences for both mothers (such as increased heart- and lung-related illnesses) as well as the newborn (higher chances of stillbirth, being born prematurely and lung-related illnesses). On the other hand, the antenatal period provides a window of opportunity to change health-related behaviours in the entire family. Interventions that are effective in reducing the exposure of pregnant women to second-hand smoke have been tried successfully in richer countries but have not been adapted for large-scale implementation in lower and middle-income countries.   Our proposed project addresses this gap in two such countries - urban Bangalore, India and peri-urban Comilla, Bangladesh. The sites are situated in a region with the greatest burden of disease from the effects of second-hand smoke globally. The project has two broad aims: The first is to adapt existing knowledge about what is known to work, into an acceptable and feasible intervention that can be delivered to the woman and her family members. This may include informing the woman and her family about the levels of second-hand smoke in her body measured by a simple test on her saliva; educating the whole family about the harmful effects of second-hand smoke on the mother and baby; and using &apos;communication-techniques&apos; from the field of psychology and behavioural sciences to encourage husband and other family members to change the habit of smoking in the pregnant mother&apos;s presence. The second aim is to apply scientific methods to test the effectiveness of this intervention in reducing the exposure of pregnant women and newborn to second-hand smoke in both sites, and to determine the costs versus benefits of implementing such an intervention.   The project will be undertaken in two phases. In Phase 1 (Development Phase: Months 0-12), we will interview pregnant women, their husbands, and other family members to gain an in-depth understanding of all the issues surrounding the problem of second-hand smoke in the household, including barriers we may face in trying to change this. We will use this information to develop an intervention that can overcome these barriers in an acceptable way. During this phase, we will also help our Indian and Bangladeshi counterparts gain the expertise needed to develop such interventions, and in scientific methods to test them. In Phase 2 (Trial Phase - Months 13-36), we will conduct a strict scientific experiment (called a randomized controlled trial) to compare our new intervention with education about second-hand smoke through a leaflet. We will identify 920 mothers in early pregnancy, who are exposed to second hand smoke at home (460 at each site), to receive either the intervention or only the educational leaflet. This will be done in a way that each woman has an equal chance of being in either group. We will collect information on all these mothers and families when we recruit them into our study and then in late-pregnancy, 3 months after both groups have received either of the two interventions. We will also collect information when the new baby is born, and then 3 months after his/her birth. The information collected will include how the pregnancy and birth fared; levels of second-hand smoke in the mothers&apos; and infants&apos; body through a test on their saliva; health of both mother and baby, and smoking behaviours of family members. We will compare the information collected in the two groups to see how well the intervention did. We will also collect more detailed information from some families to understand how the intervention worked (or failed to work, in some cases).   The findings from the study will be shared with key academic, policy and community stakeholders throughout the duration of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The broad aims of the study are to culturally adapt, and then evaluate for effectiveness and cost-effectiveness, evidence-based strategies to reduce second-hand smoking in the home environment in urban Bangalore, India and periurban Comilla, Bangladesh.   The study is delivered in two phases with the following objectives:  Phase 1 (Development Phase: Months 0-12)  a) To explore key family members&apos; knowledge, attitudes and practices (including positives practices) that promote (or inhibit) SHS exposure at home. b) To explore the best format, delivery platform, setting and integration strategies for the components of the intervention aimed at the various target recipients         (sequence of delivery; number of sessions and dosage of intervention; group vs. individual; face-to-face vs mobile phone). c) Using the data from (a) and (b) above, to culturally adapt motivational-enhancement and cognitive behavioural therapy (CBT)-based strategies that can assist in bringing about behaviour change at the maternal, paternal and family-levels. d) To develop manualised training and delivery procedures for the intervention. e) To conduct a pilot study of the intervention. f) To adapt measurement protocols, along with relevant training to allow us to measure key outcomes in the Phase 2 trial. g) To build capacity in partner institutions to conduct formative research to develop and pilot complex interventions.  h) Prepare a report of our findings for the MRC and DBT. i) Prepare a detailed protocol for the Randomised Controlled Trial (Phase 2).   Phase 2 (Trial Phase: Months 13-36) a) To compare the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of the multicomponent intervention with standard health education, using a two-site, two-arm single-blinded randomised controlled trial (RCT), in reducing SHS exposure in the perinatal period. b) Build capacity in partner institutions to conduct randomised controlled trials of complex interventions. c) To prepare a report and scientific publications, disseminate findings through local and regional workshop(s) to influence policy and practice.  The project is of direct relevance to this call as a) it aims to develop a generalizable intervention to address a major and unaddressed public health hazard to the health of mothers and infants; b) it explores innovative ways to reach low-resourced and under-served populations; and c) has the potential for being scalable and sustainable in such settings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-07-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-09-21">110660.34</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-09-21">138493.89</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-09-21">295563.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N006224/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-10-01">27664.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006224_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-01">27664.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006224_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">23021.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006224_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-01">23021.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006224_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">23204.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006224_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">23204.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N006224_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000660">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN006224%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
