<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_P026206_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Fund: Enhanced Rice Milling and Maximised Valorisation of Rice Milling By-products</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Achieving optimal efficiency in the post harvest handling and processing of rice is a ubiquitous challenge for India&apos;s agri-food sector. Rice is the staple food of 65% of the population and India is the world&apos;s 2nd largest producer, accounting for 103 MT p/a and exporting 12MT of this. On average, head rice return in post production handling is a low 50% of the paddy weight, with 50% of waste by-products consisting of rice brokens, husk hulls and bran that aren&apos;t utilised. Current processes for separation are energy intensive and abrasive. Conventional mills are traditionally low capacity units handling 300-500kg/h of paddy, with an est.125,000 of these mills across India, operating at 50-60% efficiency rates.  The project aims are twofold: (i) develop a lower energy milling process that will reduce rice brokens from 28% to 8% and increase total rice output by 7% and 12% for modern and traditional mills respectively, resulting in an additional 10.6MT of rice p/a nationally, with total energy savings of 2.57BT p/a; (ii) optimise by-products -process rice bran into nutritious food ingredients (7.72MT of additional food) and process rice husks into rice husk ash (5MT) for building materials.  Rice production generates high levels of waste in straw, bran and husk which go to animal feed or waste. This project will address (a) post-harvest handling and processing  by developing a post harvesting and rice milling solution that (i) reduces loss of food grain in the supply chain resulting in an optimal 12% increase in high quality rice output for national consumption and export ; (ii) reduces post harvest spoilage by 10%, by controlling the humidity of the rice prior to milling (iii) develops a new modern processing technology that is suitable for and accessible (in size and cost) to small scale local and regional milling facilities that will reduce broken rice waste from 28% to 8%; (iv) reduces overall energy consumption and costs per plant by 80% per annum; (b) Process technologies to enable new products from waste by (i) enabling millers to add value by processing the currently wasted by-products from the process into re-usable raw materials and saleable commodities (ii) recycling rice bran into highly nutritious protein and carbohydrate based food products (iii) promoting the use of rice husk ash (RHA) for the Indian construction industry by improving the rice combustion process and developing RHA based cementitious (concrete and alkali activated) materials. The challenge is to develop a novel, energy efficient, low abrasion, commercial milling and separation process that increases rice harvest yield, and minimises energy consumption and food waste in small batch production, which enables the capture of waste streams suitable for further processing to produce nutritional products and sustainable construction materials.  The output will be a blueprint (system optimisation, business models and training) for implementation to be piloted in the Punjab. Dissemination is via well-established commercial, academic and national networks in India.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UK project team has engineering innovators and manufacturers at Koolmill and KMF, rice processors and traders at East End Foods, microwave designers at Process Technologies and food scientists at Marlow Foods and New Food Innovation group. These companies will be supported by academics at NCEFE (Sheffield Hallam University) developing bran processing and investigation and evaluation of rice husk ash production and application, testing and exploitation in India. The Indian project team has a rice equipment manufacturer and distributor Vishavkarma Machine Tools, rice processor Rajdhani Rice and Kuantum Papers Ltd who will process the rice husks. The team is supported by research institutions IIT Roorkee who will project manage the Indian team and lead the work on rice husk ash utilisation. Punjab Agricultural University and NABI-CIAB will investigate the valorisation and processing of the rice bran. Project description - WP 1 focusses on Project Management of the consortium and delivery of each of the work packages. WP2 Rice milling: Developing the technology to make a step change in rice milling capability. Koolmill will develop new milling capability in cooperation with KMF, NCEFE and East End Foods to significantly enhance rice milling capability and demonstrate the capability of the new process with respect to conventional mills. The technology will be evaluated  for implementation in India by Vishavkarma Machine Tools and Rajdhani Rice supported by technical expertise at Punjab Agriculture University. Additional investigations will be conducted by Process Technologies to identify  microwave technology to provide high efficiency drying of the rice paddy and bran stabilisation prior to processing. Koolmill will develop enhanced control of bran removal to support the bran exploitation route. Working with KMF, NCEFE and Punjab Agriculture University, Koolmill will investigate the quality standards resulting from the enhanced processes as well as the financial models for the utilisation of the technology in the Indian market. WP3 Bran processing: This work package provides new value and new food products from the rice crop. The WP will research, test and evaluate extraction techniques for proteins and carbohydrates from the rice bran. The initial work will integrate appropriate technology to stabilize the bran. This will be followed by technical development of extraction processes by NCEFE, NABI-CIAB and Marlow Foods. This team will then further exploit these materials into new food products with the additional input by New Food Innovation. WP4 Rice husk ash: An investigation and development of technologies to extract and utilise materials from rice husk ash to exploit in building products. Extending previous work, NCEFE and IIT Roorkee will work with Kuantum Paper Mill and the rice milling operator Rajdhani Rice to refine the capability of burning below 850 degC and gasification of rice husk to produce  a safe and reactive amorphous ash for incorporation into building materials (concrete and alkali activated cementitious materials) and products. The alkali activated materials (geopolymers) will not use high CO2 generating Portland cement. WP5 Evaluation of system performance: Working closely with the industrial partners in the UK and India, NCEFE, NABI-CIAB, Punjab Agriculture University and IIT Roorkee will provide access to technical resources that will evaluate the economics, energy consumption efficiency and technical capability of the project&apos;s investigations and equipment development in the three main project areas of rice milling capability, bran removal and rice husk ash extraction and utilisation in building materials. WP6 Knowledge Transfer and Dissemination: This activity disseminates the project outcomes, identifies IP exploitation and supports training and education for rice producers and millers in India through national networks and reports the key outcomes from the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sheffield Hallam University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-14">161221.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-14">121895.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-14">323749.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to Sheffield Hallam University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP/P026206/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sheffield Hallam University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FP026206%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-03-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
