<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluating the role of fiscal policy in improving diets and preventing chronic disease in Chile: impact evaluation and modelling</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chronic diseases (e.g. stroke, heart diseases, and diabetes) - often driven by unhealthy diets - account for a fast growing share of mortality and morbidity in developing countries. They impose not only a disease but also a substantial economic burden to the countries concerned. Chile is facing an enormous challenge to curb rising rates of obesity and diet-related ill-health. Much of this disease burden is affecting the poor more than the rich within Chile. Making healthier choices more affordable - and unhealthier options more expensive - might appear as a promising option to tackle the problem. After all, using price incentives has been shown to work very effectively in the efforts to reduce tobacco and alcohol consumption, where tax policies have long been applied. Yet when it comes to using economic incentives to promote healthier diet choices, we are so far left with preciously little, convincing evidence on whether such tax or subsidy policies would in fact have the desired results. This is because the bulk of the &quot;evidence&quot; is based on hypothetical modelling of such policies, rather than on the evaluation of actual examples of cases where they have been implemented in the real world. Chile is one out of a handful of countries world-wide that have now - in September 2014 - implemented a price incentive for healthier diets. More specifically, the Chilean Government has increased the excise tax on sugar sweetened beverages (SSBs), while reducing the tax on what it considers as non-SSBs. This is a great and extremely rare opportunity to first of all evaluate whether this policy has worked over a comparatively short period of time (1 year). Conducting such an evaluation is challenging and requires the use of methods that produce credible impact evidence, even though the policy has not been implemented as a randomised experiment (which is what would have happened if evaluating the effectiveness of a new drug). This is the case in many areas of public health, however, and there are methods out there that have been, and can be, applied. The other challenge is that suitable data is not readily at hand in many countries, including in Chile, to conduct such an analysis. There is, however, high quality, detailed household purchasing data routinely collected by certain commercial market research companies, and we strongly believe this is the only data that currently allows us to assess the policy impact. Such data is exceptionally fine-grained, providing information on essentially all take-home purchases of beverages made by a nationally representative set of households over several years before and after the Chilean policy entered into force. Once we have evaluated whether the policy has &apos;worked&apos;, in terms of reducing unhealthy beverage purchasing, we then also want to know whether this short term effect translates into meaningful longer term health effects. This can only be done via complex modelling of the longer term consequences, and the team has the expertise and track record to develop such models. In addition, the Chilean Government is keen to explore further refinements to this policy. In order to directly inform such deliberations, we will use our model to also analyse a range of related tax or subsidy policies, again aimed at promoting healthier diets, which appear at least promising on the basis of existing evidence. We have established a suitable, two-way communication channel with the senior policymakers in the Ministry of Health that will help ensure that the kind of evidence we produce will answer to the knowledge needs of the Government, without unduly interfering with the research.  Overall, this research will contribute vital evidence not only to the Chilean government but also to many other low- and middle-income countries also facing the challenge of diet-related ill health and eager to understand the actual scope for fiscal policies in the promotion of healthier diets and the prevention of chronic diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project pursues three overarching objectives:  1) To evaluate the short term effects of the tax policy implemented in Chile:  since September 2014, the Chilean Government has increased the tax on sugar sweetened beverages (SSB) - defined as those containing at least 6.25 grams of carbohydrates per 100ml or higher - from 13% to 18%, while at the same time reducing the tax on beverages below this threshold from 13% to 10%.  Using fine-grained, commercial household purchasing data for a representative sample of the Chilean population, we will employ a range of quasi-experimental, empirical methods to assess the impact of the policy over a post-intervention period of one year, in terms of household purchases of healthier vs less healthy beverages.  We will assess the average population level effect as well as the effects across different socioeconomic groups.   2)  To model the mid- and longer-term effects of the SSB tax policy: building on the short-term impact estimates of purchases, we aim to develop a mathematical epidemiological model to simulate the medium and longer term health consequences of the policy, as well as its consequences in terms of both direct health care cost and indirect costs, i.e. labour market productivity.   3)  To model the mid- and longer-term effects of additional fiscal policy scenarios, in order to directly inform the further development of the policy by the Chilean Government: using the epidemiological model, we aim to simulate the expected medium and long term consequences and costs of a set of policies that appear promising on the basis of the existing literature, some of which are currently considered by the Chilean Government (e.g. increasing the tax on high sugar content, solid foods) as potential further revisions of and additions to the recently implemented policy.   4) To effectively contribute to capacity building in this research area, via active dissemination and communication of the methods, tools and results through a range of channels: in order to maximise the research impacts to academics, policy makers and wider public audiences, we will set up a series of dissemination activities, including publication as research articles, a non-technical policy report, as well as capacity building and dissemination workshops in Santiago. Moreover, while it is beyond the scope of the project to model all conceivably relevant policy interventions to address diet-related health issues in Chile, the epidemiological model will be made available for others to freely access and use (in consultation with the present research team).  In this sense we will produce a public good, providing a tool that will allow the researchers and interested policymakers in the future to analyse the consequences and costs of additional policy options, or variations of the ones that will already be analysed as part of this project.  The model will be sufficiently flexible and transparent to accommodate changes to its structure and input parameters.    Through its empirical evaluation of one of extremely few cases worldwide of an actual tax policy reform aimed at improving diet, combined with the modelling of its long term consequences as well as the evaluation of potential expansions of or additions to these fiscal policies, the proposed research has the potential to not only inform policy decisions within Chile, but also in many other low- and middle-income countries facing similarly growing burdens of diet-related morbidity, mortality and associated economic costs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chile</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-21">329211.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N026640/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-01">29880</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">29880.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-01">29880.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">29880.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">30122.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">30122.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">30122.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">30122.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">30366.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">30366.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N026640_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN026640%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
