<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_M007693_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Radio Astronomy for Development in Africa - A Newton Fund Project</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- Provide a basic training in radio astronomy to ten trainees per year in Zambia, Kenya and Namibia to enable them to use the 30 m radio antenna in these countries that will form the African VLBI Network. The STEM skills they learn will also enable them to drive economic development in a variety of industries such as telecommunications, space science, computing and big data.  - Provide advanced MSc and PhD training to a small number of students from SA and the targeted AVN countries to enable them to carry out research using the AVN. Those who complete PhDs will be able to form the foundation of radio astronomy groups in their countries which will then encourage more take up of advanced STEM subjects and subsequent economic development.  - Build a sustainable network of African radio astronomers who can collaborate with each other and utilize the AVN. They will also build links with both UK and SA experts in the fields of radio astronomy and related industrial fields that will lead to a sustainable collaborative network.  - Construct a virtual centre of excellence - the Centre for African Radio Astronomy - that will act as a repository for training materials, a contact database for academics and industrial partners, and a place for entrepreneurs and business ideas to develop.  - Conduct an outreach programme in schools and engaging the wider public in the targeted AVN countries to encourage take up of STEM subjects at school and university. This will use the inspirational nature of astronomy and the location of world class radio astronomy facilities in these countries as a springboard for growth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will conduct a training programme in radio astronomy in Africa that will help to drive economic growth. South Africa will host part of the Square Kilometre Array (SKA) - the major next generation radio telescope. A network of up to 3000 dishes will eventually spread out across southern Africa to give the telescope its powerful resolution to see small structures in the sky. To this aim South Africa is partnering with eight other countries in Africa that will host these outstations. However, there is virtually no astronomy activity in these countries at present and so SKA-SA are building the African VLBI Network (AVN) as a precursor instrument and very useful addition to the world&apos;s radio astronomy networks in its own right. The AVN will consist of 30 m class radio dishes in each partner country, either converted from defunct telecommunications dishes or newly built ones. This project targets Zambia, Kenya and Namibia that are next in line to obtain their dishes once the first one in Ghana is up and running. The UK team has experience of training radio astronomers in Ghana and in the conversion of old telecommunications dishes for radio astronomy purposes.   The UK team, together with SA colleagues will provide a basic training in the targeted countries so that the local people can use and help run the radio telescopes there. The STEM skills learnt as part of this training can be applied to a range of industries such as telecommunications, space science, land management, computing and big data. Therefore the training will result in a pool of local talent who can help to drive economic growth in the targeted countries. An integral part of the training programme will be interaction with entrepreneurs who have experience of setting up businesses using related technologies and with those who are using their expertise in big data to solve modern day challenges. Advanced training will take the form of a small number of MSc and PhD bursaries. The students will undertake research training using the AVN telescopes and spend time in both the UK and SA to help forge strong research links. A virtual centre of excellence will be established that pulls the various strands of training, research and industry together.  Working together with colleagues from the IAU&apos;s Office of Astronomy for Development in Cape Town and their regional offices in Africa we will conduct an outreach programme to increase the take up of STEM subjects at school level. Awareness events for school children and teachers by the visiting UK academics and the trainees themselves will take the inspirational subject of astronomy and mankind&apos;s origins into many locations in the targeted countries. Showcasing the radio astronomy facilities in these countries and demonstrating how the skills and technologies used in radio astronomy can be applied to many areas of industry and commerce can lead to a general upskilling of the population.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-06">50405</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-06">501218.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-06">232038.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-06">25612.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-06">25612.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
