<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M017990_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pilot study: a cluster randomised trial of the provision of alcohol handgel to postpartum mothers to prevent neonatal infective morbidity in the home</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The research question is &quot;Is the provision of alcohol hand gel to pregnant women in rural Uganda a clinically and cost-effective way of preventing early infant infections?&quot;. To provide context to this question across the globe, there are an estimated 3 million neonatal deaths annually. In Uganda, with over 1.5 million live births annually, 142,000 newborn infants die every year before reaching their fifth year with 33% of these in the neonatal period. This places Uganda 153rd out of 163 countries in the global rank for frequency of neonatal deaths. Most newborn infections and deaths occur in the community, and are frequently unreported to the health sector.  For example, preliminary findings from the Iganga/Mayuge Demographic Surveillance Site showed that 60% of all deaths occur outside a health facility setting and go unreported. African community studies suggest an infection rate of around 30%. In terms of infection prevention hand washing with soap  even when washed with unclean water results in a large reduction in hand contamination. A recent systematic review concluded that there was a lack quality evidence for the effect of clean birth and postnatal newborn care practices on neonatal mortality. However, the need for clean birth and postnatal care is widely accepted. A Delphi expert consensus process judged that clean birth practices at home with no skilled attendant could reduce neonatal sepsis deaths by 15% and tetanus deaths by 30%. The panel judged that postnatal newborn care practices could prevent 40% of neonatal sepsis deaths, but that more research is needed particularly on the content and quality of care during the early postnatal period. A research priority-setting exercise by World Health Organisation (WHO) on the reduction of newborn infection deaths found that the top ranked question was &apos;what is the feasibility, effectiveness, and cost of different approaches to promote the home care practices especially hand washing of caregivers?&apos; Despite this being 4 years ago, there are no registered studies addressing the use of alcohol hand gels for mothers in the neonatal period, and local experts know of no similar study. The importance of hand-washing in preventing infective deaths has led WHO to develop guidelines for hand hygiene both within health care settings and in the community and integrate hand hygiene into neonatal community care programmes. For hand hygiene, the current recommended practice at the household level is handwashing with soap. However, studies show widespread non-adherence to the household guidelines, often due to a lack of water. An alternative option could therefore be alcohol based hand gel. This is cheap ($0.6 for 60mls) and active against a broad range of Gram-positive and Gram-negative aerobic bacteria, including staphylococci, streptococci, and enteric Gram-negative bacteria. Although alcohol-based hand rubs effectively prevent acute diarrhoeal diseases.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This pilot study&apos;s main objectives are: 1. To determine the effectiveness of providing alcohol hand gel to pregnant women in rural Eastern Uganda as a way of reducing infant infective morbidity in the first 3 months of life 2. To determine the cost-effectiveness of providing alcohol hand gel to pregnant women in rural Eastern Uganda as a way of reducing early infant infections in the first 3 months of life 3. To prevent maternal infection in the first 3 months postnatally  4.           To assess the reliability of data collected and whether this method of data collection would be transferrable to a larger scale study Levels of poverty within Uganda are so high that many facilities taken for granted as being freely available in the West are denied to women in Uganda. Quite often, mothers are required to buy the basic maternity necessities such as gloves, razor blades, cord ligature, syringe and needles, cotton wool, sanitary pads and soap. The absence of these items during delivery increases chances of sepsis or infection to all the parties involved in child delivery - mothers, newborns and midwives. In addition to this, expectant mothers in some health units were required to come for child delivery with mattresses and linen.   A Ugandan government initiative introduced in 2003 with the support of the WHO aims to reduce illness and deaths of mothers associated with poor hygiene and unclean environment at delivery. Implementation of the Maama birthing kit (Consisting of - plastic sheet,sterile gloves, razor blades, cord ligature, cotton, sanitary pads, tetracycline and soap) was one of the initiative. This has contributed to addressing some hygiene issues.  However not all areas in Uganda have had the benefit of available Maama kits. At the launch of the kit it was estimated that nation wide, about 60% of expectant mothers were being delivered at home either by Traditional Birth Attendants or relatives. Reasons for the low utilization of health services include the perceived poor quality of antenatal and delivery services at the health facilities, and poor attitudes of health workers stemming from the lack of basic supplies at the health centres and hospitals and poor remuneration. Therefore it is key that women, wherever they delivery their babies has the benefit of something which will contribute towards providing a safer and more hygenic delivery. alcohol This study will look at comparing the use of a Maama kit versus a Maama kit plus a bottle of alcohol based handgel. It is not feasible to randomise individual women in a study of this nature. 10 rural villages will be used as study sites and it is the individual vilages which will be randomised to the study protocol.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-03">150020.42</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-03">150020.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M017990_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FM017990%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
