<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006205_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Digital records as evidence to underpin global development goals. (HN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this project is to create a research network of archivists, records managers, historians and leading experts in the expanding field of digital humanities, to discuss how the effective management of digital records can contribute both to the achievement of current development goals and to the protection and preservation of the historical record. Particular emphasis will be placed on how developing nations in Africa can benefit by applying best-practice developed in the area of archives management. The project will place particular emphasis on exploring how records management can tackle the problem of corruption, which bedevils so many development initiatives. But it will also examine the role of digital data it tracking and verifying the progress towards a range development goals and will seek to define records management protocols necessary to ensuring that public sector digital records remain accessible as a trustworthy source of evidence. At the same time, the project seeks to situate the creation of practical instruments of these kinds within the framework of broader socio-political factors which have hindered economic development in sub-Saharan Africa. Hence, the project seeks to encourage a dialogue between records management practitioners and academics who have studied the development of the post-independence African state.  Taking an interdisciplinary approach, the project will deliver two who-day workshops in London to discuss both the relationship between records management and development goals, with particular emphasis on combatting corruption, and the potential for producing a common set of requirements for incorporating digital records management elements in development planning (the &apos;Digital Records Protocols&apos;). The workshops will bring together specialists in data and archive management and Humanities scholars with representatives of governmental and non-governmental bodies with an interest in development and anti-corruption. The initial outcomes of the network will be delivered through a website making available a range of materials, an edited volume and a report disseminated through the Open Government Partnership network.  The network will be led by Professor Philip Murphy (Director, Institute of Commonwealth Studies (ICwS)) as PI and Dr Anne Thurston (Senior Research Fellow, ICwS). Professor Murphy is a leading contemporary historian of Britain and the Commonwealth and Dr Thurston is founder and director of the International Records Management Trust (IRMT). The IMRT&apos;s experience of the realities of weak information control regimes in lower resource countries, particularly in the digital environment, and of the impact this has on governments&apos; ability to function effectively and citizens&apos; ability to claim rights and entitlements, remains unique. The project will have as its principal partner the School of Information Science at Moi University in Kenya. Its Professor of Records and Archival Science, Professor Justus Wamukoya, is one of the leading figures in records and archives management in Africa.   The ICwS is the ideal base for these meetings, enjoying, as it does, close links with practitioners in all these fields. In June 2015, for example, it hosted a symposium for the Association of Commonwealth Archivists and Records Managers on &apos;Government Secrecy in the Era of Openness&apos;. The Institute is part of the School of Advanced Study (SAS) which, under the direction of its Professor of Digital Humanities, the historian Jane Winters, is at the forefront of the study of the preservation of digital data. The project will be guided by an advisory group which will meet 5 times over the duration of the project. Its membership will be largely UK-based and will draw on the extensive scholarly and practitioner networks of the ICwS and the IMRT. It will also include representatives from Moi University participating via a telephone or video link.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project examines the crucial role of records management (and increasingly digital records) in the attainment of current development goals. The launch of the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in September 2015, has made it increasingly essential to recognise and address weakness in the way governments&apos; official evidence base is managed and used. Plans to measure and monitor the SDGs are based on the assumption that it will be possible to access meaningful data as a basis for benchmarking and eradicating poverty.  Unfortunately, it is often the case that records are incomplete, inaccurate, inaccessible or lost completely, with the result that data and statistics derived from the records are flawed.   The rapid transition to the use of digital records has encouraged and been closely linked to &apos;open government&apos; initiatives, aimed at making records and data publicly available. Again, this has a direct bearing on the achievement of current development agendas in ensuring that government is more transparent and accountable. Yet in the digital environment, records created by computerised information systems do not remain reliable or accessible, even for short periods of time, without a control regime of laws, policies, practices and skills as defined in international standards. If digital repositories are not developed, where digital records and data can be managed securely through time, there is no guarantee that they will remain available or reliable. Unfortunately, it is precisely those countries that stand to gain most from progress towards the SDGs that have the greatest problems putting effective data management systems in place.  The objective of this, which project builds on the expertise within the School of Advanced Study (SAS), its networks and partner organisations, is to bring together academics, records managers and archivists and a range of NGOs to consider how the management of digital records and data can assist in the achievement international development goals, particularly the SDGs, in sub-Saharan Africa. An important element in the achievement of these goals is the combatting of corruption, something that severely hinders justice, good-governance and development in many countries. Managing records efficiently will not in itself halt corruption, but anti-corruption goals cannot be achieved without trustworthy records as evidence. As such this will be an important thematic focus of the project. It aims to disseminate its findings via and dedicated web resource and an edited volume of articles. The project will also consider the feasibility of a globally-applicable set of protocols for digital records management to help ensure that records management policies, principles and practices become a core aspect of development in the digital environment.   A key feature of the project is a two-stage cross-fertilisation of expertise. In the first stage the workshops will be to encourage a dialogue between experts in the area of records management (from both the developed and the developing world) and academic experts on the politics, economics and history of post-colonial Africa. The second stage will allow them to engage with those actively involved in implementing international development goals. As such, measurable outcomes will be extent of the follow-up initiatives that emerge from these dialogues, and the extent to which the immediate outputs of the research network are fed into the policy-making process.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-29">42482.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-29">48579.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Research Networking Award to University of London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/P006205/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">42482.24</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006205_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">-2173.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006205_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FP006205%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
