<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_R001928_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton STFC Capacity Building with LIGO-India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the proposal are three-fold;  1. to foster the growth of the GW community in India and create strong ties with them by creating a training network to build capacity for interdisciplinary research. This training network will allow PhD students and early career researchers from India to be trained by UK GW experts, taking this knowledge back to India to strengthen capability. The UK consortia has significant experience in developing technology and data analysis tools, whilst at the same time sharing these outputs across international collaborations. A particular highlight was the development of world-leading R&amp;D under the advanced LIGO UK (ALUK) project. Here the Universities of Glasgow, Birmingham, Strathclyde and Rutherford Appleton Laboratory worked collaboratively to deliver the suspension hardware, sensors and electronics necesary to provide the quietest reference frames on earth; the aLIGO mirrors. These 40kg optics move no more than 1/1000th the diameter of a proton at 10Hz and were essential pieces of hardware to enable the first 2 direct detections of gravitational waves (GW150914 and GW151226). We propose a model where staff/postdoc/student exchanges to/from UK and Inda will be an effective method to share knowledge, experience and solve the technological challenges during the development of a new infrastructure in India. The vision is to equip India with the tools necessary to implement the most sensitive of the international gravitational wave detectors, and this represents a fantastic opportunity to further strength UK-India scientific relations.  2 to encourage entrepreneurial activity. The very nature of our field, where we are pushing the boundary of technology and analysis tools, and observing the most extreme astrophysical events in the universe has a numbers of applications which can directly benefit the development of entrepreneurial activity. Specific examples in the UK include data analysis tools for line rejection, analysis of retinal images, development of MEMS-based accelerometers, low power gas sesnors and stem cell differentiation through vibration. We will share best practice with our Indian colleagues by allowing them to engage with the academics and researchers who have been key in developing these spin-offs, to identify how this was performed, the funding routes, and opportunities for follow on funds included taking products to market. In preliminary discussion there already appears to be strong inkages with Indian companies in the areas of machine learning, High Performance Computing, big data, and precision lasers &amp; optics, which we will fully capitalise on. We will engage with companies including Planys Technologies, Helia Photonics, Gas Sensing Solutions, Persistent Systems Limited, Honeywell, Safran, Hindustan Aeronautics Limited, UUrmi, Nex Robotics via links through IUCAA and University of the West of Scotland.  3. implementation of a strong and vibrant outreach programme. The UK consortium also has a strong record of public engagement and enthusing the general public and school children about GW astronomy. Again this is an essential component to recruit the next generation of scientists. We propose to work closely with contacts in India to further develop outreach resources (suitable for both Indian/English speaking participants) and utilise the as a teaching tool to generate interest at early stages of schooling, ultimately with the aim of enhancing the provision and retention of STEM based students studying in high school and university. The programme allows the fabrication of outreach exhibits to take into Indian schools and science fairs, developing CPD for teachers by utilsiing cutting edge scientific themes such as Gravitational Waves.We also propose to engage within the Indian science outreach community including the India International Science Festival.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With the first direct observation of gravitational waves from coalescing black holes by the LIGO Scientific collaboration last year there has been great interest around the world in extending the reach of the future detector network, as gravitational wave astronomy breaks open a new window on the Universe. With the siting of the 3rd aLIGO detector in India there is an essential need for critically skilled students, postdocs and early career researchers to be trained at the highest level in gravitational wave astronomy, for construction of the infrastructure &amp; technology, development of high performance computing/machine learning algorithms and efficient data pipelines. In turn, the LIGO India project will help Indian scientific community to be a major player in the emerging research frontier of GW astronomy. Based on the model of the LIGO Scientific Collaboration, there is a huge potential for inclusive growth across many areas of industry, academia and society. The UK consortia also have a strong track record of outreach &amp; public engagement, which will be shared with our Indian collaborators.   The Indian partners will be those institutions jointly coordinating and executing the LIGO-India project and their associates: the Inter-University Centre for Astronomy and Astrophysics (IUCAA), Pune, the Indian Institute for Science Education &amp; Research (IISER) and the TIFR Center for Interdisciplinary Sciences, Hyderabad. Over the coarse of the project we will also develop linkages with the Department of Atomic Energy organisations: Institute for Plasma Research (IPR), Gandhinagar and the Raja Ramanna Centre for Advanced Technology (RRCAT), Indore who will be leading the development of infrastructure (laser, vacuumm system, suspensions and seismic isolation).  The main objectives of this proposal are to build up technical capacity and capability in India in a broad range of multidisciplinary fields associated with gravitational wave detection. This field is very wide in nature and the technologies required range from delicate mechanical instrumentation, through high and low power laser optics to signal processing and large data handling, and thus capacity built up from the work of this proposal will have wide application in other fields. We have already identified several UK-India comapny linkages in the areas of machine learning, sensors &amp; autonomous systems &amp; data algorithms, and we propose to share our experience of methods to spin-out high technology research into applied fields.  The consortium behind this proposal in the UK - the Universities of the West of Scotland, Glasgow, Cardiff, Birmingham, Southampton, and Sheffield - has a strong and extensive track record in detector development, data analysis and background theory and astrophysics for the gravitational wave field, as well as working with industry, in public outreach and school teacher CPD. Thus it is ideally suited to provide training for PhD students, research assistants and early career researchers in the ODA country of India to build capacity and make these countries major contributors to the international community and to provide dedicated summer schools/workshops in the UK utilising the expansive UK training network, for training the incoming members from the ODA countries in the necessary data analysis and experimental hardware techniques. Further the consortium will arrange opportunities for researchers to travel to/from India and the UK to capacity build and perform on-site training of researchers.   Such a model has already shown to be extremely valuable in the transfer of UK expertise to both the US during the construction of Advanced LIGO and in Japan, during the construction of KAGRA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-03">100565.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-03">101380.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-03">102813.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
