<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R020981_2</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Role of HbA1c and 50g GCT in early detection and prediction of gestational diabetes and associated maternal and fetal complications in Thailand</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) is one of the most common obstetric medical conditions and if undetected can cause significant adverse outcomes for the mother and child. The risks to the mother include a doubling of pre-eclampsia, higher frequency of Caesarean deliveries, anxiety and depression. Women with a history of GDM have a 7-fold risk of developing type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) later in life. Up to half of them will develop T2DM within 10 years after delivery. The immediate risks to the children include macrosomia (20%-30%), being small for gestational age (7%-10%), shoulder dystocia, neonatal hypoglycaemia and hyperbilirubinemia, respiratory distress syndrome and in rare situations, stillbirth. Children born to mothers with GDM are predisposed to childhood obesity and diabetes later in life. Treating GDM improves the obstetric adverse outcomes by approximately 50%.  Diagnosis is made usually between 24-28 weeks of pregnancy using a 75g oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT), but by then some adverse consequences to the baby may have occurred and any delay in screening and treatment may make it too late to improve outcomes.  In Thailand, the Royal Thai College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists advocates screening with the 50g Glucose Challenge Test (GCT) at first antenatal visit for women with high risk for GDM; if 50g GCT &gt;= 140mg/dl or 7.8mmol/l (positive) then further testing with 100g OGTT is performed; if negative, the OGTT is repeated at 24-28 weeks gestation.  But, the rate of screening for GDM in Thailand varies from none at all in rural areas to 78% in urban areas.  Although universal screening is recommended by many guidelines, this is not uniformly followed across the world, because of a lack of resources and doubts about cost-effectiveness. The major limitations are difficulty in conducting OGTT, which requires prompt access to laboratory facilities (glucose degrades in storage), in lower middle income countries (LMICs), where majority live in rural settings. Even in high-income countries like the UK, universal screening is not adopted due to the lack of cost-effectiveness in specific populations. An alternative to 50g GCT screening is with HbA1c at booking clinic, which has been advocated by the International Association of the Diabetes and Pregnancy Study Groups (IADPSG). The HbA1c is a one-step test and patients do not need to fast. However, the relationship of different HbA1c levels in first trimester/early second trimester of pregnancy and outcomes of pregnancy (including the development of GDM as per current criteria) is yet to be determined in Thai women.   The primary objectives of our project are:  a) to assess the value of HbA1c and 50g GCT testing at first antenatal visit at or before 20 weeks gestation in predicting later GDM and adverse outcomes of pregnancy, including determining levels of HbA1c and 50g GCT that might rule out later GDM. b) to examine the relative cost-efficiency of different screening strategies i.e. universal versus selective screening;  c) to determine whether diet and lifestyle interventions, can prevent the development of GDM by a nested RCT in women with non-diabetic hyperglycaemia.  The secondary objectives of the study will be:  a) assessing the value of risk factors that can be easily measured in resource constrained settings (such as gestational weight gain, baseline body mass index, blood pressure, socioeconomic status, educational attainment, etc.), and their relative contribution to the prediction of GDM;  b) to see if HbA1c and/or 50g GCT testing in early pregnancy can reduce the overall need for OGTT by early detection of GDM or impending GDM; c) to determine the risks of adverse outcomes of pregnancy by bands of glucose level, in order to consider the level at which treatment is required; d) to develop a research network and data to underpin a larger study.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">High blood glucose levels in pregnancy called gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) is one of the most common medical conditions during pregnancy. It can cause harm to the pregnant woman and her child. GDM affects 10-15% of Thai women. More women are being diagnosed with GDM now because a lower level of blood glucose is being used to diagnose GDM.  If not treated, GDM can cause high blood pressure in pregnancy, increased numbers of caesarean deliveries, anxiety and depression. Women who have had GDM have 7-8 times higher life-time risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). There are risks to the children too. They may be too big or too small. If too big, they can have shoulders damaged during the birth. Their blood glucose may fall too low after birth. They may get jaundice soon after birth, or have difficulty in breathing. A very few may die before birth (stillbirth). In the long term, these children are at higher risk of becoming overweight and diabetic.  The diagnosis of GDM is usually made between 24-28 weeks of pregnancy using a glucose drink test called an oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT). Although treatment can improve pregnancy outcomes, some of the damage may have already been done to the unborn baby.  So screening to detect high glucose levels earlier in pregnancy may be better. However, there can be harms as well as benefits from screening. As a recent British Medical Journal article said:  &quot;a label of gestational diabetes brings with it an intervention package that includes glucose monitoring, extra clinic visits, more obstetric monitoring with greater likelihood of labour induction, operative delivery and admission of the baby to special care, and finally for the mother a label of high risk for diabetes&quot;.   Some people think that all women should be screened with OGTT has been advocated but that may not be needed. The test requires pregnant women to come to a clinic having not eaten anything for at least 8 hours. In many countries including the UK, women are selected for OGTT based on risk factors such as overweight and older age. However, selecting women based on these factors can miss up to half of all women with GDM.   In Thailand, women at high risk for GDM are supposed to be screened at the first antenatal clinic visit with the 50g Glucose Challenge Test (GCT). But, the rate of screening for GDM in Thailand varies from none at all in rural areas to 78% in cities.   Another blood glucose test done by a simple finger prick (called HbA1c) might do instead. It would be done at the first antenatal clinic visit. The HbA1c is a one-step test and patients do not need to fast. However, the value of HbA1c testing is not yet known in Thai women.  The aims of this study are to find out whether HbA1c and 50g GCT testing at first antenatal clinic visit can predict later GDM and if there is a level that can rule out later GDM. We also want to compare testing of all pregnant women with testing only those with risk factors. We will do a trial to see if diet and lifestyle interventions can prevent women developing GDM.  Accurate HbA1c and 50g GCT levels that can safely rule out GDM in women at low risk would help pregnant women. They can be reassured. Avoiding the need for OGTT would save them time and money. In contrast, if the HbA1c and 50g GCT levels identifies them as at high-risk, healthy eating and lifestyle advice can reduce their risk of getting GDM. In addition to the benefit to mothers and their children, this study will also be useful to people who provide health care in Thailand. They can focus care more on women at high risk. The results could be used by other countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-25">132997.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-25">132997.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-25">97670.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
