<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R022747_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">How is the current crisis reshaping Brazil&apos;s health system? Strengthening health workforce and provision of services in S&#xE3;o Paulo and Maranh&#xE3;o</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Economic crises are very common worldwide, and they have been shown to carry multiple effects on national health systems; they can increase the burden of disease from specific mental health and poverty-related conditions, but also drive health workers away from the public sector and the country in search of better working conditions. Some scholars have suggested that it is often the associated policy responses - the so-called austerity measures - that carry a negative impact on health systems and workforces.  In Brazil, the health system effects of the economic crisis that has affected the country since 2015 have not been fully understood, with press reports and anecdotal evidence suggesting that services are being shut down and physicians are abandoning the public sector, particularly in rural areas. As part of its policy response to the crisis, the Government is introducing measures to limit public health spending, promote the growth of private health insurance plans, and fill the gaps in the workforce through international recruitment. However, an objective assessment of the health systems effects of Brazil&apos;s crisis is lacking, and so is the evidence base to elaborate policies to address them.  The present study aims at exploring the impact of the current economic crisis and of the associated austerity measures on the health system and workforce in Brazil, with a specific focus on public sector physicians - an essential pillar of any health system-, and on how to foster the debate on suitable health policy options. We will look specifically at the cases of S&#xE3;o Paulo and Maranh&#xE3;o states, two very diverse settings where we expect the diverse effects of the crisis to be felt differently because of their uneven economic development. We will do so by analysing the existing data on the effects of the crisis from available health financing and medical workforce datasets, and by conducting interviews and surveys among phsycians in the two states. The study findings will be presented in facilitated policy dialogues workshops in S&#xE3;o Paulo and Maranh&#xE3;o, where health policy-makers will be invited to review the fresh evidence produced, and to consider examples of health policy responses from other countries.   It is hoped that this study will help identify suitable policies to alleviate the effects of the crisis on the health system, health workforce and provision of services in Brazil, particularly for the most vulnerable populations in S&#xE3;o Paulo and Maranh&#xE3;o. The study findings will also contribute to the growing body of knowledge on economic crises and health systems world-wide.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">54705.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">55148.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">55595.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This research aims to explore the impact of the current economic crisis and associated austerity measures on the health system and workforce in Brazil. Specific attention will be given to (a) understanding public sector physicians reactions, (b) their repercussions to the provision of services in developed and underdeveloped settings, and (c) fostering the debate on suitable policy responses to the crisis. The study has four specific objectives:  First, to collate, analyse and synthesise the available data on the changes happening in Brazil in connection to the economic crisis in health financing, in the development of the private sector, and in the distribution of the national health workforce. We will do so by conducting multivariate analysis of secondary data already acquired by our Brazilian partners on national health spending, and national medical demography data.  The second objective is to generate hypotheses on the impact of crisis and associated austerity measures on the health workforce, and their current or planned reactions and coping strategies. For this objective, we will draw from the existing literature to conduct qualitative interviews with health sector key informants in the two states, interrogating them about changes happening in the public and private health systems, and about physicians&apos; and nurses&apos; reactions.  Testing quantitatively such hypotheses will be the third objective for this study. We will organise two surveys in S&#xE3;o Paulo and Maranh&#xE3;o, where quantitative and qualitative information will be collected from representative samples of approximately 1,200 physicians from the two states, looking specifically at changes in earnings, workload, engagement with private services, intentions to leave the public sector. Association and causality will be established between personal characteristics, effects of specific policy measures, and changes taking place in the public and private sector.  The last objective will be to feed the study results into the current debates on suitable policy response to the crisis in Brazil&apos;s health sector. For this purpose, we will organise and facilitate two policy dialogue workshops with health sector stakeholders in S&#xE3;o Paulo and Maranh&#xE3;o, where we will present the study findings as well as the international evidence on economic crises, health systems and associated policy measures from other countries.  It is expected that achieving the above four objectives will contribute to the ongoing academic and policy debates on how economic crises affect health systems, as well feed directly into the national debate on the government&apos;s policy response to the crisis in Brazil."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
