<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N013689_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Developing rice resources for resilience to climate change and mitigation of carbon emissions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Climate change associated with global warming poses a threat to our ability to produce sufficient food, energy and water to meet the demands of the growing human population. Human activity is helping to drive the upward trend in global warming by increasing the levels of warming agents such as greenhouse gases in the atmosphere. Episodes of severe weather, such as drought and flooding, increase as global temperatures rise, and this can lead to losses in crop yield. Rice is one of the main staple crops grown in the world and represents a major source of food and livelihood for many people, particularly in the tropics. Every year more than 700,000 million tons of rice straw is produced in the world and much of this is burned in the field in order to make way for the next season&apos;s crop. This releases large amounts s of black carbon and tropospheric ozone into the atmosphere with negative consequences for air quality, human health (respiratory illnesses), crop yield and global warming. One of the main aims of the proposed research is to help move rice straw away from being a waste product and toward its widespread utilisation as a valuable resource. Rice straw is primarily composed of lignocellulosic structural cell walls that provide support to the growing plant. Lignocellulose is a strong and resistant fibre composite material composed of a network of structural polysaccharides (polymers of sugars). These polysaccharides are potentially a rich source of sugars that could serve as nutritious animal feed, or be used as feedstock for fermentation to produce biofuels or other valuable chemicals and polymers that can replace those derived from petroleum. Unfortunately, the polysaccharides in lignocellulose are difficult to digest into sugars for animal nutrition or fermentation partly because they are sealed in a highly resistant polyphenol called lignin, and partly because they are partially crystalline, both of which block access to digestive enzymes. In rice straw, this situation is further exacerbated by the presence of large amounts (up to 10% dry weight) of silica, which makes it unpalatable to most animals and also precludes the use of rice straw in biomass furnaces to make electricity as it causes severe slagging of boilers.  This project brings together the expertise of five world class laboratories to tackle the complex problem of environmental resilience and carbon footprint in a world staple food crop. We will use cutting edge plant genomic approaches to identify the genetic basis of natural variation in straw digestibility, lignocellulose composition and silica content found in large diversity collections of rice collected in the Philippines and Vietnam. We will employ genome wide association scans in these diversity collections to identify associations in the variation of digestibility, composition and silica content with differences in the sequences of DNA in regions of the genomes of these plants. This will identify molecular markers that can serve as proxies for improved straw quality and allow rapid marker assisted breeding approaches to be used. The same methods will also allow us to identify the genes that have strong influence on these traits in rice. We will also identify regions of the genome influencing the ability of rice crops to deal with drought (a major problem resulting from climate change) and produce molecular markers for improved drought tolerance. Our work will identify existing rice varieties with low silica or highly digestible straw and we will use these to investigate and demonstrate the advantages of using straw with better quality for applications as animal feed and for biofuel production. We will use the results from our research to alert farmers and other stakeholders to the potential benefits of using rice straw in these applications to improve farmer income, local livelihoods and air quality as well as helping mitigate the damaging effects of human activity on global warming.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective is to improve the climate resilience of rice production through the development of more stress tolerant cultivars, and to mitigate the global warming emissions from rice straw burning by developing varieties with better quality and lower silica content for energy production and animal feed based on rice straw. We will develop applications of rice straw for use as animal feed and as feedstock for biofuel production, in order to create value from this resource and divert it from biomass burning. This will be achieved in a two-pronged approach through the improvement of the raw material quality of rice straw and by development and demonstration of the potential benefits of these applications. Our approach to feedstock improvement makes use of genome-wide association scans by taking advantage of two diversity populations assembled from local land races and breeding resources, one in the Philippines and the other in Vietnam. As well as fulfilling these applied objectives, the work has significant potential to improve our fundamental scientific knowledge in the area of plant cell wall biochemistry. In addition to straw characteristics, these populations are being used to identify quantitative trait loci (QTL) for drought resistance as drought is an increasing issue for rice production as a result of climate change. The specific objectives are to:  -identify QTL for straw digestibility, silica content and drought resistance to generate markers for breeding -make bi-parental crosses to establish recombinant inbred lines in order to further resolve QTL for straw digestibility and silica content -identify candidate genes responsible for the observed variation in digestibility and silica content at selected QTL -validate candidate genes using knock out mutants and other methods -use straw from lines identified to have high digestibility in demonstration activities for animal feed and biofuels applications -use straw from selected low silica lines in animal feed applications -carry out dissemination activities with local stakeholders in order to demonstrate the benefits of making use of rice straw and avoiding biomass burning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-15">212493.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-15">276499.61</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-15">239881.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
