<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R011125_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Displacement, placemaking and wellbeing in the city</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will contribute to our growing understanding of the structures, dynamics and processes through which people who are enduringly displaced succeed or fail to become part of European and Indian cities.   Globally, forced displacement levels are hitting a record modern-day high. UNHCR reports 65.3 million people were displaced from their homes by conflict and persecution in 2015. Every minute, on average 24 people were forced to flee somewhere in the world, and these levels were four times higher than a decade prior. 2015 also marked a watershed moment in Europe, with hundreds of thousands of migrants and refugees arriving on its shores, after often perilous journeys. In India, cities grow rapidly, and continue to receive many people that are internally displaced due to agrarian crisis, conflict, development induced displacement and abject poverty.  Protracted displacement is now chiefly an urban affair. Cities offer economic and social opportunities, however, they can also be places of rising inequalities, deprivation, isolation and exploitation. The flow of displaced groups quickens urbanisation, and may create (actual or perceived) competition for jobs, quality housing and limited essential services such as health and education. The UN Sustainable Development Goal 11 sets out the global ambition for inclusive, sustainable and secure cities, and the New Urban Agenda (2016) explicitly calls for inclusion of urban refugees within existing city structures. Yet, India and European cities&apos; efforts to manage inflows often face populist backlashes. Greater understanding is hence needed of the ways in which people succeed or fail to make urban spaces into places of belonging, participation and wellbeing in conditions of scarcity and growing urban inequality. This will require attention to the placemaking processes and practices that structure refugees&apos; and forced migrants&apos; political, social and economic citizenship, access to livelihood opportunities, connections with existing communities and, ultimately, to define and achieve a &apos;right to the city&apos;.  This project offers new ways of cross-disciplinary thinking, methodological innovation and action. To this end, the project will adopt a mixed methods approach. Combining quantitative and qualitative social science techniques will provide a better understanding of research problems than either used alone. We will compare multiple case studies in each of the four countries - India, Finland, Norway and the UK - located in diverse urban settings, spanning from town to megacity. We will undertake key informant interviews, structured wellbeing surveys, and mapping of physical structures, features, form, functions and use of urban spaces. In addition, we will conduct policy analyses and stakeholder mappings to understand in what ways displaced groups&apos; use of space for economic activity and leisure is enabled or restricted. We will also set up innovative Design Studios for architecture and design students to support the project through analysis, design of solutions and learning from their active engagement in fieldwork with senior researchers, and by pairing them up with social science students. As such, the project seeks to break down disciplinary boundaries between the social sciences and humanities; humanitarianism and development; urban planning, architecture and design; and the integration of creative and engaged research methods that better interrogate and allow for the expression of a wide range of knowledge and experiences.  The study will provide important knowledge for policy-makers at all levels of urban governance, as well as in development agencies and NGO/CSOs, about what roles they can play to support (and not to impede) greater equity, reduced inequalities and wellbeing in cities. Finally, the project will actively seek to engage and inform the general public in India and Europe through targeted media activities and public exhibitions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research directly addresses the &apos;Sustainability, equity, wellbeing and cultural connections&apos; aspects identified in the call. It investigates through what processes forcibly displaced people become part of cities, in ways that sustainably contribute to economic development, cultural advancement and wellbeing. To this end, we will build a detailed understanding of the relations between placemaking processes, modalities of reception and wellbeing outcomes for displaced groups in Indian and European cities. We do this in a context of rapidly growing human displacement, forced migration and refugee flows to cities globally, and in European and Indian cities that are witnessing rising inequalities. The research objectives, in approximate order of importance, are:   (i) Gain a deep understanding of the material and cultural production, design and architectural organisation of urban spaces of displacement and placemaking processes.  (ii) Critically examine the ways in which these spaces and the displaced people in them are governed, through assemblages of actors and particular modalities of reception, to produce particular wellbeing effects.  (iii) Assess in what ways and why displaced people negotiate access to these spaces.  (iv) Develop, design and build strategic interventions that foster equity and inclusion in urban spaces, grounded in the wellbeing priorities of vulnerable displaced groups.  (v) Build student and academic capacity for current and future cross- and trans-disciplinary research, design and learning relating to migration management in cities. To achieve these objectives, the study is guided by an overarching research question: How to curate processes that foster displaced people to become part of the city, and to sustainably contribute to its economic development, socio-cultural cohesion and wellbeing? This question is broken down into four sub-questions:  1. Through what kinds of placemaking processes in physical and digital spaces do displaced people inhabit, build, make, give meaning and derive wellbeing? 2. In what ways and why do modalities of reception structure economic participation, socio-cultural cohesion and wellbeing outcomes for displaced people?  3. What is the role of urban informality, temporality and scale in placemaking processes and in the visions and functioning of modalities of reception? 4. What strategic architectural and policy interventions can advance equity and wellbeing for displaced communities in urban spaces? These questions, along with the wellbeing framework and the highly interdisciplinary methods that the study proposes, ensure that it addresses cross-cutting issues and themes highlighted by the study call, including urban inequalities, the (formal and informal) urban governance features, and practices that interact with vulnerable groups as they are engaged in placemaking processes to critically shape equity and wellbeing outcomes.  The project will convene European and Indian social science and humanities research communities to jointly conduct cross-country investigations into urban protracted displacement across lower-middle income (India) and higher income countries (Finland, Norway, UK). The comparative case study analysis across cities of various scales (from town to megacity) will advance new empirical, conceptual and theoretical insights.  This project also offers a unique approach to analysis and capacity building, making sure that the insights and skills gained amongst the consortium will last beyond the end of the project. We will systematically pair senior researchers and students from Architecture and Design studies and Social Sciences to advance a highly inter-disciplinary approach that has great potential to generate new insights and to advance architectural and policy solutions that address growing urban inequalities and economic development, and improve equity and socio-cultural wellbeing in a sustainable manner.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-07">23618.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-07">96181.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-07">99979.65</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-07">24002.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-07">291787.958</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R011125_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FR011125%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
