<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S013245_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated upstream and downstream thinking to mitigate water security challenges from Peruvian glacier retreat</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acceleration of glacial melt has severe implications for water-food-energy security and inter-connected livelihoods of vulnerable populations in river basins fed by glaciers. For example, in the Ancash Region of Peru, glacial melt from the Andean Mountains provides up to 67% of dry season water supply going up to 91% during extreme drought (annual average 19%). Rapid retreat of glaciers in the Cordillera Blanca has already had notable impact on that supply, with evidence to suggest the majority of rivers now exhibit decreasing dry-season discharge i.e. have reached and passed &apos;peak water&apos;. Challenges associated with a reduced supply of water to downstream agriculture, industry and hydropower generation are exacerbated by enhanced sediment and contaminant flux in extreme wet season floods.  Climate change impacts compromise ecosystem service provision at times of both augmented low and high flow. While low flows and water supply are being increasingly impacted by the huge loss of water storage in shrinking glaciers, ENSO-related extreme events are leading to catastrophic delivery of excess water and sediment during high flows which compromise water and environmental quality downstream. Climate change is driving a hydrological regime of extremes with no advantage at either end: from supply and quality issues at low flow to more water than the system can handle at high flow, compromising water and soil quality downstream. Understanding the changing dynamics of glacial melt, hydrology and regional climate change is crucial in order for the design of infrastructure solutions and planning to be effective and resilient.  Responsible, efficient and sustainable water use is necessary in national and transboundary watersheds, to ensure adequate supply and mitigate emerging quality problems. In order to achieve this consultancies and advisory organisations require high quality robust scientific evidence to underpin their design decisions for watershed management. This entails moving from (inefficient) sectorial management of water to a more integrated and holistic approach that takes into account the need for conserving ecosystems services. Indeed, while the Peruvian Congress passed a historic Ecosystem Services law in 2014 to take a holistic approach to tackling these challenges, implementation of integrated action to achieve Sustainable Development Goals has been hampered by a lack of evidence of glacial-fed watershed processes and function. While studies to date have been conducted in the Cordillera Blanca in relation to dynamics of glacial retreat, associated natural disaster risk, hydrology and past glaciations we do not have a sufficiently holistic and integrated knowledge of the wider impacts of glacial melt on current and future ecosystem service provision which is hampered by complexity of human-environment feedbacks, a knowledge base essential for mitigation of future uncertainty and risks.  We propose that a basin-wide understanding of water, sediment and contaminant budgets within Peruvian glacial-fed basins is required to bring policy change for socio-economic benefits through (a) offsetting storage lost from shrinking glaciers through augmentation of mountain ecosystem service provision for landscape water retention and (b) providing the foundation for adaptive management strategies to support and enhance livelihoods under threat from high flows and downstream environmental quality consequences. This research is essential for the design of large-scale energy infrastructure, such as hydropower in glacier-fed regions. Likewise, bringing back and maintaining a balance between sustainable livelihoods and the environment is critical to build community resilience to environmental change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Taking a basin-wide water-food-energy-environment nexus approach in the Santa River Basin, Peru, this project aims to (1) close critical process knowledge gaps in dynamics of water budget change linked to glacial retreat, connectivity between upstream change and downstream consequence and the sources and fluxes of material during high and low flows, and (2) build a stakeholder decision support framework for mitigation and adaption strategies to both rebalance ecosystem service provision regarding water supply and mitigate downstream impacts. This will be achieved through four objectives (Os 1-4).  O1: Identify the dynamic role of glacial melt in the basin water budget: work will draw upon existing glacier and hydrological monitoring networks in the Cordillera Blanca and remote sensing data to a) develop a water budget of the study catchment from glacial versus mountain ecosystems, b) assess the current contribution of glacial meltwater to streamflow; c) evaluate glacial catchment response to meteorological events and climatic change; and d) use this knowledge to predict future long- and short-term variability in meltwater production. This objective directly feeds into Call Challenge 2 regarding quantification of tropical glacier roles in water resource provision past, present and future.  O2: Develop a conceptual model of structural and process connectivity in the Santa Basin: work will determine the links between upstream pressures and downstream responses through identification of sources of water, sediment and contaminants from both glacier and non-glacier-fed areas and assess the relative contribution to basin fluxes. This objective directly feeds into call Challenge 2 regarding spatio-temporal changes and variability in runoff/water supply and demand and specifically to evaluate sources, contributions, transport pathways and fate of sediments and contaminants through application of environmental forensic tracer tools.  O3: Evaluate upstream and downstream environmental impact: to evaluate the downstream impact of variability in water and sediment supply on contaminant levels and environmental quality. This will include a) an assessment of the impact of variable water supply and siltation on Hydro-Electric Power (HEP); b) an evaluation of the impact of natural and anthropogenic contaminants on water and environmental quality; and c) a review of the competing pressures on water resources and the impact of these pressures on downstream water availability and quality. This objective builds on call Challenge 3 and 4 specifically in determining the spatial and temporal patterns of basin-wide impacts and complex responses to human-environment interaction.  O4: Build a sustainable project legacy through establishment of local capacities to mitigate supply challenges through co-design of a Payment for Ecosystem Services (PES) model: to develop collaborative networks with a range of local stakeholders to co-design strategies for innovative water resource management in the Santa basin as an exemplar of how the 2014 PES law can be enacted. Working with UK specialists in PES (Westcountry Rivers Trust), the Peruvian National Water Authority (ANA) and industrial stakeholders (Mott MacDonald, water board and hydropower companies), this will encompass co-designing a response to a long-term trend of decreased water availability and increased (competing) demands on resource, and development of PES strategies for improved management of mountain ecosystem functionality for water storage and sediment and contaminant retention. The objective feeds into Challenge 3 through development of a co-designed, stakeholder led PES system that supports (i) socio-economic and ecological resilience to changes, with a focus on informing future water management strategies and (ii) promoting an improved understanding of inter- and intra-regional variability, and the transferability of results to inform monitoring in other, under-studied catchments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Plymouth</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Peru</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">30258.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">126640.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">143754.75</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">65914.91</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-21">366568.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to University of Plymouth</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE/S013245/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Plymouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">36156.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S013245_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Plymouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FS013245%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-10"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
