<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V006398_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mitigating climate change effects through traditional land management practices</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Soqotra Archipelago - located in the north west Indian Ocean 380km south of Yemen and 80km east of Somalia - is rightly renowned for its natural heritage and was inscribed on the World Heritage List in 2008 for its unique and rich biodiversity. However, it has also been the recipient of a range of large-scale international development and conservation programmes since 1990 focusing on environmental issues, and recent studies have suggested that these have been in part misguided and have left Soqotra largely dependent on external funding rather than leaving a sustainable legacy. Further, these programmes have focused almost entirely on the biodiversity, or the natural heritage of Soqotra: the cultural heritage of Soqotra has been little studied despite demonstrated value by the Soqotri people themselves, and the links between natural and cultural heritage - a separation not recognised by Soqotri people - have been almost totally ignored. In addition, very limited research has been undertaken on the climate of Soqotra - and none at all on how the climate of Soqotra has changed and will continue to change in the future - which is somewhat surprising due to the current importance placed on the global climate emergency against a backdrop of unique heritage recognised as a World Heritage Site. Soqotra is a small island system, with a diverse landscape and a complex climate. It is already being hit hard by extreme weather events which are increasing in severity and frequency, and fresh water is always in short supply. Within living memory, the people of Soqotra moved seasonally with their grazing animals to ensure healthy lives for themselves and their animals, but this knowledge is being lost as development proceeds and young people are less interested in their traditional ways of life. Yet, this traditional knowledge evolved to cope with extreme and unpredictable weather and may hold some answers as to how climate change can be adapted to locally. In order to achieve this, it is necessary not only to further study these systems of knowledge and the climate they evolved to cope with, but to ensure they are understood and valued on Soqotra by merging traditional knowledge with contemporary development and livelihoods for the future. The proposed project will further document and update knowledge about traditional systems on Soqotra, assess how much knowledge has already been lost and which practises are no longer in use, and assess how they match climate in the past, present and future. It will establish how traditional knowledge is linked to climate management and recommend how such knowledge can be revived to help cope with climate change in the future.  Rather than undertaking scientific study and recommending management options to local stakeholders at a later stage, the research will be conducted in partnership with a team of heritage experts from Soqotra trained under the Soqotra Heritage Project and supported by expert scientists from the UK. This will be done in partnership not only with local experts, but also local communities and decision makers supported by experts in land management, climate change and the heritage of Soqotra. The result will be a better understanding of the linkages between climate and a traditional way of life that has contemporary relevance, and the ability to better predict and manage the effects of climate change on heritage and biodiversity on a unique island. The methods developed can be application in other island systems globally as well as areas affected by similar climates where heritage is under threat.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The primary aim would be to develop strategies and participatory processes that integrated humanities and science-based data with stakeholder perspectives that could be used in the adaptation and mitigation measures required to tackle climate change. This will involve assessing climate data and developing models with existing and future data and assessing how traditional loand management practices cope with adverse climate and can be encouraged to adapt to future climate scenarios in a isolated island system. The main objectives of this study can be summarized as follows: Review knowledge available about the traditional land use practices of Soqotra with particular reference to climate adaptation, and augment and update this knowledge to document contemporary land use in comparable communities; Review available knowledge and methodologies for documenting and predicting the climate regime of Soqotra, taking into account topographical island systems and the availability of water through orographic precipitation; Investigate and understand the temporal scale relationship between humans and their environment on Soqotra and the potential for implementation of existing land management knowledge to counter predicted climate change scenarios; Document the value placed upon traditional management systems on Soqotra; Develop awareness of the potential effects of climate change and whether traditional management systems have application to mitigate the effects; Articulate knowledge gaps and recommend data acquisition and analyses to improve outcomes for rural communities and resource conservation in the face of climate change on Soqotra; Assess the methods developed and recommended for application beyond Soqotra into the Arabian Peninsula and especially in zones of conflict, water scarcity and degradation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-29">119617.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/V006398/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">35885.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V006398_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FV006398%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
