<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S006699_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quantitative Attribution of Secondary Organic Aerosol in Beijing to its Precursors</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Breathing particles in polluted air leads to the worsening of many health conditions and ultimately to premature death.  The atmosphere of Beijing is well known for its very high concentrations of airborne particles and there is an urgent need for further control measures.  A large proportion of those particles (referred to as &quot;haze&quot;) are not emitted directly into the atmosphere but form within the atmosphere from chemical reactions of gases and vapours.  This project is concerned with finding out which gases and vapours emitted into the atmosphere from road traffic, fuel burning, refuse incineration and many other sources are responsible for the formation of particles within the atmosphere of Beijing and the amount which they contribute to the concentration of particles.  The scientific approach is to fill a reaction chamber with the vapours of a single chemical compound and let them undergo chemical reactions which lead to particle formation.  The particles formed are then subject to very detailed chemical analysis and constituent molecules are identified which are characteristic of the compounds originally put into the chamber.  Then, by making measurements of the same compound in the atmosphere, it is possible to estimate how much of the particles arise from the reaction of a particular gas.  Control policies can then be formulated to reduce the emissions of those gases most responsible for particle formation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="CHINA (PEOPLE&apos;S REPUBLIC OF)"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-24">34279.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-24">186538.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-24">93685.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Concentrations of fine particulate matter in the atmosphere of Beijing are currently falling year-by-year but annual averages remain stubbornly high in international terms, and haze events caused by elevated PM2.5 are still a regular feature of air quality.  A breakdown of the PM2.5 into its major components indicates that all major classes of PM2.5 (e.g. sulphates, nitrates, primary particles etc), other than secondary organic aerosol, are declining in concentration.  On the contrary, concentrations of secondary organic aerosol are changing little and if effective mitigation measures are to be developed, better knowledge of the specific precursors of secondary organic particles is urgently needed.  This project is concerned with generating such information.    The established approach to estimating the contributions of precursors to secondary organic aerosol mass concentrations is by identification of reaction products specific to a particular precursor and using chamber experiments to estimate their relationship to the mass of secondary organic aerosol arising from that precursor. Through measurements of such tracer compounds in the atmosphere, it is then possible to predict the contribution to particle mass.  Currently such tracers are available for only four precursor compounds and account for only about 50% of secondary organic aerosol.  The objectives of this study are: (a) To conduct studies in the chamber at the Institute of Chemistry of the China Academy of Sciences in which the more abundant high molecular weight organic compounds are subjected to oxidation and the resultant aerosol is sampled.   (b) To use advanced analytical techniques not previously deployed in China to identify reaction products as candidate tracers for the secondary organic aerosol produced.   (c) To analyse particulate matter from the atmosphere of Beijing in order to quantify the concentrations of the candidate tracer compounds. (d) To analyse primary particles from common combustion sources in order to evaluate possible interferences in the interpretation of tracer data. (e) To use the data collected to provide quantitative source attribution of secondary organic aerosol to the precursors responsible for its formation."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
