<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T029781_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building healthy communities in urban Brazilian slums</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrating a community-based participatory approach into an adaptive management framework to design, implement, and evaluate youth-led interventions that improve social and environmental conditions and, through these, health outcomes in urban slums by:  1- Empowering local communities in three urban slums in Salvador, Brazil, especially the youth, through giving them ownership of the project and the authority to critically evaluate results from the Foundation Project, identify and prioritise health challenges and design suitable interventions. This includes:  a) Establishing, in each community, a working group led by young residents that consists of researchers, local stakeholders, and community leaders  b) The working group critically evaluating data from the Foundation Project to identify necessary health, environmental, and social metrics to prioritise health and social challenges c) Designing infrastructural and community-based interventions and activities to mitigate risk from vector-borne, environmentally, and directly transmitted diseases and improve the local lived experience.  2- Through an adaptive management paradigm led by the working group, comparing relevant epidemiological, environmental, and social metrics collected before, during, and after the implementation of interventions. This includes:  a) Collecting baseline incidence data on leptospirosis and enteric infections, Dengue, Zika, and Chikungunya viruses, and TB and HIV prevalence and treatment status b) Collecting, amongst others, knowledge, attitudes, and practices data to better understand and communicate the lived experience of the residents c) Evaluating, through metrics collected after the first round of interventions, the intervention process and its effectiveness, before deciding whether to modify or maintain the interventions for the second round d) Collecting health, environmental, and social data to evaluate the overall effectiveness of the interventions, and communicating the results to stakeholders at the local, regional, and national scales. e) Evaluating, from a social science perspective, the process from start to finish, to explore how to improve community engagement and participatory research</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urbanisation provides one of today&apos;s major public health challenges. In low income cities, infectious diseases, linked to contaminated water and food and limited sanitation, exist alongside increased risks of air and water pollution. Social violence is often epidemic. The young are amongst the most vulnerable but also often those with least voice in decisions about their future. The city of Salvador, Brazil, where this project is based, exemplifies these problems.   Financial constraints mean that there is an urgent need for sustainable, locally-developed interventions to improve multiple health outcomes in these settings, and in selecting interventions, we need a framework that targets the common drivers of poor health. Community-based mitigations must be based, also, on local knowledge of determinants of risk, and managed to ensure that they can be adapted to the local context.   Here, therefore, we adopt an approach based on adaptive management, through which an initial, evidence-based management plan, developed through consensus between experts and local stakeholders, is repeatedly re-assessed and, if appropriate, modified (adapted) in the light of additional evidence, collected on an on-going basis. Our aim is to enhance wellbeing in communities in Salvador, and provide a blueprint for similar projects in urban slums worldwide.   We will focus on the interacting effects of infectious diseases that represent three different transmission routes, and on interventions to mitigate their risk. 1) Leptospirosis and enteric (gut) infections, which are environmentally transmitted via rats, water and soil where sanitation is poor. 2) Zika, Dengue, and Chikungunya, caused by mosquito-borne pathogens whose risk is associated with mosquito infestation and reproduction. 3) Directly transmitted infections, including Tuberculosis whose transmission is predominantly domestic, and sexually transmitted infections including HIV. Interventions varying in purpose will be chosen from a range of possibilities on an evidence-based basis, by groups comprising the residents themselves, with a special focus on youths, facilitated by our team.   Work will be based in 3 urban slum communities where we have already collected and analyzed data on a range of communicable diseases, having established relationships with residents&apos; groups, fully and enthusiastically committed to the program. We will evaluate changes in incidence rates for diseases before, during and after interventions, as well as data on multiple aspects of knowledge, attitudes and practices of residents, environmental data in public, peri-domestic, and domestic areas, the presence, extent and location of open sewers and trash accumulation, and relevant water/soil samples to quantify pathogen loads.  At the beginning of the project, in each community, a working group of residents and experts will be established, who will critically evaluate current findings to identify and guide acquisition of additional data required to choose interventions. Thus, over the first year, each community will use the previously- and newly-collected data as a basis for defining key interventions and relevant metrics to evaluate the interventions. Further pre-intervention metrics will be collected during the second 6 months.  Then, at the end of the first year, community-specific interventions will be implemented - either environmental (eg closing sewers) or behavioural (eg improving access to health visitors), following which further data will be collected. After a further 9 months, the management groups will undertake an evidence-based assessment of the interventions&apos; effectiveness, reflecting on the outcomes. This will lead to a re-considered, modified, set of interventions (or a decision to maintain the status quo), followed by further data collection, and ultimately to a full assessment of both the interventions, and of the processes that led to their initial genesis and subsequent adaptation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">164033.02</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">229920.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">662786.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">927643.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
