<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Can norethisterone enantate (NET-EN) reduce the risk of recurrent bacterial vaginosis in women at high risk for HIV infection?</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bacterial vaginosis is a common condition in which the balance of bacteria inside the vagina becomes disrupted. Bacterial vaginosis can cause an abnormal discharge and unpleasant odour, and it is one of the most common reasons women seek reproductive health care, although many women have no symptoms. We do not understand the causes of bacterial vaginosis or how to control it long-term. Importantly, it is a risk factor for premature births, pelvic inflammatory disease, and sexually transmitted infections, including HIV. This is of particular concern among women at high risk for HIV infection where bacterial vaginosis is also highly prevalent. In a study among female sex workers in Kampala, Uganda, we found that 56% of the women had bacterial vaginosis, and after treatment, 72% of these women tested positive again within 3 months. Developing more robust treatment for bacterial vaginosis is important for HIV prevention in key populations at increased risk for HIV infection. Several types of hormonal contraceptives have been shown to decrease a woman&apos;s risk of bacterial vaginosis, including an injectable progestin-only contraceptive called depot medroxyprogesterone acetate (DMPA). However, the use of DMPA to prevent bacterial vaginosis is problematic because there is evidence that DMPA also increases the risk of HIV infection. Thus, there is a paradox: both bacterial vaginosis and DMPA are risk factors for HIV infection, yet DMPA is protective against recurrent bacterial vaginosis. DMPA is the most popular form of hormonal contraceptive in East and Southern Africa. However, there is growing evidence that newer forms of progestin-only injectable contraceptives, such as norethisterone enantate (NET-EN) do not have a harmful effect on HIV risk. Newer contraceptives such as NET-EN may serve a dual purpose of preventing recurrent bacterial vaginosis and increasing options for safe, acceptable and reliable hormonal contraception among women at high risk for HIV. To date, no published studies have investigated the effect of NET-EN on vaginal bacteria. Safe and effective hormonal contraception may augment current or future treatment for women with recurrent bacterial vaginosis, but we need to know more about the effects of non-DMPA hormonal contraception on the vaginal bacteria and reproductive tract.  We work with a cohort of female sex workers in Kampala, Uganda. Approximately one quarter of women in this cohort use DMPA, and no women use NET-EN even though it is available from the clinic. We plan to carry out a study to investigate the effects of NET-EN and DMPA on a wide range of outcomes, including vaginal bacteria, in this cohort. We will invite women who are HIV negative and bacterial vaginosis positive to join our study. All women will be treated for bacterial vaginosis. Consenting women who are not currently using a type of reliable contraceptive will be allocated at random to receive either NET-EN plus condoms or condoms only. Consenting women already using DMPA will also be enrolled. Both groups will be followed 7 months to see the effects on the vaginal bacteria and reproductive tract. We will also interview women who have started NET-EN as a part of this study to find out their opinion about using NET-EN. Outcomes from this study will provide information for future treatment trials for both bacterial vaginosis and HIV prevention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-07-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="UG" type="UGANDA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-21">251278.18</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-21">258645.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-21">235253.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The injectable progestin-only contraceptive depot medroxyprogesterone acetate (DMPA) may decrease prevalence and recurrence of bacterial vaginosis (BV), but increase the risk of HIV infection. Encouraging women to start an alternative injectable progestin contraceptive, such as norethisterone enantate (NET-EN), may mitigate HIV risk whilst decreasing the risk of recurrent BV. Safe and effective hormonal contraception may augment current or future (e.g. probiotic) treatment for women with recurrent BV, but more evidence is needed on the effects of non-DMPA hormonal contraception on the vaginal microbiota and mucosal inflammatory markers.  The proposed study, Hormonal Contraception &amp; BV (HCBV), will investigate the effect of NET-EN and DMPA on recurrent BV, vaginal microbiota and inflammatory markers among women at high risk for HIV in the Good Health for Women Project (GHWP) in Kampala, Uganda. The hypothesis is that NET-EN will show a similar beneficial effect on recurrent BV and vaginal microbiota as DMPA, without inducing signs of mucosal inflammation. The specific objectives are to 1. Compare the time to second BV diagnosis (i.e. recurrence) between women randomised to NET-EN plus condoms and condoms-only (primary comparison group) and women currently using DMPA and condoms-only (secondary comparison group) 2. Compare the composition, abundance and stability of the vaginal microbiota between the primary and secondary comparison groups 3. Compare markers of inflammation between the primary and secondary comparison groups 4. Assess the acceptability of, and adherence to, NET-EN among women initiating NET-EN.  All women will need to meet the following inclusion criteria: enrolment in the GHWP for 6 months or longer; aged between 18 and 35 years; BV positive; HIV negative; and meet WHO medical eligibility criteria for hormonal contraception use. The study will have randomised and observational components. Women who are not currently on a reliable contraceptive will be invited to enrol for randomisation to either NET-EN plus condoms or condoms only. Women who are currently using DMPA will be invited to enrol as an observational comparison group.  Eligible and consenting women will be interviewed for socio-demographic information, family planning/reproductive health, sexual behaviour and medical history. A gynaecological examination will be carried out, and samples for sexually transmitted infections, vaginal microbiota and inflammatory markers obtained. Women will be treated for BV. Women who are eligible and consent for randomization will be randomised to either NET-EN plus condoms or condoms only; women currently on DMPA will continue with DMPA. Participants will be asked to attend for follow-up after 1 week, and then at 1, 3, 5 and 7 months. Sequential in-depth interviews will be carried out to assess the acceptability of, and adherence to, NET-EN among a sub-sample of women who have initiated use as a part of the study. Outcomes  Objective 1: Nugent scoring will be used to diagnose BV, and survival analysis will be carried out to assess the time to diagnosis of recurrent BV by the primary and secondary comparison groups using Cox regression analyses. Objective 2: 16sRNA sequencing will be used to characterise the vagina microbiota, and bioinformatic clustering techniques to categorise the microbiota by diversity and abundance into community state types. Logistic regression with random effects will be carried out to assess association of community state types accounting for within women correlation by the primary and secondary comparison groups. Objective 3: Concentrations of 24 different cytokines and chemokines will be measured using Luminex multiplex. Linear regression and logistic regression will be used to investigate differences by the primary and secondary comparison groups. Objectives 4: Data from interviews will be used to describe factors that support or reduce acceptability of, or adherence to, NET-EN."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">172400.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">78878.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">75983.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">63270.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">60665.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">58726.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">58509.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">58914.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">58914.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">58914.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N023692_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
