<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R014922_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Health Drivers of Antibacterial Resistance in Thailand</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Like many Overseas Development Assistance (ODA) countries, and particularly those in South and South East Asia, Health and well-being in Thailand is significantly undermined by the high prevalence of antibacterial drug resistance (ABR) in disease-causing bacteria found in humans, animals and the environment. ABR reduces the ability of doctors to treat infections with antibiotics and other antibacterial drugs, with an estimated impact on Thailand in 2010 of 38,000 deaths and an economic loss of 1.2 billion US$. ABR rates continue to rise and its impact is rising in parallel.  Because of the threat of ABR, the Thai National Strategic Plan on Antimicrobial Resistance (2017-2022) has been instigated. This will involve improved national surveillance for ABR bacteria to quantify the problem, initiatives to reduce the rates of infections and those to reduce the usage of antibiotics and other antibacterial drugs, which are known to select for ABR bacteria. However, even when this strategic plan starts to pay dividends, there will be much still to learn about ABR in Thailand, and in other ODA countries, as is also true for developed countries where ABR reduction strategies have been in place for some time.  In this development project, we will build on partnerships we have already initiated between UK and Thai clinicians and academics. We will develop a consortium grant application to address knowledge gaps about ABR in Thailand, which we have identified through discussions between UK and Thai partners. The consortium will consider whether chemicals in the environment - present naturally or as a result of agricultural pollution (e.g. herbicide use) - can select for ABR bacteria. This would render strategies to reduce antibiotic use less effective in reducing ABR in a community where chemical pollution of the environment is common. We will also consider whether ABR bacteria circulate within local environments in rural Thailand, and will measure how this changes over time as the Thai National Strategic Plan on Antimicrobial Resistance progresses. We will perform research aimed at understanding key behaviours around antibiotic use by farmers, farm management practices, and how people make decisions around healthcare. We will use the information that we generate from the microbiology, genomic and chemical screens and the anthropological research to produce mathematical models that can be used to predict useful changes that can be made to reduce ABR in Thailand and other ODA countries. We will also help Thai policymakers  evaluate the effectiveness of changes initiated through the Thai National Strategic Plan. Finally, we will develop technologies that will be used to streamline our research; technologies that may also be useful to help local communities tackle the problem of ABR.  During the development project we will run a series of workshops in Thailand, which will be used to develop the details of our proposed research project and to identify the study sites we will use. These workshops will also give us the opportunity to share knowledge amongst Thai and UK ABR experts, and bring together a group of early career academics, to raise the knowledge base around ABR in Thailand. We will also discuss postgraduate education strategies, and public engagement events in Thailand. The development phase will also involve a comprehensive investigation of policymaking around ABR in Thailand, enabling us to tailor our consortium research project to the needs and knowledge gaps  of these groups and individuals</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our aim is to develop an inter-disciplinary consortium grant application for a project that will provide a holistic, One Health view of the cultural, behavioural, environmental and chemical drivers of antibacterial drug resistance (ABR) in rural Thailand. The research is designed to have a positive impact on human health and well-being in Thailand and other Overseas Development Assistance Countries, by revealing and prioritising possible interventions aimed at reducing ABR in bacteria carried by humans, animals and in the environment in rural communities. Furthermore, our consortium research will allow evaluation of existing and proposed ABR-reducing interventions announced as part of the Thai National Strategic Plan on AMR (2017-2022).  In order to develop this consortium application, during the development phase, we will:  1: Plan and run a three-day series of workshops at Mahidol University and Chulabhorn Research Institute, Bangkok in November 2017 to be attended by 20 UK participants (14 CoIs, 5 additional collaborators and one research analyst) and 20 Thai participants (5 Thai CoIs, 9 Thai collaborators, plus additional Thai participants invited to be part of the stakeholder analysis (see below).  2: Report the outcomes of this development event by way of a defined programme of research to address each of our main research aims (see below), and to define a series of study sites in rural Thailand representative of common environmental and agriculture/aquaculture systems. Using follow-up teleconferences etc, we work these reports together to produce a full application for consortium funding.  3: Informant interviews will be conducted ahead of the workshops to develop an initial mapping of the ABR policy landscape in Thailand. Then, during the development workshops, we will conduct an initial stakeholder analysis, which will seek to map key stakeholders at local, regional and national levels relevant to the research, with membership of a stakeholder group being informed by the initial mapping exercise.   4: Report on the outcomes of the initial stakeholder analysis so that it can be used during the development of our full consortium application, but also by others.  5: During the workshops and throughout the development phase, we will generate impact from this new collaborative framework. We will focus on establishing a UK/Thai postgraduate student and early career ABR research network; we will engage with industrial partners around technology development; we will share expertise and best practice concerning public and professional engagement around ABR and antibacterial drug usage reduction.  The aims of our consortium research project, to be developed here are:   1: To categorise the relative importance of environmental and anthropogenic factors that influence the selection and transmission of ABR in a One Health context in rural Thailand.  2: To uncover social and cultural drivers of the anthropogenic factors under study.  3: To test the effectiveness of existing interventions aimed at reducing ABR in Thailand, and to develop an ABR-reducing intervention model, holistically representing the cultural, social and environmental influences that we identify.  4: To develop novel technologies that allow field-ready identification and quantification of ABR bacteria in resource-poor settings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-02">35412.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">35412.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R014922_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">23682.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R014922_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
