<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S005021_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Strategic Award to establish an International Centre for Genomic Medicine in Neuromuscular Diseases</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Neuromuscular Diseases (NMD) affect at least 17 million children and adults globally. They cause either premature death or are chronic diseases causing lifelong disability with economic impact. They include many different disorders affecting muscle and nerve function and account for ~20% of all non-infectious neurological diseases. Examples include muscular dystrophies, congenital myopathies, neuropathies, motor neuron diseases, muscle channelopathies and mitochondrial diseases. Advances in genetics have improved our ability to diagnose patients in the UK, and this has resulted in improved patient care and enabled clinical trials. However the benefits of genetic advances have not been realised in Official Development Assistance (ODA) defined Lower and Middle Income Countries (LMICs), partly because of a lack of neurologists trained specifically in genomic NMD medicine.  NMDs are commonly genetic and are inherited. Identifying genetic pathways and applying genetic testing has led to some of the most important advances in disease understanding alongside patient management plans and the development of new therapies. Many of the key interventions involve the inexpensive practical applications of widely available medical technology (e.g. low-cost off-licence medication, targeted vaccination, cardiac monitoring and respiratory care), but their application is contingent on making a precise diagnosis. For example, a precise genetic diagnosis can lead to a personalised and often simple management plan following established care guidelines that includes basic screening for known complications (e.g. cardiac, respiratory, gastroenterological and metabolic) and often simple interventions that improve health outcomes - interventions that could be implemented easily in LMICs providing an accurate genetic diagnosis is made. In the UK, a muscle biopsy has been the mainstay in the investigation algorithm in many patients, but this requires a specialist laboratory equipped for frozen section analysis with a growing panel of diagnostic antibodies. However, recent advances in genomics provide the opportunity to diagnose with high precision based on a DNA sample and clinical data collected remotely.  Our central objective is to build ethnically diverse cohorts of children and adults with NMDs and undertake genomic analysis to find known and identify new disease genes. We will increase the number of patients with a precise genetic diagnosis to both improve patient care and to increase knowledge on the comparative genetic architecture of NMDs across four continents.  This is a brand new transcontinental programme led by UK professors at UCL, Newcastle and Cambridge Universities. The research programme will train a new generation of academic doctors, generate the world&apos;s largest cohort of 15,000 ethnically diverse NMD patients and will investigate the causative genes. We will work with five LMIC clinical and academic centres in: India, Turkey, South Africa, Zambia and Brazil. The trained doctors will be the future clinical academic leaders to undertake research and improve NMD patient care in these countries. The fellows will already be fully trained in neurology and will spend a year in the UK for specialist training in NMD genomic medicine and spend three years in their country building NMD patient cohorts that will be assessed in detail clinically and will undergo full genetic analysis to achieve a precise diagnosis and optimise patient management. All data produced will be anonymised and shared by all researchers. Importantly, we have access to several thousand ethnically matched control DNAs already and will build this control resource further, complementing those available through the Genomics England 100,000 genomes project, the NIHR BioResource and international collaborative resources. We will train a new generation of NMD doctors who will pursue their research career in their own country, discover new genes and improve patient care.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our Mission To create a transcontinental genomics research and capacity building partnership between the UK and Official Development Assistance Lower and Middle Income Countries (ODA-LMICs) with an initial focus on India, Brazil, South Africa, Zambia &amp; Turkey. We will discover new disease genes, define the genetic variants in known neuromuscular genes, understand comparative genetic architecture in different populations and explore disease mechanisms. We will dramatically increase the number of patients with an accurate genetic diagnosis, build &quot;trial ready&quot; cohorts and ultimately improve health outcomes for patients with this unmet health need drawn from a combined population of over 1.5 billion people.  Our Vision To deliver a mature transcontinental clinical academic partnership led by a new group of outstanding clinical academics graduated from our training programme. They will be an enduring locally sustained legacy of expertise and they will harness genomics to improve the lives and health outcomes of children and adults with serious neuromuscular diseases (NMDs).  Objectives 1. Establish an international clinical fellowship training programme to generate a group of highly trained clinical academics who will be a legacy of leaders in personalised genomic medicine in the LMICs. These fellows will establish enduring mutually beneficial collaborative scientific links with the UK NMD clinical and genetic expertise based in Newcastle, Cambridge and UCL. 2. Establish a core international bioinformatics platform, pipeline and cloud-based clinical and genetic database. Openly share phenotypic and genetic data and encourage other LMICs to join this collaborative programme.  3. Build ethnically diverse cohorts of children and adults with NMDs which we will deeply phenotype and comprehensively genotype. 4. Identify known and new disease genes and assess comparative genetic architecture of NMDs across four continents. Use this knowledge to understand phenotypic variability, disease progression and disease mechanisms. 5. Increase the number of patients in LMICs with a precise genetic diagnosis ultimately enabling delivery of a personalised disease management plan, based on care guidelines to identify and manage complications using widely available and cheap interventions to improve health outcomes. 6. Enhance genetic diagnostics in UK-based Indian, Brazilian, Turkish &amp; African NMD patients. 7. Build sustainability after five years, through retention of trained fellows in LMICs and through collaboration with host institutions, patient organisations, and local health care providers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-05-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-05-09">3214179.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/S005021/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">168619.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S005021_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">168619.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S005021_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">168619.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S005021_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">168619.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S005021_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">169984.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S005021_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">169984.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S005021_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FS005021%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-06-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
