<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024405_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Public Health Initiative on LMIC Air Pollution (PHILAP)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Air pollution is a major concern in the burgeoning urban centres in low and middle income countries. It captures the complex relationship humans have with environments and how the environment impacts human health. Indeed, air pollution is shaped not only by geographic locations and local practices, but by global structures of socio-economic development as well. PHILAP brings together a multidisciplinary team of clinical epidemiologists and ethnographers, computer scientists and social scientists, informaticians and statisticians, animators and designers, to bear their expertise on this complex and multifaceted problem. PHILAP therefore presents a unique opportunity to combine a range of qualitative approaches together with scientific methods, protocols and wearable wireless sensor technology to address the following objectives which are equally important:  1. To gauge the level of burden of disease among vulnerable populations such as asthmatic adolescents, especially ones living in the margins of society, and how might approaches to mitigating asthma in adolescents be feasibly applied in Delhi, India. We will estimate the exposure-response relationships between ambient concentration levels of particulates (PM10, PM2.5), and respiratory parameters such as breathing rate/flow, by collecting contemporaneously personal exposure and respiratory data using novel body-worn sensors.  2. To understand how young people&apos;s sense-making of asthma and its causes impact on the actions they take to confront asthma, and the social factors that impact on mitigation options. PHILAP will adapt an eco-social approach, using a set of established methods for placing epidemiological data into environmental and social contexts. We will investigate how factors such as gender, occupation, nutritional practices, schooling status and medical beliefs combine with exposure to contribute to asthma prevalence, as well as important variations in long-term strategies for developing resilience.  3. To communicate effectively scientific and ethnographic data on urban health concerns to the communities for which they are intended. Employing participatory methods and practices of knowledge co-production, PHILAP addresses a major theme in global health: the obligation to generate relevant scientific evidence for the public. Resulting from a series of participatory activities, the animation MEMEs will explore ways of presenting, or &apos;designing&apos;, the social and scientific data to encourage debate and critical reflection between science and its publics. Inspired by developments in the digital humanities that emphasise the inventive capacity of our research methods, PHILAP will not only re-present scientific findings in visual ways, but will also interpret these in relation to the social and cultural context of urban Delhi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The PHILAP proposal brings together a multidisciplinary team with a range of expertise to bear on the problem of health effects of air pollution in Delhi, India which is not only a critical case but also a microcosm of a wider global health concern in low and middle income countries, tied up with questions of social justice and equity. In particular, PHILAP seeks to characterise the burden of asthma in adolescents living in the slums of Delhi - a marginalised section of the population who have dropped out of the school system and are engaged in ad-hoc work in the informal sector. PHILAP will employ state-of-the-art miniature wearable sensors currently deployed in Delhi in the MRC-/NERC-funded (2016-21) DAPHNE (Delhi Air Pollution: Health and Effects) as part of the Air Pollution and Human Health (APHH) - Delhi programme, to measure actual personal exposure to particulate pollution and contemporaneously recording its physiological effects, such as changes in the respiratory rate/flow and physical activity levels, with the aim of correlating disease control of asthma with air pollution exposure. These measurements will be situated, and made sense of, in the social and cultural contexts of people&apos;s everyday lives through ethnographic fieldwork and interviews. By engaging the ethnographic data in dialogue with the scientific data of urban air pollution and exposure and its clinical effects, we hope to unpick the multiple strands in the entwined health dimensions of breathing and living with air pollution. PHILAP will harness these vast data-sets, produced and mobilised across the work-packages, into a series of public facing visual narratives that seek to foster dialogue at the interface of science, arts and humanities research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-01">166146.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R024405/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">166146.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024405_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">23112</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R024405_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007790">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR024405%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
