<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development and evaluation of system dynamics methods to engage with policy makers on the prevention and control of diabetes in a middle income region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diabetes is a serious and growing problem globally. Evidence suggests diabetes disproportionately affects people in low- and middle-income countries, where 80% of people with diabetes live, both in terms of numbers of people affected as well as outcomes and deaths. Diabetes affects between 10 and 20% of the adult population in the Caribbean region with deaths due to diabetes estimated to be 35% higher than in the neighbouring United States. Not only are prevalence and mortality a large burden but also rates of complications such as lower-limb amputation are also high. Much of the high burden of diabetes can be attributed to major risk factors such as physical inactivity and obesity.  Health systems with limited resources in these developing countries are struggling to meet the growing epidemic. There is a strong political will in the region to tackle diabetes and other non-communicable diseases (NCDs). In 2007, the Heads of Government of the Caribbean Community put forth the Port of Spain Declaration (POSD) on NCDs, definitively challenging the high burden of these diseases in the region and pledging action through policies to strengthen prevention and treatment.  This laid the groundwork for a global political movement to recognise NCDs on the public health agenda culminating in the United Nations High Level (UNHLM) meeting on NCDs in September 2011.  Both the POSD and UNHLM strongly emphasise the importance of policy measures for reducing NCD risk factors and put forth policies and targets.  However, evidence on how to achieve a reduction in overweight/obesity and physical inactivity and subsequently reducing NCDs at the population level is scarce, particularly in developing countries. While the risk factors and determinants of NCDs like diabetes are well studied and established, research has not been able to conclusively demonstrate real-world interventions that can reduce their popburden or change the course of the epidemic.   Systems science, which combines multiple factors and complex interrelationships, may offer a solution to evaluating and testing policies for diabetes reduction. It does this by explicitly taking into account system behaviour that is non-linear and complex, with feedback loops and time delays. Within systems science, system dynamics modelling is a methodology incorporating input from experts and stakeholders and combining that with quantitative research evidence to produce a map of a system with the ability to simulate outcomes by changing parameters. The approach has been used effectively in a wide variety of fields including engineering, agriculture, energy planning, business dynamics, and health including diabetes. However, few models have been developed for use in middle-income countries.  This study will be the first to explicitly develop a model for diabetes in developing countries, drawing from work successfully conducted by the Centers for Disease Control in the United States and their model for diabetes. The study will apply the rigorous qualitative methods required by interviewing stakeholders, experts and policy makers in the region as well as gathering evidence from research published on risk factors, outcomes, and health system performance for diabetes in the Caribbean. The study will use the developed model to engage stakeholders and policy makers in time for the on going evaluation of the POSD as a tool for effective policy planning. It will also evaluate the utility of this method in the region in engaging policy makers to think in terms of systems and with long time horizons. The results of this development study will be used to build a larger model incorporating economics and costs, which can then be adapted and used in other low- and middle-income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-22" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-15">17526.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-06-15">70195.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overarching aim towards which this development grant will contribute is to develop and evaluate system dynamics modelling to engage with and assist policy makers in LMICs in setting priorities for diabetes prevention and control.   The main objectives for this development grant are to:  1. Undertake with policy makers and other stakeholders in-depth interviews and a quantitative data evidence review on the systems driving obesity, physical inactivity and access to effective diabetes care; 2. Develop accordingly a model for use in the Caribbean, based on the conceptual models and evidence reviews; 3. Use with policy makers the simulation model to explore the potential impacts and interactions of different policy options, including the feasibility of achieving relevant targets from the WHO Global Monitoring Framework; 4. Evaluate from the perspectives of the policy makers and stakeholders the utility of both the qualitative and quantitative aspects of the modelling process.  Meeting these objectives will enable guidance to be produced on using SDM, both qualitative and quantitative aspects, to engage with policy makers in other LMIC settings, and to expand the use of the simulation model to incorporate costing of policy interventions."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q1">17526.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q2">17526.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">17526.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">17616.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">17616.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">15390.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">-17616.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005384_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the West Indies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
