<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005803_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Activating the Arts for International Development: Community Education, Innovative Models and Transnational Networks</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;Precarious Publishing in Latin America: Relations, meaning and community in movement&apos; (hereafter &apos;Precarious Publishing&apos;) is an ongoing AHRC project funded by the Global Challenges Research Fund from 2018 to 2020. &apos;Precarious Publishing&apos; focuses on a contemporary publishing phenomenon known in Latin America as editoriales cartoneras, often translated as &apos;cardboard publishing&apos;, because one feature that unites these 250 community organisations is the material from which they make their books: recycled cardboard. Yet the term &apos;cartonera&apos; encompasses far more than the word &apos;cardboard&apos;. It is also a reference to the cartonero figure - the cardboard collector or waste picker, a consequence of economic crisis, unemployment and poverty - that was so central in the formation of the first cartonera publisher Eloisa Cartonera in Buenos Aires (2003). Fifteen years on, some of these publishers, like Eloisa and Dulcineia (S&#xE3;o Paulo), continue to work with waste-pickers. Many others have recycled the model of promoting change through community workshops, adapting it to address specific social and economic challenges: some work with groups of school children from marginalized rural areas, others with human rights in conflict zones, and others still, promoting sustainable production and consumption of materials and other resources.   The &apos;Precarious Publishing&apos; research team has developed an innovative and interdisciplinary methodological framework to research on - and contribute to - cartonera practices in Mexico and Brazil. This framework is composed of a constellation of collaborative methods, including encuentros cartoneros (round-table debates and open forum discussions), co-publications, exhibitions, and workshops. The &apos;Activating the Arts&apos; Follow-on-Funding develops the potential for impact arising from this process, by creating unforeseen pathways arising from ongoing engagement with our cartonera collaborators. Together, we have identified the cartonera workshop as the most robust and portable model of community outreach activity, able as it is to respond and adapt to different short and long-term development challenges. Our Follow on Funding brings together academics from Durham University and the University of Surrey, four cartonera publishers (two in Mexico, two in Brazil) - project collaborators with whom the research team have strong existing working relations - and other public stakeholders from the Ministry of Education in Mexico to the Director of the M&#xE1;rio de Andrade Library in S&#xE3;o Paulo. Together, we will build, test, share and track an innovative programme of collaborative, creative workshops focused on education for sustainable development (ESD). The four cartonera publishers have been chosen because of their existing engagement with different global challenges, most particularly their work relating to inclusive and quality education; sustainable cities and communities; tackling stigma and inequality; and the promotion of peace and justice.   &apos;Activating the Arts&apos;, will first pilot 4 sets of 15 workshops in rural and urban locations in Mexico and Brazil. These workshops will incorporate reflection with action, artistic creativity with social awareness, to build capacity to respond to specific local challenges - which in turn map onto global challenges including quality education, equality, peace and justice, and sustainability. On the basis of this pilot, we will then create a cartonera outreach programme - designed to instantiate multidimensional social and welfare impact - to be shared with all cartonera actors and their collaborators working in NGOs, social movements, and other social initiatives. The potential scalability of this portable socio-artistic model, combined with the transnational networks and collaborations that are already in place, provides an exciting opportunity to build capacity for sustainable development in hard-to-reach, marginalized communities in LMICs across and beyond Latin America.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-02-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-20">84069.77</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Our aim is to develop innovative approaches to International Development in Latin America that are underpinned by methods located within the arts. By putting into practice the research findings from our &apos;Precarious Publishing&apos; AHRC Research project, we seek to mobilise the networked potential of the cartonera artistic model to propose dynamic engagements with community solutions to global problems.   Objectives include:  1. To design and run four pilot cartonera workshop projects aimed at tackling different global challenges in Mexican and Brazilian rural and urban community contexts through equitable partnerships. These will have different areas of focus (and corresponding titles), which map onto specific, though interrelated, global challenges: A/ Cartoneras for Education, led by project collaborator Catapoesia, which will focus on (and model)  inclusive and quality education in the context of rural communities in Brazil; B/ Cartoneras for Equality, led by project collaborator Dulcin&#xE9;ia Catadora, which will concentrate on tackling stigma and inequality in the context of a marginalised social housing project in the centre of Sao Paulo; C/ Cartoneras for Peace, which will strengthen our Guadalajara-based project collaborators&apos; partnership with Mexican peace and justice movements through workshops that are at once reflexive and creative, reparative and constructive; and D/ Cartoneras for Sustainability, which will build on the work of project collaborator La Cartonera (Cuernavaca, Morelos, Mexico) with indigenous communities to tackle environmental challenges through indigenous approaches to holistic, self-determined development.  2. To understand, assess, and analyse the implementation and outcomes of the pilot projects through a horizontal process of qualitative data analysis with project collaborators involving reflexive semi-structured interviews. This will focus on: the specific methods used in both rural and urban workshops to engage with the above global challenges; participant responses to these different cartonera models; the potential pathways to impact of workshop activities in diverse communities.   3. To develop, through collaboration, an interdisciplinary cartonera workshop programme, to include open access capacity-building PDF materials and documentary tutorial films. Together, these materials will offer a detailed methodology for any reader/viewer (whether a cartonera publisher, a social movement actor, an NGO member or a member of the general public) interested in setting up the programme in their own location. They will include: some context about the cartonera movement and how it relates to different global challenges; practicalities of the workshops (lists of materials required, techniques, timeframes, possible locations, etc.); descriptions of person-centred pedagogies and collaborative methods based on our pilot workshops; and relevant contacts in key locations. This will be shared, through our project website, social media and YouTube, across a) the 250 strong cartonera network across and beyond Latin America (from Bolivia and Ecuador to Mozambique and China); and b) NGOs and activist groups focusing on education, human rights and sustainability in LMICs, through cartoneras&apos; existing connections and networks.   4. To design a model through which to track and capture the reach of the above collaborative programme as it is taken up across  transnational cartonera networks (beyond the lifespan of the grant). This will consist a range of different qualitative and quantitative methods to include: the capture of download metrics and video views; ongoing discussions and feedback through our project website and social media presence; semi-structured interviews with project collaborators and participants; the creation of an online questionnaire built into our website."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">84069.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005803_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">-396.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005803_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
