<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N007220_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-led Heritage Regeneration in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The purpose of this project will be to establish how regeneration initiatives involving local communities in &apos;edge&apos; and forgotten areas can: - Identify alternative historic narratives of place, local values, tangible and intangible heritage; - Use these as a basis for modest interventions and regeneration schemes that improve the lived-in environment and the shared public spaces that frame them; - Combine and use improvements to deliver socio-economic benefits to the locality, including through tourism  - Establish how heritage preservation can have city-wide impact including the integrity of the city, improved quality of life for residents and its appeal to visitors. The academic objectives and outputs of the project will be:  - Through a pilot case study research ways in which &apos;edge&apos; areas can be regenerated through community-led processes to protect their heritage assets and deliver local and city-wide regeneration (and tourism) benefits.  - To evaluate the most effective tools in engaging local communities in shaping their environment alongside public authorities and non-governmental stakeholders.  - Establish and develop academic networks that include non-academic partners to further this research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research network application proposes an action-research methodology for two University partners, Oxford Brookes University and the School of Planning and Architecture, Delhi to develop appropriate methodologies for and actively engage in &apos;community-led heritage regeneration&apos; in collaboration with local NGO, Center for Urban and Regional Excellence (CURE), public sector authorities and experts with the participation of local communities.   Through a selected pilot project, focusing on the Mughal river front gardens of Agra, and the communities residing along the riverfront, the project aims to explore a model of urban conservation which is both community led and community driven.  Additionally in mapping and addressing the issues pertaining to the neglected historic gardens along the river front it attempts to bring the river, the river edge and its associated natural and cultural ecologies back into the lives of the larger population of Agra.   The city of Agra is synonymous with Mughal history and Mughal architecture and as such is a major draw for tourism. However, the economic benefits of tourism are only being enjoyed by a select few, with few trickle down benefits. While the city has grown in all directions, it has turned its back to the river and the built and landscape heritage on its banks, even as the major landmarks like the Taj Mahal and Agra Fort stand out as exceptions. Some of the surviving Mughal gardens, besides being tourist spots, continue to give respite to the people of Agra, as the green lung of the city. The river edge has also changed its character from that of an elite area to one housing the poor and the marginalized in large pockets.  The existence of these historic gardens, and attempts at their conservation, offer a unique opportunity to not only help reconnect the riverfront to the city, but also through community driven conservation proposals which engage the communities with the heritage surrounding them, can provide livelihood opportunities, which in turn would improve the quality of life and habitat of the communities residing in these areas.   The project proposes to bring together academics, researchers, practitioners and representatives from NGOs and local government organisations to: - Establish ways in which community led urban conservation projects can be initiated in the India context, identify challenges and opportunities (workshop 1); - Develop methodologies for gathering/understanding values from local communities and other stakeholders (workshop 1) - Test these methodologies on a &apos;live&apos; pilot project in Agra (action-research), using postgraduate students from the School of Planning and Architecture, Delhi and Oxford Brookes University (live project field work) - Working with the students in a shared and collaborative project, develop regeneration project proposals for the area that considers the rehabilitation and conservation of the architectural heritage, the revitalisation of urban spaces and in particular the waterfront, and considers the feasibility of the project and the social and economic benefits it can bring to the communities, locality and the city (live project, internal workshops at the Universities) - Through a series of locally organised events including exhibitions, public participatory workshops and presentations engage a range of stakeholders in recognising the potential for caring for the heritage and engaging with the processes that can achieve results (workshop 2 and dissemination event) - Demonstrate to the city authorities and other potential donors the potential and value of the historic environment in the urban regeneration process (dissemination)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-04" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-03" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-11">24519.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-11">465874.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N007220_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Oxford Brookes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FN007220%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-12-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
