<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00816X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding the role of music and sound in conflict transformation: The Mozambique Case Study</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Music making is known to have benefits for social cohesion. As a social practice, music depends on personal interaction, dialogue, agreement on conventions and trust. Previous work on music and conflict has highlighted the transformative power of music and demonstrated that activity in this area has a direct impact on conflict resolution, peacebuilding and reconciliation. This research is conducted with the Mahamba group in Maputo, Mozambique towards a case study that evaluates existing practices while introducing new strategies from the sonic arts to expand these practices and produce a new participatory radiophonic piece which reflects relationships between sound and conflict.  This project employs multiple methodologies to address three research phases which focus on the effectiveness of participatory music making, training of community leaders in sonic arts methods and strategies in order to expand their practice and finally the co-creation of a one-hour participatory sound piece for radio which employs field recordings and interviews to reflect personal stories and narratives of conflict embedded in the everyday. By combining methods and approaches from social sciences, arts and humanities we aim to address the arts in a society marked by conflict from multiple perspectives. A recognition of the complexities of the role of the arts, and more specifically sound and music has led to the development of a research programme which is highly participatory and with direct impact to those involved.  The project aims to make a contribution to conflict resolution and peace building in Mozambique. This contribution is focused on the opportunities offered by art provision (specifically music and sonic arts) in societies destroyed by conflict. The project&apos;s activities are aimed to identify and promote good practices which can make a contribution to welfare.  The project partners are the Eduardo Modlane University, and the Mahamba group in Maputo, Mozambique.  Mahamba is a music and theatre group founded in 1995 in Maputo and has 6 core members and with regular project activity. They produce shows in Portuguese, English and Tsonga and have regular cultural production in Mozambique and abroad (e.g. South Africa, Denmark, Brasil). Mahamba runs regular training programmes in association with international NGOs and local schools, and are heavily involved in civic education and social action.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project aims to make a contribution to conflict resolution and peace building in Rwanda. This contribution is focused on the opportunities offered by art provision (specifically music and sonic arts) in societies destroyed by conflict. The activities proposed in the project are aimed to identify and promote good practices which can make a contribution to welfare.  The project aims to: - Evaluate current Musicians without Borders music programmes in Rwanda, responding to a request from that organisation to have an independent and critical analysis of their practices - Offer training in sonic arts to expand the types of music activities already underway. Training is delivered to community leaders who will subsequently incorporate sonic arts strategies in their practice. - Produce a sonic arts piece in the form of a radiophonic work which reflects everyday life, approaches to conflict, notions of memory and identity. This work is intended to be presented publicly in both Rwanda and the UK. Further objectives are based around disseminating the project to ensure that the research as a reach which is as wide as possible. This will be achieved through the academic networks of the researchers involved and through Musicians without Borders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MZ" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mozambique</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-11">80177.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-11">80177.676</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00816X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FP00816X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
