<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P02906X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Clear Road Ahead- Developing a Combined Technological and Socio-Economic Approach to Freeing Affected Communities from Anti-Vehicle Landmines</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Clearing landmines both saves and improves lives in numerous different ways. Demining can help a community access agricultural land, markets and food supply, schools, hospitals and other essential services, through the clearing of transportation links and routes. By clearing anti-personnel (AP) and anti-vehicle mines (AVMs) from roads and fields, people and communities are reconnected, and this can bring huge socio-economic benefits to developing countries where these are most needed. Clearing AVMs from roads can also be a prerequisite for other aid agencies and government services to access remote communities. It restores freedom of movement and fosters freedom from fear. However, efforts to clear roads and fields from the threat of landmines are complicated by two issues: 1) the slow speed of current demining approaches particularly for certain classes of landmine; and 2) the need to prioritise the order in which different areas and land types are cleared for maximum benefit in the shortest possible timeframe.  We propose a project to tackle both of these issues, creating a new technological tool for detecting landmines alongside a methodology for examining cultural, political, and socio-economic factors at the national, district, and even community levels. This approach can guarantee the deployment of the technology for the greatest possible benefit in the shortest possible time.  To the best of our knowledge this is the first time that a combined strategy of this kind has been attempted. The particular target of the project is minimum-metal AVMs laid in roads and fields, which is a class of landmines that is very difficult to detect by other methods, and thus very slow and costly to clear. Beyond this synergistic approach, the project will benefit from the unique advantages of our proposed technology for the clearance of AVMs. This is because our sensor relies on a frequency-sensitive detection of the explosive material, which is contained in large quantities in anti-vehicle mines. The sensor&apos;s underlying technology is based on a quadrupole resonance (QR) approach, which relies on a simple detection mechanism: a pulse or series of radiofrequency (RF) pulses is applied at a particular frequency for the explosives of interest, and the presence (or absence) of a return signal is sought. As with metal detectors, a specially-designed planar RF antenna is placed close to ground level and fed with a sequence of RF pulses at or close to the QR frequency of the explosive to be detected. The same antenna is then used to detect the weak signals emitted by the explosive following the excitation. The important difference from metal detection is that it is the actual explosive contained within the mine that is detected and not any feature of the mine (such as the casing or the trigger), so the false alarm rate is low. This is particularly important for humanitarian demining, which aims to clear most, if not all, of the landmines in the interrogated terrain.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our overall aim is to make a significant difference in developing countries and communities affected by landmines by delivering a novel, low-cost, portable prototype system designed specifically to clear anti-vehicle mines. The technology will building on the team&apos;s recent development of a prototype for anti-personnel mines. For the first time worldwide, we aim to complement this technological breakthrough with a socio-economic analysis to develop a &quot;priorities selection&quot; demining strategy, which can maximize impact. To achieve this ambitious goal, we are targeting the following objectives which extend beyond a technology development project into a truly interdisciplinary programme: - Reconfigure an already developed quadrupole resonance (QR) sensor to a system designed specifically for the detection of anti-vehicle mines. Innovative hardware design will be complemented with novel signal processing techniques to detect QR responses due to the explosive in signals dominated by noise and interference. - Accelerate adoption of the technology by validating it to the satisfaction of the demining community. This otherwise lengthy process will be facilitated by the close partnership with the HALO trust, which will employ and train people from the mine-affected communities to use the technology.  - Develop a &quot;priorities-selection&quot; mine-clearance strategy by: analysing interactions across social, political and cultural factors, and economic development concerns in the overlap between peacebuilding, political/peace settlements, and reconstruction and demining activities at community and national levels; and, examine the extent and potential participation of affected communities in demining activities and analysing potential impact on peacebuilding and reconstruction across economic, social and political spheres. - Develop a modified &quot;market access&quot; approach to prioritise demining strategies. This will be achieved in four stages: 1) correlate data on the spatial distribution of AVMs with geographical information on their clearance operations; 2) exploit time variation in the demining process to assess its impact on economic activity; 3) employ recently developed techniques in quantitative trade literature, to examine the economy-wide implications of AVMs clearance; 4) combine the previous stages to run policy simulations that allow estimating the likely gains of a centrally coordinated and planned demining strategy. To maximize uptake of the technology by relevant stakeholders, the project&apos;s first stage will focus on delivering hands-on demonstrations of the technology and fostering a dialogue to arrive at a technical solution that maximises value and impact. The second stage will design larger-scale trials of the devices in a number of countries, to further develop a unified concept of operations. The third and final stage will focus on validating our operations further, and disseminating the results throughout the demining community.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-18">251895.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-18">507871.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-18">1011661.248</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P02906X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FP02906X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
