<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF:Thanzi la Onse (Health of All):  Frameworks and analysis to ensure value for money health care - developing theory, changing practice</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In all countries, difficult decisions are needed on how health care is financed, organised and provided for the benefit of populations. Decisions include how to determine and to secure appropriate levels of funding for health care; which interventions to fund; how to pool and distribute resources between geographical localities; and when to invest resources in strengthening key components of the health care system to improve the quality and coverage of existing interventions versus introducing new effective interventions. All health care systems face the reality that the cost of the available opportunities to enhance benefits always exceeds the available funding. The decisions made affect the kinds of interventions provided, who receives health care, who goes without and, ultimately, the magnitude of benefits to populations. Resources are particularly scarce in low-income countries.  For example, total health care spending is US$39 per capita in Malawi, a country that is also highly dependent on aid, representing about 62% of that funding, resulting in local preferences regarding how resources are used having to be balanced against donors&apos; priorities. In sub-Saharan African countries (such as Malawi), the opportunities for improving population benefits are great, but the consequences of getting these decisions wrong are potentially severe in terms of forgone benefits.    Thanzi la Onse (TLO) provides an integrated programme of multi-disciplinary research to inform decisions in low-income settings on health care resource allocation. This challenging policy area lies at the intersection of health, economics and politics. The structure of this proposed research reflects that reality. The centrality of &apos;value for money&apos; in determining domestic and international development activities is now widely accepted, particularly so in low-income countries, but tackling the challenges of policy formulation and resource allocation decisions, given the evidential and institutional constraints faced by health care systems in poor countries, remains an urgent research priority. This work will build research capability to address this need by evaluating alternative policy options in terms of locally-realised health benefits achieved through alternative spending commitments. This requires evaluating the benefits of any commitments and also what is foregone as a result of resource constraints prevailing in health care systems. Understanding the magnitude and distribution of such outcomes is key to ensuring value for money for spending on health.  The value of specific interventions needs to be understood within the context of the health care system in which it is delivered. TLO will study the inter-relationships between the impact of different interventions and policies on population benefits and the range of characteristics of the system in terms of how it funds and delivers care, its weakness and constraints. Research to support decision-making also needs to recognise the potential barriers to its acceptance and implementation, requiring close links with policy-makers. Themes of research in epidemiology and health economics will be complemented by a third theme on politics and governance; realising inter-disciplinary complementarities which hitherto have not been fully exploited.  The initial focus of TLO will be working with policy-makers and informing resource allocation decisions in Malawi and Uganda. This will include modelling the whole health system in Malawi to fully reflect its limited resources, the needs and characteristics of the population and the value of competing claims upon resources. Activities will receive international attention and inform the priorities of international organizations. Over the longer term, the programme is expected to work closely with policy-makers across the east, southern Africa region and beyond to ensure health care delivery is as fully informed as possible by leading research methods.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">384941.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">1373731.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">1359968.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">1691964.45</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">709453.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The core objective of the Thanzi la Onse (&apos;Health of All&apos;) programme is to improve population health and reduce health inequities through enhancing the efficiency and equity of health care provision through data-informed priorisation of resource allocation in low-income settings.  The programme will initially build upon deep-rooted relationships and past research activities in Malawi; which, by some measures, is the world&apos;s poorest nation.  The central goal is for Malawi to become the leading model for the application of government-led, analytically-informed health care decision-making on resource allocation in the African continent.  The depth and scale of activities in Malawi will also have spill-over benefits and inform approaches in other countries.  Regional structures will be supported, including partnership with the East Central and Southern Africa (ECSA) Health Community. These will help facilitate sharing of research experiences and lessons on how sustainable improvement in policy-making from Thanzi la Onse are achieved; the building of capability and advocating for the use of such approaches in other countries.  In Uganda, Thanzi la Onse will support a local research team that will be actively engaged in supporting the use of health economic and modelling analyses for policy-making.  We aim to support research capacity and policy recognition for the programme&apos;s core disciplinary approaches in Uganda within 4 years.  In order to achieve its core objective, Thanzi la Onse will realise five specific short-term aims, to be achieved within the programme&apos;s lifespan:  I. Build an ambitious &apos;whole system and all-disease model&apos; as well as comprehensive analytical methods and implementation strategies to inform the Malawian Government&apos;s health care policy decisions. II. Enhance researcher capability in health economics, disease-modelling, and policy engagement in the Sub-Sahara African region through close collaboration between UK and African researchers based in Malawi and Uganda.   III. Facilitate the strengthening of partnerships between local researchers and Government analysts and decision-makers in Malawi and Uganda to encourage greater collaboration and consultation on future health care policy decisions.  IV. Better inform the UK international development academic and policy-making community about the resource allocation and policy challenges affecting sub-Saharan Africa with the establishment of committed partnerships between UK and African health economics, modelling and political science specialists.  V. Engage with international stakeholders and policymakers to inform this community about the challenges constraining effective resource allocation in the region, and to champion the reflection of and ways to overcome these challenges in future international health care policy guidelines.    The long-term objective of Thanzi la Onse and its legacy initiatives is to adapt the resource allocation methods and strategies to other nations in sub-Saharan Africa, in order to address the resource allocation needs specific to the region&apos;s governments and their citizens.  We expect the policy and social impact of this work to occur at a range of geographic levels (local, national, regional, and international) and over a broad timeframe (short-term within the programme&apos;s lifespan, and longer-term beyond Thanzi la Onse&apos;s initial phase).  Through extensive Impact Realization activities, we aim for the programme to be recognised as a leading international example of collaborative partnership and mutual learning by the full range of global health funder and implementer organizations (e.g. bilateral donors, WHO, BMGF, universities, NGOs).  The Programme&apos;s multi-faceted proposals for capability building will enhance the number of researchers working in the key research disciplines needed to support resource allocation decisions in health, and develop skillsets in those associated with policy in health in low-income settings."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">192309.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">192632.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">342049.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">342049.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">344816.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">344816.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">344816.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">344816.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">336763.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">333571.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">336763.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">336763.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">339478.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P028004_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
