<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T028939_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mosquito-Borne Disease Prevention in Africa- Network (MosquitoNET)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sub-Saharan Africa is characterized by a great mosquito-borne disease burden as well as by the weakest public health infrastructure in the world. One of the key challenges that our proposal aims to tackle is to use digital technologies to combine surveillance and epidemic preparedness and response activities for priority mosquito-borne diseases. The infrastructure and level of support for surveillance, research and training on emerging infectious diseases in Africa are limited and our initiative is directly relevant to developing the necessary tools to accelerate these efforts.   The MosquitoNet partnership brings together researchers, industry, NGOs, policymakers and practitioners to develop digital solutions to development challenges caused by mosquito-borne diseases.  The Network consists of a diverse group of experts and stakeholders from the UK and countries in sub-Saharan Africa, combining local expertise and experience with some of the latest digital innovations, to address current gaps and develop the regional capability for detection and response to mosquito-borne diseases.   Digitally-based technologies such as satellite data and communications, mobile phones, apps, tablets, telemedicine, 3D printing and medical drones can provide digital solutions which mostly by-pass traditional infrastructures or national regulations and cost less than the usual medical equipment.  MosquitoNET will propose the development of digital technologies aiming to improve the reporting, monitoring and controlling of mosquito-borne disease, but also to incorporate aspects of health communications and managed healthcare for remote communities.  This will cover the following areas: - Forecasting and warning of MBDs using freely available earth observation data and satellite-based weather forecasts; - Use of mobile phones to collect near real-time information on the outbreak of mosquito-borne diseases; - Satellite-navigated drones to deliver medicines and diagnostic kits for mosquito-borne diseases;   - Telemedicine tools to enable the communication and sharing of medical information.  The vision for MosquitoNET is to see emerging and new digital innovations make a substantial impact in mosquito-borne diseases in Sub-Saharan Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-03-16"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-22">137931.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The main objectives of the MosquitoNet partnership are to:  A) Bring together researchers, industry, NGOs, policymakers and practitioners to identify digital solutions to development challenges caused by mosquito-borne diseases.  We are proposing the creation of a business led, interdisciplinary research network to work within the Digital Health thematic area, with a focus on improving reporting, monitoring and controlling the spread of mosquito-borne diseases, but also incorporating aspects of health communications and managing healthcare for remote communities.   B) Find the most effective ways that the latest digital innovations can contribute to the reduction of mosquito-borne disease in Africa. This will be achieved by putting together expertise from the UK and from Africa to explore: - The application of each area of digital innovation in a single country or region; - The transfer of successful innovations from country-to-country or region-to-region; - The synergy possible when combining a variety of innovations together.  C) Assess the feasibility of the most promising ideas and combine them to develop a proposal for the second round of DIDA funding.  D) Fill the knowledge gaps that currently exist by facilitating not just North-South learning, but South-South learning and pan-African learning. The network, if funded, would be in the frontline of helping to protect communities in sub-Saharan Africa from major mosquito-borne diseases."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">34482.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T028939_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">H R Wallingford Ltd</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">34482.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T028939_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">H R Wallingford Ltd</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">34482.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T028939_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">H R Wallingford Ltd</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
