<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">After disaster strikes and other stories:  The political construction of Typhoon Pablo in insurgency affected communities in Mindanao</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disasters, such as the Asian tsunami (Sri Lanka &amp; Indonesia), the Indus Floods (Pakistan) and on-going droughts in the Horn of Africa, have increasingly taken place in parts of LMICs affected by violence and conflict. Yet, surprisingly, very little is known about the way in which people living amidst conflict interact with the state, with insurgent groups or the military in the aftermath of the disaster and how this is experienced in their &apos;everyday&apos; lives. The question this research seeks to address is how are climatic disasters locally constructed in communities living with conflict in LMICs? In so doing, this project will help understand the complex political space where development interventions in disaster recovery and rehabilitation take place. Fitting perfectly within the framework of the PaCCS and the GCRF this project project will address a tangible gap in conflict and disaster research. It&apos;s findings will have a significant impact in the design of development policy aimed at improving welfare of communities living in LMICs.  This research project is unique and innovative in the political space that it is interested in studying - the intersection of disasters with conflict. The approach it follows is innovative and risky, drawing together social science scholarship and methods with arts and humanities methods. Additionally in working with non-academic partners proficient in visual methods, this research allows me to build capacity as an early career scholar, interested in developing an interdisciplinary approach to studying the disaster and conflict space in LMICs.  Based on physical and digital ethnographic research in two barangays (villages), in Surigao del Sur and in Manguindanao provinces, in Mindanao this project will politically construct Typhoon Pablo that devastated the southern Philippines in 2012. This region has been facing a protracted armed insurgency between the communist New People&apos;s Army (NPA) and the Islamist, Moro Islamic Liberation Front (MILF), and the state. Though political geography often discusses disasters as a manifestation of state &quot;weakness&quot; that fracture the social contracts between the states and their citizens, allowing insurgent groups to capture this space, my previous research shows such a narrative as being too simplistic. It fails to take into account the complex, haphazard and informal ways in which state-citizen relationships have been forged, invented and reinvented in the postcolonial world.  To explore this complexity, my ethnographic fieldwork will also include twenty digital stories from community members who were affected by Typhoon Pablo and have been living amidst an active insurgency. I will be working with local partners Swito Corp based in Davao City Mindanao, who run an exciting start-up using digital storytelling as a medium of engaging local communities, particularly in areas of conflict resolution and peacebuilding. Additionally a community NGO in Mindanao, PeaceBuilders Community Incorporated (PBCI), with grassroots networks will be collaborators on this project.   This will be one of the first research project exploring local construction of a disaster in a conflict-affected region in an LMIC, such as the Philippines. It is therefore not only an innovative piece of work but in providing a contextual and socially relevant framework through which to understand the disaster and conflict intersection, but can be used to design policy interventions in Mindanao and beyond. Additionally, this project will also be one of the first to use digital storytelling as a method of ethnographic data collection. Thereby, enabling participation of respondents in developing their own digital storyboards and driving their own narrative. A guiding framework in this regard will be provided by the specialist company Limetools Ltd in the UK, experienced in using media and digital storytelling for policy work thereby improving capability of Filipino partners as well.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Very little is known about how communities living with conflict experience climatic disasters, the primary objective of this research project is to address this lacuna in the literature. It will do so by looking at local narratives and understandings of people affected by Typhoon Pablo (2012), in the most conflict affected regions of Mindanao, the provinces of Surigao del Sur and Maguindanao, in southern Philippines. This project will shed light on the lived experience of how disasters and conflict interact in the &apos;everyday&apos; and enable a better understanding of this political space that helps or impedes recovery.   A second objective of this research is to, in the words of Anthony Carrigan, disentangle &apos;disaster studies&apos; from &apos;normative politics&apos;. The project will generate a new body of empirical data through fieldwork in two conflict-affected barangays in Mindanao devastated by Typhoon Pablo. It will re-orient debates away from Eurocentric notions of a state-citizen contract damaged by disasters, creating an enabling space for rebel and armed groups, to developing a more culturally orientated and socially relevant understanding of the intersection of disasters and conflict in LMICs, such as the Philippines. This understanding is critical to addressing policy failures of the security establishment in the post 9-11 world, and of profound significance in designing disaster and development interventions in insurgency affected areas that are often still driven by a &apos;winning hearts and minds&apos; approach.  The third objective of this research is capacity building: for my Filipino partners and myself. As an early career researcher this relatively small research project presents the perfect opportunity to take on an innovative and challenging research project using new technologies and involving multiple partners. While for Switco Corp in Mindanao the collaboration with Limetools Ltd in the UK providing guidance and advise on how to get the most out of the digital stories can prove truly transformative in the their development from a small start-up to digital and media experts at a regional scale. Hence building in-country expertise in the Philippines to undertake such international development projects.   The fourth objective showcases innovation, and is one I find most exciting as an ethnographer - to explore the potential of digital storytelling as a research method in ethnographic research. Allowing participants to tell their own stories and be their own data collectors has immense promise. This research project provides me with an excellent opportunity to work with; a dynamic and small start up, Swito Corp and a community based NGO PeaceBuilding Community Inc (PBCI) in Davao City, Mindanao, to explore the value of digital storytelling as an emancipatory and empowering research method. Instead of assuming that people in conflict affected regions of LMICs, such as Mindanao, politically construct disasters through a discursive lens, of fractured social contracts and rebel groups as alternative political agents to the state. This research project enables agents to construct their own story in words and videos, in an attempt to take us a step closer, &quot;towards a postcolonial disaster studies&quot;.     In line with this call&apos;s specific interest in &quot;hidden, forgotten or suppressed conflict narratives&quot;, the research project&apos;s fifth objective is to use people&apos;s experiences of Typhoon Pablo to understand the ways in which a conflict spanning five decades is &apos;naturalised&apos; by people in their everyday lives. At a time when Filipino newspapers are printing articles that state &quot;Surigao del Sur to be insurgency free by end 2016&quot;, there is a real risk of losing the chance to study a conflict that the military is keen to show no longer exists. This new data will be disseminated to a range of academic and non-academic audiences in the UK and the Philippines through publications, conferences and events with policy makers in London and Manil</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-09">64506.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-09">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-09">43228.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-09">43496</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">32253.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">0.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">0.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">0.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">43228.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">43496</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">5566.21</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P008194_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Holloway, Univ of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
