<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009905_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To Work and Back: Exploring Palestinian Labour Mobility and its Development Effects on the West Bank</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mobility is one of the key development challenges in the Global South. This is reflected in the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, which underlines the role of labour migration through well-managed policies for promoting inclusive economic growth and productive employment (United Nations 2015). Labour migration from the Palestinian West Bank into Israeli jobs has a history that goes back nearly fifty years, and has played a central role in the dynamics of the regional political economy (Farsakh 2005; Hanieh 2006). Increasing the mobility and deepening the inclusion of migrant workers is often considered to enhance development goals. But in this context of political and geographic segregation (Yiftachel 2001) and systematic de-development (Roy 2004), inclusion and labour mobility have disempowering side-effects that limit the benefits for the economy and social wellbeing in Palestinian home areas. This project will build on key-insights about the role of unequal mobility gained from the PhD thesis on Palestinians in Tel Aviv. It will include six weeks of additional research to study the impact of Palestinian labour migration into Israel on the workers&apos; home areas in the West Bank. The objective is to generate important empirical evidence that will help to avoid the negative development effects of disempowering labour mobility. This Fellowship will serve as a catalyst in moving from the PhD research towards a comprehensive analysis of Palestinian labour mobility. Through knowledge exchange and research the project will broaden the analytical scope towards the wider political economy of Israel/Palestine while also tightening the conceptual grip around key-dimensions of unequal mobility that emerged from the thesis. A strategic partnership with the International Labour Organization (ILO) will ensure that conceptual innovation is followed by instrumental impact on policies. Combining sustainable user engagement with a focused career development programme, intensive publishing and minor additional research, this programme builds capacity from the PhD thesis on Palestinian labour mobility and from the evidence provided by publications on the relationship between mobility, inequality and conflict (Hackl et al. 2016; Hackl 2016b; Hackl 2016c; Hackl 2016a). The main objectives of the proposed fellowship programme are to: *Build on the PhD through focused knowledge-exchange and targeted additional research to produce effective outputs with impact on practitioners and academic networks. *Produce evidence and disseminate insights on labour mobility in face-to-face meetings and briefings so governmental and non-governmental agents for change can strengthen the social and economic resilience of people in occupied territories with concrete measures. *Work closely with the mentors to produce research outputs in leading journals and to develop a book proposal. *Increase the impact and quality of publication outputs from the PhD through targeted international collaboration with key-experts and research networks at the School of Social and Political Sciences at the University of Melbourne and at SOAS London. *Contribute to the development of innovative policies and shifts in applied thinking through a strategic partnership with the Regional Office for the Arab States of International Labour Organization (ILO). *Develop a new competitive research proposal on the basis of the PhD research with the mentor and international key-experts. *Grow essential skills for a successful career after the Fellowship: **Participation in workshops at the Institute for Academic Development (IAD) in Edinburgh: &apos;Getting the First Lecturing Job&apos;, &apos;How to Peer-Review Manuscripts for Journals&apos;, and &apos;Practical Project Management for Researchers&apos;. **One month of advanced Arabic training to replenish fluency at the intensive summer programme of the Institut fran&#xE7;ais duProche-Orient (IFPO) in Beirut (where the ILO&apos;s regional office is located).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One in four people live in fragile and conflict affected states and the role of secure labour mobility is essential to enhance resilience of affected populations: a sustainable level of security, justice and jobs helps to &apos;break cycles of insecurity and reduce the risk of their recurrence&apos; (World Bank 2011). This project examines the contribution of labour mobility to socio-economic development and resilience in the Palestinian West Bank against the backdrop of inequality, segregation and conflict. The focus is on Palestinian labourers who move into Israeli workspaces in daily and often strenuous commutes. Generating empirical evidence on the diverse effects of labour migration in this context will illuminate new opportunities for governmental and non-governmental interventions that strengthen the positive impact of labour mobility. This research is particularly important at a time when numbers of Palestinian workers in Israel have risen steadily for several years with some 92,000 Palestinians currently working in Israel and another 36,000 in Jewish settlements in the West Bank (BOI 2015). Palestinian labour commuters have played a key role in shaping economic growth patterns and in securing jobs and income, but their mobility also increased dependence on Israel and undermined sustainable growth at home (Farsakh 2005; Hanieh 2006). Palestinians in the West Bank increasingly face an obligation to keep on circulating due to increasing demand for &apos;cheap labour&apos; in Israel and lacking opportunities at home. A better understanding of how the empowering and disempowering dimensions of labour mobility intersect is essential for the building of social and economic resilience despite an intractable conflict and ongoing military occupation. &apos;Economic resilience&apos; is meant to decrease the vulnerability of economies to crises or disasters by strengthening their capacity to absorb &apos;shocks&apos; and achieve growth (R&#xF6;hn 2015; Hallegatte 2014). However, in the context of the West Bank these &apos;shocks&apos; have been institutionalised in relations of systematic economic &apos;de-development&apos; (Roy 1999), intermittent closures and legal segregation (Weizman 2012; Yiftachel 2001), as well as economic dependency of the Palestinian periphery on the Israeli core (Portugali 1993; Roy 2004). This has consequences for questions about how social and economic resilience, as one form of &apos;getting-by&apos; under occupation (Allen 2008), can be strengthened in inclusive and sustainable ways without further deepening dependency. Despite the benefits of comparably higher wages in Israel the positive spill-over effects into Palestinians&apos; home areas remain severely limited by legal exploitation, widespread fatigue and unreasonable commutes. Building on these conceptual underpinnings, the proposed work-programme has five pillars: a) Research and analysis: generate new insights about how the disempowering effects of labour mobility can be alleviated with concrete policy-interventions, based on two years of PhD research on Palestinian employment in Israeli workspaces and on additional research to be conducted for six weeks in the West Bank. b) Knowledge exchange and impact: maximize the academic and non-academic impact of the research outputs through strategic partnerships with users, targeted academic collaboration and the publication and dissemination of high-quality evidence. c) Sustainable partnerships: engage in a strategic and sustainable partnership with the ILO to inform UN policies on labour migration while developing important skills in effective user engagement. d) Academic collaboration: collaborate with key-researchers and projects in order to achieve the highest possible quality of publication outputs during the fellowship and to establish a sustainable international network. e) Skills development: develop the skills necessary for securing a position after the Fellowship with the help of career development workshops, courses and well-structured mentoring.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-03" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PS" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">West Bank and Gaza Strip</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Post Doctoral Fellowship Award to University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009905_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP009905%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
