<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S003517_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">What aspects of participatory design can help urban revitalisation; in particular in the restructuring of former industrial zones in China.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Post-industrial sites in Chinese cities are being redeveloped as catalysts for the regeneration of urban areas. Examples such as Beijing&apos;s 798 Art Zone and 751 D-park are exemplars of this strategy, tuning into the creative cultures of these cities to provide platforms for creative enterprises to flourish. The success of these projects in driving the development of China&apos;s creative economy has led to a number of copy-cat redevelopment projects, creating a blueprint for the format of industrial zones and cultural parks in cities around the country. While many urban renewal projects are ambitious in seeking to foster economic growth, they often fail to respond to the different contexts of each location within the design and planning. So, although performing well commercially through providing retail and entertainment facilities, they perform poorly in providing other opportunities for developing local enterprise, or addressing social welfare needs. This is particularly pertinent for the development of local creative economies, where an understanding of local skills, trading histories, cultural heritage, and the social narratives that bind cohesive community identity, can help deliver more effective and sustainable regeneration strategies.    In responding to these issues, this proposal aims to establish a multi-disciplinary research network of UK &amp; Chinese academics to pursue research activities through engagement with cultural organisations, commercial stakeholders, and other constituent groups in both Europe and China. The investigation focuses on generating alternative strategies for sustainable urban renewal of China&apos;s post-industrial areas. In the search for new drivers of growth, China is moving from a model of expansion, to one of revitalising its urban areas. As western economies have expanded from manufacturing-based to service-orientated sectors, so the creative industries in China become increasing important in stimulating its future economic growth.  This proposal focuses attention on the three Chinese cities of Shenyang, Dalian, and Wushan, Each of the areas offer particular histories, social demographics, economic characteristics, and cultural identities, that afford different opportunities for regeneration though a diversity of creative economy activities. Post-industrial sites within each city, currently earmarked for potential re-generation have been identified by the research partners, providing a focus for the research investigations in each location.  Led by Liverpool John Moores University, UK, the project will run together with the three Chinese partners that include: The Public Art Centre of China National Academy of Paint (CNAP), Luxun Academy of Fine Arts (LAFA) and Dalian Polytechnic University (DPU). Academics and creative industry practitioners from these institutions will engage in a series of research activities, employing an evidence-based research methodology through each stage of the project, including case study analysis, ethnographic studies, and participatory design-led workshops. Promoting inclusion and critical analysis will be highly important in balancing potentially competing agendas such as social welfare, commercial enterprise, and centric urban renewal strategies.The delivery of spatial concepts for the urban renewal of the specified locations, an on-line web resource, industrial handbook, and series of dissemination events, plus associated publications, will provide an effective means of informing stakeholders in future planning and investment strategies, therefore answering the core needs of the audience as outlined by the research funding call.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal aims to establish a multi-disciplinary research network of UK &amp; Chinese academics to pursue research activities through engagement with cultural and commercial stakeholders, and other constituent groups. Utilising observational and participatory research methods the researchers will investigate alternative strategies for sustainable urban renewal of China&apos;s in post-industrial areas.  This will be achieved through the following objectives:  To explore how both cultures may benefit from shared dialogue, a combined study of existing precedents in Europe and China will be conducted, where the spatial redevelopment of existing sites have been used for, or as part of a regeneration programme linked to promoting the creative economy. This will enable researchers to identify particular issues that have emerged since the regeneration of such sites, and will enable the consideration of how western approaches may, or may not, be suitable to China. Examining what measures of success have been applied, the social and cultural impacts of the regeneration projects within a range of stakeholder groups will be explored.  To generate new knowledge and insight, through identifying the local cultures and social narratives that prevail in the three locations within the cities of Dalian, Shenyang and Wushan, via a programme of participatory activities that incorporate novel, context rich research methods (e.g. &apos;walking interviews&apos;).  To inform urban renewal strategies at a local level, through the development of spatial concepts that target the regeneration of specified sites/locations in Shenyang, Dalian and Wushan. Delivering a series of inclusive stakeholder workshops that will generate strategies in response to the needs and ambitions of particular sites: e.g. the regeneration of the decommissioned cement factory in Wushan.   To provide a greater visibility and promote wider dialogue of the issues being addressed through this research, a series of interim research findings will be published within UK/Chinese academic conferences and relevant journal publications, engaging academics in related fields and other influential stakeholder groups, (a) following the case study analysis, and (b) the participatory design workshop events.  To promote dissemination and critical discussion amongst key stakeholder groups of the conclusive projects findings, the research will be disseminated through regional symposium events, supported via a project website and industry handbook, providing further vehicles for engagement that generates dialogue across regional, national and international perspectives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-10" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-09" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-09" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">32970.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">66208.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">66745.02</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">33507.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">199431.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/S003517/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool John Moores University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FS003517%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-21"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
