<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009875_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Illicit Drug Economies, Governance and Security-Development in the Global South: a Case Study of State-Narco Networks in Post-Transition Bolivia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Conventional policy and academic discourse holds illicit drug economies in the Global South as necessarily violent, and both a cause and consequence of weak institutions, stunted development and general instability.  This thinking has been evident in the repressive counterdrug measures that have dominated the international response to the drug trade in developing nations.  These broad assumptions, though, fail to account for the complex ways in which drug economies become intertwined with local social, political and economic structures.   The nature of these relationships has wide implications, determining, for example: whether or not the drug trade is associated with high-levels of violence; the local political (dis)order and the function of state institutions; and the effects of the drug trade on economic growth and development indicators.  In many cases, the failure to grasp these underlying dynamics has led to damaging unintended policy consequences.  From both a policy and development perspective, then, a more contextualised analysis is needed to improve understanding of the interplay between illicit economies, governance and the security-development nexus in the Global South.  My research adopts such an approach; moving beyond the mainstream orthodoxy to examine a crucial historical case, which continues to hold great contemporary relevance: post-transition Bolivia (1982-1993).    This approach reveals the influence of state-narco networks across different spheres of Bolivian life.  These effects confound the typical expectations of the mainstream discourse on drugs.  First, local trafficking organisations were absorbed into existing political structures, which acted to manage and mediate the violent excesses of the coca-cocaine economy.  While its Andean neighbours descended into various forms of drug-related violence, Bolivia&apos;s illicit trade thus remained relatively peaceful.  Second, tacit-acceptance of drug links running through the military and police was bound to the maintenance of fragile political equilibrium.  As Bolivia made its long-promised transition from authoritarian government, toleration of such practices ensured the continued support of these major political actors for democratisation.  In this sense, the illicit economy was interwoven with Bolivia&apos;s uneven democratic governance.  Third, the booming drug trade helped to stabilise the national economy during crisis and harsh structural reforms.  The coca-cocaine economy acted as a social safety net, providing employment and inward investment, while also bolstering the banking system.  For many Bolivian farmers, coca-cocaine offered the most viable route out of poverty.  Taken together, these factors created ambivalence toward the illicit economy and resistance to the escalation of &apos;destabilising&apos; US counterdrug efforts.    These research findings raise important questions around security, institution building and development in the context of illicit economies.  Such issues remain salient within Bolivia.  The country continues to be a major producer of coca-cocaine and, increasingly, a transit point for the international cocaine trade.  Many rural communities are still reliant on the illicit economy for their income; organised crime and corruption inhibit the function of democratic institutions and the rule of law, with sporadic outbreaks of drug violence in the east of the country.  Looking beyond Bolivia, similar (often, more severe) problems are encountered elsewhere around the globe, from the heightened violence of the Mexican Cartels to the opium fuelled conflict of Afghanistan.  My own research speaks to these cases, providing strong insights into the development challenges posed by illicit economies.  Analysis of these processes is crucial to the formulation of better policy responses; decoupling the drug trade from these countries while avoiding widespread violence, institutional decay and damage to precarious livelihoods.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-01-02"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-17" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="BOLIVIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The research project will address the significant development challenges posed by illicit drug economies in the Global South, examining the interplay between the drug trade, governance and the security-development nexus in the case of post-transition Bolivia.  This provides crucial insights into the processes that underpin the establishment of effective institutions and the maintenance of security and political order, as well as illuminating the illicit drug trade&apos;s interaction with poverty, livelihoods and economic growth.  My approach also reveals the shortcomings of international counterdrug policy responses, frequently criticised for causing further harm to the development prospects of drug producing nations.  The research project, therefore, aims to bring nuance to our understanding of the relationship between drugs and development.  In support of this overarching aim, I will work to achieve a range of objectives: maximise the impact of my research through engagement activities with policy and practitioner audiences, establish professional networks, develop publications in prominent journals, and advance my training and personal development.    I will maximise the impact of my research and enhance my professional networks through the following work strands.  First, I will take-up a three month placement with Red Andina de Informacion (Andean Information Network - AIN) in Bolivia.  This will allow me to share my findings locally and enhance my knowledge of the needs of local academic and user organisations, as well as exploring opportunities for collaboration with Bolivia-based researchers.  This includes delivery of a joint-workshop with El Centro de Investigaciones Sociales (CIS), where I will use existing contacts within the Bolivian Government, the EU Mission to Bolivia, the UNODC and the British Embassy in La Paz to engage key stakeholders, and promote dialogue on the illicit economy&apos;s interaction with issues of governance, security and livelihoods.  This will mirror my work with the Global Drug Policy Observatory (GDPO) and SCIAF to stage a one day conference in Glasgow on the broad theme of research project.  This will be aimed at academics, as well as policymakers (the Scottish Government, DFID and the EU) and practitioners; offering an opportunity for exchange between different sectors and opening my Bolivian research to comparison with other cases in the Global South.  Finally, I will contribute to Christian Aid&apos;s drugs and development agenda by presenting a paper at the NGO&apos;s 2017 conference in London, as well as sitting on the conference organising committee.  This builds on their landmark discussion paper on this topic (Gutierrez, 2015), and will bring together academic and non-academic stakeholders from across the world.  These actions will strengthen capability for research and innovation within Bolivia and the UK, ensure impactful research and bolster my ability to advance effective research with practical application.    I will utilise material from my PhD thesis to establish a strong track record of publications, disseminating my ground-breaking research within academic circles and furthering knowledge of the relationship between the drug trade and development.  I will develop two articles for publication, targeting prominent journals that speak to the themes of the GCRF.  This will include one article based on the main findings of the thesis, addressing the interplay between illicit economies, governance and the security-development nexus in post-transition Bolivia.  In addition to this, I will publish in a Latin American area studies journal on the advancement of the &apos;war on drugs&apos; in Bolivia and its social, political and economic implications.  As part of this, I will submit papers based on these articles for two conferences: ISSDP 2017 and SLAS 2017.  My publication strategy will thus ensure my research findings are distributed widely with high academic impact."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">0.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009875_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009875_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">-0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009875_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
