<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M010015_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DNA hydroxymethylation, TET enzymes and regulation of stem cell activity during skin regeneration and wound healing</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Biological mechanisms that regulate the development of mammals, including humans, continue during the lifespan of individuals and are altered during ageing. As an organ that covers the body, the skin protects us from a variety of environmental insults, such as mechanical injury, ultraviolet irradiation, and variations in temperature. The skin also provides a unique system for studying the mechanisms that control organ development, regeneration and ageing. Skin development results in formation of the epidermis, a stratified self-renewing epithelium. Additional structures of the skin include hair follicles, nails and glands. After birth, the epidermis continuously regenerates using the ability of epithelial stem cells to supply progeny cells that form all epidermal cell layers. Meanwhile, epidermal regeneration, following skin injury, is controlled by stem cells derived from the hair follicle. Data obtained during the last decade has revealed that many cellular biochemical pathways controlling skin development and its postnatal regeneration are of particular importance. Recent data demonstrate that activity of these biochemical pathways is governed by epigenetic regulatory mechanisms. These mechanisms include covalent modifications of the DNA molecule and methylation/hydroxymethylation of the cytosine nucleotides, which play important roles in the control of gene activation and repression. This project will look at how enzymes called Tet1/2/3 that regulate DNA hydroxymethylation  impact normal physiological skin regeneration and when induced by injury. This project will also explore how Tet1/2/3 regulate different molecular signals in epithelial stem cells and their progenies (that form skin and hair follicle epithelium), and their involvement in wound healing. Studying the skin as a model system in this way, will cast light on the mechanisms that control the development and regeneration of other epithelial tissues, such as the epithelia of the intestine, teeth, kidney and lung. The knowledge gained from this study will also provide new opportunities for the development of novel epigenetic therapies to cure aberrant tissue growth and regenerative conditions, such as impaired wound healing in diabetic patients and in elderly individuals.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the era of developing new approaches for stem-cell driven tissue regeneration, it is important to understand how multi-potent stem cells establish distinct programs of gene expression during their differentiation into specialized cell lineages and why these programs are altered in pathological conditions associated either with stem cell loss/exhausting (impaired tissue regeneration, wound healing) or their uncontrolled expansion (cancer, autoimmune disorders)  The long-term goal of this collaborative research programme between Botchkarev&apos;s and Xu&apos;s laboratories is to understand the mechanisms that control the establishment of lineage-specific patterns of gene expression and chromatin organisation in adult stem cells during the process of differentiation into specialised cell types in normal and regenerating epithelia. This proposal represents a logical continuation of an existing collaboration between two laboratories funded in 2012-2013 by MRC/NSFC grant (MR/K008870/1) to undertake the project &quot;Epigenetic control of stem cell activity during epithelial tissue regeneration&quot;, which has already resulted in one joint publication (Development, 2013, 2013, 140, 780-88).   Here, we will extend these studies to address the role of DNA hydroxymethylation and TET (trans-eleven translocation) enzymes in the control of stem cell activity during skin regeneration and wound healing. We will test the hypothesis that Tet1/2/3 proteins are critical determinants that control gene expression programmes in adult epithelial stem cells and their progenies during skin regeneration and wound healing.  The Objectives of this project are: 1) Define the impact of the Tet proteins on self-renewing and differentiation potentials of epithelial stem cells and their progenies during physiological hair cycle-dependent skin regeneration.  2) Identify the role of Tet and 5mC oxidation in the control of activity of skin epithelial stem cells and their lineage-committed progenies (epidermal keratinocytes) during wound healing.  For both Aims, we will use genetically-engineered mice with loss of Tet1/2/3 activities, as well as in vitro and ex vivo models involving human skin for analyses of the dynamics of stem cell activity during physiological skin regeneration, as well as during wound healing. We will isolate epithelial stem cells and their progenies (epidermal and hair matrix keratinocytes) by FACS-sorting to determine the changes in their transcriptomes, genome-wide distribution of 5-methyl/5-hydroxymethylcytosines associated with Tet1/2/3 deficiencies, as well as to correlate these data with the genome-wide distribution of Tet proteins to identify their target genes. We will also define the impact of enzymatic versus non-enzymatic Tet activities to rescue gene expression in skin epithelial stem cells and their progenies by administration of lentiviruses expressing cDNAs encoding enzymatically active or inactive forms of Tet1/2/3. Researchers from both labs will exchange knowledge relevant to their areas of expertise (Botchkarev&apos;s lab - skin and stem cell biology; Xu&apos;s lab  - molecular biology and epigenetics). Xu&apos;s lab will provide genetically engineered mice with loss of Tet1/2/3 activities to Botchkarev&apos;s lab, while Botchkarev&apos;s lab will provide methods for stem cell isolation, culture and functional analyses from mouse and human skin to Xu&apos;s lab. Researchers from both labs will visit each other (3-4 visits per year), as well as communicating on regular basis via e-mail, Skype and telephone to discuss the data and writing manuscripts.    The generated outputs from this project will provide new important insights into fundamental mechanisms that regulate stem cell activity and cell fate decision inside and outside of the skin, and will serve as an important platform for the development of novel epigenetic drugs to target stem cell methylome for the needs of regenerative medicine and stem cell-based therapy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bradford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">43383.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">170105.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">160142.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">120835.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-11-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-17">10878280.688</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Bradford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M010015_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bradford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FM010015%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-02-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
