<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_P003257_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding Cadmium Uptake by Cocoa Plants via Cd Isotope Analyses</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cadmium (Cd) is a trace metal that is highly toxic even at low concentrations. The relatively high Cd abundances often found in cocoa are a serious problem for the cocoa producers of developing nations, as the European Union plans to implement strict new upper limits for Cd in cocoa products in 2019. This development has recently spurred research into the causes of Cd enrichment in cocoa. Such work has mainly focused on the impact of external factors, such as soil type, pH and cultivation practices, on the Cd content of cocoa but until now, these investigations have failed to provide conclusive results. Hence, it has been suggested that Cd accumulation may vary across different cocoa varieties but this possible link has yet to be investigated.  The current project constitutes collaborative research by Prof M Rehkamper, an isotope geochemist at Imperial College London, and Prof J Dunwell, a plant physiologist at the University of Reading. Previous work of Rehkamper has shown that coupled Cd concentration and stable isotope analyses, initially developed for planetary science research, can provide unique insights into Cd uptake and translocation by plants. Furthermore, a 2015 pilot study of Rehkamper and Dunwell revealed that such analyses are also promising for cocoa.  In the current 6-month project, the results of the 2015 pilot experiment will be verified, to ensure that coupled Cd concentration and isotope data indeed provide a reliable measure for Cd uptake by and translocation within plants. Furthermore, a suite of different cocoa varieties will be analysed to characterise the overall variability of Cd uptake and accumulation amongst different types of this plant. Together, the results will enable an initial identification of cocoa varieties that are particularly suitable for cultivation because they feature minimal Cd accumulation in beans, due to low uptake of Cd by the plant and reduced transport from the roots to the fruit. As such, the results of this study can make an important contribution to the development of sustainable methods for the production of cocoa beans with safe levels of Cd, thereby ensuring a reliable source of income for cocoa producers in developing nations and boosting the economies of rural communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching aim of the study is to improve understanding of cadmium (Cd) accumulation in cocoa and contribute to the adoption of cultivation practices that support sustainable production of cocoa with safe levels of Cd. This aim is of particular relevance to cocoa producers of developing countries because the European Union intends to adopt strict new upper limits for Cd in cocoa products in 2019.  The investigation is led by an interdisciplinary team consisting of PI Prof Mark Rehkamper, an isotope geochemist, and Project Partner Prof Jim Dunwell, a plant physiologist. In the proposed 6-month study, coupled Cd concentration and stable isotope measurements, initially developed for meteorite and planetary science research, will be employed in analyses of samples from cultured cocoa plants to address the following objectives: (i) Initial analyses will be carried out to confirm and validate the results of a pilot study, which first revealed that coupled Cd concentration and isotope measurements provide constraints on the efficiency of Cd uptake by cocoa plants and the translocation of Cd within the plants from roots to shoots. (ii) Further analyses of about 30 relevant cocoa genotypes, including varieties of particular economic importance, will be performed to characterize the overall variability of Cd uptake and accumulation amongst different genotypes. (iii) A careful assessment of all available data will be completed to identify cocoa varieties that feature relatively low Cd uptake and minimal translocation to beans, and which should hence be particularly suitable for cultivation. (iv) To achieve impact, the dissemination of results is an important objective. This will be accomplished by direct briefing of cocoa stakeholders on key findings, to ensure that the project can have a positive effect on the cocoa cultivation practices of rural farmers, thereby supporting local economies in developing countries. In addition, the results will be published in a high-profile international journal.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-04">48171.67</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-04">48171.668</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC GCRF Futures Award to Imperial College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_P003257_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ST%2FP003257%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
