<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R00787X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interdisciplinary approach for the management and conservation of UNESCO World Heritage Site of Historic Cairo. Application to Al-Ashraf Street.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt is very rich with archaeological sites. These sites contribute significantly to the tourism industry which is one of the main income sources for the Egyptian economy. However, the management and conservation of these sites is a challenging task due to the ever-increasing threats such as population growth, urbanization, pollution, natural hazards, among others. These threats result in the gradual deterioration of these sites, and hence results in significant economic losses.  Interdisciplinary management is fundamental to the conservation of these sites, particularly when dealing with large areas such as Historic Cairo which contains more than 600 listed historical structures.  Unfortunately, however, Historic Cairo suffers from the following: 1) deterioration of its historical structures at an alarming rate; 2) poor site management; 3) disempowerment of local communities, thus depriving them of their role as main stakeholders and beneficiaries of heritage; 4) deteriorated infrastructure resulting in decrease in quality of life and hampering socio-economic growth; 5) rising of groundwater level inside historical structures; 6) absence of plans for waste management; 7) poor security and safeguard of heritage sites resulting in trespassing on historical structures by misuse, demolition, wrong restorations, illegal construction activities, and so forth; 8) lack of studies related to structural assessment, safety evaluation and health monitoring of its historical structures; and finally 9) absence of plans for adaptive re-use of historical structures after restoration.  All these problems are epitomized in Al-Ashraf street and its historical structures which makes it an ideal choice for the application of this study. The street is about 600m long starting near to Al-Sayeda Nafisa square and ending at the intersection with Ahmed Ibn Tolon street. It contains 8 historical structures dating back mainly to the Fatimid (969-1171) and Mamluk (1250-1517) periods and constructed primarily from stone and brick masonry; among them are the Domes of Al-Ashraf Khalil, Fatma Khatun and Shajar Al-Durr. In specific, the two domes of Al-Ashraf Khalil and Fatma Khatun are suffering from a series problems that may lead to their total loss if no action plans would be taken to conserve them. The research proposed in this project will be highly complementary to previous studies carried out for the conservation of Historic Cairo. In 2010, the URHC (Urban Regeneration of Historic Cairo) (urhcproject.org) was launched by the UNESCO-WHC to assist the Egyptian government in the management of the UNESCO World Heritage Site of Historic Cairo. The URHC project, which was completed in 2014, was concerned with the whole of Historic Cairo. Its wide and overarching scale therefore did not enable detailed studies such as those related to groundwater studies, structural aspects, health monitoring and specific conservation plans, which are all dealt with in this proposal, to be addressed. In contrast, aspects such crafts, violations after the revolution of 25 January 2011, housing rehabilitations, are not given primary focus in this proposal. The proposed research will however make direct use of the findings and recommendations of the URHC study, particularly in terms of using GIS as a management tool, conducting surveys on the local population, and addressing the problem of waste management. Importantly, focusing on only one street within Historic Cairo will enable detailed conservation and intervention methodologies which incorporate disaggregated structural, groundwater, waste management and community-specific solutions to be developed.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research project aims at proposing and applying an interdisciplinary approach for the management and conservation of the UNESCO world heritage site of Historic Cairo. In order to apply and demonstrate the developed methodologies, a part of the site has been selected, namely &quot;Al-Ashraf street&quot;. The proposed project is not meant to be solely an engineering solution for the threats faced by this street but it is intended to provide a holistic approach that could be applied in other areas in Historic Cairo and, more generally, in other archaeological sites in Egypt and in other developing countries. Within this context, the specific objectives of the proposed project are: I. Develop a plan for the management of the historic site. This would include building and/or updating the Geographical Information System (GIS) of the site that includes information about existing structures, heritage value, land use, urban and demographic characteristics and state of urban systems, among others.  II. Consider advanced Structural Health Monitoring (SHM) techniques as a tool in the site management. Continuous monitoring of a site, including deformations and cracking as well as ground water levels, is essential to its management and to assessing physical deterioration so that timely intervention and preventative actions can be undertaken. III. Employ structural assessment studies as part of the site management methodology. These studies will involve detailed safety evaluation of the historical structures under the risks imposed by several natural and environmental hazards, including those arising from seismic events and groundwater/dewatering effects.  IV. Investigate experimentally the effect of rising groundwater levels on the structural characteristics and resilience of masonry load-bearing structural elements replicating the historic fabric of existing structures within the site. V. Devise optimum and non-intrusive intervention techniques that could be adopted for the conservation of representative structures, through laboratory experiments on prototype load-bearing elements replicating the main properties of the historic fabric. VI. Develop fundamental and sustainable solutions for rising groundwater levels inside and around the structures within the site.  VII. Propose sustainable solutions for locations used as garbage dumps. This would include transformation to green areas, thus improving environmental and social conditions for the surrounding community. Groundwater dewatering, as a measure for controlling rising levels, would be considered for the irrigation of these green areas. VIII. Develop suitable waste management plans which are able to mitigate the threats to the public and the environment including those related to health risks and fire hazards.  IX. Propose archaeological conservation plans for the deteriorated historical structures in the site.  X. Allow citizen participation in the street conservation and management based on an understanding of the monument as a resource not a burden.  XI. Integrate all the aforementioned into an interdisciplinary approach for the street conservation and management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-04465125" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-30" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-20">17761.1</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-20">67145.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-20">67657.1</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-20">50025.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-11-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-20">202589.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Large Grants Award to Imperial College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/R00787X/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">17010.71</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R00787X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-07-01">17010.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R00787X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-10-01">16004.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_R00787X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FR00787X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-30"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
