<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N00793X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community Experience of Conflict in Haiti: Assessing the Emotional Legacy of Civilian Deaths as a result of Intense Use of Force by UN Peacekeepers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Wills (Transitional Justice Institute, UU) and McLaughlin (School of Creative Arts, QUB) will collaborate on this inter-disciplinary project, which which will  combine socio-legal research and participatory practice, in order analyse how the law governing UN peacekeepers&apos; use of force is understood and applied in practice, through a case study of the UN Stabilization Mission in Haiti (MINUSTAH); and to explore the impact on local communities of the use of deadly force by peacekeepers. McLaughlin is a documentary filmmaker and professor of film studies. Wills is a professor of law. This project will focus on the use of intense force by MINUSTAH; but the approach could later be applied to other missions operating in situations in which international humanitarian law (IHL, also referred to as ius in bello or law of armed conflict) is inapplicable. Analysis of the effectiveness of the resort to use of deadly force is generally presented from the point of view of the authorities responsible for maintaining law and order, or from the viewpoint of local and international elites; but unless the viewpoints of the people living in the communities where force is used, are also presented, the analysis will be distorted and hence unreliable as a predictor of stability. The project will use participatory documentary film practices (which ensure that participants are co-owners of the project and have control over the use of material in which they appear) as a means by which people that are normally marginalised from international decision-making processes that affect them, may have their voices heard and taken into account in the drafting of UN mission rules of engagement and policy guidelines. The film will enable policy makers to consider  the physical, emotional and psychological (and hence political) effects of the use of deadly force on the people living in the communities in which the UN carries out its operations. Social-legal research on the limitations of a &apos;top-down approach&apos; to controlling political violence suggests that policy makers often fail to take into account the effects of repressive force in creating support for &apos;bottom up&apos; political movements that challenge the legitimacy of the authorities in charge. Two of the major tipping points that trigger violent mobilisation are killings of protestors and prisoner deaths. Under mission specific &apos;Chapter VII&apos; rules of engagement MINUSTAH is authorised to use &apos;deadly force,&apos; if lesser means are ineffective, to &apos;prevent or put a stop to acts of civil unrest,&apos; defined as the &apos;commission, perpetration or instigation of acts of violence which affect public peace and order.&apos; Under both international human rights law and IHL the right to use deadly force against civilians is very limited, except where there is a threat to life that cannot be prevented in another way. Between 2004-2007 scores of people were killed by the UN (initially denied but later admitted) during heavily armed raids into Cit&#xE9; Soleil. MINUSTAH is credited with reducing gang violence and most commentators from within the UN view the raids has having been effective in improving security: but 11 years after it was first deployed the mission remains deeply unpopular. One reason for this (among several) is the number of people not involved in criminal activity, including children, that were killed in UN raids; and MINUSTAH&apos;s response to their deaths. Since the residents of troubled communities rarely write journal articles or produce their own reports (50% of Haiti&apos;s population over the age of 15 is illiterate) their voices are usually mediated through those of their political leaders; who may also represent other interests. Participatory film-making practices allow those most directly affected by violence to tell  their own stories and thus opens up direct channels of communication between the affected communities and the policy makers (many of them from outside Haiti) responsible for making decisions on the use of force</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="HT" type="HAITI"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CARIBBEAN, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1031</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-08">39876.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-08">39876.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Using an inter-disciplinary methodology combining socio-legal research and participatory film practice, to investigate, through a case study of the UN Stabilisation Mission in Haiti (MINUSTAH), how peacekeepers&apos; legal authority to use deadly force, is interpreted (and the effects of this interpretation) in the context of a Ch. VII mandate to carry out stabilisation duties in situations of violence to which international humanitarian law (IHL, sometimes referred to as the ius in bello or law of armed conflict) is inapplicable; but which the Security Council has designated a threat to international peace and security, necessitating the presence of a mission mandated under Ch. VII of the UN Charter.    To use participatory film practices, in conjunction with socio-legal analysis, as a methodology in order to produce a documentary film that will enable the communities most affected by the use of intense force by MINUSTAH, to tell their story. To collaborate between filmmakers and the filmed in order to ensure that participants are involved in all stages of production, from research, through filming and editing, to exhibition.  By facilitating the means for people from Cit&#xE9; Soleil to tell their story in film, to create the opportunity for dialogue between  between marginalised communities affected by violence and the international decision-makers responsible for making &apos;use of force&apos; decisions that affect those communities - in order to explain, understand, and improve relationships, so that the use of lethal force is constrained and human rights are respected.   To determine what principles governed the drafting of MINUSTAH&apos;s rules of engagement; whether MINUSTAH complied with those principles when it carried out a series of major raids in Cit&#xE9; Soleil during 2004-2007; whether the UN considered international human rights law (IHRL) applicable to those operations; and the extent to which IHRL was taken into account when planning those operations.  To determine to what extent deaths of civilian bystanders (&apos;collateral damage&apos;) in the course of UN operations in violence-affected residential communities undermines respect for the UN and its perceived legitimacy in the eyes of affected communities. To explore whether civilian casualties as a result of intense use of force by peacekeepers impact on longer term prospects for stability in host states  To explore whether documentary films, made with violence-affected communities, using participatory practices, offer a means of improving best practice in UN operations by bringing the experience of community members to the attention of the UN and of the actors that influence UN policy.  To explore whether documentary films, made with violence-affected communities, using participatory practices, offer a means of improving or countering some of the widely criticized gaps in the accountability of UN peacekeeping operations and of improving perceived UN legitimacy within such communities.  To publish the results in: 1) a documentary film made using participatory practices working with residents of Cit&#xE9; Soleil 2) a briefing paper setting out the evidence obtained from the study and making policy recommendations as to how the UN might deal with use of force questions when carrying out stabilisation duties in situations to which IHL is inapplicable 3) two articles in peer-review journals   To stimulate discussion and policy consideration of the use of intense force by UN troops operating in situations to which IHL is inapplicable, through an exhibition and dissemination strategy that will include film launches in Port au Prince, London, New York, and a seminar in London to present the briefing paper together with excerpts from the film, with expert guest speakers from the UN, from Haiti, from Haitian academia, military experts, and human rights experts; and a publicity campaign to include social media with Facebook page, film trailer, and background information; blog; and Twitter"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">19938.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N00793X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Ulster</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">9969.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N00793X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Ulster</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">9969.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N00793X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Ulster</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">-0.01</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_N00793X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Ulster</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
