<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N012615_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">PRH/HHEX in intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma, disease progression and response to chemotherapeutics.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cholangiocarcinoma is cancer of the bile ducts that carry bile from the liver to the gall bladder and the small intestine. The number of cases of Cholangiocarcinoma is increasing year by year as is the number of deaths caused by this disease. There are several established risk factors for Cholangiocarcinoma including chronic Hepatitis B and C infection, autoimmune-related diseases such as Primary Sclerosing Cholangitis (PSC), and, in some countries, liver fluke infection. In most cases the disease is very advanced at the time of diagnosis and only around 30% of patients are suitable for surgery. New treatment options and biomarkers that allow early detection and/or inform personalised cancer treatment for individual patients are urgently needed. Under normal circumstances cell proliferation, cell-cell contacts and cell movement are carefully controlled and a large part this control is brought about by proteins called transcription factors that determine which genes are turned on or off in our cells and thereby determine how each cell behaves. We are studying a transcription factor called PRH/HHEX that is essential for liver and bile duct formation because this factor can inhibit many important pathways in the cell that are known to be required for cancer cell division and movement. In this project we will investigate the importance of PRH in cholangiocarcinoma. Using samples taken from patients with cholangiocarcinoma we have already shown that PRH levels are reduced in cholangiocarcinoma cells. The aim of this project is to investigate this in more detail using a larger number of samples. We will also identify genes that are regulated by PRH in cholangiocarcinoma cells and we will determine whether the products of these genes, or PRH itself, can be used as biomarkers to predict how quickly the cancer will progress or even allow us to identify people at risk of developing cholangiocarcinoma before they show symptoms of the disease. We will also determine whether changes in PRH activity alter the ability cholangiocarcinoma cells to form tumours in mice and we will examine whether changes in PRH these cells makes them more or less sensitive to drugs that are used to treat this disease. Finally we think that the re-establishment of PRH activity in cholangiocarcinoma could be a useful strategy for cancer treatment. We will test this using drugs that prevent protein modifications that we have previously shown to result in PRH inactivation and PRH degradation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma (ICC) has a very poor prognosis, on current treatment less than 5% survival at 12 months, and increasing in incidence and mortality. ICC is prevalent in South-East Asia including Thailand partly as a consequence of liver fluke infection. Other global risk factors include cirrhosis and primary sclerosing cholangitis (PSC). The etiology of PSC is unknown but thought to be linked to autoimmune activation which causes bile duct fibrosis, destruction and in a significant proportion of patients with advanced disease, malignant transition. ICC is usually advanced at presentation and although serum alkaline phosphatase and CA 19-9 and CA-125 may be elevated, these markers are not specific to ICC. There is therefore a pressing unmet clinical need for new treatment approaches and earlier diagnosis.  The transcription factor PRH/HHEX is essential for liver and bile duct formation. In adult epithelium PRH has a tumour suppressive role and PRH activity is down-regulated in liver, breast, and thyroid cancer. PRH is a direct transcriptional regulator of multiple growth factors and growth factor receptors. Our work has shown that decreased PRH levels in breast cancer cells results in epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT), increased proliferation, and altered sensitivity to chemotherapeutics such as Cisplatin. We have also shown that Protein Kinase CK2 phosphorylates PRH resulting in PRH inactivation and PRH degradation. Moreover, pharmacological treatments that inhibit CK2 block PRH phosphorylation and PRH is required for many of the biological effects of these agents. PRH levels are reduced in ductal primary ICC compared to normal liver and in ICC cell lines compared to primary cholangiocytes whereas pPRH levels are maintained or increased. Thus PRH and pPRH show opposite changes in ICC, in keeping with the inhibitory effects of PRH on cell proliferation and EMT and the opposite effects of PRH phosphorylation. A multicentre clinical trial of the CK2 inhibitor CX-4945 in combination with Cisplatin and Gemcitabine for the treatment of ICC is expected to report in late 2016. New strategies to stratify patients based on low PRH or elevated pPRH may identify patients who would benefit from this treatment and this would be of great clinical value.  Our aims are: (1) To dissect the relationship between PRH and pPRH levels in ICC and PSC and to determine whether changes in these proteins in patients with established PSC may be a useful marker of disease progression. To achieve this we will perform immunohistochemistry to examine PRH and pPRH levels in formaldehyde-fixed paraffin-embedded ICC and PSC tissue samples. (2) To determine whether restoration of PRH expression inhibits tumour growth in a mouse ICC xenograft model. To achieve this we will use repeated in vivo imaging to (i) measure tumour growth following the implantation of luciferase-labelled PRH over-expression ICC cells in nude mice, and (ii) monitor the appearance of metastases in internal organs (lymph nodes, lungs, and liver) after intravenous injection. (3) To determine whether pharmacological interventions that decrease PRH phosphorylation (CX-4945), would be of value for ICC patients with elevated pPRH. To achieve this we will examine the effects of the CK2 inhibitors and CK2 siRNA on the proliferation and migration/invasion of ICC cells expressing PRH and PRH knockdown ICC cells. (4) To determine whether PRH depletion sensitises ICC cells to chemotherapeutics. To achieve this we will determine whether reduced PRH levels alter the response of ICC cells to Cisplatin and other therapeutics. (5) To investigate whether the products of PRH target genes can be detected in serum for early diagnosis of ICC. To achieve this we will identify PRH target genes in primary cholangiocytes and determine whether the expression secreted PRH target gene products are elevated in ICC cell lines and tissue samples and can be detected in serum from ICC patients.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133784" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-12" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-28" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-11" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">34976.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">150700.83</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">151892.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">71089.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-11-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">444204.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N012615/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN012615%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-28"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
