<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005730_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing Inequalities in Public Engagement in Myanmar</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since October 2017, the AHRC-GCRF funded &apos;Deepening Democracy&apos; programme, run by the Global Research Network on Parliaments and People (GRNPP), has been supporting research into the relationships between Parliaments, politicians and people in Myanmar and Ethiopia, as well as developing a truly global research network in this field.  Within the first year of the programme, two unanticipated developments specific to Myanmar have made it imperative that we take a more active and participatory role in deepening democracy in that country:   1. The Rohingya crisis in Myanmar, which highlights the extent to which the country&apos;s transition to democracy remains incomplete. Many areas and ethnic groups have been persistently excluded from economic development and political participation in Myanmar, creating conditions characterised by instability, weak institutions, and developmental deficits. Similar barriers are evident in the case of women. While social, economic and political exclusion based on ethnicity and gender is not itself a new phenomenon, its entrenchment in Myanmar in recent months is undeniable and requires robust, evidence-based, creatively imagined, and committed action.  2. Limited understanding of how arts and humanities can contribute to political change: It has become evident in the course of our grant-making scheme supporting artists, activists and academics to conduct political research that there is a lack of inter-disciplinary capabilities through which to (i) harness deeper understandings of democracy (and its deficits); (ii) communicate research to non-academic audiences; and (iii) shape and influence policy-making towards more inclusive democratic relationships and experiences. Taken together, these represent a threat to the realisation of impactful change through the arts and humanities.  The &apos;Reducing Inequalities in Public Engagement&apos; (RIPE) project is the outcome of on-going, collaborative, and critical reflection - guided by our partner in Myanmar, the Enlightened Myanmar Research Foundation (EMReF) - about how to address these developments and transform them into opportunities for contributing to change in a positive, engaged, and sustained manner.  The RIPE project seeks to achieve impact through a series of strategies including:  1. Strengthening opportunities for civil society communication and engagement by politicians. This will improve the prospects for long-term peace and stability throughout Myanmar. The creation of a multi-stakeholder Alliance for Inclusive Democracy will work to reduce barriers to public engagement. By strengthening connections between those committed to make institutions more inclusive and better at public engagement, the project will achieve tangible and measurable impact, and enhance inclusive democracy.  2. &apos;Unlocking Creative Potentials in Research&apos;. This training workshop will help develop researchers&apos; capacity to take their findings to public and policy-making audiences in creative and impactful ways that emphasise the role of arts and humanities in understanding, and ultimately reducing, democratic deficits  The RIPE project aims to positively impact ethnic and other under-represented groups in Myanmar who are denied access to, participation in, and representation by Parliament and politicians; and whose lives have become unlivable as a consequence. It will also help establish academics in Myanmar as vital and integral partners in the movement to deepen democracy.  Additionally, the framework of collaborative, collective,  and conscientious action by multiple communities of practice in  Myanmar - which  will underpin the RIPE project - will provide a model for similar processes, practices, and partnerships to evolve in other fragile states, thereby allowing for the transnational flow of key ideas and practices that positively impact inclusive democracy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-02-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="MM" type="MYANMAR"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-20">88561.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Overall aim: To reduce inequalities in public engagement with Parliament and parliamentarians in Myanmar  Objectives  1. Improve public engagement by politicians and other policy-makers in Myanmar with under-represented, at-risk and excluded groups, by improving access to, participation in, and representation of these groups, particularly women and Rohingya, in democratic processes.  Our partners and grantees in the &apos;Deepening Democracy&apos; project (2017-2020) make clear that gendered and ethnic forms of marginalisation and dispossession in Myanmar have become entrenched and even more severe for some. As a consequence, it has become imperative - both as a matter of need and conscience - that we extend our existing &apos;Deepening Democracy&apos; project by focusing directly on influencing politicians. We have been assisting Burmese scholars to give evidence to the UK International Development Select Committee during their inquiry on the Rohingya. The next step is to contribute to shaping a political environment that is sympathetic towards, and committed to, advancing political support for, and protection of, at-risk and excluded groups.  2. Create an &apos;Alliance for Inclusive Democracy&apos; in Myanmar to agree priorities for action by a range of stakeholders and implement strategies to reduce inequalities in engagement between the public, and Parliamentarians and other policy-makers.  Since the commencement of the AHRC-GCRF funded project on &apos;Deepening Democracy&apos; in October 2017, the socio-political landscape in Myanmar has moved towards deficits rather than deepening democracy for its citizens. Enlightened Myanmar Research Foundation (EMReF), our partner in Myanmar, has witnessed these changes, and at their urging we have worked in partnership with them to identify how the Global Research Network on Parliaments and People can seek to intervene and help reshape the narrative around political access, participation and representation in the country. EMReF have identified potential champions for change in Myanmar who currently operate as distinct and isolated communities of practice. By bringing together sympathetic Parliamentarians, other policy-makers, NGOs, CSOs, artists, activists and academics we will promote an &apos;Alliance for Inclusive Democracy&apos; (see Case for Support for more details). This will construct a strong and unified foundation upon which to influence the deepening of democracy in the currently fragmented and fragile democracy of Myanmar, in both the short- and long-term.   3. Enable selected P4P grantees in Myanmar to develop powerful creative research-based outputs that communicate the role of arts and humanities in achieving deeper and more inclusive democracy.  The existing &apos;Deepening Democracy&apos; project includes a grant-giving scheme that supports arts and humanities-based research on Parliaments and people and develops our grantees&apos; inter-disciplinary capabilities. We have, for example, organised ethnographic and historical research training workshops, as well as supporting organisations like the Yangon Film School to deliver film-making courses. In the course of doing so, however, we have become aware that there is limited understanding about the role that arts and humanities research, and the creative industries more generally, can play in deepening understanding of politics and contributing to political change. Therefore, working in collaboration with Positive-Negatives, who are experts in advocacy-through-creativity, we will partner our grantees with creative industry artists to produce research-informed creative products via an &apos;Unlocking Creative Potentials in Political Research&apos; workshop. The outputs from this will be used in communication with non-academic audiences, including policy-makers in Myanmar, to help strengthen the proposition that arts and humanities subjects have an important role to play in creating change. Evaluating this impact will be an integral part of the monitoring we conduct throughout."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">88561.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S005730_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">SOAS University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
