<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S019898_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Point of care tests in the diagnosis of chronic and allergic aspergillosis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chronic and allergic forms of aspergillosis are an increasingly recognised global health problem. They are caused by the fungus Aspergillus, a very common environmental mould. We breathe in fungus particles daily, but we are usually able to clear them from the lungs. In some cases though, the fungus can establish itself in the lung and cause disease. This usually happens in people with weak immune systems, such as after chemotherapy for cancer, but can also happen on a background of chronic lung disease, like previous tuberculosis (TB) or chronic obstructive lung disease (COPD). This disease is termed chronic pulmonary aspergillosis (CPA).  One in 5 people is expected to develop CPA after successful treatment of TB: this means that CPA affects 1.2 million people globally as a consequence of TB. The number of new TB cases in Indonesia exceeds 1 million per year, making Indonesia the country with the 2nd largest number of TB cases in the world. As TB and CPA may present with the same symptoms, CPA may be mistaken and treated as TB. If CPA is not diagnosed and treated, it can result in lung destruction, weight loss, cough and blood in the sputum. Treatment exists in the form of antifungal medication. It is difficult to diagnose CPA, as diagnosis relies on specialist laboratory tests not available in most low and middle-income countries. A point-of-care (POC) blood test, performed in clinic without the need to send the sample to a laboratory would make CPA much easier and cheaper to diagnose.   We plan to use a recently developed POC test that detects Aspergillus antibody in blood in patients who present with suspected but not confirmed TB in Indonesia, and to compare with a standard serological test. The results will be made known to the physicians who can then decide on best treatment. So we can assess the importance of the result, we will follow the patients for 12 months for signs of deterioration in their symptoms and chest X-Ray. We will also compare the outcomes in patients who were treated with antifungal medication for CPA. We hope we can prove that the POC test can be used to diagnose CPA in low and middle-income settings.  In high-income settings where TB is less common, such as the UK, CPA mainly affects patients with chronic respiratory disease like COPD or bronchiectasis. The diagnosis is made by bronchoscopy and testing of bronchoalveolar lavage fluid for Aspergillus; however, the tests are neither sensitive nor specific. Turn around time, even for specialised labs, may be long and cost is high. A POC test for diagnosis of Aspergillus from pulmonary secretions would speed up diagnosis in this setting too. We plan to compare two POC tests with the conventional methods for the diagnosis of CPA in patients having bronchoscopies. As the gold-standard, we will use a new technology to analyse the entire population of fungi in the lung (called the mycobiome).   Allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis (ABPA) complicates 1-4% of cases of asthma globally. It results in poor control of asthma, frequent admissions to hospital and use of long-term steroids which have several side effects. Diagnosis requires either an allergy skin test or blood test. Treatment with antifungals improves symptoms and leads to reduced steroid use. There are more than 13 million asthmatics in Indonesia, and more than 300 thousand with ABPA according to estimates; the majority would be unrecognised if testing is not undertaken. Due to lack of diagnostic facilities, this is the case in most low and middle-income countries. A POC blood test detecting sensitisation to Aspergillus would be ideal for quickly screening patients with poorly controlled asthma. We will screen patients with uncontrolled asthma in Indonesia with the POC test and compare with the standard-of-care blood test. This will help provide an estimate of the rate of ABPA in Indonesia for the first time, and validate the use of this POC test for use in the screening of ABPA.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-04-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ID" type="INDONESIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-18">149471.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-18">111778.41</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="1. To explore the feasibility and performance of point-of-care (POC) testing of Aspergillus IgG for diagnosing chronic pulmonary aspergillosis (CPA) in patients with presumed tuberculosis in Indonesia  We hypothesize that CPA is an important differential diagnosis of smear negative tuberculosis in low and middle-income countries (LMIC) with high rates of TB such as Indonesia. Misdiagnosing CPA as TB results in misuse of anti-TB drugs, high costs and resistance. Missing the diagnosis of CPA results in CPA progression with ongoing lung destruction. Lack of diagnostic facilities in LMIC is the main barrier to distinguishing these 2 entities. A POC test would circumvent the problem by suggesting diagnosis without reliance to a specialist laboratory, while also minimising costs. Patients with suspected but not confirmed TB seen in respiratory clinics in Indonesia will be enrolled and tested with a POC Aspergillus IgG test. This will be compared to a standard serological test already in clinical use. The patients&apos; symptoms and X-Ray findings will be recorded at baseline and followed for 12 months to assess whether a positive Aspergillus serology has an impact on persistence of symptoms. The results of the POC test will be made known to the clinicians. Patients fulfilling the recently proposed algorithm for diagnosis and management CPA in LMIC will be analysed separately in order to provide an operational validation of the algorithm. Workshops on recognition and management of CPA will be undertaken in Indonesia as part of the study. If the POC test is confirmed to be equivalent in performance to the standard of care, it will greatly facilitate testing for CPA in LMIC.  2. To assess POC testing for Aspergillus antigen as a part of the bronchoscopy procedure to rapidly identify patients with suspected aspergillosis in the UK  Diagnosis of CPA is suboptimal even in high income settings, as all tests have poor sensitivity and specificity. Aspergillus galactomannan and Aspergillus PCR increase the sensitivity, they can only be performed in specialist laboratories and the turnaround time can be several days due to batch testing. The performance of these tests is even less well described in patients with chronic lung disease (eg COPD, bronchiectasis) with suspected CPA, which form the majority of cases in TB low-prevalence settings like the UK. In this population, CPA can remain undiagnosed resulting in progression and worsening lung function. Recently, two POC tests to detect Aspergillus antigen in the BAL have become available. We will enrol patients with chronic lung disease (COPD, bronchiectasis) undergoing diagnostic bronchoscopy for lung lesions (eg cavities, infiltrates) where CPA is in the differential diagnosis. We will perform the POC test as well as the standard of care tests. Performance of all tests will be gauged against the subsequent diagnosis of aspergillosis. We will use the lung mycobiome, which will be analysed simultaneously, as a gold standard against which the sensitivity and specificity of all tests will be compared. This study will enhance our understanding of the performance of fungal diagnostic tests in CPA and validate the use of the new POC tests. It will also provide insight for the first time into the dynamics of the lung mycobiome in chronic lung disease.  3. To evaluate whether POC allergy testing assists in the rapid diagnosis of fungal asthma in Indonesia and UK, expediting the optimal use of antifungal therapy in this population  ABPA is a frequent complication of asthma. Diagnosis can be made by Aspergillus specific IgE or skin test. In LMIC, tests may not be available, and the condition will remain unrecognised, whereas timely antifungal treatment has been shown to improve symptoms. We will test patients with uncontrolled asthma for ABPA using 2 POC tests and compare with standard of care to assess whether bedside diagnosis of ABPA is feasible in a LMIC setting and in the"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
