<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_M029239_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">14CONFAP From Comparative genomics to Phylogenomics: uncovering the genomic complexity and evolutionary adaptations of twenty species of protozoa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A fundamental schism exists between organisms with cells such as our own which contain nuclei (eukaryotes), and bacterial cells which do not. The vast majority of eukaryote species are single celled organisms or protozoa displaying enormous genetic diversity leading to huge variation in biology, myriad form and function. In just a few groups of protozoa the ability to parasitize animals such as ourselves has arisen. Kinetoplastids and Diplomonads are two such groups of protozoa which are believed to have diverged from the animal lineage not long after the last eukaryotic common ancestor (close to the root of the eukaryotic tree). Within both groups are important but neglected pathogens of humans - those which cause the deadly vector-borne trypanosomiases and leishmanias; and those that cause the waterborne diahorrea, giardiasis and a variety of other pathogenic species and free living species which are free living rather than parasitic. Comparison of the genomes from pathogenic and apathogenic members of these groups will highlight the evolution of groups of genes encoding proteins which act to circumvent the defences of animal hosts and upon which the pathogenicity and virulence of these organisms depends. Such genes are also key targets for vaccination, drug and monoclonal therapeutics. The proposal brings together an expert team of parasitologists, protozoologists, evolutionary biologists, genome biologists and bioinformaticians from the FioCruz Institute in Brazil and from TGAC and the University of East Anglia in the United Kingdom. The project undertakes to deliver the first high quality genome sequences of twenty kinetoplastid and diplomonad genomes.  The genomes selected will span the breadth of the genetic diversity in these groups and will be analysed in concert with existing genomic data from the key pathogenic species. The technology involved is state of the art and constantly upgraded and the expectation is that the genomes and transcriptomes produced will be of the highest possible quality. There will be a reciprocal exchange of expertise, with bidirectional knowledge transfer of technical and analytical techniques facilitated by exchange visits of key personnel and students. Our basic strategy will be to culture the organisms, making use of the Wolfson laboratory for emerging pathogens at UEA for the culture of the pathogenic members of the group. We will harvest and purify the nucleic acid using a chaotropic buffer to disrupt the cells and silica affinity for nucleic acid purification. Will we use a mixture of methods and technologies to assemble high quality genomes including whole genome sequencing and optical mapping  for the genomes and RNA-seq to delimit the transcriptome. Finally, we will combine the data sets for each lineage to infer details from the genomic complexity relating to evolutionary adaptations for parasitic lifestyle.  In so doing we will establish sustainable collaborations between UK and Brazilian researchers that will lead to publications, and substantial advances in the field upon which the new collaborations can build future projects. Overall, the purpose of these analyses is to add insight into the functional biology of two groups of divergent flagellated protozoans which have independently evolved from free living organisms to major human and animal pathogens. Each group is biologically distinctive and famously defined by peculiarities in cell and molecular biology - elucidating how these peculiarities have evolved and continue to do and their contribution to the evolution of parasitism in these distinct lineages is fundamental biology and will be the primary objective of this work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposal aims to study the evolutionary relationships of Protozoa of Tropical Neglected Diseases, using the phylogenomic approach on 20 Kinetoplastid and Diplomonad genomes of basal kinetoplastid lineages such as Endotrypanum, Herpetomonas, Trypanosoma desterrensis, Trypanoplasma and Azumiobodo hoyamushi and diplomonads including other Giardinae, Hexamitinae and Retortaminidae. It also aims to infer the evolutionary relationships (Phylome) of all proteins of the genomes of these species. Objectives can be highlighted as follows: 1) Use Illumina sequencer (HiSEQ 2500) available at Fiocruz (Brazil) and Pacific Biosciences RS single molecule sequencer (PacBio) available at TGAC (UK) to sequence the genomes of the above-mentioned Kinetoplastida. 2) Undertake RNAseq for each species facilitating semi-automatic (re)annotations (based on phylogenetic similarity and not only on the genomes of Protozoa) 3) Infer the genomic complexity and the evolutionary adaptations for parasitic lifestyle. 4) Establish sustainable collaborations between UK and Brazilian researchers that will lead to publications of the investigations.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Earlham Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-18">10966.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-18">32898.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-18"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-18">701831.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Small Grants Award to Earlham Institute</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_M029239_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Earlham Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FM029239%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
