<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_T005009_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Digital urbanism &amp; diasporas: walking the cultural heritage of Calcutta&apos;s riverfront</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indian cities suffer rapid urbanisation increasing demand for housing, infrastructure and services, causing densification, an increase in lower income households and informal populations in slums and squatter settlements, and urban sprawl.  At the same time, rapid transformations in the digital technologies offer new opportunities to city decision-makers in adopting smart solutions to urban challenges and &apos;smart&apos; city plans offer a digital vision in which all citizens have equal access to and participation in a city life which is safe, secure, inclusive, healthy and desirable. However it remains unclear whether &apos;smart&apos; urbanism is equally inclusive of migrants and diaspora communities, challenging notions of equality and social justice. Here we focus on the tangible and intangible cultural heritage of migrant communities living in one of India&apos;s largest cities - Kolkata. Historically known as Calcutta it has a long and rich tradition of trade, commerce and migration, which has left a lasting legacy in both contemporary society, its traditions, cultures and practices and also in the built environment. Working with local diaspora communities and social enterprises this project will focus on the Hooghly riverfront to engage with, document and co-curate Heritage Walks which narrate the stories of under-represented diaspora heritage in all of its forms. Through the use of social media and digital technologies, as well as public walks and an exhibition, the diversity and traditions of different urban groups will be shared, building increased awareness and understanding, a renewed sense of place and fostering social cohesion. By engaging with municipal authorities, institutions and policymakers this project aims to change the way diaspora heritage is viewed and valued and to inform regional and national heritage conservation policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-12-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-05" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-30">12096.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-30">24193.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="To work collaboratively with a non-academic SME and relevant community groups, to plan, co-design, research and develop different diaspora Heritage Walks, exploring the tangible and intangible heritage assets of different riverfront migrant communities;  To undertake relevant archival research to map and document supporting material to enrich the oral histories and storytelling of the diaspora communities;  To analyse visual information, including contemporary and past photographs and videos of places, people, food, artefacts and festivals and share expertise and knowledge on ways in which they can be useful in digital heritage interventions;  To curate our findings into public walks and to undertake those walks with freely invited members of the public in order to explore migrant and host responses to hidden and under-represented diasporic cultural heritage;  To create a vibrant international network of heritage academics and enthusiasts to share knowledge, understandings and expertise."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
