<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00945X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Augmenting Jordanian Heritage</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) To develop a methodology for the 3D virtual reconstruction of damaged or fragmented heritage objects, statuary, and monuments. 2) To produce high quality digital 3D records of a sample of artefacts and monuments at high risk such that they can be reconstructed if damaged or destroyed. 3) To produce high quality digital 3D data of fragmented objects of historical or cultural significance located at the Jordan Museum and to reconstruct them in virtual space. 4) Train staff at the Jordan Museum to be able to undertake the task of 3D digital recording of objects. 5) Develop an immersive public display system within the Jordan Museum for the presentation of reconstructed heritage objects and monument. 6) Enhance the existing Jordan Museum website (Jordanmuseum.jo) with engaging virtual content of the museum and its collections by adding 3D virtual object manipulation tools and spherical virtual walk around content. 7) Contact relevant museums and organisations engaged in the preservation and reconstruction of sites impacted by war, earthquakes, or climate change to determine where we can provide assistance and to prepare future research activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is an enhancement to the AHRC &apos;Fragmented Heritage&apos; project, which aims to revolutionize landscape, site, and artefact analyses by bringing new transformative digital recording methods and computed analysis to fields that are traditionally labour intensive. The scale of the resultant technology and capability will generate a paradigm shift in the way that spatial and functional data are studied in the heritage sciences. Fragmented Heritage has developed a means for refitting knapped (flaked) stone tools. In this extension of that research, we aim to apply the method to reconstruct broken and fragmented heritage objects and monuments that have sustained damage as a result of human and natural agencies. This cutting edge research will provide museums and heritage sites the opportunity: 1) to record their important heritage materials in 3D; 2) to refit fragmented heritage objects digitally, which can then be displayed in 360 degrees; 3) to decide whether to repair the fragmented object physically using the digital model as a guide. This research allows us to contribute much more directly to public outreach in places where disasters such as war and earthquakes have impacted on the great heritage that exists or once existed.  Until now no one has been able to produce a methodology to refit broken three dimensional objects back together digitally. Our methodology is at the very forefront of heritage and engineering sciences. By demonstrating this research at the Jordan Museum, we expect the results will greatly impact on the heritage fields (e.g., archaeology, history, conservation), and for museums and organisations specialized in the presentation and distribution of heritage understanding. This project extension serves to bring direct capacity and capability to the heritage infrastructure in Jordan and to afford the same to other ODA countries as a result of interactions during project dissemination.  The aim is to transform the existing virtual presence of The Jordan Museum. We will digitally reconstruct a sample of fragmented heritage objects to demonstrate the potential application of the 3D refit methodology for objects, statuary, and monuments damaged as a result of climate change, warfare, earthquakes and other harmful events. It builds on the existing Fragmented Heritage project by translating and applying research conducted as part of that program of research in the area of digital refitting and presentation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="MIDDLE EAST, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-10">205954.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">102977.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00945X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bradford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">102977.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P00945X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bradford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
