<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T022078_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A systems approach to examining health sector responses to cholera epidemics in Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives of the study  The aim of the study is to examine the health sector responses to cholera epidemics, to develop a systems-theory-based description of the said responses, and to further provide recommendations that may help break their continuous and cyclical nature.  Consequently, the specific objectives of the study are: 1. To examine the health sector responses to cholera epidemics through the development of a system-theory-based description of the responses in order to break the continuous and cyclical nature of cholera in Kenya 2. To explore pathways to strengthening the resilience of health systems in the delivery of health services in emergencies and outbreaks 3. To assess the utility of a health systems approach in preparing for and responding to health emergencies 4. To provoke the development of a research agenda around health emergencies using systems analytic techniques that parallel healthcare  And as may be evident from the above objectives, we are convinced that an understanding of how the building blocks of the health systems interact, especially during health emergencies, will have a profound effect on how to effectively strengthen the response systems and hopefully break the cyclical nature of the cholera epidemics as experienced in Kenya in recent years. Thus, in taking this systems perspective, the research is focused on the following research questions: 1. What was the nature of the health system responses in Garissa and Turkana to the health crisis occasioned by the cholera outbreak? 2. What was the impact of the health crisis occasioned by the cholera outbreak on the local (county-level) health system? 3. What decisions, actions and factors could have contributed to the performance of the health system in responding to this crisis? 4. What vertical and/or horizontal integration issues in the health system, if any, could have impacted on the performance of the health system in responding to the health crisis?  5. How resilient are the local health systems in their ability to absorb humanitarian crises and continue to deliver services after the crises is over?</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Simple Summary Kenya has experienced an increased disease burden due to cholera outbreaks characterized by continuous transmission in the refugee camp settings of Garissa and Turkana, and sporadic transmission in cities such as Nairobi and Mombasa. However, while inquiry has been made regarding how the health sector has responded to and how populations have been impacted by epidemics such as cholera, not enough attention has been paid to causal relationships between the unique components of the health systems leading to an inadequate understanding of how the building blocks of the health systems interact in disease surveillance and epidemic response. Consequently, this research effort focuses on examining the health sector responses to these epidemics, developing a systems-theory-based description of the said responses, and based on the results, provide recommendations that may help break the epidemic&apos;s continuous and cyclical nature.  The study will be conducted in Turkana and Garissa in Kenya, as well as in Nairobi. These are counties that have diverse levels of health system sophistication and recent experiences of cholera epidemics. Moreover, the study draws on several systems analytic frameworks to determine the actors and their decisions, as well as their inter-relationships, linkages and dependencies. Thus, the study appropriates systems-oriented research techniques and applies them in a novel fashion to the assessment of health service delivery. The findings of this study are expected to guide interventions aimed at improving disease surveillance and epidemic response. The study will also act as a primer for the research community by assessing the utility of systems-thinking approaches in such settings, and subsequently opening a related research agenda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-28">45857.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-28">45012.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-28">159840.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to Strathmore University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T022078_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT022078%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
