<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003583_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF: Developing an Environmentally-adjusted Index for Multidimensional Poverty</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The intersection of poverty and environment policies that is the focus of the Sustainable Development Goals provides an important opportunity for the use of secondary data. Whilst both areas have been intensively individually studied, most if not all globally accepted poverty indicators have ignored the role of the natural environment.  ESRC funded research programmes such as ESPA (Ecosystem Services for Poverty Alleviation) have furthermore highlighted that much of the ecosystem services literature in low and middle income countries has been primarily concerned with the role of ecosystems as an instrument for getting food, energy or better living standards (i.e. ecosystem&apos;s provisioning services). However, there is growing recognition that being able to engage with the natural environment in a meaningful way (culturally, spiritually) and the ability to withstand shocks and reduce vulnerability through access to nature are intrinsically valuable, in addition to the generally accepted provisioning services. These dimensions of human dependence on nature are so-called &apos;functionings&apos; in the Capabilities Approach, developed by Amartya Sen (1999), and allow people to live a &apos;good life&apos;. This approach forms the theoretical basis of the well known Multidimensional Poverty Index (MPI), officially used by over 100 countries to identify the poor. The MPI provides rigorous statistics on poverty incidence and intensity, and includes dimensions related to health, education and living standards. It is therefore a strong instrument to support the SDG agenda, which pays particular attention to the inclusion of environmental factors. Operationalisation of a post-2015 global MPI that allows cross-country comparison in relation to the SDGs depends on the availability of adequate and appropriate secondary data on environment and poverty. This proposal aims to develop such a measure.  Using secondary data from Brazil (see details justifying this focus in the Case for Support), we propose to develop and test the possibility of developing an environmentally-adjusted MPI that can help measure progress towards the achievement of the post-2015 SDG agenda. We will compare the environmentally-adjusted MPI statistics to existing MPI statistics to understand the patterns of incidence and experience of poverty and wellbeing, as measured by these alternative indicators. For instance, poverty may be the same if people identified as being poor under the current MPI are the same as those unable to deal with risks of natural hazards and climate change, and unable to access and engage meaningfully with the natural environment.  Secondly, there is a need to understand whether the observed improvement in GDP and income (in Brazil) are reflected in the more broadly defined environmentally-adjusted MPI. Therefore, we will look into the trends in the different MPI dimensions over time and space. We will aim to evaluate national level poverty-alleviation strategies in Brazil, such as the Bolsa Familia programme of Brazil&apos;s Fome Zero programme, to evaluate if the focus of these policies (in terms of the choice of targeted interventions and choice of beneficiaries) can explain the observed trends in both the existing MPI and an environmentally-adjusted measure.  Building on the detailed analysis of the Brazilian case, we propose to use our strong existing research and collaborative networks in Nepal to test this measure in a contrasting ODA-eligible context. For globally comparative analyses, it is important for the measures that emerge from this project to be applicable in diverse contexts. Data availability, research capacity and the context for implementation all matter, and are very different in Nepal relative to Brazil. By collaboratively exploring the different needs and challenges of an environmentally-adjusted MPI measure in Nepal with key research and impact partners, we will investigate the potential for such a globally comparable measure.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective of this proposal is to couple global and national level secondary datasets that deal with the environment and poverty, in order to develop an environmentally-adjusted index for the assessment of multidimensional poverty. With the shift in attention from the Millennium Development Goals (MDGs) to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), there is greater recognition of the interdependence of multiple causal factors that affect wellbeing and poverty outcomes, especially in relation to the natural environment. In previous work we have argued for the inclusion of environment as an additional dimension in the internationally adopted Multidimensional Poverty Indicator (MPI), and have developed the conceptual basis for an environmentally-adjusted MPI.  The global MPI developed in alignment with the MDGs, covering health, education and living standards indicators, and progress in relation to these measures is largely positive: there is a declining trend in multidimensional poverty (Alkire and Vaz 2014). Yet the absence of environmental indicators in the existing measurement of multidimensional poverty implies that the MPI excludes environment-related wellbeing and may present an overly optimistic picture of sustainable development. Where interventions to reduce extreme poverty have neglected associated trends in the environment, existing MPI results may either misinform poverty strategies or even provide perverse incentives (encouraging short-term environmental degradation), damaging countries&apos; potential for long-term sustainable development. The proposal has four key objectives. The following first three objectives are to operationalise and demonstrate the importance of coupling environmental and poverty data in the context of the SDGs: 1. Examine the extent to which environmental and poverty data in Brazil can be usefully coupled for analysis at spatial and temporal scales that are meaningful for policy-relevant insights on the extent and incidence of multidimensional poverty (inclusive of environmental dimensions); 2. Analyse the difference in overall poverty statistics between the existing MPI and the environmentally-adjusted MPI, using secondary quantitative data; 3. Evaluate the usefulness (policy relevance, legitimacy and acceptability) of the environmentally-adjusted MPI through a stakeholder workshop and wider stakeholder engagement within Brazil (see Pathways to Impact for more details); This aspect of the proposal will focus on Brazil, an upper-middle income country that has seen rapid economic development over the recent decades, but is also characterised by high inequality and high poverty rates. Brazil also has a wide variety of ecosystems. The vast natural capital of Brazil is under stress from logging, agriculture and mining activities, and degradation has led to conflict over human rights and negative impacts on health and risk exposure. Statistics on both social and environmental indicators are available, making this a suitable country for our focused case study. The learning from the Brazilian context provides the motivation for our fourth objective: 4. Evaluate the suitability of the methods for constructing an environmentally-adjusted MPI in Nepal, through sharing insights from the Brazilian research and engaging key stakeholders in Nepal through a carefully targeted impact strategy and a key informant workshop (see Pathways to Impact for more details).  Critically, the proposal further directly responds to the GCRF&apos;s and Official Development Assistance (ODA) objectives by building capacity and engaging with national planners and statistical agencies in Brazil and Nepal to co-produce analyses on the overlaps between available environment and poverty data. Furthermore, this project will also build capacity among early career researchers, by including one early career Co-Investigator and one early career Researcher Co-Investigator.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-16" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-15" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-17">43608.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-17">87217.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-17">174435.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003583_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP003583%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-02-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
