<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004053_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Drying Prayers: Peace Dance from a Central African Perspective</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This follow-on project responds to a community need, which is the promotion of culture for development among displaced communities in Central Africa. Our previous research has built capacity for knowledge exchange (Phase I) and training (Phase II). We now require support from AHRC for impact and engagement activities. Our new focus group are women and children. These developments are part of a long-term collaboration between PI Salazar Sutil and non-academic partner Taigue Ahmed (Artistic Director of Ndam Se Na). Ndam Se Na has conducted community engagement work in refugee camps for almost 15 years, developing a unique pedagogy for community-building through dance. The focus of this project is the Baga Sola UNHCR refugee camp located in the Lake Chad region, which is a new area of activity for NSN. This fund is supporting the growth and expansion of NSN&apos;s methodology both within Chad and internationally. The reason for conducting work in Lake Chad is all the more relevant given the fact that this region is experiencing one of the largest humanitarian crisis in the world due to the disappearance of the lake, a problem aggravated by Boko-Haram related violence.   This project will enable us to take our research programme in new directions through development of a novel impact and engagement plan that enhances previous research, while engaging new communities and partners in defining and responding to the above-mentioned need. This fund will enable a new team of African artists and researchers to be recruited through open call. The team will conduct practice-research on the subject of &quot;peace performance,&quot; exploring embodied ethical values found within traditional Chadian dances used in Ahmed&apos;s pedagogy. The team of practitioners will spend three weeks in the Lake Chad, and will facilitate rhythm and dance workshops with our new focus group (women and children). In September 2019, we will conduct a festive event in N&apos;Djamena to showcase the art co-created with lakeside refugees. This event will also give our trainees from the previous research project an opportunity to showcase new work done in their home countries. This will inform our feasibility study and impact report, as we will evaluate the impact of Ahmed&apos;s training (Phase II) in new regional contexts beyond Chad (i.e. Mali, Senegal, Cameroon and Madagascar). The event will also support policy-making and match-funding activities.  In addition, this fund will support the collation of audiovisual records of the fieldwork, to be carried out by the PI. The research material amassed during Phases I, II and III will be housed in a new project website, which will include blogs and unpublished material concerning Pas en Avant pedagogy (including a downloadable toolkit).   Finally, the artistic research will lead to the production of a novel work of documentary dance, also led by Ahmed and his team of 8 unnamed artists. The piece, entitled &quot;The Drying Prayers&quot;, will be presented in Germany, UK, France and Chad, and it will be co-produced by a number of high-profile cultural organisations for maximisation of artistic and cultural impact. This work of documentary dance will provide an opportunity for the realisation of talks and Q&amp;As, so as to engage new academic communities, dance experts, and art researchers from across Europe and Africa.  The choreographic work and academic talks will promote the basic conceptual framework of our research, which draws on dance philosophy to construe an embodied understanding of &quot;peace&quot; as creative praxis. The project demonstrates creativity and innovation through promotion of a distinctly Chadian perspective on peace dance, as well as through the development of the emergent medium of documentary dance. The success and legacy of this project is ensured by a trusting relationship built through our continuing work with African experts, scholars, and the participating communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project builds on work completed as part of Social Choreography Network grant (AH/P012299/1) and the Highlight Notice AHRC grant entitled Pas en Avant (AH/S004068/1110263). This proposal thus constitutes Phase III (Impact and Engagement) in a three-part research program into dance for development led by the School of Performance and Cultural Industries (UNIVLEEDS). The proposed pathway to impact activities have not been taken into account in previous phases of funded research. Our project will produce new knowledge exchange, interactive public engagement activities with new user communities and audiences, and a feasibility studies that will test the potential application of ideas emerging from our previous research in new regional contexts. Our vision has evolved through collaborative work, much like this proposal.  Our aim is to promote values of community integration, cohesion and peace via Chadian dance and rhythm.  The project hinges on the power to mobilise social harmony through traditional Chadian rhythm, gesture, and movement (especially in the context of Bazaga and Mbile ritual dances). While critical theory has much to learn from a renewed engagement with Global South perspectives, how are we to avoid a recolonization of traditional practices , as decolonial and post-colonial philosophical projects partially risk? How can the praxis of peace be transmitted through the ethical wisdoms underpinning dance practice, and can transmission of ethical values through dance be more than a postcolonial supplement to dominant Western discourse?   Objectives  -To engage women and children living in the Lake Chad community of Baga Sola in community engagement workshops that promote peace through African dance (Pas en Avant methodology).  -To disseminate and celebrate the cultural activity of the local community of Baga Sola, as well as new participating artists, researchers and policy-makers, via a public event to be held at the Institut Francais in the Chadian capital of N&apos;Djamena.   -To develop the community engagement workshops into a new production of documentary dance to be presented in the summer of 2020 at the German National Theatre (Weimar), HOCHX (Munich), Stage@Leeds (Leeds), Royal Court Theatre (London) and, potentially, Centre National de la Danse (Paris).  -To make all the work and research co-created as part of Phases I, II and III available through a new project website + toolkit,  for the benefit of academic and non-academic international communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-14" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Chad</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1028" percentage="100" vocabulary="MIDDLE AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-04">18144.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-04">6048.16</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">6048.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004053_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">6048.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004053_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">6048.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004053_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">6048.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004053_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
