<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004371_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indigenous food systems, biocultural heritage and agricultural resilience</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives are:  1) To establish a new cross-sector research partnership and network on indigenous food systems, linking interdisciplinary academics with agricultural and sustainability researchers and policy makers in the UK, Kenya, India, China and globally (FAO). An existing IIED partnership of agriculture/sustainability researchers and NGOs working with indigenous communities in Kenya, India and China will be expanded to include interdisciplinary and humanities experts in the UK and the 3 countries. This new partnership will develop novel interdisciplinary research approaches for the study of indigenous food and agricultural systems through local workshops in the case-study areas. A wider network on indigenous food systems research will also be established, bringing together the new partnership, other UK humanities and agriculture experts, FAO, international and indigenous experts. The network will explore the role of indigenous food systems in resilience, nutrition and sustainability through a workshop in the UK, and develop new research agendas to address key issues at the interface of indigenous food systems, agrobiodiversity, cultural heritage, rights and livelihoods. The new partnership and network will promote a whole food systems perspective, linking experts working on different parts of the food system; and will integrate research on gender dynamics and strategies for women&apos;s empowerment across its work.  2) To co-design new interdisciplinary research approaches and increase interdisciplinary capacity to explore indigenous food and farming systems past and present, and from farm to plate. The partnership will design novel interdisciplinary approaches integrating ethnobotany, oral histories and historical approaches to explore indigenous food and farming systems in: the Rabai community (Mijikenda tribe: Kilifi county, coastal Kenya); the Lingsey and Lingseykha communities (Lepcha and Limbu people: W. Bengal, NE India); and Naxi ethnic communities (in less well-known villages adjacent to the Stone Village in Yunnan, SW China). The project will build the capacity of agriculture and sustainability researchers to use interdisciplinary ethnobotanical and historical approaches for indigenous food systems research. It will also enhance the capacity of interdisciplinary and humanities academics (in the UK and the 3 target countries) to influence agricultural research and policy and contribute to community development processes. 3) To advocate the importance of using traditional agricultural knowledge, crops and landscapes to create strategies for agricultural resilience. The project will collate and disseminate evidence on the role of indigenous food systems in agricultural resilience, nutrition and sustainability. The interdisciplinary research methods it develops aim to explore, and generate evidence of, the long-term use of traditional crops, which can help suggest their suitability for local agroecological contexts. Project findings aim to inform agricultural researchers and policy makers about community-orientated strategies to enhance resilience and protect threatened heritage.  4) To contribute to ongoing community-led processes to establish biocultural territories to protect threatened crops, cultural heritage and rights and enhance sustainable livelihoods. A highly participatory and empowering action-research approach will be used which actively engages community co-researchers, including women and youth, in designing and facilitating local workshops and future research in each country. 5) To help address the drivers of change affecting indigenous food and farming systems. Using humanities approaches will facilitate a better understanding of the cultural and temporal context of changes (alongside environmental or economic factors), and of the barriers and opportunities for addressing negative drivers of change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The world&apos;s 370-500 million indigenous peoples are amongst the poorest and most food insecure. IIED and partners have been conducting research on indigenous farming systems and traditional knowledge in Kenya, India and China, without humanities inputs or training. This project aims to expand this existing partnership of agriculture and sustainability researchers and NGOs to include humanities and interdisciplinary academics. The new partnership will develop novel interdisciplinary approaches to explore indigenous food systems, past and present, from farm to plate, including crops, processing and cuisine. It will design new research methods that use ethnobotany and oral histories alongside agricultural surveys, as well as information from historical and archaeological sources. The areas of research are: (i) the Rabai community, Mijikenda tribe in coastal Kenya; (ii) the Lingsey and Lingseykha communities (Lepcha and Limbu people) in the Himalayas, West Bengal, NE India; (iii) the Naxi people in the Stone Village area of Yunnan, SW China. These areas have a rich diversity of traditional crops which are adapted to local conditions and hence important for agricultural resilience; but many of these crops have declined in recent decades, becoming minor, and associated traditional knowledge is rapidly disappearing. A key driver of change is the spread of modern high-yielding varieties promoted by agricultural research and extension services. The new research is expected to generate evidence of the long-term use of certain traditional crops which suggests suitability for local agricultural contexts, to inform agricultural researchers and policy makers, and community crop choices. The project will also establish a wider global network on indigenous food systems bringing together the new partnership, other UK humanities and agriculture experts, FAO, and international and indigenous experts working on indigenous food systems. The network will connect researchers working largely in disciplinary and sectoral silos and using very different approaches, to jointly identify and develop new areas of interdisciplinary research critical for addressing the food systems challenges of indigenous peoples in developing countries. The project has 3 main objectives, each of which forms a work package:  1. Establish a new cross-sector research partnership and network on indigenous food systems, linking interdisciplinary academics with agricultural and sustainability researchers and policy makers in the UK and LMICs and globally (FAO). A workshop will be held in the UK to bring together these actors, take stock of research to date on the role of indigenous food systems in resilience, nutrition and sustainability, and identify key areas for further interdisciplinary research. The workshop will also begin to develop interdisciplinary approaches for research on indigenous food systems in the study communities in Kenya, India and China. 2. Co-design new interdisciplinary research approaches and develop interdisciplinary capacity to explore indigenous food and farming systems past and present, and from farm to plate. Local workshops will be held in each country to develop new approaches tailored to each local context in collaboration with indigenous communities, agricultural researchers and policy makers and local humanities experts. Ethnobotanical questionnaires will be developed collaboratively and tested by local partners. 3. Advocate the importance of using traditional agricultural knowledge, crops and landscapes to create strategies for agricultural resilience. The results will be used to prepare workshop reports in English and local languages; a journal article; and a project proposal for future in-depth research in the 3 sites. The results will also be presented at international policy meetings on sustainable development, biodiversity and culture, and at DFID. They will be disseminated more widely through a blog and a news story.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Institute for Env and Dev</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-29">86957.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-29">87895.81</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-29">4546197.396</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to International Institute for Env and Dev</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004371_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Institute for Env and Dev</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT004371%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
