<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_P003168_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Advanced Technologies for Radio Telescopes in Mexico and the UK</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project has two main components. In the first, electronics hardware that has been developed in the UK for a large radio telescope project, the Square Kilometre Array, will be used on a new Mexican telescope, the Large Millimetre Telescope (LMT), situated on a mountain top in Mexico. The grant will pay for three researchers, one in the UK and two in Mexico, to develop software to process data from two high frequency radio receivers on the LMT. This will allow more detailed observations of radio emission from stars and star-forming regions in our own Galaxy as well as in external galaxies. More importantly, as this is an international development project, it will train the Mexican scientists in the use of the latest high-speed digital technology, which has applications both in astronomy, in science generally, and in commercial applications.   The second part of the project will focus on the use of redundant satellite communications antennas for radio astronomy. Mexican engineers will build a feed horn (the component in a large antenna that actually captures the radio waves) for an antenna in the UK that is being converted from communications to astronomy use. With the advice of UK scientists, they will also study how to convert a similar antenna in Mexico. This should lead to the possibility of a complete network of new radio telescope in Mexico and Latin America, co-operating with similar arrays in Europe and Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project has two primary objectives.  Both are focussed on transferring knowledge and skills from the UK academic and commercial sectors to Mexico. The first is to enhance the capabilities of Mexican astronomy, making Mexican-based science internationally competitive, attracting new students and researchers from within Mexico in to the research sector, and attracting foreign researchers to Mexico. The second is to provide Mexican researchers with skills and knowledge in several areas of leading-edge research that have both scientific and commercial applications.   This will be achieved via two linked projects. Firstly, we will develop a collaboration between Mexico and the UK in digital signal processing (DSP) as applied to radio astronomy.  This will result in two new high-resolution spectrometers for the Large Millimetre Telescope (LMT), and bring Mexico to the forefront of modern digital systems applications. Over the course of this two-year project, this will bring the Mexican group up to the leading edge in the application of this technology. This will not only ensure the success of the Mexican effort to develop a high spectral resolution spectrometer for the LMT, but will also permit Mexican participation in the development of systems for, for example, the SKA telescope.  There are also many commercial applications of FPGAs, access to which will be opened up to Mexico by developing expertise in this area.  Secondly, we will formulate a plan to equip Mexico with a relatively low-cost, research-grade radio telescope for centimetre-wave single-dish radio observing and for Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI) with both astronomical and geodetic applications. The conversion of existing telecommunications antennas for astronomical use is a relatively low-cost means to obtain substantial (30-m class) dishes, as shown by experience in the UK and South Africa.   An important result of this feasibility study will be a formal proposal for the conversion of the Mexican antenna.  The proposal will include not only a detailed work plan with cost estimates (for the conversion) but also a proposed business model for the operation and funding of the telescope that addresses the needs of all stakeholders. This knowledge exchange will give the Mexican community the expertise it needs to begin to convert Mexican and other Latin American antenna assets to productive scientific infrastructure, enabling future collaborations with European and African VLBI networks. To provide a direct practical component to the antenna conversion work, Mexico will build a feedhorn for the antenna conversion being done at the UK earth station at Goonhilly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MX" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mexico</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1032" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-07">154013.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-07">308707.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-07">154694.22</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-07">617414.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST/P003168/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FP003168%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
