<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S013210_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WateR security And climate cHange adaptation in PerUvian glacier-fed river basins (RAHU)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The anticipated impacts of climate-change induced glacier shrinkage on the water security of mountains and downstream lowlands is a major global concern. However, the connections between climate change, glacier shrinkage, water security and local adaptive capacity are multi-dimensional and non-linear. In many regions of the world including Peru, the physical and human processes that govern them are poorly understood. Therefore, understanding these process, their impacts and implementing adequate science-based adaptation strategies requires an interdisciplinary approach. This approach should combine advancing the state-of-the-art of glaciological and hydrological process understanding, with new insights in current and future levels of water security, human vulnerability, and adaptive capacity.  We propose to address this challenge by developing an integrated glacier - water security assessment model to transform our understanding of the impact of glacier shrinkage on water security and to inform policy practices in Peru. We identify the lack of glaciological, hydro-climatological, and water resources data as a major bottleneck to achieve this. Therefore, we propose participatory water resources monitoring as a radically new approach to transform our knowledge of physical processes, constraining water resources models, and supporting evidence-based policy-making.   We have assembled a world-leading consortium that combines high-level expertise in field monitoring and computer simulation of glaciers and water resources in Peru, with pioneers of participatory data collection for sustainable development and policy-support. This consortium is ideally placed to generate a breakthrough in data availability on the link between glacier reduction and current and future water security. This is needed to build the next generation of glaciological and hydrological models that can support the design and implementation of adequate climate adaptation strategies.  We will use the Vilcanota-Urubamba Basin in southern Peru as our case study. This basin hosts the largest tropical ice cap (Quelccaya) and it is characterised by a very complex water management context and high data scarcity. Our project will follow a &quot;source to tap&quot; paradigm, in which we will deliver the first fully integrated water resources vulnerability assessment framework for glacier-fed basins, comprising state-of-the-art glaciology, hydrology, water demand characterisation, and water security assessment. We will design targeted glacio-hydrological and water resources monitoring campaigns, to complemented existing monitoring efforts of our project partners and collaborators, and new remotely sensed data sets. This campaign will be implemented using the principles and tools of participatory monitoring and knowledge co-creation that our team has pioneered in the tropical Andes.  The datasets produced by this approach, combined with existing monitoring implemented by our team and collaborators, will allow us to build an integrated water supply-demand-vulnerability assessment model for glacierized basins, and to use this to evaluate adaptation strategies at the local scale.  For the latter, we have engaged with a set of policy stakeholders in Peru that play a key role in the implementation of recent transformative legislation on Peruvian water resources management, and in particular in the new law on the implementation of water funds to invest in catchment interventions (Law 30215).  Working directly with these stakeholders will ensure that our approach focuses on locally relevant adaptation strategies, including novel approaches such as the use of nature-based solutions and the restoration of ancestral water &quot;seeding and harvesting practices&quot;, thus providing both the scientific basis and the operational tools that support the implementation of this legal framework.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="PE" type="PERU"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-18">50905.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-18">195700.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-18">172287.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-18">85267.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The Peruvian Andes are a hotspot of water resources vulnerability because of the propensity for water stress, the highly unpredictable weather, the sensitivity of glaciers, and the socio-economic vulnerability of its population. Using the Vilcanota catchment in Southern Peru as a case study, we will address this issue by means of the following objectives:  O1. Develop a fully-distributed, physically-based glacier surface energy balance model that allows for a realistic representation of glacier dynamics in glacier melt projections  The current state-of-the-art in Peruvian glacio-hydrological melt modelling does not include a realistic representation of glacier dynamics, which may lead to incorrect estimations of the impact of climate perturbations. This objective will address these limitations by constructing a fully-distributed, physically-based surface energy balance model to constrain the parameters of simplified models to be used in less well-instrumented catchments nearby.  O2. Design and implement a glacio-hydrological monitoring and data collection approach to quantify non-glacial contributions to water resources and the impact of catchments interventions  Our consortium has pioneered the implementation of a participatory hydrological monitoring network of paired catchment to quantify the hydrological response of high-Andean ecosystems and the impact of catchment interventions on water resources. Recent research has shown that the method is successful in characterising the impact of catchment interventions, and upscaling the observed trends. In addition, the participatory approach directly involves local communities, NGOs and other relevant stakeholders from the start, which has proven to be highly effective to support local water resources management.  Here, we will build upon these successes and adapt this methodology to implement (1) short-term monitoring of glacierized catchments to constrain our glacier models; (2) characterisation of high-altitudinal wetlands (locally known as &quot;bofedales&quot;); (3) evaluate the impact of catchment interventions such as land-use change and nature-based solutions on water resources, and (4) support locally-based and inclusive water resources management.  O3. Mapping of human water use at high spatiotemporal resolution and determining current and future levels of water (in)security.  Most water use in glacierized catchments occurs at considerable distance downstream of ice-covered headwaters, where meltwater is mixed with water sources of non-glacial origin. Combining the results of O1 and O2 will make it possible to quantify the glacier-melt contribution and its future changes at the point of water use. O3 is concerned with mapping and predicting water demand at unprecedented spatial and temporal resolution (&lt; 1km). The combination of these activities will make it possible for the first time to evaluate the impact of changes in glacier melt contributions on water security while fully accounting for direct climate change impacts as well as changes in water demand.  O4. Integrate O1-3 in a glacier - water security assessment model and evaluate this tool&apos;s capacity to support locally-embedded climate change adaptation strategies.  Peru has created recently an innovative legal framework to support integrated watershed management, including the use of innovative approaches such as nature-based solutions, and the restoration of ancestral water &quot;seeding and harvesting&quot; practices. Integrating the results O1 - 3 allows us to create the first encompassing human vulnerability assessment framework. This will support directly these policy efforts, as it makes it possible to evaluate in a quantitative manner the capacity of various catchment interventions to offset the negative impacts of glacier melt and to improve water security."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
