<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_V003089_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Blue Futures: Building youth resilience in coasts under climate change</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For the first time in history, young coastal resource-users will emerge into independent adult life under the shadow of climate change, and their entire adulthood will unfold under the predicted worsening outcomes to 2050 and 2100. For instance, at 2 degrees C of warming there is expected to be a step-change in climate impacts, including the irreversible loss of coral reef ecosystems. In developing counties, climate impacts intersect with other significant development challenges related to accelerating environmental change and increased competition for resources, widespread and extreme poverty, high levels of youth unemployment, and a lack of formal agency. Young people may be required to leave behind the identities, livelihoods and culture of past generations as they re-adjust their future development aspirations. Transformation will occur in ways and for reasons that are unprecedented. 

Young people are renowned for their open-mindedness and resourcefulness, yet they are rarely included in decision-making about their future. The &apos;Greta Thunberg&apos; effect has opened a window of opportunity globally to amplify youth voice, include them in governance and catalyse meaningful action on climate resilience. Young Blue Futures leverages young people&apos;s desire to connect, experiment and express themselves in order to build a network of young participants, academics and practitioners in the Western Indian Ocean (WIO) dedicated to addressing the intersecting risks and structural barriers facing young coastal resource-users. This network will co-produce new knowledge of the multi-scale and gendered determinants of resilience to underpin innovative, cross-cutting solutions that build youth resilience. Young Blue Futures integrates the frontiers of research on youth resilience (from human development) with the state-of-the-art on system resilience to environmental, climate and intersecting risk (from sustainability science). It will be the first project to apply a multi-scale approach to understanding psychological, social, institutional and environmental determinants of youth resilience, and their amplifying and dampening feedbacks, in social-ecological systems. 

Through creative community engagement activities, the Network Development phase explores young men and women&apos;s own interpretations of youth, resilience, climate change, and the structural barriers they face across five countries: Kenya, Madagascar, Mauritius, Mozambique and Tanzania. It also consolidates best-practice in supporting youth resilience-building from a diverse practitioner community bridging conservation and development (see network partners), health, education, business, and disaster response. Best-practice will be distilled through desk-top review, stakeholder consultation and knowledge-sharing activities at a regional workshop. This new knowledge will inform co-creation of novel resilience pathways for implementation in the Network Plus that cut across sectoral divides (e.g., environment and business), bring to the fore neglected facets of young people&apos;s resilience (e.g., leadership, mental health), and are tailored to gender and different contexts. Moreover, responding to regional demand for new partnerships to underpin resilience interventions, Young Blue Futures will consolidate best practice in partnership-building and apply it to novel, strategic partnerships with the private sector and creative industry. These partnerships will foster two-way problem solving and capacity development for youth, industry and system resilience.
.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Young Blue Futures works with young coastal resource-users to explore gendered youth perspectives and experiences of resilience to climate change and intersecting everyday adversities. Network Development activities integrate these youth perspectives with multi-sector practitioner knowledge and interdisciplinary science to uncover the neglected facets of young resource-users&apos; resilience, and identify structural barriers to their resilience and development across scales. This new understanding will inform the co-creation of novel resilience solutions and partnerships that attend to youth priorities and amplify their existing voice and action across the different contexts of the Western Indian Ocean. These pathways will be refined and implemented in the Network Plus. The following objectives relate to scoping and data collection, network strengthening and capacity building, working from grounded experience to the project legacy at regional level. They relate to the Network Development phase and will continue into the Network Plus.
1.	Engage young male and female coastal resource-users in Kenya, Madagascar, Mauritius, Mozambique and Tanzania in interactive and creative activities to explore their own interpretations of youth, resilience, climate change and everyday adversity across diverse contexts.
2.	Connect young coastal resource-users to each other, and to practitioners and academics across sectors and disciplines at the regional level to distil best-practice in resilience building and identify opportunities for new, integrated solutions focused explicitly on the youth.
3.	Build capacity in transdisciplinary working across the network by integrating academic, applied and lay knowledges of resilience: enhance coastal resource-users and practitioners&apos; understandings of resilience theory from multiple fields; immerse academics in the everyday experiences and practicalities of responding to climate and intersecting risk in challenging development contexts.
4.	Work towards building critical consciousness in young coastal resource-users so they can recognise and challenge internal and external constraints to their resilience and development.
5.	Co-produce new knowledge on specific and general resilience to singular (climate) and intersecting (climate and numerous development challenges) risk, and advance progressive understandings of the multi-level psychological, social, institutional and environmental determinants of youth resilience, and their interactions.
6.	Build strategic links to academics, organisations and existing networks in the UK and WIO region to foster a diverse and inclusive Network Plus. This includes extending from expertise in sustainability and community development towards human development perspectives in health, education and disaster response. 
7.	Create opportunities for practitioner organisations within the WIO region to share knowledge and enhance their own programmes of work with coastal communities. 
8.	Scope the potential for equitable partnerships between young coastal resource-users and private sector and creative industry partners for two-way capacity development towards youth, industry and system resilience. 
9.	Initiate an enduring Resilience Network connecting communities, practitioners, academics, government, and private and creative partners to continue sharing best-practice in resilience-building in the WIO region. The WIO Resilience Network will be hosted by WIOMSA during and beyond the lifespan of this project. 
10.	Build capacity in international network governance across the team. The leadership of senior Co-Is Francis and Bandeira will be instrumental in enhancing the governance capabilities of PI Evans and the UK team who are mid-career scientists. In addition, resources will be co-produced to support network governance, including joint protocols on gender equality, research ethics, safe-guarding, data management and risk management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">179620.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Exeter</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/V003089/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Exeter</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FV003089%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
