<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S00145X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mental health literacy in urban and rural communities in Kerala India: An interdisciplinary approach using applied theatre methodology</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This highly collaborative international interdisciplinary partnership examines the applicability of the evidence based intervention of mental health literacy (MHL) for urban and rural communities through a multi-centre study in India using participatory theatre and media. We believe that our mutual sharing of research experiences, cultural identities and interdisciplinary exchanges will enable us to build our capacity for planning collaborative research of international significance. Our vision is to work towards the UN 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development goals 3, 5, 8, and 10.The WHO estimates that mental and behavioural disorders account for about 12% of the global burden of diseases and this is likely to increase to 15% by 2020 . Our focus is in Kerala which has higher prevalence of mental ill-health (14.4%), suicidal risk (12.5%) and alcohol abuse than the rest of India. Thus there is a dire need to develop acceptable and affordable evidence based mental health interventions that are responsive to the local cultural and social contexts.  Despite the high Human Development Index (HDI), stigma is widespread in Kerala and hence people with mental ill-health can internalise the public perceptions and become resistant to approach mental health facilities. Mental health literacy is proposed as an evidence based approach for enhancing tolerance, self-care, care for others and to reduce stigma. It is proposed that raising MHL can improve understanding about the risks to mental health, and methods of coping with these risks, thus promoting mental health for all.  This project will extend partnerships and develop new collaborations between UK and Indian academics &amp; researchers, service users, families, theatre practitioners and NGOs. Our plan is to conduct a multi-centre study using a &apos;theatre for development&apos; (TFD) model, adopting a participatory approach to engage and empower urban and rural communities through co-production and co-creation of culturally appropriate knowledge and practice in promoting MHL. We will use participatory co-research methodology embracing the principles of co-production and use theatre and media for research engagement and data collection. Our mode of practice and co-production will draw heavily upon the methodologies employed under TFD but we will also incorporate and extend the community storytelling approaches in partnership with local communities and theatre workers to pilot an approach that allows communities, policymakers and professionals working with mental health to explore mental health as an issue of social justice and to promote MHL. It will do this by creating an interrogative performance space that brings together local practices and attitudes, professional orthodoxies, policy-related data and the latest understanding of mental illness in a way that allows multiple stakeholders to collectively imagine possible solutions. This project will also include widespread public engagement with people in creating mental health literacy through active public engagement programmes.  The partnership will innovate and develop new knowledge by: (1) developing and promoting a culturally appropriate MHL programme  (2) developing a participatory  applied theatre  model for promoting mental health literacy  (3) co-producing a piece of applied theatre on MHL reflecting the lived experiences of urban and rural communities (4) public engagement of users, families and communities on talking about MHL and pathways of services.  Our partnership will facilitate the development of lasting research partnerships combining knowledge of public mental health challenges with awareness of evidence based interventions and its cultural transferability, adding value to health humanities, mental health research and service development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal details a novel and highly collaborative approach to our understanding of how urban and rural communities in Kerala, India construct mental health literacy (MHL) for mental health well being. Our emphasis is on formulating knowledge in new, creative and accessible ways, through use of applied  theatre and media engagement as an intervention to enable knowledge to be used in genuinely empowering and emancipatory ways by citizens of Kerala (India), researchers and health service agencies. Our specific focus is in the state of Kerala in India which is witnessing an alarming rise in mental health disorders within a fast-changing socio-economic societal context with a higher prevalence of mental ill-health and alcohol abuse than the rest of India. Our focus will be on developing culturally appropriate, acceptable  and accessible mental health literacy,  and we will develop this through engagement with users and stakeholders. This will be achieved through our exploration of lived experiences of Mental Neurological and Substance Use (MNS) disorders and their effect on families and communities; their narratives on understanding these through social, economic and cultural factors; and how intersecting inequalities affect the ability to  access treatment, help and support. MHL is defined as knowledge and beliefs about mental disorders which aid their recognition, management or prevention.     Our overall research question is: How effectively can we promote culturally appropriate MHL in urban and rural communities using applied theatre methodology? This focus will be addressed through specific research questions: (Q1) How is MHL shaped by economic, social and cultural contexts in Kerala? (Q2) How do urban and rural communities construct appropriate meaning for MHL? (Q3) How can we best engage with urban and rural communities in Kerala to discuss mental ill-health? (Q4) How might we use a participatory applied theatre model as an intervention for developing MHL?  (Q5) How can we best engage with communities, professionals, services, policy-makers and Governmental agencies in promoting MHL?  These questions will be addressed through the following objectives: (O1) Conduct a rapid participatory literature and practice review for developing community engagement for MHL (O2) Collaborate with theatre practitioners in the UK and India to advance and develop new and hybrid models of participatory theatre practice that develop the &apos;voice&apos; and agency of urban and rural communities to examine MHL for positive coping and wellbeing (O3) Develop narrative data sets on lived experiences of MNS disorders (O4) Co-production of pilot pieces of community theatre practice reflecting the lived experiences of urban and rural communities to test their applicability in promoting MHL (O5) Engagement and participation of the general public and stakeholders using social media, linking with film, television and other media (O6) Co-produce policy and practice guidance for policy makers and professionals for promoting MHL, mental health and well-being. Our approach is based on a transformative emancipatory paradigm. Our collaboration will facilitate the development of lasting research partnerships combining knowledge of public mental health challenges with awareness of evidence based interventions and their cultural transferability providing more insight into the socio-economic and cultural contexts of MNS disorders and people&apos;s understanding of them.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">De Montfort University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">114884.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">230698.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">232567.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-08-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-08-27">578150.014</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to De Montfort University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S00145X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">De Montfort University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FS00145X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
