<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Challenging Inequalities: a Indo-European perspective</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research aims at appraising the inequalities in human condition that continue to blossom in our fast growing and increasingly globalized world, with a special focus on India and Europe. Europe and India are, in effect, two interesting environments in which to perform such an appraisal. Both are indeed major players in the globalized world to the production of which they contribute about 25%. Europe is made of mature economies with virtually zero extreme poverty (as defined by the income threshold of 1.7 US dollar a day in purchasing power parity) that exhibits modest yearly per capita growth and slow structural changes. India is by contrast a fast-growing developing country that concentrates one third of the world&apos;s extremely poor population and that is changing its social organization at an unprecedented pace. In so far as income and wealth inequality are concerned, the European countries are facing the challenge of sharing a mildly growing per capita GDP. By contrast, India faces the challenge of sharing the spectacular growth among the various segment of its population, including the extremely poor. But inequalities in income, consumption or wealth are by no means the only dimension by which individuals differ. Inequalities in variables such as health, education or access to decent housing are also extremely important in this perspective. So are the more subtle inequalities in social status, or the inequalities of opportunities that individuals coming from various groups are facing. Europe and India are interesting laboratories to analyze all these inequalities also because of the different attitude that their population seem to have with respect to these inequalities. The ethical acceptability of the different inequalities is an extremely important factor that seem to differ somewhat between India and Europe and, for that matter, even between European countries themselves. For example, there is a widespread view in European countries of protestant culture that income inequalities which result purely from a different exertion of effort are not ethically objectionable. This view seems to be less prevalent in countries of catholic culture. Similarly, India, with its still prevailing caste system, is often perceived as being more tolerant to inequalities in social status than Europe. The proposed research will make several contributions to our understanding of the inequalities in Europe in India. The first one will be to provide new tools for appraising some of these inequalities that are both easy to apply and based on clear ethical premises. Some of these tools concern inequalities in variables such as social status, education or access to a decent housing that can not be easily measured on a cardinal scale. For such variables, the conventional tools for measuring income or wealth inequalities can not be meaningfully applied. The research will also contribute to the design of tools for appraising inequalities in a multidimensional perspective that takes due account of the correlation that may exist between, say, income and health inequalities. As a last methodological contribution, the research will develop new criteria for appraising the inequality of opportunities between social groups. A second broad expected contribution of the research is to gather information about the individuals&apos; attitudes to inequalities and to the policies used to reduce the adverse impact of these inequalities. This information will be collected by either questionnaire surveys or by experimental methods in which subjects are asked to take carefully designed decisions that reflect their attitude to inequalities. A third contribution of the research will be to evaluate some of the inequality-alleviating policies themselves. A last contribution of the research is to provide a more qualitative assessment of the impact of those inequalities on individual lives. A special focus will be put here on Nepal migrants and workers in large firms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">inequalities in human condition continue to be one of the major challenge that our fast growing and integrating world is facing. Yet inequality is a complex notion. Besides the usual wealth and income inequalities, the public debate often address more subtle inequalities of opportunities among social groups as well as inequalities in health, education, access to new-technologies, exposure to environmental risks, etc. The complex nature of these inequalities, which take different forms in developed and developing countries, raises important challenges for the individuals who are affected by them, the policy makers who want to alleviate them, and the social scientists who want to understand them. One of these challenges concerns the very meaning and measurement of these inequalities. The standard tools for appraising income or wealth inequalities - for example by means of inequality indices or Lorenz curves - are in effect inadequate for appraising inequality in more qualitative or ordinal dimensions such as social status, health or education. The standard tools of inequality measurement are also imperfectly suited to address the multidimensionality of the attributes that are distributed among humans. In effect, when one deals with, say, health and income inequality, it is important to properly account for the correlation that may exist between these two variables, in addition to the usual dispersion of each of the variable in isolation. An important output of the research project will be to propose new methods for appraising these inequalities that duly account for both the ordinal or qualitative feature of many of the concerned variable and the specific issues raised by their multidimensionality. Another challenge raised by those inequalities lies in the attitudes that people develop about them. A country like India for instance is commonly depicted as being more tolerant with respect to inequalities in social status - that underlie the continuing prevalence of the caste system - than European and North American countries. The research project will accordingly examine how these cultural differences in attitudes to inequalities affect the very way by which these inequalities are appraised and analysed.  The last challenge raised by inequalities concerns the policies put in place to mitigate their most adverse consequences. India has implement various programs that aim at reducing pecuniary poverty and inequality on the one hand and inequalities of opportunities among castes on the other. The project will provide an extensive analysis of two such programs. It will also perform various empirical analysis of the consequences of inequalities in India, and will favor for this sake a pluridisciplinary perspective made of a mixture of quantitative analysis of large survey data and a more qualitative one based on interviews and on &quot;live trajectories&quot;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-07">311400.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Warwick</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/R010811/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">28073.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">28073.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">28073.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">28073.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">25178.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">25178.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">25178.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">25178.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_R010811_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FR010811%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
