<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P029280_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In-reservoir destruction of Blue-Green Algae and their toxins</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One of the greatest global challenges currently facing human-kind is access to reliable safe clean drinking water. This is particularly acute in developing countries where human activities often adversely impact water quality. While the earth is known as the blue planet with 71% of its surface covered in water, nearly all of this is seawater and not suitable for human consumption or is utilised in industrial and agricultural processes. Only a tiny proportion of the earth&apos;s water is freshwater (about 3%) and of this less than 1% is available for use, since much of the remainder is frozen at the poles or in glaciers. Water levels and quality in drinking water reservoirs across the globe are seriously depleted with the United Nation predicting that 1.8 billion people will suffer serious recurrent water shortages by 2025 and two thirds of the population living in areas of water stress. Of the water that remains in these depleted reservoirs, nutrient (nitrate and phosphate) levels from agriculture, industry and domestic waste are found to be high resulting in the mass growth of blue-green algal blooms along with the production and release of dangerous toxins. These toxins can cause acute and chronic symptoms in humans and animals resulting in ill-health, fatalities and cancers. When present in high numbers traditional water treatment often fails to eliminate the blue-green algal cells resulting in human exposure. Furthermore, the toxins they produce are also very stable during treatment allowing them to pass unaltered into drinking water. Innovative water treatment to eliminate these problems which uses light and a simple catalyst (TiO2 photocatalysis) has been pioneered by Professor Linda Lawton (Environmental Microbiologist - RGU) and Professor Peter Robertson (Chemical Engineer - QUB). We have successfully demonstrated the rapid and effective removal of 4 out of the 6 classes of toxins (evidence suggests the remaining 2 classes, saxitoxins &amp; BNAA, will be easily destroyed as they are more simple chemical structures). Furthermore, we have also shown that the same treatment is effective against harmful microbes in water. We have extensively evaluated this exciting technology both in the laboratory and on a pilot scale with considerable interest from water utilities in seeing the full implementation within the provision of drinking water. One limiting factor has been developing a simple strategy to expose and illuminate catalyst in contact with water while ensuring that the catalyst can be readily removed. The most efficient destruction has been found for nano-particulate catalysts which cannot easily be removed from water. We aim to transform the approach to dealing with blue-green algal contamination of reservoirs by developing and testing exciting new photocatalytic treatment pods which are continually powered by integrated, floating solar panels which drive low energy LEDs. Professor John Irvine (Electrochemist - St Andrews) will bring his world leading expertise in catalyst modification and characterisation along with electro-optimisation. Dr Christine Edwards (Biotechnologist - RGU) along with Professor Lawton have led the field in the production and detection of cyanotoxins and we will collaborate with leading scientists in Brazil where reservoirs are currently extremely depleted and suffering from significant blue-green algal blooms and their associated toxins. This collaboration will allow us to test the in-reservoir deployment of our novel treatment system in water bodies which are consistently contaminated with blue-green algae and in an environment with excellent solar irradiation with which to drive the very low running cost treatment. On completion of this research we will launch a fully scalable in-reservoir water treatment system which will be transferable to any developing or developed country to eliminate hazardousblue-green algal blooms, other pathogens and a wide range of toxic pollutants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching aim of this research is to design, construct and evaluate a full scale, in-reservoir treatment system for the elimination of toxic blue-green algae (cyanobacteria) and their toxins from freshwater reservoirs using environmentally benign components with little or no post-fabrication running costs.  The specific objectives in order of priority are: 1. To develop an in-reservoir water treatment system for the removal of toxins and microbes suitable for continuous use in developing countries, combining proven TiO2 nano-particulate photocatalyst technology supported on recycled expanded glass beads (c. 1-4 mm) and housed in UV-illuminated glass fibre mesh pods for deployment within drinking water reservoirs. While we have previously demonstrated the efficacy of TiO2/UV photocatalysis against 4 classes of cyanotoxins and against microorganisms, the full scale application has been prevented due to the limitations of using nano-particles in water treatment processes.  2. To select the optimum expanded glass bead size, TiO2 coating/integration and buoyancy for the efficient destruction of blue-green algal cells and their toxins. This will include comparing the performance of catalyst loading by sol-gel deposition and the direct addition of catalyst during the glass foaming process. Where necessary buoyancy and bead size will be controlled during the foaming process by modification of physicochemical parameters e.g. ground glass particle size, modifier addition and temperature. 3. To use our expertise in mass cultivation of blue-green algae, cyanotoxins analysis and purification to underpin the work of this project and to transfer analytical protocols to our Co-I in Brazil. To facilitate this we will prepare a panel of cyanotoxin analytical standards for use in partner laboratories. This will ensure inter-laboratory comparability and develop a regional centre of excellence in the analysis and monitoring of waterborne cyanotoxins. 4. To design and fabricate glass fibre mesh pods as housing to retain TiO2 composite beads with integrated UV-LED illumination. Mesh size selection will be balanced between being small enough to retain the composite catalyst beads while being sufficiently large enough to allow the free flow of toxins and especially blue-green algal cells and colonies to have close enough proximity to the catalyst where the reactive species (hydroxyl radicals) are produced which facilitate the destruction of blue-green algae and their toxins. 5. To select the most appropriate (energy efficiency, cost, reliability, configuration) UV-LEDs for integration into the catalyst pods. Availability, cost and formatting of LEDs is constantly improving and we envisage integrating LEDs, potentially as strips, during fabrication and utilising the electronic cabling as tethers between pods. 6. To model the deployment of floating solar photovoltaic panels which will provide sufficient power to drive the photocatalytic treatment  while also generating stored battery power for operation during the hours of darkness. We will also model the configuration of these panels on the reservoir surface to allow the added benefit of reducing surface evaporation which is a significant problem, reducing the available water. 7. To perform evaluation of the full-scale treatment system in a heavily contaminated drinking water reservoir in Ceare, Brazil, determining the effective removal of cells and toxins by photosynthetic assay and LC-MS analysis. During the full-scale deployment impact on non-target species will be determined as will the overall changes in microbial community profiles. 8. To review the economic and environmental impact of all aspects of the process from selection of raw materials, scalability of manufacturing process within developing world context, predicting long-term effect on ecosystem health along with costs of continued deployment (maintenance).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Robert Gordon University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-23">317790.63</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-23">427152.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-23">430612.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-23">1281486.736</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to The Robert Gordon University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P029280_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Robert Gordon University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FP029280%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
