<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029110_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender-Just Digital Innovation in Africa (GeDIA): Uniting women changemakers (and their male allies) to co-design gender-just digital futures</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Digital innovation in Africa (and globally) is taking place in highly unequal societies, and there is a risk that the shift to digitisation will trace or even amplify these inequalities. Gender inequality is one such inequality, and it intersects with inequalities along education, class, ethnicity, location, marital status, sexual orientation and disability lines. Gender equality is a Sustainable Development Goal (SDG 5) in itself and also has been shown to have significant secondary effects on the achievement of other SDGs.  Thus both women and men stand to gain from more gender equal societies, and yet in project design in the areas of digital literacy, Information and Communication Technologies for development (ICT4D), and digital-related service design, often gender equality is an afterthought, rather than being a key aim from the start. Women are frequently seen as &quot;hard-to-reach&quot;, relatively passive participants who need special encouragement to be included. This network seeks to shift this paradigm and instead position women as active agents in their own digital futures. We unite leading women changemakers, and their male allies, in a network that partners with other women changemakers across African countries to develop digital action research with women (alongside men) as central actors.  The network unites academic leaders from the field of ICT4D, Human Computer Interaction Design, digital literacy training, Data Science, with gender equality activists and partners from business (GSMA&apos;s network) from NGOs (Oxfam, Malala Fund) and women&apos;s networks (Asikana, Coding Space). Participants come from Zambia, Uganda, South Africa, Tanzania, Kenya, the UK and Sweden, and each bring their own networks. Thus as a network of networks we will be able to share good practice, identify gaps in our knowledge, and develop a joint research agenda. Together we will apply for a GCRF Large Grant which will allow us to undertake impactful action research together.        We seek to explore this overarching question: How can women changemakers in Africa be empowered to co-create a more gender-equal digital future?  Based on our analysis of the structural barriers to women&apos;s participation in digital innovation, GeDIA will concentrate on three focal areas where we see vital levers for change:  1) Amplifying advocacy in gender equality and equal participation in civic life by developing training opportunities for activists to better use the new tools of digital civics, social media campaigning, data science and data visualisation 2) Ensuring fair access for women and girls to education, training and careers in IT and Data Science       3) Developing gender-just service design. Developing better co-design processes for digital-related public services (e.g. sensor monitored water, sanitation, hygiene; apps for maternal health) with women as active partners in design.    We will convene a series of workshops and webinars, to bring together the members of the network. Here we will offer each other trainings, share best practice and existing methodologies.  We will nurture a GeDIA Academy which supports female academics in African universities through peer support and mentoring. Male allies from Data Science Africa will host a training school focused on women as learners, and male allies from the Zambian Innovation Hub BongoHive will help host our workshops.    A members&apos; directory will allow journalists and conference organisers to find female commentators on Africa&apos;s digital future. We have the support of DFID and GSMA who are on our advisory board, and our partners Oxfam, Malala Fund, INIITKenya have together pledged 40 person days to contribute to co-shaping this research agenda. They recognise the urgent need for collaborative research and action if women and girls are to have equal digital rights and participate in Africa&apos;s digital future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our aim is to unite women changemakers (and their male allies) from across academia, practice and industry (25 overall, of which 10 Co-Is, 7 partners, 8 to be co-opted) to develop strategies for gender-just digital futures in Africa. Together we will move gender equality from an afterthought in digital development to the heart of decision-making in inclusion, research, training, and design. We seek to unite the best gender and digital innovation research and together with women changemakers in African countries develop an action research agenda (to be executed in stage 2) to ensure that people of all genders have a fair share in Africa&apos;s digital future. We will work in 3 focal areas, with related research questions:  A. Supporting advocacy for gender equality with digital tools and Data Science A1) How can advocacy for gender equality in Africa be improved with sophisticated use of digital tools (data science tools, data visualisation, SMS, social media etc)? A2) How can better digitalisation, datafication and data science lead to better gender-specific and intersectional data in Africa?  B. Ensuring fair access for girls and women to training in IT and Data Science B1) How can structural barriers be overcome?  B2) How can digital literacy training and curricula be changed to support women and girls&apos; decisions on privacy and data sovereignty while helping them minimise their online risk (harassment; trolling etc)?  B3) How can African women as creators of technologies (e.g. in IT professions) be supported? C. Developing methodologies for gender-just service design for digital-related services    C1) How can digital design processes be developed that put African women&apos;s priorities and agency at the centre?  C2) How can women and men together change the structural barriers that prevent gender equal outcomes in service design?    We will:  1. Convene a series of workshops and webinars to jointly develop an analytical framework and action research agenda. We will apply scholarship in ICT4D and gender; Data Science; HCI; service design; and gender studies.  2. Form a Network of Networks bridging the business community (via GSMA), women changemakers in development (Oxfam; Malala Fund), women in the IT sector (Asikana) and networks of academics (our centres,UCT alumnae in ICT4D; ICT4D North)   3. Co-produce a Large Grant GCRF DIDA application (stage 2) to carry out the action research.  4. Develop a methodology for gender-just participatory service-design (to be piloted and scaled in stage 2)  5. Engage in mutual capacity building among the participants, drawing on the diverse expertise and existing training tools (e.g. Oxfam&apos;s social media training). Build a mentoring network, GeDIA Academy, for early career female academics in our area at African Universities. 6. Partner with the Data Science Africa Training School to run a first-ever training school focused on female participants&apos; needs and priorities (20 participants).  7. Through a website, membership directory, videos, blog and e-book, amplify the voice of African women changemakers. Throughout and beyond the project period, the network will be a go-to address for journalists or prospective research collaborators to find relevant female public commentators and collaborators.  Key non-academic partners and advisors:  - DFID have stressed that our bid is highly aligned with their Digital Strategy, are enthusiastic, and have agreed to serve on the Advisory Board - Industry: The Connected Women Programme of the GSMA (global trade association of mobile phone providers) are very supportive, will serve on Advisory Board and will make introductions to industry partners  - NGOs and enterprise: Oxfam GB (Gender team, Research team, Digital team); Malala Fund; INIITKenya have co-developed the proposal and will contribute in-kind (40 days of staff time). Zambian NGO Asikana Networkfor Women in IT will co-lead (time funded)</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-22">102868.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-22">3840441.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029110_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT029110%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
