<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P002072_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Negotiating the transition from rurality to higher education in Southern Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives of the proposed research are: 1. To close the knowledge gap that exists regarding the transition from rural school and home contexts to university learning in Southern Africa 2. To identify the dimensions of rurality as experienced by students transitioning from home to university in the Global South 3. To identify the practices that shape approaches to learning of students from rural areas in universities in Southern Africa  4. To identify the challenges for students from rural areas who face higher education curricula that remain imbued with colonialism 5. To explore how and in what ways digital technologies, social media and mobile communications influence rural students&apos; higher education trajectories 6. To identify how and in what forms inclusive and living curricula can be developed that build on the experiences of all students, including those from rural contexts in Southern Africa 7. To produce findings that will enable us to propose how the complexities of rurality can be conceptualised in relation to higher education 8. To enhance the capacity for research into teaching and learning in higher education in the Southern African region 9. To engage in dialogue with policy makers, university administrators and academics in the Southern African region about the implications of the findings of the study- The objectives address key themes identified by the ESRC-NRF Newton Fund, in particular &apos;equity in higher education access and participation&apos; and &apos;curriculum, pedagogy and modes and levels of provision&apos;. Objectives 1 - 7 will be achieved by: a) Reviewing international literature and data to map existing research; to explore how rurality is conceptualised in the different but similar contexts of Canada, New Zealand and Australia and how it is understood in relation to learning and teaching in higher education b) Gathering narrative accounts from 48 second year undergraduate students from rural areas attending three differently positioned universities in South Africa - the University of Johannesburg, Fort Hare and Rhodes universities - foregrounding the social and cultural capital they bring and how they are shaped by their home, school and community.  The students as co-researchers will be drawn from the STEM and humanities disciplines and will be enabled to depict their experiences of the transition from rural school and home contexts to university learning in South Africa using a variety of qualitative and visual research methods c) Gathering data from focus groups each consisting of six academics from similar disciplines to the student co-researchers in the three universities.  These focus groups will encourage academics to explore and describe their support for students from rural areas, inclusivity and diversity within the curriculum and pedagogic practices and where there are contradictions and tensions. Focus groups and interviews will investigate how inclusive and &apos;living&apos; curricula that address diversity at multiple levels might be developed d) Interviewing the senior administrator responsible for teaching and learning in each university. Objectives 8 -9 will be achieved by: a) A series of professional development workshops facilitated jointly by the UK and South African teams.  These workshops will focus on research methodology, understanding of teaching and learning in higher education, developing high quality research and publishing outcomes b) The involvement of the Southern African Universities Learning and Teaching (SAULT) forum which will cascade the findings and their implications to member universities in Southern Africa c) Disseminating  findings to national policy makers via the National Department of Higher Education and Training (South Africa), the Council for Higher Education (CHE) and organisations in Southern Africa such as the Southern African Regional Universities Association (SARUA) and the Rural Education Access Programme (REAP).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The research addresses the knowledge gap that exists regarding the transition from rural school and home contexts to university learning in Southern Africa. The study aims to trace the implications of this transition in order to develop inclusive teaching and learning practices and support mechanisms in universities, as well as to make an international audience aware of the influence of rural life on higher education, and how this influence plays out in Southern Africa as a specific region. The research will make significant contributions to debates on widening participation, equity, social justice and post-colonial curricula in higher education across Southern Africa and more widely across the Global South. The study should shed light on the many misconceptions and stereotypes about rural existence, but in addition, explore the extent to which there are real constraints as well as opportunities provided by living in rural areas. It will also investigate how the students strategise to manage the constraints they have experienced and strengths they possess. In order to ensure context-sensitivity and sustainability, a participatory research approach will be adopted. This involves the training of a select group of students to document their own experiences as researchers, using personal documentaries created using iPads, engaging in dialogue with lecturers and administrators at key moments in the project. Three research strategies are key to the project:  the first is an advanced literature review and a scrutiny of publically available documentation on macro-trends and socio-economic indicators on rurality. The second is the training of 48 second-year students in the humanities and the science and technology fields to become educational researchers. The students will document their prior learning in rural areas and their experience as university students, as well as how they negotiate the transition, and what social and technological resources they draw upon. This will be accompanied by interviews with administrators and academics in order to obtain a varied perspective on this transition, and to ascertain if there are examples of good practice to draw upon. This data collection will take place at the universities of Johannesburg, Rhodes and Fort Hare, which represent a range of South African higher education institutions, all with students from rural backgrounds. The third strategy is to share the interim findings and the research methods with academics and academic developers from Botswana, Lesotho, Malawi, Mozambique, Namibia, Swaziland, Zambia and Zimbabwe. The purpose is to engage in dialogue on the research methodology, the interim implications for developing post-colonial learning and teaching, and to ascertain to what extent these findings are common to the Southern African region. Academic developers and academics from these countries belong to an academic development network, the Southern African Universities Learning and Teaching (SAULT) forum. The network will allow for the use of the findings in the entire region. Attention will be paid to the capacity of the researchers within South Africa and the SAULT forum, including support for conducting similar research in the region and for academic writing. The mainly qualitative data will be analysed using thematic and narrative analysis. The themes informing the analysis are broadly drawn from socio-cultural theories of teaching and learning, with an emphasis on practices. This includes attention to the contexts in which students learn, the material conditions as well as cultural practices, the interrelationships amongst individuals and groups, and the formation of student identities.  The proposed study benefits from a strong and practised collaboration between academics at the universities of Johannesburg, Bristol and Brighton, with expertise in teaching and learning in higher education, social inclusion, digital technologies and participatory research methods.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-21">92864.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-21">186480.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-21">187990.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-21">20406.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-21">17558694.504</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P002072_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP002072%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
