<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_P007503_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Accelerate CHNUK AMR discovery: Establishing joint China/UK training and research platforms enabling highthroughput fragment based inhibitor discovery</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antimicrobial drug resistance (AMR) is a growing threat to global public health in China and worldwide. Multidrug resistance in &apos;ESKAPE&apos; organisms - which includes Pseudomonas aeruginosa, Staphylococcus aureus and Escherichia coli, exacerbates this as these pathogens are responsible for many life- threatening infections in hospitals. Resistance amongst these organisms is widespread in Gram-negative bacteria of particular concern in China causing a high prevalence of carbapenemase-mediated  resistance in hospitals, including the recent emergence in E. coli of transmissible resistance to the last line drug, colistin. There is a clear and urgent need for new classes of antibacterials that sidestep resistance. Only two new classes of antibiotics have been developed in the last 20 years this compares unfavourably to the &apos;golden era&apos; of antibiotic discovery, where. inspired primarily by the early successes of penicillins, 20 new antibiotic classes were developed. In addition to the challenges and complexities of antibacterial drug discovery, contributing factors halting the development of new antibacterials include the difficulty and indeed unpredictability of gaining regulatory approval, the resulting low profit margins and the regulatory restrictions on use as resistance levels continue to rise. These factors have seen the pharmaceutical and biotechnology industry substantially withdraw from investing in antibiotic discovery. The accompanying loss of expertise in the sector has only compounded the threat.   Thus there is a pressing requirement for significant investment in training and discovery to overcome the woeful lack of new antibacterials.  We plan to tackle the lack of specialised AMR training for the next generation of researchers by building a network of activity between outstanding, well funded, AMR research groups in the Uk and China. We will train a cohort of the next generation of researchers in advanced biophysical techniques to accelerate the discovery of new chemical inhibitors. These compounds will prove invaluable tools to probe fundamental aspects of biology and become the chemical start points for the development new antibacterial discovery programs. To achieve this we have exceptional support from industry and have included letters of support from them (for our 5yr UK collaborative  SWON alliance science program which provides an important component of the underpinning science for CHNUK). We will arrange joint SWON CHNUK scientific advisory panel meetings to help focus priorities for fragment based discovery.  China and the UK have committed major capital investment in synchrotrons and associated beam lines required for structural biology, and additionally in the UK for fragment based drug discovery. Transfer of automated fragment discovery technology from Harwell to Shanghai (see letters of support) will enable China researchers trained in the UK as part of this program to extend activities available to them to China researchers, further accelerating discovery.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-06-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="CHINA (PEOPLE&apos;S REPUBLIC OF)"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-26">194249.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-26">240649.34</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-26">227396.64</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Accelerate CHNUK AMR discovery brings together some of the UK and China leading experts in AMR research, who are  recognised world leads in complementary aspects of bacterial biochemistry, chemistry, genetics and physiology and structural biology in the areas of cell metabolism, RNA polymerase and the establishment of novel bacterial virulence targets. All groups will benefit from integrating high throughput structural approaches to fragment based lead discovery to deliver novel chemical probes that will deliver fundamental mechanistic understanding, validate novel targets and hopefully the start of chemical leads that are essential for industry partners to more effectively target the key enzymes . Together with an exceptional scientific advisory panel (already assembled to support our MRC AMR SWON collaborative)  composed of key academic partners from Leeds (C Fishwick) alongside an unprecedented breadth of commitment from pharma experts (D Shales, L. Silver, L. Czaplewski), current senior pharma executives from  Entasis, Merck, Novartis, and involvement from Dstl (see advisory panel letters of support for parallel underpinning science MRC SWON alliance), we expect highly interactive input to maximise the future translational development from the major objectives of the project in priority below.  We will  1.Establish a high-tech trans-national training environment for the next generation of researchers in China and UK who will develop as a cohort now and into the future 2.Enable FBLD technology transfer between Diamond and Shanghai synchrotrons to accelerate antibiotic discovery in China 3.Add FBLD for biological probes and inhibitors to high profile AMR funded projects in China and UK 4.Establish knowledge and technology transfer across China and UK research groups 5.Accelerate the validation of novel targets, and discovery of inhibitors for validated targets      This will prime new research projects, to underpin the future development of new ways of inhibiting valid targets PBPs and RNAP and novel targets e.g. SrtA, Clp: a. in the near-term train the next generation of researchers and validate novel antibacterial targets b. in the mid-term, develop innovative non-lactam antibiotics that target PBPs but are resistant to lactamases, and new ways to target RNAP c. in the long-term, new antibiotics that are different in their mode of action potentially targeting virulence determinants in combination with traditional antibiotics  All together helping deliver a CHNUK AMR solution, and develop a sustainable pipeline of transnational collaboration, and innovation."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
