<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T003995_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Syphilis self-testing to expand test uptake among men who have sex with men (SST)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Across a wide range of resource-constrained settings, syphilis infection causes substantial morbidity. Syphilis increases the risk of acquiring and transmitting HIV infection, but is frequently asymptomatic. Many men who have sex with men (MSM) with high risk sexual behaviours are unable to receive syphilis testing because of centralized testing sites and stigma associated with testing sites.  One way to increase syphilis test uptake among MSM is syphilis self-testing. Syphilis self-testing has a person use a test kit and interpret their own test result. HIV self-testing programs have already introduced the concept of self-testing to MSM and created an infrastructure to distribute and measure uptake of self-testing. Sensitive and specific syphilis self-test kits are available and can be used to detect syphilis infection, similar to treponemal serologies commonly used in clinical practice. Syphilis self-testing could decentralize testing and decrease stigma associated with testing. Our nationwide study found that 174/699 (24.9%) of a Chinese MSM sample already use syphilis self-test kits. We have organized five randomized controlled trials focused on increasing HIV test uptake among MSM. To date, there have been no studies evaluating the efficacy of MSM syphilis self-testing compared to facility-based testing. Our long-term goal is to organize a large two-country study to evaluate if self-testing can improve syphilis diagnosis and treatment. As a first step, we will finalise and pilot an intervention to promote syphilis self-testing and linkage to clinical services. This will establish a strong foundation for a randomized controlled trial if the pilot is deemed effective. The study will take place in Guangzhou (China) and Harare (Zimbabwe), two settings with a high burden of syphilis infection, strong linkages to MSM community organizations and health services, and ongoing HIV self-testing programs. Many research tools and methods developed to measure HIV self-testing can be directly applied in this study. We expect that our China-Africa project would facilitate adoption of the intervention in both other Chinese provinces as well as other less-developed African countries. This project will synergize with and benefit from ongoing China-Africa STI collaboration.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our preliminary data suggest that syphilis self-testing already occurs in China and could be integrated into HIV self-testing systems in Zimbabwe. We plan to organize a two site (Harare, Zimbabwe; Guangzhou, China) individual randomized controlled trial that will evaluate the efficacy and safety of community-based syphilis self-testing among men who have sex with men (MSM). This proposal focuses on the developmental phase of the study in these two cities. Our specific aims for this developmental award include the following: (1) To finalise and pilot a syphilis self-testing intervention   1a. To pilot a comprehensive intervention tailored for individual MSM focused on syphilis self-testing integrated within HIV self-testing systems 1b. To measure the acceptability and feasibility of using syphilis self-test kits (2) To finalise the primary and secondary outcomes of the subsequent trial 2a. To optimise the use of sending a test kit photograph for results reporting 2b. To determine optimal methods for distributing self-test kits in each of the two settings 2c. To identify clinical sites in the two study cities (Guangzhou, Harare) for facility-testing and linkage to care (3) To determine a preliminary estimate of the intervention effect and retention rate in order to inform RCT sample size calculations. 3a. To determine the required sample size necessary for the trial 3b. To estimate MSM retention and contamination within a future trial 3c. To estimate costs associated with implementing the intervention and the trial We will evaluate whether a future trial is justified based on the following a priori criteria: Aim 1: We will use a process evaluation to examine the extent to which the intervention is acceptable and feasible to MSM and local implementers. The process evaluation will examine the following aspects of the intervention: acceptability of distributing syphilis self-test kits online (in China) or through MSM community facilitators (Zimbabwe); ease of using the test kit and following pictorial instructions; feasibility of results reporting systems; capacity for the system to capture potential benefits (e.g., first-time testing) and harms (e.g., pressured testing) associated with self-testing. We will conduct in-depth interviews to better understand the uptake of the intervention and potential barriers and harms associated with implementation. Aim 2: This objective will be measured by examining data from the pilot for completeness and validity. Confirmation of self-testing will be assessed by photographic verification, using encrypted social media that are commonly used among MSM in each country (WeChat in China, WhatsApp in Zimbabwe). We will determine clinical trial readiness at MSM-competent clinical sites in Harare, Zimbabwe and Guangzhou, China to provide facility-based syphilis testing and linkage to care confirmation. Aim 3: We will estimate the retention rate by examining the number of MSM who are able to follow up at six months. The criteria for progression to a trial will be retention rate of 80% at six months. We will estimate the intervention effect size by comparing the number of MSM diagnosed and treated for syphilis among men in the control and intervention arms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-28">49480.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-28">99362.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-28">148843.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T003995_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT003995%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
