<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005831_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Business-Peace Models in Asia - Development Award</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The focus of the Network Plus project proposal is the role of private business and philanthropy in conflict and post-conflict processes in Central and South/South-East Asia.  While the &quot;business for peace&quot; movement has been celebrated and promoted for a decade or more, less attention has been paid to forms of economic nationalism and especially the use of philanthropy, corporate responsibility, and social business models in and for ethno-religious nationalist movements - what Widger, drawing from research into the Sri Lankan and Myanmar contexts, has termed &quot;philanthronationalism.&quot;    Our vision is to support ground-breaking inter-disciplinary research, knowledge exchange, and impact activities that can help to tackle the causes of conflict by better understanding the role played by the private sector in causing or maintaining conflict and violence, and by becoming effective actors in peacebuilding processes.  We propose to advance a critical comparative understanding between two regions - Central and South/East Asia - which are not often studied together, and may offer novel insights into business-peace models in Asia.  Network Plus projects will be commissioned via three networks established for this purpose - the Philanthropy for Peace (P4P) Network, which will explore inclusive and sustainable funding mechanisms and partnerships for civil society organisations involved in conflict resolution and peacebuilding; the Corporate Sustainability &amp; Peacebuilding (CSP) Network, which will explore governance and business frameworks for large companies wishing to take the lead in conflict resolution and peacebuilding activities themselves, or in partnership with civil society organisations, and the Social Enterprise in Conflict-Affected Regions (SECAR) Network, which will explore support mechanisms for impact investment in small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) that can tackle the economic and social roots of conflict.    The Development Award will be used to build extend strong, equitable, and sustainable partnerships with the International Co-Investigators and key collaborators in the target LMICs, and conduct scoping research and network development activities at national and international levels to help inform the grant writing process.  The funds will be used to address specific comments raised by the reviewers of the preliminary application, the general feedback provided by the AHRC, and additional priority areas that have since been identified by the team members (partly in response to changing political conditions on the ground, for example in Sri Lanka).  The Development Award will also have potential for producing new research and impact outputs that could be built upon if the final proposal was not successful, including supporting research and career priorities of the International Co-Investigators and impact activities associated with the PI&apos;s forthcoming book project on philanthropy, nationalism, and Buddhist-Muslim conflict in South and South-East Asia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-08-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-17">54237.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall aim of the Development Award will be to support the involvement of three International Co-Investigators (Datta, Haniffa, and Tiulegenov) and practice partner International Alert in the grant development process, the employment of a Post-Doctoral Research Assistant (Mullard) in Durham to support the Principal Investigator coordinate and prepare the full grant submission, and travel for two International Co-I&apos;s to the grant interview panel if shortlisted.  These activities will in addition produce new knowledge that will be of value to ongoing research and impact work of the project team.  Specific objectives will include:  1. Conducting a critical review of academic and policy literature to ensure the intellectual contribution of the Network Plus project advances the state of the art; 2. Conducting a rapid appraisal of partner capabilities, research priorities, opportunities for new partnerships, and stakeholder impact agenda in the four primary target countries (India, Kyrgyzstan, Myanmar, and Sri Lanka);  3. Drafting a Risk Review and Strategy for the proposed Network Plus model; 4. Drafting an Equality, Diversity, and Inclusion Review and Strategy for the proposed Network Plus model; 5. Refining the Network&apos;s research aims, objectives, and questions, and developing a Theory of Change; 6. Reflecting on areas of success and failure of the Award to shape the full proposal."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">54237.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005831_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
