<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T003618_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antenatal Couples&apos; Counselling in Uganda (ACCU)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this project, we would like to develop and evaluate a complex intervention for reducing deaths in mothers and babies, by improving birth planning and uptake of contraception after delivery in Uganda.  Every year, thousands of women and children in Uganda die as a result of problems during pregnancy and childbirth. Our research in 2011-2015 showed that about 20% of these deaths could have been avoided by use of contraception, to prevent unwanted pregnancies. Another 25% or so could be prevented by ensuring mothers go to the most appropriate health facility for their delivery. In Uganda, many women will not take these decisions without the approval and support of their husband; 43% of women still do not give birth in a health facility. Even of those who do deliver in a health facility, many high-risk women deliver in a small health centre which is unable to offer emergency surgery if needed.  If a woman does deliver in a health facility, although she may never return for postnatal check-ups, there is a key opportunity to provide contraception immediately after delivery. Although several projects have trained health workers to provide the contraceptive coil immediately after delivery, few women go home with a method of family planning in Uganda.  To understand why, our team interviewed 80 women, men and health workers in Uganda in 2015. Many women wanted time to discuss contraception with their husband (who was often absent at the time of delivery) and to recover from the birth. Women feared side-effects such as bleeding, and the impact these would have on their marriage; men were also concerned about side-effects and the cost of managing these. Many people we interviewed suggested that more awareness-raising on family planning was needed. Several people also suggested that men should accompany their wives to antenatal clinics (which rarely happens in Uganda) to discuss future family planning with a health worker. This would also be an ideal opportunity to discuss the birth plan with the couple, and to gain the husband&apos;s understanding and cooperation in deciding on the safest place for the delivery.   Thanks to a MRC-AHRC partnership development award, we have now developed health education documentaries and dramas on contraception, in two local Ugandan languages. The films have been edited to incorporate feedback from local audiences, and are now ready to be evaluated on a larger scale. However, it is likely that films alone would have a limited impact, unless they are followed up with counselling of couples to address their specific questions and concerns.  We have sought feedback on the concept of antenatal couples&apos; counselling in 18 focus groups with women, men and health workers in central and southern Uganda. Almost everyone liked this concept, but there remain several logistical challenges. Firstly, men are often reluctant to attend antenatal clinics, because of transport costs, location and timing. They suggested that their attendance could be increased by holding &quot;outreach&quot; antenatal clinics in villages which are far from health facilities, and by holding antenatal clinics at weekends. Secondly, some men are reluctant to be tested for HIV together with their partners. Thirdly, some health workers felt that they would not have time to provide in-depth couples&apos; counselling in addition to their existing workload.  In this project, we would like to build on our existing research to develop and pilot a complex intervention to deliver couples&apos; counselling in antenatal clinics in Uganda, in order to increase appropriate place of delivery, and increase uptake of post-partum contraception. This would include (a) training of village health teams to counsel antenatal couples and encourage them to attend antenatal clinic together; (b) health education films on family planning; (c) training of health workers in antenatal clinics toprovide effective couples&apos; counselling on birth planning and post-partum family planning.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main aim of this project is to develop, pilot and test the feasibility of a trial of a complex community-based intervention to reduce maternal, perinatal and neonatal mortality in Uganda. The intervention will focus on provision of information and counselling to antenatal couples about birth planning and post-partum long-acting reversible contraception. This project will provide feasibility data to support a future proposal for a full-scale trial.  The specific objectives of this project are: 1. To develop and pilot training packages for Village Health Teams (VHTs) and health workers in Uganda, on delivering counselling to antenatal couples about post-partum family planning, and encouraging couples to attend antenatal clinics together 2. To determine feasibility and acceptability for Village Health Teams in Uganda to provide information and counselling to couples on joint attendance at antenatal clinics, and post-partum family planning 3. To assess feasibility and acceptability of showing health education films on family planning in antenatal clinics in Uganda. 4. To evaluate feasibility of providing counselling to couples and of gaining their consent for post-partum family planning (PPFP), in antenatal clinics in Uganda 5. To assess feasibility of combining couples&apos; counselling on family planning with counselling on birth planning in antenatal clinics in Uganda. 6. To evaluate feasibility and acceptability of offering antenatal clinics and counselling at weekends. 7. To estimate the proportion of couples who are able to reach agreement on a method of post-partum contraception after a single counselling session, and of those who do not, the proportion who return for a second counselling session.  8. To assess feasibility of recruiting pregnant women to a trial of the intervention, following them up and recording their place of delivery and use of post-partum contraception up to 12 months after delivery, in both urban and rural areas. 9. To assess the feasibility of village health teams using smartphones to collect and record data on participants, using a secure data transfer system. 10. To measure current levels of uptake of post-partum family planning, and estimate by how much this could be increased after couples&apos; counselling is introduced (in order to estimate sample size for a future trial).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-06" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-05" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-28">37801.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-28">38107.97</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-28">151819.174</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to University of Southampton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T003618_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT003618%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-03-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
