<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M010422_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">iPSC-derived cardiomyocytes to model estrogen receptor modulation of stress cardiomyopathy and arrhythmic syndromes</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It has long been known that young women are relatively protected from heart disease compared to men. For sudden death arising from disrupted heart rhythm, men are 80% more likely to be affected. This often occurs after sudden or chronic stress, and is triggered by adrenaline. We have been studying a newly described syndrome in which a sudden extreme shock (accident, bereavement) produces not sudden death, but a temporary reduction in heart function which then reverses.  Sufferers come in to hospital thinking they are having a heart attack, but recover within days to weeks to have normal heart function. Interestingly, 80-90% of sufferers are women around or after the menopause.  We reproduced this in an anesthetised rat model, and showed that a single dose of adrenaline could give the same effect.  (In fact one dose of adrenaline from an epi-pen can sometimes have the same result in people). We found that very high adrenaline could switch from being stimulant to depressant, through an effect on its receptors on the heart cell surface.  When we tried to stop it being depressant on the heart function, we induced sudden cardiac death. Our idea is that high adrenaline goes from being stimulant (but damaging) to depressant (but protective) through a receptor switch, and that this protects against sudden death.  Here we want to know why this happens particularly in women at a time when estrogen is dropping, and whether this can give us insights into male/female differences.  For these experiments we want to move away from animal models to human pluripotent stem cells (hPSC).  We know hPSC can reliably be turned into beating cardiac cells (hPSC-CM), and that they can show the same disrupted rhythm as a patient from which they came. They have adrenaline receptors more like human than are found in animal species, and adrenaline can produce the same kind of rhythm effects in the dish as in the whole heart.  They are also very long-lasting in culture, and can be more easily experimented on - for example to turn off and on specific proteins.  We already have ways to measure their beating activity and how easily they can be damaged.  We also have a number of hPSC lines reflecting different natural gene variation in human populations. We aim to discover the mechanism of the adrenaline switch and how it can be changed by female hormones.  The ideal goal for us would be to find a way to harness the protective effect without producing the temporary loss of heart function, and to develop a drug to use that mechanism.  One other advantage of the hPSC-CM is that they can be produced in large quantities and used in multiple assays at the same time.  The same cells and methods are being used now by pharmaceutical companies to test drugs, which means that any of our promising findings can go more quickly into drug development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="CHINA (PEOPLE&apos;S REPUBLIC OF)"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">28399.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">113826.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">114748.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-11-18">57722.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The general observation that females before menopause are relatively protected against heart disease is well known.  This is most evident for arrhythmic syndromes, largely catecholamine precipitated, where the 80% of sudden death due to cardiac arrhythmia occurs in males. Recently, we (the UK and Chinese laboratories in collaboration) have studied a syndrome of extreme catecholamine stress, where post-menopausal women are particularly vulnerable. We believe this to be an aborted sudden death syndrome, and to represent an intermediate state between the protected young female and the vulnerable male, as estrogen protection is partially withdrawn.  In a paper published between our two laboratories we have shown key roles of biased agonism of the beta2AR in Takotsubo Syndrome or Stress Cardiomyopathy (SCM), which sheds light on arrhythmic syndromes in general.  A deeper understanding of the mechanistic interaction between arrhythmia, estrogen and the beta2AR, as well as population variation in this effect, is an important clinical goal. The induced pluripotent stem cell-derived cardiomyocyte (hPSC-CM) as an in vitro model system will allow us new insights not previously achievable with animal or human primary cell models, both because it is human and genotype-specific, but also for the ease in which it can be cultured and genetically manipulated.   Our hypothesis is that beta2AR switching from Gs-adenylyl cyclase-cAMP signaling to Gi-p38 MAPK signaling decreases contraction at the same time as conferring protection against arrhythmias and cell damage, and that estrogen signalling modifies this.  Our aim is to investigate the effect of estrogen on the biased agonism of the beta2AR and the relationship of this to the genotype of the SCM patient.  We will investigate separately the cardioprotective (anti-arrhythmic, cell survival) and cardiodepressive effects of the beta2AR -Gi switch, asking the questions.   1) What is the effect of the estrogen on beta2AR contraction, arrhythmic and cAMP responses in untreated cells, and after adrenaline shock.  2) Is the effect mediated through the Gi-alpha subunit or Gbeta-gamma/ beta-arrestin mechanisms? 3) What are the downstream signalling pathways activated, and how are these influenced by estrogen?  Is there dissociation between change in cAMP and the suppression of beta2AR positive effects, implying a separate Gi-activated negative inotropic pathway?  4) What is the influence of beta2AR or GRK5 haplotype on beta2AR /estrogen interactions?  Contraction, calcium transient and action potential duration will be used as readouts of function and to detect arrhythmia occurrence (early or delayed after-depolarisations).  cAMP levels will be measured using transfected EPAC2 FRET sensor. These methods have been validated, are in routine use in the UK laboratory, and will be scaled up to high throughput assays in most cases.  Cardiotoxicity experiments for apoptosis and necrosis will use the high content automated microscopy system, Cellomics ArrayScan, with readouts including loss of mitochondrial membrane potential, caspase 3 activation, nuclear condensation, increased cell permeability and decreased cell number. We are developing in a parallel project a number of hPSC-CM lines, either by CRISPR gene editing or by reprogramming of lymphoblasts from available subjects with the correct haplotype. These include lines overexpressing the main beta2AR SNPs with fluorescent (SNAP tag) labelling to allow monitoring of beta2AR movement during catecholamine/beta-blocker challenge, as well as a beta2AR knockout line that will be a valuable control for the experiments described above.    An ideal outcome would be to find a difference in signalling between cardiodepression and cardioprotection which could be exploited in design of beta2AR -Gi agonists to produce an antiarrhythmic and cardioprotective effect without depression of cardiac function."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
