<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T005068_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gendered Journeys: the trajectories of STEM students and graduates through higher education and into employment, in multiple global south contexts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching objectives are: 1. Mapping the patterns of gendered differences in STEM student and employee journeys, using national &apos;big data 2. Investigating longitudinally (via large-scale online standardised surveys) 3. Exploring (via in-depth qualitative methods), influential factors for overcoming perceived barriers to success in STEM study and employment 4. Applying novel interdisciplinary theoretical and analytical frameworks to existing secondary data (building on UKRI-funded big data investment) 5. Disseminating globally a range of academic and user-focused outputs, activities, and events   In order to achieve this aim, the deliverables of the project are as follows: 1. To harness the power of big data, and novel technology Evidenced by:  Aggregated, linked datasets prepared for archiving and onward supply with the UK Data Research Network, via Urban Big Data Centre curation, to be subsequently produce academic outputs, government briefs (&apos;white papers&apos;) and the final project report. 2. To create an innovative culturally embedded evidence base triangulating longitudinal quantitative and qualitative primary research in India and Rwanda; collecting a range of fieldwork data and collectively conducting rigorous, high quality interdisciplinary analyses of women studying STEM and in higher education, as well as entering into skilled employment Evidenced by: Rich and complex mixed-methodology datasets, and related contextual materials to be prepared for archiving at the UK Data Archive or as appropriate; findings to be written up in final project report 3. To co-create, with diverse stakeholders, gender-sensitive &apos;toolkit&apos; resources for future STEM students in India and Rwanda, and CPD resources for STEM employees/employers, tailored to each country context. Evidenced by: The co-creation, and global dissemiantion of toolkit resources and CPD resources (for HEIs) to be made available on the Genderd Journeys Partner Network hosting platforms. 4. To disseminate impactful, transparent, online resources aimed at public stakeholders, and tailored to the needs of policy-change-makers and HEI curriculum development managers alike, launched at user/stakeholder-focused events in India, Rwanda and the UK, and disseminated continuously throughout the research programme via a vibrant global web and social media presence- simultaneously creating a virtual network support women into STEM careers. Evidenced by: Hosting of three &apos;showcase&apos; events, one each to be held in India, Rwanda and the UK; including livestreaming and other &apos;virtual&apos; participation/presence to grow these expert-led networking events virtually worldwide.  5. To produce a range of academic outputs, according to principles of equity, transparency and commitment to valuing and supporting academic research and researchers from the global south, exchanging knowledge, skills, data and methodology to achieve both academic and real-world impact from such outputs. Evidenced by: The production of at least ten journal articles springing from the findings of the project, with authorship collaborations and credit agreed by the team during the project inception phase. 6. To value, nurture and develop the skills and expertise of the Gendered Journeys Partner Network, particularly early career researchers- but also the participants- who themselves will include early career women studying and working in STEM areas, promoting knowledge exchange, skills-building and co-learning activities and workshops equitably led across the national teams, participants and the entire Gendered Journeys Partner Network. Evidenced by: The successful participation in these public-facing knowledge exchange workshops produced by and for team members and others at the host universities, to be launched from the UK, Rwanda and India in conjunction with team, advisory board and wider network meetings (both face to face and virtual).</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will investigate how far, and in what ways, gender may have an influence in the progress of students through higher education, graduation and progression into skilled employment in the STEM sector in India and Rwanda. This is important because science has a critical role in supporting global sustainable development that will not be realised unless it makes better use of the potential skills of women and girls.  At present, girls and women are markedly under-represented in STEM areas both as students and in the workforce in most countries across the globe. At Higher Education level, only 35% of students enrolled in STEM studies internationally are women (UNESCO, 2017a). Addressing this problem is vital in ensuring equitable access to quality education and meaningful work, and is crucial for countries seeking to prioritise equitable economic development, speaking directly to UN  SDGs 4, 5, and 6.    Both our countries of focus, India and Rwanda, currently have a severe under-representation of women STEM students in HE, and in relation to the skilled workforce (WEF, 2018), and there is a limited amount of research in these countries, as in many global south contexts, on gender and STEM issues post-secondary school (for an overview see e.g. UNESCO, 2017a). What is particularly under-researched is the gendered journeys of students once they have accessed university, and beyond into skilled employment (UNESCO, 2017a, EGHE, 2018). Moreover, most lower and middle-income countries do not collect detailed disaggregated data to document access, retention, transfer/dropout, and successful graduation at HE level, especially by institution and discipline (see Chanana, 2007). Neither is there information on the onward journeys of students after they leave education Our research thus seeks to address these gaps.  The project has been organised into 5 distinct work packages (WPs). WP1 involves secondary statistical data analysis of gendered patterns of HE participation and achievement, utilising available data in India and Rwanda, with UK data utilised for comparative purposes. WP2 involves largescale primary survey data with STEM students in both countries. WP3 comprises a range of in-depth qualitative methods, including in-depth interviews with three sets of participants in India and Rwanda: first-year STEM students and final year STEM students at a university in each country and employees in a key STEM employer in each country. All participants will be interviewed again a year later, to explore their experience over time, and for the second group, potential experiences of transition into employment. The team wished to acknowledge similar issues of under-representation according to gender in STEM in the UK, and also to contribute more equitably to the knowledge exchange between countries, hence WP4 involves secondary data analysis of a number of different, relevant qualitative/mixed method datasets in UK Data Service archives.  Responsibility for impact activities will be shared equally between partner HEIs. Academic outputs will include at least 10 journal articles to be submitted to high impact journals in appropriate fields. Non-academic outputs will include the development of gender-sensitive virtual support &apos;toolkits&apos; , developed in conjunction with student participants; and gender-sensitive CPD materials developed in conjunction with STEM academic and industry staff, tailored to appropriate national/regional contexts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">84604.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">339103.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">118431.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-09">456044.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">84604.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T005068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">84604.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T005068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">84604.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T005068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">84604.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T005068_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
