<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_S018964_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bean Breeding for Adaptation to a Changing Climate and Post-Conflict Colombia (BBACO)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In Colombia, about 3.4 million people are employed in primary agricultural production in rural areas with typical wages of less than four dollars per day. Beans are a major source of protein and mineral nutrition in the diets of the rural and urban poor. The development of improved, locally adapted bean varieties and extension of the current bean growing area is indispensable for the improvement of health and nutrition of the population, which is a prerequisite for social stability and economic growth in Colombia. This is also particularly important for regions where ex-combatants are settling and the post-conflict transition from illicit to food and cash crops.  In many areas where beans are grown, or will be grown in the future, high temperatures in combination with water stress severely reduce crop yield. Stress tolerant beans are therefore urgently needed to prevent food insecurity and secure farm incomes today, and even more so in the future, when heat events will be more frequent and severe due to climate change.   Applying a holistic, multidisciplinary approach and building on CIAT&apos;s previous breeding efforts and data generated in Stage I, this project will develop novel methods for the breeding, screening and adoption of heat-tolerant beans, therefore reducing breeding, delivery and adoption time. This will enable the development of climate resilient beans, as well as models and decision tools to identify suitable areas for bean cultivation and socio-economic factors relevant for adoption by farmers and consumers. This will contribute to climate resilience, poverty reduction, and nutritional outcomes in current and new (post-conflict) growing areas).  This will be achieved by (i) providing a mechanistic understanding of high temperature tolerance in beans grown in current climates and simulated future climates (heat, high CO2), (ii) translating mechanistic understanding into state-of-the-art crop-climate models to identify target environments and stresses for breeding, (iii) linking mechanistic understanding of stress with genomic tools for breeding (GWAS, GS), and (iv) guide seed breeding and delivery efforts to enhance adoption of heat tolerant beans through fundamental understanding of the socio-economic dynamics of farming and non-farming (ex-combatant) communities.   For this project, two pump-priming (Stage I) projects on beans have been merged to bring together cutting-edge expertise and experimental facilities and approaches in breeding and genetics, as well as in crop and molecular physiology, paired with crop-climate modelling and socio-economics. This multi-disciplinary team with complementary expertise will work closely together to ensure that the outcomes of this project are relevant and directly applicable to the targeted areas and that there is engagement for ensuring  impact in the affected communities.   This project thereby contributes to food security, improved nutrition for the rural and urban poor in Colombia and will help improve livelihood and perspective of poor Colombians and ex-combatants.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Signing of the Colombian peace accord requires sustainable livelihoods for ex-combattants and displaced people, many of whom live in low altitude tropical regions. While bean is widely proposed as a highly nutritious and marketable crop for these groups to cultivate, its productivity may be constrained by high temperatures. Rising temperatures is already threatening the livelihoods of existing smallholder bean growers in the Andean regions. While the International Centre for Tropical Agriculture (CIAT) has lowland breeding stations to discriminate genetic variation in heat tolerance based on seed yield, two major knowledge gaps could undermine the efficiency of its breeding for heat tolerance. First, stress patterns associated with low-altitude heat may not reflect the overall seasonal stress patterns or diurnal temperature excursions predicted in current areas where beans are grown or recommended to be grown, and second, the physiological mechanisms underpinning existing genetic variability are poorly understood. Moreover, it is not clear whether available heat tolerant germplasm will be readily accepted by the target beneficiary groups.  Accordingly, our OVERARCHING objective is to develop a suite of novel methods for the breeding, screening and adoption of heat-tolerant beans so as to create a more effective and efficient heat-tolerance breeding, delivery and adoption pipeline that will deliver poverty reduction, enhanced resilience and better nutritional outcomes via the efficient, targeted delivery and adoption of heat-tolerant bean genotypes.  Our SPECIFIC objectives are to: 1. Develop a detailed understanding of precisely which physiological and developmental processes respond differently to precisely timed heat/humidity stresses at different developmental stages for common bean and seek validation of the relevance of these responses in the field (Work Package (WP) 1 including Tasks 1.1-1.4 address this high level objective) 2. Incorporate our new understanding of heat stress responses into bean crop models in order to develop an enhanced capability to predict impacts of a variety of climate scenarios in Colombia and beyond. (Task 2.1) 3. Use the improved bean model to predict impact of stress patterns found across the climatically diverse Colombian territory both at present and in the future and develop from this analysis recommendations for selection sites for breeding which reliably deliver stress patterns shown to have widespread significance in the future (Task 2.2) 4. Use the novel precise screens developed in WP1 on whole populations segregating for heat tolerance in order to map genetic loci controlling this trait; availability of molecular markers will facilitate environment-independent selection of components of heat tolerance in early generations of the breeding programme. 5. Investigate adoption pathways for heat-tolerant bean varieties amongst traditional and new (ex-combattants and those displaced by conflict) bean growers and assess the economic potential of heat tolerant beans in a changing climate using data and insights from the experimental and modelling WPs to refine the impact analysis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-01">358306.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-01">231344.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-01">72345.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-01">661997.36</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Reading</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/S018964/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Reading</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FS018964%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
