<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening South Africa&apos;s health system through integrating treatment for mental illness into chronic disease care (Project MIND)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrating mental health care into general health services could reduce the impact of both chronic communicable and non-communicable diseases (NCDs). Like many low- and middle-income countries (LMICs), South Africa (SA) faces the challenge of how to reduce the high prevalence and impact of these disorders within its under-resourced health care system (1). The NCD burden in LMICs includes mental disorders, globally the leading cause of non-fatal burden of disease (2). More than 70% of the global burden of disease for mental disorders lies in LMICs where a substantial treatment gap exists (3). For example, 30% and 17% of adults in SA meet diagnostic criteria for a lifetime and past 12 month mental disorder respectively, yet less than a quarter ever receive treatment (4).  The effective detection and treatment of mental disorders is critical to a fully operational health system (5). This is key as people with chronic physical diseases, including HIV and diabetes, are at increased risk for mental disorders, which in turn contribute to sub-optimal adherence to treatment (6-7), treatment failure, and more rapid disease progression (8-9). As treatment failure increases health service utilisation and health care costs (10), health systems in LMICs must be expanded to include mental health care.  Collaborative care models that allow for the integrated delivery of chronic disease and mental health services have been shown to improve access to mental health care and patient outcomes for single mental disorders, especially when mental health care is task shifted to non-specialty staff (11). Yet there have been few studies of the effectiveness of collaborative care for treating multiple mental disorders, their impact on chronic disease outcomes, or of the cost-effectiveness of these models, particularly in LMICs (5). In SA, service integration has been hampered by questions about how to include mental health care in chronic disease services so that these services are acceptable to providers and patients and feasible to implement with few resources. Formative work is needed to identify barriers to integration and to guide the tailoring of proposed collaborative care models for chronic disease services. Integrated mental health and chronic disease care has also been delayed by uncertainty about whether vertically integrated services (where mental health and chronic disease care are co-located but provided by condition-specific services and mental health services are delivered by supervised, dedicated lay counsellors) offer an advantage over horizontally integrated services (where mental health and chronic disease care is concurrently provided at point-of-care by the same general health practitioners) (12-13).   To address this gap, we propose comparing two models for integrating mental health care into chronic disease services. To this end we have partnered with the Western Cape Department of Health (WCDOH). The overall goal of this study is to identify a feasible, acceptable and effective model for integrating mental health services into chronic communicable and non-communicable disease care for patients at risk of treatment failure in Cape Town, SA. Specific objectives are: 1. To conduct a health systems analysis to assess the feasibility and acceptability of a vertical and horizontal model for integrating mental health care into HIV and diabetes services respectively, in order to identify potential barriers to implementation. 2. To conduct a randomised controlled trial (RCT) within HIV and diabetes services in order to compare the impact of a vertical model of service integration relative to a horizontal model relative to treatment as usual (TAU), with a) depression and b) risky alcohol use as primary outcomes and c) HIV1 RNA viral load and d) HbA1c as secondary chronic disease outcomes. 3. To conduct a cost-effectiveness analysis, comparing a vertical model of service integration relative to a horizontal model relative to TAU.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrating mental health care into primary health care services could reduce the impact of both chronic communicable and non-communicable diseases (NCDs). Like many low- and middle-income countries (LMICs), South Africa (SA) faces the challenge of how to reduce the high prevalence and impact of communicable diseases and NCDs, including mental disorders where limited services are available. Mental disorders are important to address among patients with chronic diseases as these problems are associated with poor adherence to treatment, more rapid disease progression and treatment failure. As treatment failure increases the use of health services and health service costs, chronic disease care in LMICs must be expanded to include mental health care. The integrated delivery of mental health services and chronic disease care has been shown to not only improve access to mental health care but also the mental health of patients living with a chronic disease. .   Yet, limited knowledge of how mental health care can be integrated into chronic disease services in ways that are acceptable to patients and providers and feasible to implement with few resources has delayed the integration of services in SA. The provision of integrated mental health and chronic disease services has also been delayed by questions about whether services should be vertically or horizontally integrated. Vertically integrated services are delivered at the same location, but mental health and chronic disease services are provided by separate cadres of health workers. Horizontally integrated services are delivered at the same location by the same staff are responsible for mental health and chronic disease care. The goal of this project is to answer these questions by assessing current capacity and barriers to integrating mental health services into chronic disease care and by comparing the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of a vertically and horizontally integrated model of service integration among patients receiving treatment for HIV or diabetes and who are at risk for treatment failure in Cape Town, SA. Through this project we hope to identify a feasible, acceptable and effective model for integrating mental health services into chronic disease care that is applicable to other LMICs. Findings from this study are likely to be highly relevant for use in other LMICs given similarities between the burden of disease, treatment populations, and treatment systems in SA and other LMICs.  The study will comprise two phases. In the first phase, we will conduct in-depth interviews with a range of healthcare providers in HIV and diabetes services to assess barriers to integration and the feasibility and acceptability of our proposed models of service integration (Aim 1). Findings from this phase will be used to adapt our evidence-based mental health service package for optimal integration into chronic disease services. In phase two, a clustered randomised controlled trial will be conducted. We will select 24 HIV and 24 diabetes clinics to randomise to a vertically integrated arm, horizontally integrated arm, or treatment as usual (no integration). We will recruit 25 patients at risk for treatment failure from each of these clinics (total 1200 patients). After study enrollment, a baseline assessment will be completed by a fieldworker. Participants recruited from clinics randomised to either the vertically integrated or horizontally integrated arm will then receive their intervention sessions. All participants, irrespective of their intervention arm, will be tracked for 6- and 12-month follow-up interviews.  At these interviews, fieldworkers blinded to their intervention arm will re-administer the baseline assessment and biological specimens will be collected to assess for chronic disease outcomes. Findings from this phase will be used to evaluate the relative effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of our proposed models of service integration (Aims 2-3).</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-10">305780.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-10">77042.59</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-10">230301.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-10">214239.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q1">77042.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Medical Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">79604.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Medical Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">79523.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Medical Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">71173</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Medical Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">71413.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Medical Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">71413.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Medical Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">71413.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M014290_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">South African Medical Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
