<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005378_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Development Award on Protection from Enduring and Overlapping Forms of Violence</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This Development Award establishes the preliminary work for a Network on Protection from Enduring and Overlapping Forms of Violence. Humanitarian protection is often associated with particular situations of crisis. However, the vulnerability of specific individuals and groups is also rooted in enduring and multiple forms of conflict and violence. The Protection Network therefore starts with the recognition that there is a need to broaden our conceptual and empirical understanding of protection. In doing so, it examines the challenges of protecting vulnerable people from the perspective of those in need of protection rather than formal organisations, frameworks and norms. The proposed Protection Network is a partnership between the University of Edinburgh, Open University of Sri Lanka, Law and Society Trust, USIU-Africa, Aalborg University and the University of East Anglia and will extend out to include other researchers and practitioners interested in the complex protection needs of vulnerable populations.   Conceptualising protection from the bottom up allows us to appreciate the multiple forms that protection needs take, as they are embedded in social, economic and political contexts. Focusing on people rather than events or normative frames means we can see crisis as non-exceptional, and break with the divide between prevention and response. Doing so also helps us move beyond the silos that have shaped humanitarian interventions, to learn across distinct research and policy domains and to support new communities of practice. It allows us to understand the multiple ways in which people seek to protect themselves from violence - which may, for example, relate to livelihoods as much as legal entitlements - whilst acknowledging that these practices might themselves be contradictory, counter-productive and exclusionary. Either way, starting with on the ground protection needs and practices is essential if we are to begin to find solutions to affirming protective rights and to develop interventions that are both more responsive and more effective.  Kenya and Sri Lanka will act as central hubs for the Protection Network as they are sites of enduring crisis in their own right and because they are regional access points for South and Southeast Asia and East Africa. The two separate hubs will also create opportunities for new forms of South to South collaboration and learning. Both countries are marked by prolonged forms of state and non-state violence, natural disasters and displacement. At the same time, both countries have vibrant humanitarian and human rights communities and have been the site of diverse forms of international intervention.   The Protection Network will produce holistic and actionable knowledge that will be fed into more established forms of expertise. By establishing a research agenda that is rooted in lived realities rather than policy categories, the Network will bridge areas including human rights, humanitarianism and international development, forced migration studies, security and gender studies.   This Development Project advances the objectives of the Protection Network by consulting with stakeholder and beneficiary communities, beginning a multi-sector and multi-disciplinary conversation about the meaning of protection and the scope of protection activities in Kenya and Sri Lanka and creating opportunities for sustained conversation on these topics among the Network project team.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This Development Award seeks to inform the development of our Network Plus proposal to establish a Network on Protection from Enduring and Overlapping Forms of Violence. The Protection Network recognises that vulnerability is rooted in multiple, overlapping forms of conflict and violence and seeks to develop understanding of protection strategies as similarly enduring and overlapping. The Protection Network therefore examines the challenges of protecting vulnerable people from the perspective of those in need in protection rather than with reference to narrowly-defined categories, organisations, frameworks and norms. Starting with on the ground protection needs and practices is essential if we are to begin to find solutions to affirming protective rights, and to develop interventions that are both more responsive and more effective. The Protection Network&apos;s activities will be focused on the creation of deep contextual knowledge in two hubs: Sri Lanka and Kenya.   The overall aim of the Protection Network is to support individuals and groups from vulnerable communities affected by enduring forms of conflict and violence to develop and strengthen effective and inclusive protection mechanisms. Four linked objectives will contribute to this aim:  1. To develop an international and multi-disciplinary network of practitioners and researchers concerned with the complex protection needs of people from vulnerable groups.   2. To create new knowledge about the diverse protection needs, experiences and practices of people from vulnerable groups, in order to develop understanding around which protection practices work, in which contexts, for whom and in which ways.   3. To strengthen research and research-to-practice capacity in partner countries at all levels of the research and practice base.  4. To create new opportunities for developing communities of practice around protection issues, particularly across specific domains of protection expertise.   This Development Project shares the overall objectives of the Protection Network, and seeks to advance those objectives by establishing processes of communication and engagement that can contribute to building and strengthening equitable partnerships, strengthening contextual knowledge and understanding and engaging with less-easily accessed research participants.  These objectives will be pursued by holding participatory stakeholder workshops and potentially additional one-on-one meetings with community-based organisations; by commissioning scoping research to map the protection environments and protection actors in Kenya and Sri Lanka (including international and national agencies, non-governmental organisations and community-based organisations).  This will inform our development of the Network Plus proposal and will establish a baseline shared understanding and knowledge of the protection contexts in Kenya and Sri Lanka that can underpin the first stages of a Network on Protection from Enduring and Overlapping Forms of Violence.  Further strengthening our international partnership, the University of Edinburgh will provide support to enable Kenyan and Sri Lankan CoIs on the Network Plus proposal to attend an interview in the UK, should the proposal get to that stage.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">54718.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">0.06</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">54718.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Large Grants Award to University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/T005378/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">54718.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005378_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">0.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005378_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">-13855.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005378_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of East Anglia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FT005378%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
