<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004277_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NetDiploma: Network for Digital Public Library of Modern Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The rapidly growing population of Africa calls for: 1. Education and training vis-&#xE0;-vis employment of an exploding African youth population; and  2. Sustainable management of human (cultural integration and peaceful coexistence) and natural resources.  UNESCO&apos;s actions for Flagship programmes 5 and 6 (http://unesdoc.unesco.org/images/0022/002244/224489e.pdf) propose: - &quot;Improve universal access to information and knowledge as well as build capacity in the field of ICT use in Africa&quot; (p.11) - &quot;Promoting universal access and preservation of information and knowledge&quot; (p.13) - &quot;Culture (heritage in all its forms and contemporary creativity) is mainstreamed into public development policies&quot; (p.13) - &quot;Young people made aware of the values of the heritage and mobilized to protect and safeguard it.&quot; (p.13)  Analysis of the key UN resolutions and policy documents shows the importance of access and sharing of information for achieving the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) (Chowdhury &amp; Koya, In Press). However, information services in Africa face a number of challenges: - common information delivery channels, viz. mass media; information services (libraries); education and training programmes including conferences, workshops etc.,  benefit only a small section of society (educated and city/urban dwellers) while the majority of the population who live in rural areas cannot reach or use these information services (Uzuegbu, 2016) -  libraries in Africa suffer from lack of funds to build an ICT infrastructure, to subscribe to online information resources, and to train personnel (Chisenga, 2015) - management of digital content remains a huge challenge in the public sector as there is no technological infrastructure to manage and provide access to digital information properly; hence millions of digitised archival documents remain inaccessible.  Research also shows that mobile access to cultural heritage information services is rapidly increasing in Europe (Nicholas et al, 2013; Liew, 2014).  Use of mobile phones is contributing to development in Africa, especially in the rural areas, through internet banking, micro-loans, micro-enterprises, market integration, social mobility, health etc (Cibangu, 2016). Indeed mobile banking has brought a revolution in Africa, and an IMF report (https://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/reo/2016/afr/eng/sreo0416.htm) recommends that &quot;there is significant potential to replicate the Kenyan experience in the rest of sub-Saharan Africa&quot; [p. 74].  We intend to explore whether this approach can be applied to the delivery of digital information, including cultural heritage information.  Bringing together a consortium of academics, researchers and professionals, key local partners such as the national libraries, national archives and universities in three African countries (Ethiopia, Kenya, Malawi), and international organizations including IFLA, UNESCO, UNECA and the African Union, we will seek to understand the historical, cultural, linguistic, technological and transregional challenges to inform the research and development agenda for building a Digital Public Library of Africa (DPLAf). A bottom-up approach will be taken to explore and prioritise various user needs to complement the ongoing activities in Africa,  like the Access to Scientific and Socioeconomic Knowledge in Africa project (http://askia.uneca.org),  in order to  match the demand  and supply of information while preparing a blueprint for the DPLAf for achieveing SDGs in Africa.  The network will provide a collaborative vehicle to communicate development needs to the multiple disciplines required to undertake the research and design. It will inform policy and strategy development for providing digital, and wherever possible mobile, access to information for African populations to facilitate education and sustainable development in any sector. Hence it will facilitate the achievement of UN SDG 16.10 (public access to information).</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-09-11"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-10" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-08" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">37262.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">15969.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Access to and sharing of information is paramount for sustainable development in all areas [1]. UN SDG (Sustainable Development Goal) 16.10 (https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/post2015/transformingourworld) specifically advocates for ensuring public access to information, yet knowledge access and sharing are some of the key challenges in modern Africa, whose population is growing rapidly with large numbers of people being marginalised or left out. Communications with the project partners in Africa revealed that millions of records and information objects have been digitised by various memory institutions, but largely remain inaccessible because of a lack of ICT infrastructure, human and other resources. Such inaccessibility to information assets has implications for access to education, healthcare, agriculture, industrial innovation and development, environmental sustainability and disaster response.   In line with SDG17.16 and the UN Addis Ababa convention (http://www.un.org/esa/ffd/ffd3/press-release/countries-reach-historic-agreement.html) the NetDiploma project will build a sustainable global multi-stakeholder network to mobilize and share knowledge and identify future collaborative research required to build a Digital Public Library of Africa (DPLAf) that will promote access to information for everyone and support economic and cultural development. The objective of NetDiploma is to explore how the life, education and empowerment capabilities of people, including those that are &quot;left behind&quot; (https://consultations2.worldhumanitariansummit.org) can be improved by information access and use, utilising enabling technologies, systems and policies appropriately adapted to the culture and context of people in Africa. To achieve this, the project will address the following questions:  1. What are the key cultural, historical, political, linguistic and technology enablers and challenges to community access to information in Africa? 2. How can modern ICT and mobile technologies be used to facilitate access to information required for education, health and wellbeing, cultural integration, agriculture, tourism etc? 3. What policies and practices are required for developing and managing a free DPLAf? 4. What further research is needed to enable the development of a DPLAf? The network will explore how lessons learnt from the recently launched Digital Public Library of America (DPLA) (https://dp.la/) that brings &quot;different viewpoints, experiences, and collections together in a single platform and portal, providing open and coherent access to our society&apos;s digitized cultural heritage&quot;, can be adapted to the socio-economic and cultural context of Africa, especially  languages, economic and human resources, technology infrastructure, regulations, policies, socio-cultural practices, and information/digital literacy. A bottom-up approach will explore and prioritise various user needs to complement the ongoing activities  like the Access to Scientific and Socioeconomic Knowledge in Africa project (http://askia.uneca.org) in order to  match the demand  and supply of information for SDG, and prepare a blueprint for the DPLAf. Through one event in the UK and one in each of the three participating African countries the network will engage with researchers and professionals in memory institutions, international and national organisations and NGOs. NetDiploma will focus on the cultural, behavioural and literacy issues of people as the key enablers in exploring how everyone, including the poorest and most vulnerable, can benefit from better access to and use of information. The project will develop an arts and humanities led interdisciplinary research agenda to inform and facilitate the achievement of UN SDG 16.10 (public access to information) to support change in Africa.  1 Chowdhury, G &amp; Koya, K. (2017) Information practices for sustainability: role of iSchools in achieving the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). JASIST. In Press"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">37262.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004277_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northumbria University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">15969.72</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004277_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northumbria University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">-3476.61</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R004277_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Northumbria University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
