<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029927_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Women&apos;s Equality &amp; Digital Access: Rights To Expression WE-DARE</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main goal of the research is to explore how access to digital platforms and innovation can protect and further women&apos;s basic rights in Africa and protect them against violence and inequality. Our focus is on addressing the problem of violence against women and a lack of access to digital citizenship in South Africa, and potentially in a broader African context. Recent events related to violence against women in South Africa (Karim and Mthethwa, 2019) and in Nigeria (Human Rights Watch, 2019) have increased the urgency to address this problem across societal institutions. Business schools have the capacity to leverage corporate connections and design cross-sectoral collaboration to enable a comprehensive and interdisciplinary understanding of the problem, as well as the capacity building required to address it. Our 4 key objectives are: 1) understanding the influence of the &apos;digital gender divide&apos; on women; 2) improving women&apos;s access to digital innovation; 3) facilitating digital participation to improve service delivery and 4) creating a speak-out culture against gender-based violence.  The multifaceted precarity of women in society is acknowledged in the literature on gender intersectionality (Hill Collins and Bilge, 2016), and our focus will be on understanding the way in which the &apos;digital gender divide&apos; exacerbates the problem. On-going technological transformation and the digitalisation of our lives pose considerable opportunities but also risks for the agency, rights and work of women in Africa (Madzwamuse and Kouakou, 2018: 5). Digital spaces, and the industries that produce, utilise and enjoy them, are by no means neutral. Extant research into gender and women&apos;s rights in digital spaces recognize that inequalities and exclusions in the real or offline world, including gender stereotypes and gender-based discrimination and violence, are often reproduced online (van der Spuy and Aavriti, 2018). This stems from a number of elements suggesting a &apos;digital gender divide&apos;.   In terms of access, women in Africa face much greater barriers than men in accessing ICTs and developing digital literacy; few women in Africa also enter STEM-related fields, resulting in less women than men owning, designing and operating online platforms and content, as well as influencing policy related to technology (Madzwamuse and Kouakou, 2018). In terms of their participation in online spaces, the emergence of various online labour markets (e.g. data entry, &apos;byte&apos; contract work, and the &apos;gig economy&apos;) that operate without clear regulations to guarantee decent work standards, social benefits, or gender equity, also contribute to the continued precarity of women in the workplace (Chimedza, 2018; Bhatasara and Chirimambowa, 2018). Finally, the persistence of targeted harassment and gender-based violence online has rendered women and gender-diverse people hyper-visible in some contexts, yet limits to free expression (e.g. censorship around sexual expression tend to target women but not women&apos;s bodies) also render women invisible (Avriti et al. 2018).   Our aim is to build research networks to understand and address the complex interplay of racial, gender and economic inequality, information poverty and the lack of access to digital means. Meeting our objectives will entail: 1: Understanding the way in which the digital context may affect women&apos;s rights, both positively and negatively; 2: Identifying the primary local barriers to access that undermines the agency of women in realising their rights and protecting them against violence in both the public and private domains; 3: Identifying strategies by which the participation of women and other gender-diverse groups in relevant policy platforms could be supported and streamlined in order to enable easier access to government services; 4: Co-creating new digital innovations that could enable a stronger speak-out culture against violence and inequality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project involves two interrelated approaches: a) organising networking events and other in-depth stakeholder engagements to build an active research consortium of academics and practitioners focused on combating violence against women; and b) facilitating the co-creation of problem-solving digital innovations to be implemented and studied in a further phase of the project (post-October 2020). a) The networking events and stakeholder engagements with 10 network partners (NGOs and tech companies) will explore 4 interrelated dimensions:  - Understanding women&apos;s rights in a digital context: By means of inclusive stakeholder dialogues taking place at a Roundtable and a Public Forum, we will explore how women&apos;s rights are constructed in online spaces and collective movements in South Africa and elsewhere, in order to identify the tacit roots of discrimination and victimization, and to understand how these may be reproduced, but could also be addressed, in digital settings. - Access: Through focus groups, we will identify the primary local barriers to access that undermines the agency of women in realising their rights and protecting themselves against violence and intimidation. We aim to understand both practical impediments like access to electricity, affordable data and instruments, as well as the more tacit cultural, social and individual factors that could undermine active participation in digital spaces.  - Participation: The potential of digital platforms to enable easier access to government services, especially around healthcare and justice, can play an important role in upholding women&apos;s rights, protecting them against violence and intimidation, and offering avenues for recourse and support. We will explore how the participation of women in relevant policy platforms could be strengthened and streamlined, as well as what government and corporate policy changes may be needed to protect women&apos;s rights and voices online.  - Speak-out &amp; Action: Studying the ways in which women communicate in digital spaces will allow us to identify the factors that make women feel safe, supported and empowered to speak out against violence and discrimination. The Affect Lab brings detailed expertise on participation in online chat forums, and one of their post-doctoral researchers will study engagements on a specific forum focused on violence against women that will be created within the Values Chat APP, a mobile tool which was designed and launched in a previous round of funding.  b) Our engagements with our business and NGO partners will go beyond networking events towards the co-creation of potential digital innovations. The goal would be to understand these organisations&apos; current business models, services and approaches to digitalization. This will ensure that we do not reinvent the wheel, but rather productively build on lessons learnt and leverage these insights to co-create specific pilot projects that could be funded in further phases of the DIDA grant-cycle. For instance, working with Wiconnect will allow us to understand the complex relationship between access to electricity, data and education and explore the potential impact of strengthening women&apos;s access to and productive use of digital innovations. By studying Saya-Setona&apos;s activities, women&apos;s current participation as digital citizens will be explored in order to identify specific factors that could enhance government communication and women&apos;s access to government services. We will also work with Praekelt.com, who delivers digital community projects through its sister organisation, Praekelt.org, as well as with OpenUp, which is a civic tech organisation in South Africa focused on open data for active citizenry. By studying their successful digital interventions, particularly those targeted at women, we hope to gain insight into how digital participation can be scaled and supported, and which future interventions would best address the problem of violence against women.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-22">128658.28</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T029927/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">32164.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029927_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">32164.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029927_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">32164.57</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029927_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nottingham Trent University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT029927%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
