<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MNS Disorders in Guyana&apos;s Jails, 1825 to the present day</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will research a critical but entirely neglected aspect of the prison system in Guyana, which certainly contributes to violence and instability: the definition, extent, experience and treatment of MNS disorders among inmates and the people who work with them. A UK-Guyana team will co-create new academic perspectives from Economic and Social History and Criminology, and use them to produce policy-relevant materials on mental health, cognitive impairment, addiction and substance abuse among prisoners and prison officers. The research will be shared with the project&apos;s partner, the Guyana Prison Service, which has an appetite for change and is seeking to effect transformations in prisoner well-being, health and education, during a time of unprecedented penal crisis. The project will not only model a new interdisciplinary way of working in this field, it will impact on prisoner and officer well-being and education, and on the rehabilitation of inmates.   The project&apos;s perspective is historical, social and cultural. It covers the period from 1825, when the British opened the colony&apos;s first jail in Georgetown, to the present day, following Guyana&apos;s independence in 1966. It is rooted in the hypothesis that the existence of MNS disorders in jails today can be traced back to the British colonial period, and that they cannot be disconnected from the country&apos;s history as a sugar colony that employed and controlled indigenous people (Amerindians), enslaved Africans and indentured Indian labourers. Empire created particular forms of trauma, shaped demography and religious practice, and instituted patterns of population control including through institutionalisation. We seek to render this history actively part of the process of change, by connecting new historical work to new criminological research on Guyana since independence. We are especially interested in assessing and evaluating different definitions and management regimes for people afflicted with MNS disorders in Guyana&apos;s jails, among the colony/ country&apos;s multi-ethnic and multi-religious population of indigenous, African and Asian descent, and including women and juveniles.  Guyana has serious resource constraints; in terms of GDP it is the second poorest country (after Haiti) in the southern hemisphere. Following the destruction of the country&apos;s largest jail during a prison riot in 2017, the challenges facing Guyana&apos;s prison system are unparalleled in the Caribbean region. This project is urgent and timely. The research team will conduct research on colonial-era and post-1966 archives and records, and conduct focus groups, workshop and interviews with prison personnel, communities living near prisons, and prisoners&apos; families. The project seeks to enhance academic, practitioner and public understanding of MNS disorders in the jails context; build robust relationships between academics, practitioners and policy makers; and stimulate behavioural change among key actors. Its impacts will be to enhance prison security, improve the administration of criminal justice, and respect prisoner well-being, rights and equality, whilst protecting the public from people deemed &apos;dangerous&apos;.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-09-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="GY" type="GUYANA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">200234.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">402090.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-09">405347.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Our overriding objective is for the first time to conduct historical and criminological research on a critical but almost entirely neglected aspect of Guyana&apos;s prison system: the definition, experience, management and treatment of MNS disorders. We will research MNS disorders among prisoners and the people who work with them, in the country&apos;s five jails: Georgetown, Lusignan, Mazaruni (inc. juvenile establishment Sibley Hall), New Amsterdam (inc. female prison), and Timehri. We will take a long and broad historical, social and cultural approach, covering the period from 1825, when the British Empire opened the colony&apos;s first jail in Georgetown, through to the present day, following Guyanese independence in 1966. Our intermediate objectives aim to:  1. Discover how the different ethnic and religious communities, including men, women and youths, define and experience MNS disorders in the jails context, historically and today.  2. Establish and evaluate rates of prevalence of MNS disorders in Guyana&apos;s jails (1825-present), according to the definitions of global health studies, and the findings of (1) above.  3. Find out about and evaluate MNS disorders welfare provision in Guyana&apos;s prisons, examined particularly through ethnicity, religious, gender and generational lenses (1825-present). 4. Stimulate debate and behavioural change among the Guyana Prison Service, including its Sentence Management Board, the Guyana Ministry of Health (Mental Health Department), people living close to jails, prisoners&apos; families and relevant NGOs. 5. Inform policy and practice, by enhancing support for prisoners and their families, and improving prison officer support and training. 6. Engage with academic beneficiaries over the methods and substantive findings of the project so that we contribute to wider interdisciplinary debates within global health studies, and to historical and criminological research on penality, incarceration and prisoner release in regards to health and well-being, social welfare, ethnicity, religion, gender and generation. 7. Connect present-day challenges associated with MNS disorders to the history and legacies of the British Empire in Guyana, especially in regards to jails regimes, labour management, demography and culture. 8. Strengthen the existing partnership between the universities of Leicester and Guyana, and between both parties and the Guyana Prison Service. 9. Establish new relationships with Guyana&apos;s Ministry for Public Health, NGOs and HMP Leicester. 10. Render the research findings portable to other ODA-recipient countries in the Caribbean region.  11. Enhance the knowledge base and work of the UK Ministry of Justice, HM Inspector of Prisons and HMP Leicester."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">135158.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">135158.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">135158.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">135158.22</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">136253.0025</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">136253</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">136253</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">136253</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">137356.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_S000569_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
