<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P008852_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The immunological basis of susceptibility to nontyphoidal Salmonella bacteraemia among HIV-infected adults in Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nontyphoidal strains of Salmonella are a major cause of fatal bloodstream infection in Africa, particularly among young children and people living with HIV/AIDS. These Salmonella infections are difficult to diagnose and antibiotic resistance is an increasing problem, so an effective vaccine against nontyphoidal Salmonella (NTS) has the potential to save many lives. Vaccines currently in development against NTS aim to work by stimulating the production of antibodies to a sugar known as O-antigen which is part of the lipopolysaccharide (LPS) molecule and found on the Salmonella surface. My previous research has shown that some HIV-infected adults in Africa have very high levels of these antibodies which then block killing of the Salmonella bacteria. Hence there is a risk that these vaccines may cause harm to people with HIV. This project aims to understand the basis for susceptibility to NTS bloodstream infections in HIV-infected Africans, and in particular to understand the phenomenon of blocking antibodies, with a view to designing improved vaccines that will protect HIV-infected groups against NTS. I hypothesise that NTS is present at increased levels in the gut in HIV infection and that because the gut wall does not function properly in these patients, the Salmonella bacteria are able to invade the bloodstream. Here they can go on to cause severe disease and death due to the inability of the immune system to kill these bacteria, because of the presence of blocking levels of antibodies. I hypothesise that the continual movement of Salmonella and Salmonella LPS into the circulation drives the production of these high levels of blocking antibodies, because antibody production is no longer appropriately regulated in HIV infection. I will test this hypothesis in a group of adults newly-diagnosed with HIV infection in Uganda, studying them for two years after they commence antiretroviral therapy (ART) and comparing them with HIV-uninfected subjects. Incidence of NTS bloodstream infections initially rises when starting ART and then falls, but remains much higher than in HIV-uninfected subjects. Therefore, looking at specific immune parameters with time on ART will help understand which are most relevant to susceptibility to NTS infection. Since compromise of the barrier state of the gut is key to my hypothesis, I will study samples of gut tissue taken at endoscopy, as well as peripheral blood. First, I will test to see whether NTS is present in the gut of HIV-infected participants and whether it occurs more frequently and at higher levels than in HIV-uninfected controls. Then I will investigate the transfer of Salmonella from the gut to the bloodstream and compare this with the immune status of the gut wall, seeing whether this transfer is associated with loss of particular groups of immune cells known as Th17 and mucosal-associated invariant T (MAIT) cells. Finally, I will study the levels and function of antibodies targeting LPS O-antigen, to determine whether they block or kill Salmonella, comparing them with antibodies to a protein known as flagellin which is also present on the Salmonella surface. I will test whether levels and function of these antibodies associate with changes in the numbers and function of two further groups of immune cells, Tfh and Treg cells, which are infected by HIV and which regulate antibody production. I will follow changes in these immune parameters in the group of HIV-infected participants over time on ART, and look for associations at time points with known differences in susceptibility to NTS. This will enable me to better understand which factors are most relevant for susceptibility to NTS, the mechanism of susceptibility and production of blocking antibodies, and what vaccine or other therapeutic strategies might best protect HIV-infected populations against NTS.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the project is to understand the immunological basis of susceptibility to nontyphoidal Salmonella (NTS) bacteraemia among HIV-infected Africans and the limitations of its reversal with ART. This builds on my previous research which identified high levels of antibodies to O-antigen of NTS lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in HIV-infected African adults resulting in an inability to kill NTS in the blood. After 4 1/2 years in industry developing vaccines against NTS that induce such antibodies, a MRC Senior Clinical Fellowship would allow me to return to academia to fully explore the phenomenon of these blocking antibodies in a wider immunological and microbiological context. This work is important in order to understand the potential of current NTS vaccines in development to protect or even to harm HIV-infected individuals who are highly susceptible to NTS bacteraemia, and would provide me the opportunity to consolidate my career at the interface between academia and industry as a vaccinologist and immunologist. My hypothesis consists of three components to be tested in three interlinked objectives: 1. In HIV-infected African adults, NTS is carried in the gastrointestinal tract. 2. Loss of Th17 cells and innate-like lymphocytes, particularly mucosal-associated invariant T (MAIT) cells, leads to impaired immunity of the gastrointestinal (GI) mucosa leading to increased translocation of NTS into the systemic circulation. 3. This establishes ongoing bacterial challenge and antigenic stimulation that drives production of high levels of antibodies to LPS O-antigen in the context of dysregulated Tfh cells. These antibodies, as we have previously shown, result in impaired killing of NTS and hence bacteraemia. The hypothesis will be tested in a cohort of newly-diagnosed HIV-infected adults in Uganda at the MRC/UVRI Uganda Research Unit on AIDS that I will follow for two years on antiretroviral therapy (ART), comparing findings with those in HIV-uninfected controls. Susceptibility to NTS bacteraemia initially increases on ART, then falls, but remains at a level much higher than that in HIV-uninfected subjects. Thus investigating patients longitudinally on ART provides an excellent opportunity to understand the parameters underlying susceptibility to NTS. The 1st objective is to determine NTS carriage in the GI-tract of HIV-infected African adults using microbiological culture and metagenomic analysis of the microbiome. We have previously found low levels of NTS carriage among HIV-uninfected subjects in Africa (unpublished data), but alteration of the microbiome with HIV infection suggests that NTS carriage will be more prevalent in the HIV-infected population. Metagenomics will allow me to determine whether carried NTS are of the same pathovars as those responsible for invasive disease. The 2nd objective is to determine translocation of NTS from the GI-tract to the circulation in HIV-infected patients using immunological and biochemical markers, and qPCR. I will examine numbers and function of Th17 and MAIT cells in peripheral blood and GI mucosa and test for association with NTS translocation. I predict that translocation will be much higher than in HIV-uninfected subjects and will first increase on ART then decrease with reconstitution of Th17 and MAIT cells. The 3rd objective is to understand why there are excessive blocking levels of anti-O-antigen antibodies in HIV-infected subjects. This will involve studying levels and function of antibodies to LPS O-antigen in HIV-infected subjects, comparing these to antibodies against flagellin and testing how they vary with ART and changes in translocation of Salmonella and LPS. Since Tfh and Treg cells are targeted by HIV infection and regulate antibody production, I will test association between numbers and function of these cells and LPS antibodies, and association between findings from all three objectives and time on ART to help prove or refute the hypothesis.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-28">638726.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-28">581993.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-28">293354</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-28">147865.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-28">298125.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-28">2995139.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Fellowships, FEC Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P008852_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP008852%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
