<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R009589_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">International: Use of phase-sensitive radar to monitor discharge and recharge of Moroccan aquifers</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The motivation for the proposed study is the difficulty in managing water abstraction in the absence of good information about the degree of charge of aquifers, the growing consensus that groundwater recharge will diminish in arid and semiarid areas in sub-Saharan and western Africa, and the ever-increasing pressure on aquifers from increased abstraction. The aim of the proposed work is to determine the feasibility of using a NERC-developed instrument (ApRES) to aid the management of water resources in arid and semi-arid regions by allowing water-table depths to be monitored without recourse to boreholes. The challenge has both technical and societal aspects. The Autonomous phase-sensitive Radio Echo Sounder (ApRES) was jointly developed by the British Antarctic Survey and University College London to monitor the changing thickness of the floating portion of the Antarctic Ice Sheet. Lightweight, robust and relatively inexpensive, ApRES was designed to be deployed on an ice sheet for a year or more, withstanding the harsh conditions of the Antarctic winter. The problem of detecting the changing depth of the base of an ice sheet is essentially the same as that of detecting the depth of the water table in an otherwise dry environment. ApRES can therefore potentially be used as relatively inexpensive (compared with boreholes) method for monitoring the depth of the water table, providing a tool to assist in the management of water abstraction. Our choice of country for this study is Morocco. Morocco boasts a useful range of soil types, climatic conditions, and water table depths.  Its many boreholes provide the necessary ground truth by offering an independent measure of the depth of the water table. A short pilot study was undertaken in Morocco in March 2017, funded through a NERC ODA Innovation pump-prime grant, and locally facilitated by the partners on the present proposal. The results were promising. Several sites were visited, with varying water table depths, primarily to find a suitable location for a multi-hour deployment.  The instrument was able to detect the water table at most of the sites and was able to monitor its changing depth over a 6-hour (overnight) trial. The promising results from the pilot now prompts the next step - a comprehensive study in Morocco, alongside our Moroccan partners, to determine more precisely the envelope of capability of the instrument, and to reduce impediments to its use in monitoring groundwater depth: ease of use, robustness, cost. In the proposed study visits to different field sites in Morocco will allow the utility of ApRES to be assessed for a range of soil types, soil moisture contents, water table depths, local conditions (urban/rural) and seasons (wet/dry).  The instrument and antennas will be scrutinised to see where costs can be reduced and what hardening will be needed to deal with the non-polar conditions.  Finally, the data-processing steps will be rationalised such that a non-expert could carry them out. The societal aspect of the challenge, how to ensure uptake of any new technique, will be addressed in two ways. An independently resourced, but parallel study that we have instigated (to be delivered by Development i-Teams in October and November 2017) will investigate how having the ability to monitor the discharge and recharge of aquifers in real time can be used to improve the sustainability of groundwater exploitation in water-scarce regions.  Second, our project partners in Morocco will prepare an implementation pathways document to define how the technology could be rolled out in Morocco. Should the project that we are proposing here confirm the technical feasibility of using ApRES for ground water monitoring in arid regions, the outcomes of the i-Teams study and the implementation pathways report will put us in a strong position to take the project forward to the next level of application, both within Morocco and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the proposed project are fourfold. 1. Determine through field trials the envelope of capability of the ApRES instrument at different radar frequencies in arid regions. The rate of absorption of radio waves in typical soils depends strongly on the radio wave frequency: lower frequencies are more appropriate for the detection and monitoring of deeper water tables (&gt;~100 m).  There are, however, other disadvantages to using lower frequencies. 2. Contribute to a parallel, fully resourced study that seeks to understand how the ability to monitor aquifer levels can be applied in the most transformative way. As a separate investigation, a Development i-Teams study will be determining the optimal approach to securing the best outcomes downstream of the project, specifically assessing how a monitoring network could be integrated into the diverse approaches to groundwater management adopted by different nations. 3. Assess the potential to make the instrument cheaper to manufacture and robust to the environment. The ApRES instrument is well-suited to the cold, dry conditions of Antarctica, but will need to be hardened against higher temperatures and wetter conditions. The design was not optimised for economy, and various manufacturing approaches need to be investigated to determine the cheapest and simplest, while maintaining reliability. 4. Work out how to deskill the interpretation of the ApRES datasets. At present, the ApRES dataset needs to be interpreted by an expert.  Possibly the most challenging part of the project will be to develop data-processing algorithms that can be applied by trained, but otherwise relatively unskilled operators.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC British Antarctic Survey</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Morocco</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-17">48556.63</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-17">53851.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-17">102408.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF NC&amp;C Award to NERC British Antarctic Survey</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R009589_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC British Antarctic Survey</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FR009589%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
