<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_V003070_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience+: Integrating Equity into Climate-Resilient Development (RICARDO)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the last two decades, Rwanda has experienced periods of severe flooding and drought, resulting in severe damage to crops affecting more than two million people, destruction of infrastructure and even loss of life. These climate impacts affect certain people more than others, and women and persons with disabilities are two such disproportionally affected groups. It is therefore vital to build their resilience to climate shocks. However, policies, programmes and projects aiming to do so have been criticised by many critical scholars as affording insufficient attention to the needs of marginalised and vulnerable groups. In some cases, this has been shown to lead to increasing inequalities and vulnerability rather than resilience. This project aims to address this challenge by building a Network of citizens (local women and people with disabilities from the Eastern Province), development practitioners, policymakers and academics who would come together to discuss what resilience means for different people, and what kinds of resources, knowledge and capabilities are necessary in the Rwandan context for making resilience policy and programming more equitable in its outcomes. 

The founding members of the Network include 3 UK-based universities (Glasgow Caledonian University, University of Stirling and Coventry University), 1 Rwanda-based university (University of Rwanda), 1 UK-based civil society organisation (Send a Cow UK), 1 Rwanda-based civil society organisation (Send a Cow Rwanda) and 1 government ministry (Rwanda Ministry of Environment). Critical input will also be provided by the National Union of Disability Organisations of Rwanda (NUDOR). Over the course of the project, the founding members will ensure participation from key stakeholders (e.g. Rwanda Women&apos;s Network or the Rwanda Climate Change and Development Forum). 
Over the 15 months, we envision to hold a total of 42 events at both local and national level with various stakeholders over five key stages: 1) participatory baseline assessment, 2) co-development of needs and expectations, 3) participatory action planning, 4) bid co-development, and 5) dissemination and Network consolidation. 

As part of these events, we will adopt a participatory action research (PAR) approach, whereby attendees will become co-researchers on this project, ensuring that their views, needs and priorities are adequately addressed in the choice of the above-mentioned outputs. We will apply innovative research methods such as World Caf&#xE9;-style focus group discussions, participatory landscape/timeline/body mapping, life stories of loss and damage, in addition to the more usual use of interviews, surveys and environmental assessment. In terms of the outputs, the Network members have co-identified videos, podcasts, training manuals and toolkits, policy briefs, brochures, posters, and articles as the best choices to maximise impact in the Rwandan context - all of which will be documented on a freely accessible bilingual (English and Kinyarwanda) website. All these activities will aim to build research and technical capacity among Rwandan academics, practitioners and policymakers to meaningfully include women and persons with disabilities in decision-making and research, to hear their stories and to involve them in planning for more equitable resilience. A key output of the Network will be to jointly produce a bid for a Network Plus project, which will be validated with all stakeholder groups before submission. At the end of the project, we will host the Rwanda Equitable Resilience Forum bringing all stakeholders together.

The project has been designed in such a way as to maximise its impact regardless of the success of the eventual Network Plus submission. Its legacy will include the development of a Network of stakeholders committed to ensuring equitable resilience at the local and nationallevel.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching aim of this project is to create and crystallise an equitable, mutually beneficial, interdisciplinary and multi-sectoral Network of citizens, development practitioners, policymakers and academics through a series of events and resources that emphasise participatory processes and knowledge sharing for inclusive and responsive resilience programming and policy making in Rwanda. 

Objectives:

1.	To critically evaluate the existing theoretical and practical approaches that are relevant for increasing the resilience to climate shocks of women and persons with disabilities in rural Rwanda.
2.	To deploy participatory action research with women and persons with disabilities, development practitioners, policymakers and academics, through a programme of events in the Ngoma, Bugesera and Rwamagana districts in the Eastern Province and the capital city of Kigali. 
3.	Based on objectives 1 and 2, to co-develop a theoretical and practical knowledge- and skills-base necessary for future implementation of operationalisable tools and approaches to support programming and policymaking for gender and disability inclusive, equitable resilience.
4.	Based on all of the above, to co-develop a successful Network Plus proposal to implement the above-mentioned tools and approaches in the next funding stage, with a focus on both local and institutional levels. 
5.	To solidify the Network through local, national and international dissemination of its findings and outputs using a series of agreed-upon events and channels.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="RW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rwanda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">164820.99</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to Glasgow Caledonian University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/V003070/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Glasgow Caledonian University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FV003070%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
