<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_T007311_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton STFC-NARIT: EXOhSPEC (Exoplanet high-resolution Spectrograph)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project is to realise a new kind of high-resolution spectrograph in routine operation. The concept relies on separating the complexity introduced by Earth from the requirements of the spectrometer unit itself. This separation enables a massive reduction in size and complexity on the spectrometer side and it is the natural complement to Adaptive Optics technologies being developed at NARIT and elsewhere. The concepts demonstrated with EXOhSPEC can be used to save tens of millions of pounds in instrumentation costs on the coming generation of extremely large telescopes but also be reproducible by University, public and amateur observatories and offer a competitive alternative to the purchase of large inefficient Fourier transform spectrometers in the wider marketplace. The key developments that we wish to demonstrate are, (1) a compact inexpensive design that can achieve the same performance as existing instruments in terms of wavelength coverage and spectral resolution and (2) bespoke active metrology/actuation of the system to achieve -or even surpass- the best wavelength calibration stability at a fraction of construction and operation costs and to produce a facility instrument. While the prototyping for this instrument is at the University of Hertfordshire, the facility instrument will be produced in Thailand but with the insight gained from operating a prototype versions on the 0.7m Astropark telescope at NARIT headquarters as well at that the Thai National Telescope. The Thai government has made a large investment in the National Astronomical Research Institute of Thailand and so they have the new laboratories in which to build the instrument as well as immediate access to telescopes. Current high-resolution spectrographs are large, expensive and sometimes difficult to maintain and limited to an elite handful of universities and laboratories around the globe. Moreover, because these instruments are so expensive, technology cycles and designs have evolved very little and do not take advantage of the great quality improvement and reduced costs of new materials and mass produced optics. One of the key findings of our prototyping is that the tapering of graded-index fibres is an efficient focal reduction of fibre optic signals not limited by geometrical optics. The optimisation of this by Thai specialists may prove to be a key spinoff of the project. The economic development and welfare of a country relies on key infrastructure and the capabilities of the workforce. In the field of physics and in particular astrophysics, the ability to design and make instruments and to measure and interpret the properties of the transitions in other planets, stars and galaxies is a key cornerstone to understand the properties of the Universe. High-resolution spectroscopy has for decades being a primary tool of astrophysics and a driving force in enabling new fundamental astrophysics. From the discovery of planets around nearby stars to the direct measurement of the size of the Universe. Worldwide, the most oversubscribed instruments on telescopes have long been the high-resolution spectrographs. Although Thailand has a large telescope and a number of smaller ones it does not have a high resolution spectrograph. The proposal is aimed at using Overseas Development Aid funding to develop Thai infrastructure and capabilities while at the same time deepening a collaboration which has been already been technically and scientifically productive and also have long-term benefit to the UK scientists and engineers involved in the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal is to move from the current prototype version of EXOhSPEC (EXOplanet high resolution SPECtrograph) for the Thai National Telescope to a full turn-key instrument through a number of stages. This instrument is novel in three key respects: (1) size, (2) active stablisation and (3) made primarily from catalogue components. The proposal is that the current prototype of EXOhSPEC which currently functions on the Thai National Telescope will be developed as a fully functional instrument that will be built in Hertfordshire and Thailand and used on the NARIT on the 2.4m telescope. This project is about making the current prototype into a facility instrument through joint working and shared development in the UK and Thailand. The technical requirements for the system are as follows: 1) Resolution: Required &gt;70 000, goal 100 000. This will be achieved via the high dispersion properties of an echelle reflection grating operating at a large blaze angle (75 deg), at Littrow configuration. 2) Wavelength range coverage: Required 500nm-850nm, goal 450nm-1000nm. All the optics must be selected to achieve high throughput in this range. The cross disperser (likely a prism) must be able to separate the diffraction orders while fitting in a 4k x 4k detector. 3) The image quality must be diffraction limited for 90% of the wavelength range. 4) Stability: The system must be able to keep high stability (~1 m/s) over time-spans longer than 20 min(requirement), goal (&gt;1 hour). 5) The system must be compact both for reasons of control and also so that it fits in the NARIT spectrograph room.  6) The spectrograph control system needs to suitable for general purpose operation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Hertfordshire</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-01">236809.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-01">35106.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-01">271915.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC Newton STFC - ODA Award to University of Hertfordshire</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST/T007311/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Hertfordshire</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FT007311%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
