<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P004512_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social, behavioural and economic drivers of inappropriate antibiotic use by informal private healthcare providers in rural India.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antibiotics play a life-saving role in reducing mortality and morbidity due to communicable diseases like tuberculosis, typhoid, pneumonia and gastroenteritis. However, the overuse of antibiotics in populations can lead to the disease causing bacteria becoming drug resistant over time. For example, high levels of resistance have been found in gastroenteritis causing bacteria to antibiotics like ampicillin (52.3% - 84.6%), cotrimoxazole (45.5% - 65%), and cephalexin (15.9% - 59.7%) across five sites in India and South Africa. This antimicrobial resistance (AMR) is a global threat because it can reverse the advances made in combating life threatening infections and increase the costs of treatment and hospital stays for the sick, making newer antibiotics even more inaccessible to the poorest and most vulnerable.  One major reason for the overuse of antibiotics in humans is antibiotic over-dispensing and over-prescribing by health care providers. This is a big challenge in low and middle income countries where health systems are weak, regulatory frameworks for health workers and the pharmaceutical industry either do not exist or are weakly enforced, and the majority of poor and rural populations rely on informally trained and unlicenced providers who use antibiotics excessively and inappropriately in their treatments. These informal providers or IPs may constitute from 50% to 96% of all providers in LMICs, including in India, but there is very little in-depth knowledge of the factors that influence their inappropriate antibiotic use and what interventions can feasibly and effectively arrest this inappropriate use. Evidence from the formal sector suggests that antibiotic use is influenced by socio-cultural, behavioural and economic factors. However the precise nature of these factors and how they interact has not been explored in the case of IPs. In this field study we propose to study a cross section of IPs, and the drivers of their antibiotic use in the state of West Bengal in India. Since IPs lack a clear legal status, few government programmes are willing to engage with them, but the West Bengal government has decided to train and harness more than 100,000 IPs as village health workers, from early 2016. We are therefore locating this timely study in West Bengal. We will explore provider related factors and also the perceptions of communities and various government stakeholders. This will be done through 200 structured and 30 in-depth interviews and observations of IP practices in two socio-economically different districts (Birbhum and South24 Parganas), accompanied by focus groups discussions with community members and key informant interviews with government, pharmaceutical and formal medical sector stakeholders. We will use these findings to conceptualise interventions to reduce antibiotic use among IPs and seek feedback from study participants on the feasibility and effectiveness of these interventions.  The study will be implemented by the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine in collaboration with the Liver Foundation, a non-governmental organisation in West Bengal that has worked with IPs since 2007 and has championed the harnessing of IPs with the state government.  We will use the final study outcomes to develop a proposal with the state government to implement and evaluate these interventions in the future, possibly starting in mid to late 2017.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our study seeks to understand why informal providers in rural parts of India (2 districts in West Bengal) use antibiotics irrationally, what are the major social, economic and behavioural determinants of this irrational antibiotic use, and how are they interrelated. A few programmes have tried to improve the quality of care by IPs in India and Bangladesh, but these have focused mainly on training and not succeeded in changing providers&apos; antibiotic use. We believe that a deeper understanding of the underlying factors is required to enable us to develop and implement successful interventions. This study is an attempt towards bringing about an evidence based transformation in IPs&apos; antibiotic use. We have chosen to do this in West Bengal because there is a favourable policy climate for IPs. Study objectives: 1. To examine the patterns* of antibiotic use (numbers, types/names, dosage, prescribed/dispensed, and conditions where used) by informal providers in their daily practice (method -structured provider interviews with 200 IPs; 1 day of guided observation per provider clinic and in-depth interviews with 30 IPs selected from among the 200 interviewed) 2. To explore the full range of drivers behind providers&apos; antibiotic use, encompassing behavioural (e.g. provider knowledge), social (e.g. client expectations), and economic (e.g. profit margins) factors (method - in-depth provider interviews with 30 IPs) 3. To explore the perspectives of patients/communities, and other stakeholders including government policymakers and regulators, pharmaceutical representatives and formal medical sector representatives related to antibiotic use by informal providers (method - FGDs with community members and key informant interviews with other stakeholders) 4. To conceptualise the multifaceted components of an intervention to curb and improve antibiotic use, and seek feedback from IPs as well as other stakeholders on the feasibility and the potential effectiveness of the different components. (method - discussion and brainstorming with the advisory committee, and small group activities and workshops with study participants) 5. To develop a plan for implementation and evaluation (using an experimental case-control design) of the proposed intervention, to go hand in hand with the state government&apos;s training programme for 100,000 IPs across the state over the next five years. *Please note that we are not evaluating the clinical appropriateness of the antibiotics used by providers as that would require a different approach and field staff with a medical background. We are documenting usage in general practice through structured followed by in-depth interviews and clinic observations. This will allow us to document excessive &amp; indiscriminate use beyond the providers&apos; limits which can also be considered inappropriate.  This study is small but competitive because there are very few interventions related to IPs: despite their public health significance, they are seen as quacks and outlaws of the medical system. We bring these two complex realms - IPs and antibiotic use - together in this study that is closely linked to a large scale government intervention and so there&apos;s a good chance of the study findings being accepted and put to enormous public benefit. This would be the first such study with IPs in India and among a limited few globally. We have enlisted the support of five multi-disciplinary advisors from India, Africa and the UK, who have significant interest and experience in the area of health markets, informal providers, quality of care and antibiotic use and resistance.  Our Advisory Committee includes: Mr. Amod Kumar (policymaker, government of Uttar Pradesh, India); Dr Gerald Bloom, Institute of Development Studies, Sussex, UK; Dr. Phyllis Awor, Makerere University, Uganda; Dr.K.M. Shyamprasad (former cardio-thoracic surgeon and medical educationist), Chennai, India; Professor Simon Croft, Professor of Parasitology, LSHTM,</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-01">33413</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-01">50390.14</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-09-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-01">100509.64</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P004512_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP004512%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
