<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N028473_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Epidemiological features, national burden of several HPV-related diseases and estimation of cost-effectiveness of HPV vaccines in Vietnam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The expected outcome of this study is to provide scientific evidence that will enable us to propose a strategic program for HPV vaccination in Vietnam.  At present there are various studies of HPV prevalence in different groups in Vietnam, but there is no coherent national study designed to establish the case for vaccination.  Like other developing countries, Vietnam is not only burdened by a high prevalence of HPV infection, but this is compounded by increasing sexual promiscuity, both in the general population and amongst men who have sex with men (MSM), a very poor cervical screening program, and poor quality detection and management of cancer cases.  Together these amount to a much greater burden of HPV related disease and mortality.  This is now a vaccine preventable disease, so the continuation of this burden is unacceptable.  The Government of Vietnam relies on scientific and epidemiological evidence for decisions regarding vaccine use, and as the HPV vaccines are expensive, burden of disease information is critical.  The present study is designed to bring together the critical pieces of information needed to enable the Ministry of Health to make an evidence based decision on HPV vaccine use.   In recognition of the importance of the study for public health in Vietnam, the objectives of this study are as follows: 1. To assess the prevalence and characteristics of high-risk and low-risk HPV types, and sexual behaviour of female university students in the major cities of north, central and south Vietnam. 2. To assess the prevalence and distribution of HPV types in two important population groups at high risk of HPV infection -  female sex workers (FSWs) and men who have sex with men (MSM) - in two major cities of Vietnam. 3. To evaluate the burden of genital warts and HPV related cancers (e.g., cervical cancer, penile cancer, genital warts) and to estimate the benefits of proposed HPV vaccination in terms of health improvement, HPV prevalence, medical expenditure, and economical return to the country.  4. To enhance laboratory capacity on HPV diagnostics and immunology, providing basis for future vaccine research in Vietnam.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is designed to collect the evidence that will be needed to support the introduction of the cancer-preventing vaccine HPV (Human Papillomavirus) into the national immunization program of Vietnam.  HPV is the second vaccine that has been developed that can prevent cancer (the first being Hepatitis B vaccine which prevents liver cancer).  HPV vaccine prevents HPV infection, which is responsible for almost all cases of cancer of the cervix in women.  In Western countries cancer of the cervix is much less common than in developing countries, because the regular cervical screening (Pap smears) identifies and treats very early cases.  HPV is very common in developing countries like Vietnam, and the cancers that it causes are usually detected late, leading to high mortality.  HPV is also responsible for a variety of other cancers affecting both men and women, including penile cancer, anal cancer and throat cancer.  The vaccine is used is most industrialized countries, and is given to girls, and in some countries to boys as well.  It has been introduced into very few developing countries, because of its high price, and the lack of evidence about HPV infection and disease in those countries.  Vietnam is a rapidly modernizing country, with a booming economy and a population that is becoming increasingly westernized.  HPV is spread by unprotected sex, and rates of infection are very high among sex workers and men who have sex with men.  This project will study the rate of HPV infection among young university students in north, south and central Vietnam to get a national perspective.  We will also study two important high risk groups, sex workers and men who have sex with men in both the north and south.   We will use the records of the cancer hospitals in Vietnam to estimate the proportion of the population who were affected by HPV associated cancer, and to understand better the ages affected and the outcome and treatment costs of cases.  This will enable us to predict the effect of HPV vaccine introduction on the community and calculate the money that will be saved by the health system if those cancers are prevented.  Finally we will develop, within Vietnam, the laboratory skills that are needed to study HPV disease, and especially to undertake a trial of HPV vaccines in Vietnam.  The trial is not covered by this proposal, but we hope in future to do a trial that will help us to decide which is the simplest and therefore least expensive, way to introduce HPV vaccine into a developing country like Vietnam.  The project will be undertaken jointly by five institutions.  The three Vietnamese institutions (two in the north and one in the south) will be able to share their expertise in this area and also develop new skills with help from expert groups in London (London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine) and Australia (Murdoch Childrens Research Institute).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Vietnam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">165258.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">192991.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">45968.57</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">6063288.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N028473_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FN028473%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-07-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
