<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T01556X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Power to the People: Democratising energy through decentralised manufacture and production of affordable, reliable, sustainable solar power</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A programme of GRTA activity is proposed that will demonstrate the democratisation of energy. Through decentralising the manufacture and deployment of affordable, reliable solar power into the hands of local communities, novel models of public participation and local energy ownership can be explored through the creation of new actors such as prosumers, renewable energy co-operatives and community owned power generation. SUNRISE, a &#xA3;6.5M GCRF project, is growing research capability in the UK and India in the field of next generation solar energy systems that are affordable, reliable and sustainable. As such, SUNRISE partners form the core team assembled to respond to this GRTA call. This core is enhanced through the addition of other relevant collaborators from the DAC listed countries of Mexico, Kazakhstan and South Africa. The transdisciplinary consortium comprises a combination of technical, commercial and socio-economic expertise and resources. As such, the group is ideally positioned to exploit the opportunity presented by a new, disruptive, solution processable (printed) solar energy technology - the perovskite solar cell (the underlying GCRF research). Due to the low capital equipment costs and use of earth abundant materials, perovskite technology has the potential to deliver locally manufactured, affordable, reliable, sustainable modern energy solutions for the climatic and socio-economic contexts in developing countries. Solution processable PV materials, which can be applied as an ink using printing and coating processes, present a very viable alternative to the currently established PV technologies.  Perovskite solar energy devices offer not only significant advantages in manufacturing and capital costs, but also in their application onto flexible substrates and direct integration into vehicles and buildings without excessive weight implications. Historically, the main disadvantage for printed PV has been the efficiency, which for Dye Sensitised Cells (DSC) and Organic Photovoltaic (OPV) technologies have struggled to exceed 12%, making the potential collectors quite large. However, a new technology recently developed in the UK, the Perovskite Solar Cell (PSC), has now exceeded all previous attempts to develop a solution processed PV. The performance of PSC lab devices has now reached over 23% representing a step change in performance for new 3rd generation solar cells. At present the deposition of this exciting technology can be achieved on glass or flexible plastic materials, however this capability is yet to transfer at any significant level to module prototyping and fabrication, such as that contemplated by the technical aspects of this project.  As such, the GRTA funding will be used to accelerate: + Delivery of &apos;at-scale&apos; building technology demonstrators, translating research into practical application  + Growth of global academic, commercial, NGO and government collaborations through a cohort of International Transdisciplinary Knowledge Transfer Fellows + Commercialisation of substantial relevant IPR and know-how in the solar energy space Given the imperatives of the &apos;energy trilemma&apos; global challenge (SDG7 - security, equity and sustainability), it is now timely to engage in the translational work needed to demonstrate perovskite photovoltaic technologies can be produced at commercially viable scale and cost. If this goal is achieved, it will present a global opportunity to address climate change in an equitable and sustainable manner. MIT Energy Initiative: &quot;solar energy holds the best potential for meeting humanity&apos;s future long-term energy needs while cutting greenhouse gas emissions - but to realize this potential will require increased emphasis on developing lower cost technologies and more effective deployment policy&quot;. In just one hour the Earth receives enough solar energy from the Sun to power the whole of the world economy for a year!</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A programme of GRTA activity is proposed that will demonstrate the democratisation of energy. Through decentralising the manufacture and deployment of affordable, reliable solar power into the hands of local communities, novel models of public participation and local energy ownership can be explored through the creation of new actors such as prosumers, renewable energy co-operatives and community owned power generation. This will be achieved through an international transdisciplinary consortium comprising a combination of technical, commercial and socio-economic expertise and resources. As such, the group is ideally positioned to exploit the opportunity presented by a new, disruptive, solution processable (printed) solar energy technology - the perovskite solar cell (the underlying GCRF research). Due to the low capital equipment costs and use of earth abundant materials, perovskite technology has the potential to deliver locally manufactured, affordable, reliable, sustainable modern energy solutions for the climatic and socio-economic contexts in developing countries. Rising carbon emissions from conventional energy generation, particularly in the developing world, are a heavy burden on the global environment. Despite commitment to decarbonisation targets, demand for energy continues to rise. Solar photovoltaic (PV) power has a significant role to play in the transition to a low-carbon economy. The growth of PV is projected to outperform other renewable energy technologies over the next 30 years and be a primary low-carbon power source for developing economies. At present, PV is dominated by silicon technology manufactured and supplied by China. This sustained dominance has led to stagnation and decline in the growth of alternative PV technologies globally. This is despite silicon PV remaining expensive both in terms of production, energy consumption and very high capital costs required to enter the manufacturing space. GIZ (German Corporation for International Cooperation) recently commissioned Tata Cleantech Capital Ltd to conduct a study promoting roof top solar installations in the commercial and industrial sectors in the national capital region (NCR) of Delhi. This study found that many small and medium industry (SME) consumers wanted shorter terms and more flexible power purchase agreements (PPA) with project developers to mirror the inherent nature of their businesses. As a result, there is a significant opportunity to access this commercial market opportunity if these issues can be overcome through increased accessibility of lower cost alternatives requiring shorter payback times. As such, the GRTA funding will be used to accelerate: + Delivery of &apos;at-scale&apos; building technology demonstrators, translating research into practical application  + Growth of global academic, commercial, NGO and government collaborations through a cohort of International Transdisciplinary Knowledge Transfer Fellows + Commercialisation of substantial relevant IPR and know-how in the solar energy space Delivered through: + Building Technology Demonstrators - will be used to establish and evidence how perovskite solar energy technologies can be locally manufactured and deployed in a sustainable, affordable manner in developing economies. A minimum of two demonstrators will be constructed by the GRTA project at different locations in India.  + Knowledge &amp; Innovation Fellows - a minimum of six Fellows will be trained in both discipline specific and interdisciplinary innovation skills. This blended approach will develop capacity and deliver the target of an innovation delivery team with a complementary mix of skills necessary for successfully taking technologies to market. + Commercial Models - a minimum of three business plans will be developed based on commercial models evolved from the market analysis undertaken by the Innovation Leadership Team. These business plans will be taken forward in collaboration with the K&amp;I Fellows.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swansea University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">272187</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">536048.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">3232942.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to Swansea University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T01556X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Swansea University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT01556X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
