<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N01247X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Role of heparin binding growth factors in O.viverrini induced Cholangiocarcinoma (O-CCA) development, progression and angiogenesis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cancer of the bile duct (cholangiocarcinoma, or CCA) is a severe, often fatal cancer, rare in the western world. However, it is a hundred times more common in areas of Thailand, Laos and Vietnam than anywhere else in the world. This is mainly because it may be caused by a liver fluke called Opisthorchis. This is a parasite that lives in fish found in the rivers of that area. The exact type of cancer caused by this parasite is different from other cancers of the bile duct. This means that we can think of CCA as being two (or more) different types of cancer - Opisthorchis-induced CCA (or O-CCA), and CCA cause by other causes (e.g. hepatitis, inflammatory bowel disease, smoking, etc - which we have termed NonO-CCA. In Thailand this disease is devastating, particularly in poor areas, where both men and women suffering from this disease are unable to provide for their families and leave children as orphans when they die.  There is a known class of proteins that contribute to cancer growth called the heparin binding factor growth factors (HB-GF). Heparin is a carbohydrate (starch like molecule) that is found in the space between cells, including in cancer. These HB-GFs include epidermal growth factor (EGF), vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF), and hepatocyte growth factor (HGF). Drugs that inhibit these growth factors have all been made and are used for various cancers (e.g. Herceptin for breast cancer), but not yet shown to be useful for CCA. We have recently found out that a molecule that mimics heparin, isolated from a seaweed commonly used in Thai food, can interfere with how HB-GFs help CCAs grow in the laboratory. This seaweed extract, called sulphated galactan (or SG) can stop CCA cells from growing moving, and making new blood vessels. However, we do not know which HB-GFs it sticks to, or how I stops them working. In this project we intend to develop a panel of O-CCA cells by using parts of the cancers surgically removed from patients with the disease, and compare them with NonO-CCA patients in the UK and find out whether there are notable differences in the way their heparin binding growth factors are made or work, find out whether growth of these Thailand specific cancers can be halted with drugs that target HB-GFs and whether the Thai seaweed extract can be used to tell us what is different about these types of cancer cell.  Ultimately we would like this work to pave the way for clinical trials of specific, already approved, drugs in CCA in Thailand. We think that by understanding the biology of these cancer cells we will be able to design trials that use these drugs in combination to target Thai CCA patients. Moreover, we would like to investigate whether the Thai seaweed extract can be used to help research into cancer of the bile duct in Thailand and the rest of the world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heparin binding growth factors such as EGF, VEGF, and HGF drive progression of many tumours. We have recently identified that proliferation, migration, angiogenesis and survival, four of the key hallmarks of cancer, are mediated by heparin binding growth factors (HB-GF), in cholangiocarcinoma (CCA) associated with infection with the south east Asian parasitic liver fluke Opisthorchis viverrini - a very serious, usually fatal, cancer of the bile duct. CCA is 100 times more common in parts of Thailand than in the western world. However, O. viverrini associated cholangiocarcinoma (O-CCA) is genetically distinct from the rarer (in incidence) but more widespread (and hence more cases) CCA that is not associated with fluke infection (NonO-CCA). The vast majority of recent research has been into NonO-CCA (&gt;96% of papers do not refer to Opisthorchis). We have shown that sulphated galactans, carbohydrates isolated from Red seaweed (G fisherii) grown in Thai aquaculture that interfere with heparin binding, can inhibit EGFR signalling, reduce angiogenic VEGF expression and prevent proliferation and migration of O-CCA cells. The overall objective of this proposal is to determine whether targeting HB-GF could be a potential therapy for O-CCA. HB-GF targeted therapies are on the market and there are 15 current trials targeting this pathway in CCA - but all in NonO-CCA and mostly in Europe and the US. The only published phase III trial of HB-GF inhibitors was carried out in Korea, where CCA is usually caused by hepatitis, helicobacter or Clonorchis infection rather than O. viverrini infection. This trial found that EGFR inhibitor erlotinib did not prolong overall survival significantly but appeared to give benefit in some patients. It is therefore highly likely that the response of CCA is highly dependent on the cause of the cancer, and the signalling pathways that are activated. The objectives of this project are to identify the expression levels of HB-GFs and their receptors by O-CCA and compare them with NonO-CCA tumours. We will also determine the importance of HB-GF signalling in various hallmarks of cancer including proliferation, migration and angiogenesis in O-CCA vs NonO-CCA. We will then determine the mechanisms and targets through which sulphated galactans from G fisherii act to inhibit O-CCA tumour cell effects, in vivo and in vitro. The project will also construct a tissue microarray of tumours from O-CCA from Thailand, and generate a number of patient derived tumour cell lines and xenografts from both O-CCA and NonO-CCA patients, and use these to demonstrate the applicability of investigations to the different tumour types. The aims of the project are to test the hypotheses that: a) O-CCA tumours produce growth factor combinations that lend themselves to heparin-binding mediated tumour growth, b) O-CCA mediated angiogenic growth factor production is a consequence of that growth factor signalling, c) that preventing that upregulation in O-CCA cells can slow O-CCA in animal models and d) that this can be done using sulphated galactans from G. fisherii.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-11" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">30488.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">122199.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">123189.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-11-24">61967.98</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
