<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003227_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global Engagement Network on Internal Displacement in Africa (GENIDA)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. The project&apos;s overall objectives are both scientific (2 below) and practical (3 below) in nature. Its subsidiary objectives comprise the outputs necessary to achieve the primary objectives (4 below). 2. The overall scientific objective is to organise an interdisciplinary network to develop capacity to analyse and theorise internal displacement as a major development challenge in sub-Saharan Africa. The project has defined five short-medium term objectives as steps towards achieving this aim: (a) Producing a description and analysis of this phenomenon in a selection of specially-affected States; (b) Advancing the work of academic beneficiaries across a range of key disciplines; (c) Generating innovative evidence-based policy/practice solutions to this challenge; (d) Redressing the neglect of the topic by the current scholarship; (e) Building a stronger integrated interdisciplinary research community around the overall project objective, comprising both academics and practitioners, in order to consolidate understanding and develop further advances in this area. Each of these ambitious short/medium term objectives contributes to the overall aim of the project such that there is no strict order of priority.  3. The overall practical objective is to contribute to efforts to address the humanitarian, security, environmental and infrastructural challenges that internal displacement presents to development in sub-Saharan Africa. The project has defined four short/medium term objectives as steps for achieving this overall aim. Each is specifically targeted to change the policy or practice of a sector which has a determinate influence on this area: (a) Improving national law, policy and practice in response to key challenges posed by internal displacement in selected DAC-list countries in sub-Saharan Africa; (b) Promoting concerted regional policy responses on relevant aspects of these challenges;  (c) Stimulating engagement with these cases by international organisations and agencies - as well as the third sector - to consolidate their capacity to respond to these new challenges; (d) Helping to promote a more positive, nuanced and informed public debate on the topic. Each of these ambitious short/medium term objectives contributes to the overall aim of the project such that there is no strict order of priority.  4. The pathways to achieve the objectives listed above depend upon the following concrete outputs, the production of which may also be considered as necessary objectives of the project: (a) Building the necessary research links between two leading academic centres in South Africa and the UK;  (b) Establishing a network based in the first instance around key DAC-list country academic and policy-maker Stakeholders, and ensuring participation and input from participants; (c) Gathering and analysing relevant data through research conducted by selected network Stakeholders; (d) Drafting project documents for dissemination at events and for publication; (e) Arranging a series of conferences, workshops and other events, and ensuring attendance and feedback from key participants; (f) Implementing a project launch and associated media campaign; (g) Consolidating local and international academic-practitioner networks in this area. Please see &apos;Academic Beneficiaries&apos; and &apos;Pathways to Impact&apos; for further details of the planned outputs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Global Engagement Network on Internal Displacement in Africa (GENIDA) brings together academics, policy-makers and civil society to address two major development problems: (i) the paucity of research on internal displacement in sub-Saharan Africa; and (ii) the inadequate response to internally displaced persons (IDPs) in law, policy and practice in these countries. Internal displacement is a major cross-cutting development challenge in sub-Saharan Africa. In 2017 alone, in sub-Saharan Africa, over 5 million people were internally displaced by conflict and another 2.5 million by disasters linked to natural hazards. Its impact is felt in the losses and livelihood and reintegration challenges experienced by IDPs, disruption of social fabric and distortion of local economies and politics. Yet, despite a humanitarian stop-gap response in some countries, longer-term innovative solutions to situations on the ground are needed. The first initiative of its kind, the GENIDA project aims to: (i) promote high-quality interdisciplinary research on IDPs by building and supporting research capacity in sub-Saharan Africa; and (ii) facilitate evidence-based policy change and innovative solutions in DAC-list countries in this region. The project adds real value to current research. Firstly, it will connect existing IDP researchers in universities and civil society groups to build a robust research community on this challenge. Secondly, it will promote research on IDPs among outstanding researchers in African universities not yet working in that field, supporting them within this community. Thirdly, by reaching out to a range of disciplines, it will promote interdisciplinary engagement on IDPs. Fourthly, through the work of this research community, it will develop innovative solutions to the IDP challenge in Africa. It also feeds directly into policy/practice. Firstly, it will create a policy forum to bring in policy-makers from selected national governments and international agencies. Secondly, it will build capacity and work with these stakeholders to identify key internal displacement challenges in practice. Thirdly, through researcher/practitioner exchange, it will develop innovative and practice-oriented solutions to IDP challenges and action plans to address them. Fourthly, it will provide technical support to these policy-makers in adopting and implementing the action plans and on any IDP-related query where they seek expert input from GENIDA members. The project is an international collaboration between Centre for Human Rights at University of Pretoria, South Africa, and Refugee Law Initiative at School of Advanced Study, University of London, UK. The expertise and networks of these two specialised research centres underpin the success of this open network, which will draw in researchers from universities, research institutions and civil society across Africa, as well as key development policy-makers from countries affected by serious dynamics of internal displacement. It facilitates co-production of knowledge in this area through such activities as: - 2019 Online training programme for network members - 2020 Policymaker workshop on identifying key IDP challenges - 2020 Researcher workshop on building interdisciplinary research - 2020 Joint work on developing solutions to respond to key IDP challenges - 2020 Joint workshop to develop action plans to implement solutions identified  - 2020 Policymaker activities for adoption of actions plans at national level - 2020 Researcher activities to integrate IDPs on university/research agendas - 2021 Final interdisciplinary conference and publications - Ongoing expert technical advice to policymakers Alongside the academic benefits, the project will generate user impact by improving law, policy and practice on IDPs in African States and promoting informed public debate, as well as giving international visibility to Africa/UK academic-practitioner research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Pretoria</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-17">17982.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-17">54093.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-17">18128.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-17">144444.344</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Pretoria</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T003227_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Pretoria</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT003227%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-15"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
