<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Health Services that Deliver: Improving Care for Sick Newborns (HSD-N)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In 2009, there were 42,000 newborn deaths and they accounted for 40% of all deaths among children under 5 Kenya. This high neonatal mortality is a major reason why Kenya is not succeeding in its battle to reduce child deaths in line with stated targets. Recognising this, the Ministry of Health has started to focus on improving newborn (and maternal) health with strategies aimed at communities and small clinics. However, sick or vulnerable newborns will often require inpatient care in referral facilities from skilled workers with access to basic technologies. Interventions typically delivered at this level include, for example, fluids or feeds for those unable to suck or oxygen for respiratory support. Such interventions require carers to perform the same, time-consuming tasks multiple times per day for many days. Shortage of skilled health workers often means these services are inadequately delivered, potentially delaying or preventing recovery. We are planning research that will establish: the potential burden of severe neonatal illness; what existing infrastructure and human resource capacity is available supporting access for this population; utilisation of these services; and the quality of existing nursing care services. We will do this focusing on Nairobi&apos;s population of 5 million, many of whom are very poor. With a focus on universal coverage and neonatal care meeting agreed standards, this work will provide the basis for estimating the gap between available and needed services (Gap 1) and the quality gap between existing and desired services (Gap 2). In partnership with important stakeholders, we will explore how a low-income country might best tackle health workforce challenges to close these gaps and improve provision of essential nursing care to all sick newborn babies in an affordable and efficient way. This ultimate aim of research is driven by the fact that salary costs are a major proportion of total health care costs. One option will therefore be to explore alternatives to employing professional nurses if necessary interventions can be effectively provided by other groups under the supervision of professionals - an approach known as task-shifting. Although task-shifting sounds a simple solution, it may not always be. Failure to consider national regulations, the opinions of important professionals, managers or parents may lead to the approach being rejected or failing. Taking account of the local situation may be particularly important when those being cared for are sick, newborn babies and when day to day care has traditionally been given by professional, even specialist nurses.  First, therefore, we will define with the major groups what forms of care should be available to all, learn what regulations exist on providing care, and consider the concerns of major groups with respect to task-shifting. We will examine carefully all the things that nurses have to do in a range of different facilities, explore with experts which tasks may be simple enough for others to do, and examine whether there is time to do all the essential care tasks. We will estimate how much need there is for neonatal nursing care in Nairobi and the gap between what is available and what is needed. Using all these data we will explore how many new staff might be needed to improve the delivery of essential care for all newborns in need. We will also undertake preliminary work to explore the costs of meeting this need using extra professional nurses or if tasks were shifted to other, lower cost staff. Possible roles for lower cost staff will be informed by work examining what tasks to shift and how they might fit within existing patterns of providing care.  All this work will be conducted with the major decision makers in health, health professionals and parents to develop options sensitive to local conditions. Based on this body of work we aim to develop a task-shifting approach that can be tested in Kenya in the future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2014-11-03"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="KE" type="KENYA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2014-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-16">31167.78</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-16">189268.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-16">224941.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-16">264581.25</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-16">234836.74</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Neonatal mortality accounts for over 40% of all child mortality in many countries. Yet, prior research in low-income settings suggests sick newborns often do not receive the interventions they need to ensure their disability free survival. Sick newborns require multiple interventions, repeatedly for multiple days. Their care is therefore especially sensitive to the major deficit in the nursing workforce found in low-income countries. To reduce this deficit and constrain workforce costs, task-shifting, moving responsibility for delivering some interventions from professional to lower level workers, may be a solution. Yet, such apparently rational approaches may be poorly designed or implemented, leading to their rejection in policy or practice. We will undertake multidisciplinary work, drawing on frameworks for developing complex interventions, to open a new arena for research on task-shifting using innovative methods. Phase 1 will build on existing work to (1) develop evidence based national neonatal guidelines and engage policy makers and other stakeholders and  (2) conduct formative ethnographic work on nursing culture in Kenyan hospitals.  In phase 2, we will pursue empiric work focused on Nairobi County whose officers are responsible for health services provided to 5 million people, of whom over 2 million live in poverty. Research will establish: (1) the potential burden of illness; (2) what existing capacity is available supporting access to care; (3) utilisation of these services; and (4) the quality of existing nursing services. With a focus on universal coverage for neonatal care this will provide the basis for estimating the gap between available and needed services (Gap 1) and the quality gap between existing and desired services (Gap 2). In the fifth stream of activity, we will undertake a formal stakeholder analysis of those influencing nursing policy and practice to explore views on the possible role of task shifting as a solution. This stakeholder group will be continuously engaged in discussing research as part of a long term action research agenda to explore change.  The third phase of work will focus on developing policy options to close coverage and quality gaps and draw lessons from the entire programme of work.  This work will strengthen researcher - policy maker engagement, result in 3 Kenyan PhDs, develop innovative methodological approaches through new partnerships, and generate considerable generalisable knowledge. Our specific objectives are: 1. To examine the regulatory environment and position and influence of key stakeholders on task-shifting debates in neonatal care and explore how such positions change with participation over the lifetime of the project;  2. To define, with government and key stakeholders, a core package of inpatient services for sick newborns in Kenya; 3. To assess current capacity to provide this package in Nairobi County facilities (in all sectors) and to estimate current use of services and contrast this with estimated need derived from epidemiological models at a population level (Gap 1); 4. To quantify which interventions needing delivery by nurses are provided safely in representative facilities (Gap 2); 5. To characterise neonatal nursing task frequency and duration and the skill level required for delivery to identify those suitable for task-shifting; 6. To explore workplace contexts and managers&apos;, professionals&apos; and parents&apos; perspectives to further inform design of an acceptable task-shifting strategy; 7. To develop illustrative models of the human resource costs of delivering agreed interventions for Nairobi County (closing Gap 1 and Gap 2) while varying coverage and task-shifting options to inform stakeholder discussions on design of a task-shifting intervention that considers affordability, feasibility, access and equity; 8. To draw lessons on how researchers can engage in a dynamic collaboration to inform improvements in health system"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q1">52975.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q2">52975.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">52975.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">66014.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">66014.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">66014.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">66014.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">66536.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">66536.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">61667.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">61667.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">44965.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">-12951.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M015386_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
