<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007635_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enduring Connections</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">&apos;We value our heritage most when it seems at risk; threats of loss spur owners to stewardship.&apos;  (David Lowenthal, 1996)    Climate change is the greatest challenge of our times, according to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, and combating its impacts is one of the key UN Sustainable Development Goals. One symptom of our rapidly warming world is accelerated sea level rise. With 150 million people across the world living within 3 feet of today&apos;s water levels, the consequences will affect each of us directly or indirectly. Former president of Kiribati, Anote Tong, describes the relationship between sustainable development and climate change as &apos;inseparable&apos;. For Small Island Developing States, addressing development challenges while planning for climate change is a constant struggle. Kiribati is a low-lying island nation in the Pacific Ocean, and is often defined by the grim prognosis for its future. Yet there are pressing development challenges which affect people&apos;s lives in Kiribati today, such as access to clean water, and dealing with increasing amounts of waste. As Claire Anterea from the environmental organisation Kirican has said &apos;we will drown in rubbish before we drown in water&apos;. This project team will work with Kirican, in Kiribati, to co-design a community-level programme towards sustainable development. This grassroots approach will inform the broader development field about the specific challenges facing Kiribati, and Small Islands Developing States more generally.  If heritage in its most fundamental sense is about what we value collectively, and want to preserve for the future, then it is entirely logical that academics and practitioners in the heritage field should care about the environment and sustainable development. According to a recent UNESCO report, climate change poses the greatest risk to world heritage, yet heritage concerns are not as prominent as they should be in this field. One of Kiribati&apos;s adaptation strategies is to plan for &apos;migration with dignity&apos; for its population of over 110,000. We will consult with heritage organisations in Kiribati to find out how and whether they are planning for climate change and even potential displacement. This responds to more general concerns amongst global preservation professionals, such as archivists, about their own role within climate adaptation. Should the relocation of cultural resources and archives of climate-vulnerable nations be planned? How could such an enterprise could be managed practically and ethically, and by whom? The research team will also collaborate with the artist and cultural expert Natan Itonga to make a film evoking the rich cultures of Kiribati. This is part of a creative process that aims to understand the local meaning of heritage in Kiribati, and promote awareness of what is at stake. Overall, this project explores both the scope and limitations of attempts to &apos;preserve&apos; heritage in face of rapid environmental change or when the natural environment itself is heritage at risk. What can be &apos;saved&apos; at all when the impacts of climate change are so catastrophic for nations like Kiribati, and is it still meaningful to talk about sustainable development?  This project works through ideas of loss but focuses on connections; specifically, finding enduring connections to potentially lost objects to carry us into the future, caring for our current connections to land, water and non-human life, and accepting moral connections between the most polluting- and vulnerable- countries. As Anote Tong said to participants at the Delhi Sustainable Development Summit in 2013: &apos;Are we here to secure the future of each other&apos;s children or just our own?&apos; Within this project, heritage is positioned as a pivotally important field of expertise for understanding that global challenges of magnitude will nonetheless be felt locally, everywhere.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) Our overarching objective is to strengthen and lobby for the presence of arts and humanities disciplines, and heritage in particular, in addressing global challenges such as sustainable development and climate change for the benefit of the most challenged countries. This is based on our previous experience as researchers in Kiribati, the UK and beyond, which has revealed the importance of &apos;thinking locally&apos;, even when considering globally significant issues. Culturally-sensitive approaches calls for deep engagement with issues of place, history and identity, and a creative capacity to articulate what is at stake, before then imagining new pathways into the future.   2) We will empower Kirican, a local environmental organisation in Kiribati, to implement the sustainable development goals that have been identified by the local community as their own priorities. So often represented through Western reductive frames as generic victims of a sinking paradise, it will be illuminating to discover what matters most to the local community and observe how a culturally-attuned organisation will work with them to implement these changes. By working specifically with two women in Kirican there is scope to dwell on how and whether this shapes their approach to development. This exploratory approach might inform a broader development field about the process and benefits of a grassroots, gender-aware and more participatory approach towards achieving sustainable development.    3) Our collaborative film with local cultural expert Natan Itonga will be a counterpoint to existing representations of Kiribati in the media. Together we will travel some distance over the widely dispersed nation and talk to communities and individuals, to evoke heritage in Kiribati as a &apos;sense of place&apos; informed by those voices. The motivation for this creative activity is to better understand, acknowledge and promote the rich cultures of Kiribati in a film which may become a digital heritage resource for the present and future. By screening the film internationally we hope to generate both awareness and empathy, which are precursors for urgent global action on climate change.  4) We will discover how cultural organisations are projecting and &apos;protecting&apos; Kiribati culture now, and whether there are plans for a climate-changed future, which could include wholesale displacement by the end of this century. By talking to the national museum and archives and also encouraging cross-cultural engagement with international heritage organisations and practitioners, we will explore- abstractly, practically and ethically- the scope and limitations of what can be &apos;saved&apos; for the future.  5) Through our interactions with place and people in Kiribati we will develop a greater sense of what &apos;heritage&apos; means through a particular local lens. In a country with an indigenous culture and a tradition of subsistence living, but also significant internal migration and a growing cash economy, we hope to develop a more informed and holistic understanding of heritage both in Kiribati, and generally. We will be considering the many ways that heritage can be under threat, but also how it is a process and resource with potential to support disorientating transitions. This is again a &apos;local&apos; lesson applicable to global challenges.  6) The opportunity to apply the abstract and global notion of UN Sustainable Development Goals to a specific situation allows us to fulfil important objectives: this will provide insights into the ways that these universal goals may (or may not) work in a particular settings and potentially reveal weak links in the way that they have been construed or connected to each other. This objective is significant as it could lead to new insights about the challenges faced by Small Island Developing States in particular, as they strive to meet sustainable development goals whilst simultaneously adapting to and planning for accelerated climate change.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bath Spa University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KI" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kiribati</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1034" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-10">79960.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-10">79960.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to Bath Spa University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/P007635/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bath Spa University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">79960.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007635_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bath Spa University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">-586.44</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007635_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bath Spa University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FP007635%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
