<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Centre for Global Infectious Disease Analysis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MISSION  To be an international resource and centre of excellence for research and capacity building for the epidemiological analysis and modelling of infectious diseases. The Centre has built a world-leading group of epidemiological researchers to undertake applied collaborative work with national and international agencies to support policy planning and response operations against infectious disease threats.    STRATEGY AND OBJECTIVES  To maintain and strengthen:  (a) an international centre for translating new epidemiological analysis and modelling research into practical policy guidance for controlling infectious diseases; (b) a core capacity to respond to emerging threats and time-critical global health research priorities with real-time analysis and predictive modelling; (c) collaborative relationships with national and international public health agencies and facilitate skills transfer and capacity building, including in low and middle income countries (LMICs); (d) an integrated, multidisciplinary research programme to identify the ecological, biological and social determinants of pathogen emergence and spread  (e) responsiveness to new priorities for  applied intervention research, including assessment of health and economic impact, contributing to vaccine development and evaluation, and addressing the threat posed by antimicrobial resistance.  APPROACH  Building on 9 years&apos; experience, the Centre core will consist of a shared technical resource (in project management, GIS, database analysis, high-performance computing and professional programming) and a public health stakeholder liaison team. The shared technical resource comprises the Centre scientific manager, a high performance computing technician and two professional software developers. The latter posts are dedicated to improving programming skills and operationalizing the methodological software tools developed by Centre researchers. The liaison team will consist of a research fellow dedicated to our partnership with WHO and an External Relationships and Communications Manager to facilitate capacity-building and research collaborations with external partners (notably, in LMICs) and enhance our external communications. The Centre core will be complemented by investment in capacity building in priority research areas via an expanded PhD programme, a new Imperial-MRC research fellow scheme, five new academic posts and a responsive pump-priming research fund. This structure will allow greater flexibility in responding to new priorities (whether outbreaks or urgent policy questions) and for building and sustaining relationships with a wider range of international partners.   RESEARCH THEMES   For the next 5 years, Centre research will focus on a set of 5 cross-cutting themes:   - Outbreak Analysis and Modelling - Global Health Analytics - Vaccines - Antimicrobial Resistance - Methods and Tools    This research will occur in the context of its application to 10 priority disease areas: - Zoonoses and Animal Diseases - HIV, STIs and Hepatitis - Malaria - Tuberculosis - Influenza - Arboviruses - Neglected Tropical Diseases - Enteric Infections - Bacterial Pathogens - Fungal Pathogens  The Centre&apos;s history of frequent internal as well as external collaboration in both methodological and applied research makes it exceptionally well-placed to deliver this broad, cross-cutting research agenda. Examples of work drawing on expertise from multiple PI groups from the last 5 years include analyses of the MERS-CoV and Ebola epidemics and modelling to inform business planning for the Global Fund. This collaborative culture and the overall coherence of the Centre&apos;s research is maintained by regular cross-Centre research meetings, workshops, training programmes and awaydays. Maintaining a high degree of interaction is essential for the Centre to deliver on its mission and objectives, given the highly interdisciplinary research required.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The continuing threat from new infectious diseases has been highlighted in recent years by the emergence of MERS-coronavirus in the Middle East, Ebola in West Africa and Zika in Latin America. Preparing for and responding to such threats is a priority for public health agencies and governments worldwide. Equally importantly, as scientific research delivers new approaches to controlling existing infectious diseases such as malaria, HIV, tuberculosis and polio, there is a need to determine what interventions are likely to work best to limit the disease and illness caused by a specific disease in a particular setting.  In this context, computer modelling of the spread of diseases in populations coupled with scientifically rigorous data analysis have proven themselves as powerful tools for giving insight into how diseases spread and what can be done to limit that control that spread. The Centre for Global Infectious Disease Analysis undertakes research on these scientific methods and applies them to disease threats of concern.   A key feature of the Centre is the close links it has made with with public health agencies - such as the Public Health England, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in the US (CDC), and the World Health Organization (WHO) - organisations which have to formulate and implement strategies to control infectious diseases.   Senior scientists in the Centre are world-leaders in infectious disease modelling and analysis. They have broad experience in responding to real epidemics, and undertaking epidemiological research on endemic diseases (such as malaria, HIV, tuberculosis and polio). Their work directly influences disease control policy through the many interactions the Centre has with public health organisations and governments.   Funding provided by MRC and Imperial College has allowed dedicated investment into the development of close collaborative partnerships with PHE, CDC and WHO and governments and research centres in many low and middle income countries (LMICs). We also work closely with other important organisations who work on improving health in LMICs (notably the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, The Global Fund and Gavi). With each, our collaborative research has both scientific interest to Centre researchers and contributes to the evidence base for public health decisions. Centre funding supports a core technical capacity available to all projects and pays for dedicated liaison staff who facilitate and enhance our partnerships with major global health organisations and LMICs.   MRC funding has also facilitated a greater focus on collaboration, training and career development within the Centre - training the next generation of quantitative infectious disease epidemiologists. We are also involved in increasing knowledge of advanced modelling methods in public health institutions and the wider infectious disease research community, and so have run a large number of introductory short-courses and workshops (in 13 countries in the last 5 years)  This applied activity depends on more fundamental research undertaken in the Centre on the transmission dynamics of different diseases, how diseases evolve genetically over time, and on analysing new approaches to control or treat diseases. This research is interdisciplinary, with Centre researchers working with leading clinical and experimental scientists around the world.  Continued Centre funding will allow existing partnerships to be sustained and enhanced, and new collaborations with researchers and health agencies in LMICs to be developed. By supporting PhD training and postdoctoral career development, it will also continue to expand the UK skill base in mathematical modelling and advanced analysis applied to health problems. Last, continued MRC support will pump-prime new priority research areas, including work on improving the development of new vaccines and on tackling the global challenge posed by antimicrobial resistance.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-05-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-05-17">4506171.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Centres Award to Imperial College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R015600/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">249071.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">498143.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">249071.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">230560.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-01">230560.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">230560.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">230560.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">232428.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">232428.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">232428.46</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R015600_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR015600%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
