<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_R005257_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Fund (Invitation Only) - LIVEQuest: A self-contained wearable Internet-of-Things System for Precision Livestock Agriculture</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">LIVEQuest aims to build an innovative, cost-effective, self-contained wearable Internet-of-Things (IoT) device, a local processing and control system, and a global cloud and big data decision support and response platform for precision livestock agriculture in China. The wearable IoT device will be developed and embedded on a farmer&apos;s boot to enable eye-level flock monitoring. A gateway with GPRS/3G/4G will be integrated with a low-cost edge computing unit (e.g. Raspberry Pi) and an in-house control module from our industry partner to form a smart local processing and feedback system to the farm facilities. The cloud-based big data centre will be constructed in a highly interoperable structure to incorporate data from different farms so that the data analytical algorithms, e.g. data mining and machine learning, can make use of multi-dimensional data across multiple farms which lead to global precision decisions. These decisions together with the monitoring data of local farm operation will be then fed back to farmers in real-time via an app on their smartphones. The main technical objectives are summarised as follows:  1) Wearable IoT device: a fully-networked smart farmer&apos;s boot (cyber-physical agri-boot) as an example of the wearable IoT device with multiple off-the-shelf sensors, e.g. microphone, temperature, humidity, light and gas levels will be developed to monitor animal welfare (via vocalisations) and the farm environment at flock eye-level, allowing ubiquitous, non-obstructive, automated data collection; 2) Gateway with edge computing: the in-house smart antenna will be integrated with an off-shelf gateway with GPRS/3G/4G and low power wide area network (LPWAN) to provide long range wireless connectivity for the proposed IoT platform. The gateway will be also integrated with an edge computing unit (Raspberry Pi) to host novel vocalisation algorithms and obtain initial warning decisions; 3) Automation of the farm: an interface between the gateway and the in-house control module will be built to timely automate the temperature and ventilation of the farm based on initial decisions obtained in objective 2.  4) Cloud-based data centres will be established to store the data collected by the proposed wearable IoT device in objective 1 via the gateway in objective 2 in multiple farms;  5) Big data analytics: Data mining and machine learning algorithms will be implemented to analyse vocalisation and environmental data) stored in the cloud-based big data centre. Clinical and biological data collected by the Chinese academic partner to establish a poultry health index will also be analysed; 6) Cognitive response to farmers: a mobile app will be built to feedback the decision made in objective 5, and the real-time monitoring data of local farm operation;  7) Farm trials: The smart wearable and vocalisation algorithms will be trialled and validated during field trials in 3 Chinese farms to demonstrate the software and hardware prototypes, the systematic approach, novelty and commercial operation of this project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Worldwide demand for meat and animal products is set to increase by c.40% over the next decade; China&apos;s total meat production has quadrupled over the last 20 years due to rising demand from a rapidly growing population. However, environmental and public health issues are becoming more prominent in China (similar to other emerging economies), and sustainable intensification of livestock agriculture is a key concern of Chinese policy-makers and industry stakeholders. This project converges a team of interdisciplinary experts from both industry and academia in animal behaviour, Internet-of-Things (IoT), wearable computing and veterinary diagnostics to develop a highly innovative low power and energy efficient wearable IoT device, secure cloud and big data platform, cognitive decision support and response system for precision livestock agriculture, initially focusing on poultry farming. A fully-networked Smart farmers&apos; boot (cyber-physical agri-boot), as an example of a wearable IoT device, is proposed to monitor animal welfare and farm environment at flock eye-level, allowing ubiquitous, non-obstructive, automated data collection. GuangXi province farm data will standardise flock health and welfare indices for China. This will improve farm productivity, animal welfare, smallholder livelihood and consumer nutrition, contributing to economic development and welfare of the Chinese population, and is thus well-aligned with ODA objectives.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-02-23"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-23">404916.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton RCUK Award to Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/R005257/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FR005257%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
