<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005327_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Development Award MADAR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The MADAR Development Award aims to support the co-development and co-design of a strong full application for a Network Plus that will address development challenges associated with the protection of displaced people in the central Maghreb region (encompassing UMIC Algeria and LMICs Morocco and Tunisia). The MADAR Development Award will enable us to:  1) Nurture our established strong, equitable, and sustainable partnerships with research institutions and advocacy groups in the Maghreb,  2) Enhance capability development amongst research institutions and advocacy groups in the Maghreb, and  3) Bring together expertise across disciplines and research organisations in the Maghreb and the UK.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Maghreb Action on Displacement and Rights (MADAR) Network Plus focuses on protection in contexts of conflict and displacement in the central Maghreb region of Algeria, Morocco, and Tunisia. MADAR &apos;s core team includes a wide range of regional, national, and interdisciplinary research expertise. We work with civil society organisations to respond to the protection needs of refugees and other displaced people in the region.    The Maghreb region has links across Africa, the Middle East and Europe and it is often associated with emigration and transit northwards, but the Maghreb is also a destination region for thousands of displaced people fleeing conflict and poverty in countries across Africa and the Middle East (e.g. Syria and Libya). The Maghreb countries cooperate with Europe to manage migration and reduce arrivals on European shores. But increasing numbers of displaced people in the Maghreb are at risk and in need of protection and governments lack the resources to support the most vulnerable. As a result, the rights of displaced people are undermined.     MADAR responds to Sustainable Development Goal number 16 to: &quot;Promote peaceful and inclusive societies for sustainable development, provide access to justice for all and build effective, accountable and inclusive institutions at all levels&quot;. MADAR hopes to improve the humanitarian protection of vulnerable, displaced people in Algeria, Morocco, and Tunisia. MADAR aims to: 1) Bring together the regional expertise of UK and Maghreb-based scholars from across the arts and humanities and the social and political sciences. 2) Commission research that will bring together and strengthen the work of researchers in the Maghreb and the wider Middle East and North Africa region. 3) Share best working practices to strengthen partnerships between researchers, activists, artists, and practitioners. 4) Identify ways to help displaced people to get better healthcare, education, and jobs.  5) Influence and help governments to support and protect displaced people in the Maghreb. 6) Work with civil society organisations to combat racism and xenophobia in the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-02">137228.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">55578.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005327_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">81649.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T005327_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Keele University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
