<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T015330_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unlocking resilient benefits from African water resources</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Since sustainable water resource development remains elusive (development has externalised costs to the environment and vulnerable people), there is a need for novel research theory, methodologies and praxis to shift water development practice.  Therefore the project aim is: to apply transformative, transdisciplinary, community-engaged research, to ensure that benefits from water development contribute towards local people and the SDG&apos;s. We focus on continental water development priorities - water supply and pollution.   Six country-based Case Studies (CSs) will enable local research by each Water Centre of Excellence node. Comparative analysis of CSs will be based on all CSs following a common Adaptive Systemic Approach (ASA), and together addressing three SDG-linked Research Questions. The ASA is a novel methodology that drives fundamental shifts towards sustainable and equitable water development.    Project objectives: I) To apply the ASA in each CS. II) To address equitable sharing of water supply benefits arising from contested water use, in three catchment-based CSs. III) To establish the sources, pathways and impact of selected pollutants and to develop community pollution resilience in two city-based CSs. IV) To develop participatory governance to support resilient water supply, water quality, and ecosystem protection in all CSs. V) To build an effective, excellent, partnered African water research network.  OBJ I: Apply the ASA in each CS, moving through four steps. 1. BOUND: Researchers engage with a full range of stakeholders to identify a relevant, local, water-development issue and agree on the scope of the CS.  2. ADAPTIVE PLANNING PROCESS: The PI co-facilitates Adaptive Planning Process workshops in each CS. Stakeholders co-create a contextually sound vision of the future state of their selected local issue, and co-develop an objectives hierarchy to get there. Stakeholders co-agree on project indicators of change (social, technical, economic, environmental and political). 3. CONCURRENT ACTIVITIES 3.1 RESEARCH Each CS team addresses RQs listed below. 3.2 PARTICIPATORY GOVERNANCE DEVELOPMENT Local people are linked with formal water governance institutions and together they develop co-operative capacity. 3.3 STRATEGIC ADAPTIVE MANAGEMENT (SAM). As water supply and pollution research results emerge, and stakeholders collaborate more effectively, a SAM workshop demonstrates a mechanism for collaboration. 4. PARTICIPATORY MONITORING AND EVALUATION OF REFLEXIVE LEARNING (PMERL) A novel project monitoring and evaluation process where researchers and stakeholders co-develop and co-monitor project indicators, co-reflect on progress, co-learn and adapt, using SAM.   OBJ II: address RQ1: How is water used, to whose benefit? The catchment-based CSs (Rufiji R Tanzania, Senegal R Senegal, and Blue Nile R Ethiopia) undertake research to address RQ1.   OBJ III: address RQ2:   what are the sources, pathways and impact of pollution in urban water systems? The city-based CSs (Kampala City Uganda and Lagos City Nigeria) undertake research to address RQ2.    OBJ IV:  addresses RQ 3: how can local capacity to engage in participatory governance be developed for: i) equitable water sharing, ii) community pollution resilience, and iii) ecosystem protection and restoration? In each CS, while conventional bio-physical research on water supply and pollution is undertaken (RQs1 and 2), there is active facilitation of relationship building between local people and any formal water governance institutions. This participatory governance development is researched in each CS. The habits of co-operation practices during the project will be the long-term legacy of this project.  A Rhodes U post doc, together with UoS Prof F Cleaver lead CS researchers in publication of participatory governance findings. A UoS post-doc collaborates with CS researchers on cross CS comparative publications.     All these support OBJ V.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable water resource development remains elusive because development has largely externalized costs to the environment and vulnerable people. There is a need for novel research theory, methodologies &amp; practice in order to meet the UN SDGs and realise the Africa Water Vision 2025. We propose to launch an innovative research approach: the Adaptive Systemic Approach (ASA). Our aim is to apply transformative, transdisciplinary, community-engaged research, to shift water development outcomes towards achieving the SDGs.  We focus on continental water development priorities: water supply and pollution. This collaboration brings together the ARUA Water Centre of Excellence (CoE) and UK partner, the University of Sheffield (UoS). The 8 CoE nodes are: i) Addis Ababa U, Ethiopia; U Rwanda, Rwanda; U Cheikh Anta Diop, Senegal; Dar es Salaam U, Tanzania, Makerere U, Uganda (DAC least developed); ii) U Lagos, Nigeria (DAC lower-middle income); and iii) U Cape Town, Rhodes U (CoE Hub), South Africa (DAC upper-middle income).  We propose a country-based Case Study structure to support local research development and pathways to local impact (Figure 1 in Case for Support). We use an SDG6 (water and sanitation) centred model, that links SDGs related to landscape water resources with SDGs related  to water services. (This model underpins the successful UKRI:GCRF Capability Grant:&quot;Water for African SDGs&quot;). We raise three research questions (RQ) related to water development priorities.  Three catchment-based Case Studies address RQ1: HOW IS WATER USED, TO WHOSE BENEFIT? (Rufigi R Tanzania, Senegal R Senegal, and Blue Nile R Ethiopia). Two Case Studies focus on urban water pollution (Kampala City Uganda and Lagos City Nigeria), addressing RQ2: WHAT ARE THE SOURCES, PATHWAYS AND IMPACT OF POLLUTION IN URBAN WATER SYSTEMS? A cross-cutting Case Study addresses water resource protection and biodiversity in all CSs, and a biodiversity site in Rwanda. By the completion of the project we commit to leaving local people effectively linked with institutions making decisions about water that affect them. Therefore all Case Studies address the question RQ3: HOW CAN LOCAL CAPACITY TO ENGAGE IN PARTICIPATORY GOVERNANCE BE DEVELOPED FOR: I) EQUITABLE WATER SHARING, II) COMMUNITY POLLUTION RESILIENCE, AND III) ECOSYSTEM PROTECTION AND RESTORATION?  The novel Adaptive Systemic Approach (ASA) provides a coherent methodological framework that will support Case Study comparisons, changed water development practice, and will embed pathways to impact throughout the project. The ASA requires engaged research, and draws on three core theoretical concepts, with associated methods: Complex Social-Ecological Systems, Transdisciplinarity, and Transformative Social Learning (Elaborated in Case for Support). These concepts underpin four ASA steps, followed in each Case Study: 1. BOUND: Researchers engage with a full range of stakeholders to identify a relevant, local, water-development issue, and scope the Case Study.  2. ADAPTIVE PLANNING PROCESS: Stakeholders co-create a contextually informed vision of the future state of their selected local issue, and co-develop an objectives hierarchy to move towards resolving the issue. 3. CONCURRENT ACTIVITIES 3.1 RESEARCH Each Case study team addresses the specific research questions, delivering data for resolving the problem. 3.2 PARTICIPATORY GOVERNANCE DEVELOPMENT Local people, formal, and traditional, water governance institutions together move towards local people being part of land and water decision-making. 3.3 STRATEGIC ADAPTIVE MANAGEMENT (SAM) - stakeholders will be trained in a process for systemic, responsive, contextual, co-management. 4. PARTICIPATORY MONITORING AND EVALUATION OF REFLEXIVE LEARNING Researchers and stakeholders co-develop indicators, co-monitor, co-reflect on progress, co-learn and adapt, using SAM. Following the ASA in the case studies embeds the theory of change, and the pathways to impact.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-29">1947848.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF UKRI Award to Rhodes University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/T015330/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">160599.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T015330_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">160599.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T015330_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">124743</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T015330_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rhodes University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FT015330%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
