<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S000046_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">RF Power Systems and Optimized RF structures for electron beam acceleration</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed work is driven by the ultimate goal to design a modular linear accelerator for cancer treatment with minimum subsystems making it robust, reliable and accessible to communities with lower and intermidiate incomes. The road map to achieve this goal was identified during the recent workshop hosted by STFC, CERN and ICEC in partnership with representatives from ODA countries. It is based on the idea to use the best available in accelerator science solutions and adapt them to specific problems linked to the challenging environments, financial situations and knowledge availability in the ODA countries. This project aims to design accelerating structures which can be affordable, robust, efficient and easy to look after, while keeping the design at the cutting edge of the technological solutions available. To achieve the goals the design of the RF accelerating structure will be based on the CLIC system and adapted to the 1.3GHz frequency enabling the use of either a low voltage solid state RF power supply or alternative sources like klystron or magnetron. To make it modular with minimum subsystems required the structure will be vacuum sealed i.e.no vacuum pumps will be needed to maintain the vacuum and LINAC operation. This will reduce the overall capital and maintenance cost. To reduce the manufacturing cost of the cavity a new technology of cavity manufacturing will be tested. The cavity will be machined from two aluminium blocks using CNC lathe. This will also reduce the weight of the cavity allowing the beam energy of 6MeV -8MeV to be achieved while RF cavity length is around 30cm.  The Department of Physics workshop has experience of building a 1.3GHz RF cavity using CNC lathe and will be able to manufacture the cavity in the time scale of the project. It also has experience with vacuum testing of the structures and has the equipment required. The RF bead pull test facilities (JAI Oxford and Daresbury Laboratory) will be used to measure operating and high order modes. The cavity will be sealed and vacuum tested in JAI Oxford and transported to CERN for high power RF tests. The cavity will be kept sealed to observe whether any vacuum degradation will take place with time. To ensure that the system is suitable for ODA countries the partners from Nigeria and Tanzania will be invited to the workshop in Oxford to test the system and advise on ergonomics of the design. We plan to communicate regularly (every two weeks) with all partners via web-meetings during the project to ensure stable and continuous progress as well as securing the impact of the deliverables to the overall aim of the project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-01-19"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-19" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-18" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-15"></value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The Objectives of the project are: a feasibility study and test of new manufacturing technologies and materials to build a reliable and robust, cost effective and efficient, RF accelerating structure for a medical (cancer treatment) LINAC. The LINAC should be capable of operating in a challenging environment with additional constraints (funds, expertise, quality of energy) linked to ODA countries. The proposed work is driven by the ultimate goal to design a modular linear accelerator for cancer treatment with minimum subsystems making it accessible to communities with lower incomes. The road map to achieve this goal was identified during the recent workshop hosted by STFC, CERN and ICEC in partnership with representatives from ODA countries. It is based on the idea to use the best available in accelerator science solutions and adapt them to specific problems linked to the challenging environments, financial situations and knowledge availability in the ODA countries.  This project aims to design accelerating structures which can be affordable, robust, efficient and easy to look after, while keeping the design at the cutting edge of the technological solutions available. To achieve the goals the design of the RF accelerating structure will be based on the CLIC system and adapted to the 1.3GHz frequency enabling the use of either a low voltage solid state RF power supply or alternative sources like klystron or magnetron.This is a 3 months project which has the following work packages and deliverables: WP 1. Design of 1.3 GHz RF cavity using CST Microwave studio (Deliverables: Technical drawings of the cavity); WP 2. Machining of the RF cavity using novel materials (aluminium) and its assembly. Preliminary vacuum test and RF bead pull test in Oxford (Deliverables: Assembled and tested RF cavity ready for vacuum tests);  WP 3. Vacuum test of the cavity to reach requirements needed for high-power RF studies. If vacuum tests are successful a high power RF studies of the RF cavity at CERN facilities. (Deliverables: New technology and materials for manufacturing the vacuum sealed accelerating structures. New approach to the construction of the RF accelerating structure as a fully sealed unit for application in challenging environments will be developed)."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">51640.06</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_S000046_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
