<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P016057_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Patterns of resilience among young people in a community affected by drought: Historical and contextual perspectives</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Drought is a slow-onset natural hazard that negatively impacts upon the social, economic, and environmental systems that affect young people&apos;s health and wellbeing, and is particularly problematic in semi-arid to dry sub-humid areas of sub-Saharan Africa (including southern Africa). Studies suggest that rainfall has been declining across the southern African summer rainfall zone since the mid-20th century, so finding ways for young people in the subcontinent to become resilient in the face of this challenge needs addressing. The overarching objective of this proposal is to understand better the complex relationships between drought, social-ecological systems and young people&apos;s resilience. More specifically, we wish to understand the physical and social ecological enablers of resilience among drought-challenged South African young people (i.e. those aged 15-24) living in the Govan Mbeki municipality, Mpumalanga Province. We are a multidisciplinary and multisectoral team, including UK, Canadian and South African university researchers, alongside South African and UK community partners (Khulisa Social Solutions and Boingboing). Together, we will use the results of this exploration to leverage resilience, supporting young people to articulate their perspectives and to mobilise that knowledge collectively.  Our main objective is underpinned by seven sub-aims (and supporting hypotheses): 1. To determine how drought severity is defined and quantified in the principality, how it has changed in historic times, and what the environmental triggers are for major cultural change and community crisis. Hypotheses: Historic climate change has intensified the pressure on drought incidence. There is a critical tipping point of drought that will impact on community cohesion.  2. To explore what youth living in a drought-affected community identify as their own health and wellbeing-related priorities? Hypothesis: Young people&apos;s health and wellbeing priorities reflect their life contexts, and the biopsychosocial/environmental stressors they experience.  3. To learn how young people define resilience in times of drought. Hypothesis: Young people&apos;s definition will reflect socio-cultural and historical influences.  4. To identify which characteristics/processes of young people, their families, communities, culture and physical environments support positive outcomes under drought-related stress. Hypothesis: There are contextually and historically specific patterns of interaction between characteristics/processes of different systems that predict positive youth biopsychosocial development.  5. To investigate whether there are gender and other socio-demographic differences in the way youth experience and adapt to stressors related to drought. Hypothesis: Both current and historic stressors and protective characteristics/processes affect young people in gender specific ways, with young women more likely to experience greater cumulative disadvantage than young men.  6. To reflect on the ways in which the results from 1-5 support social ecological systems to facilitate the resilience of young people challenged by drought. Hypothesis: Resilience is facilitated by a complex interplay of 1-5.  7. To explore how young people can be best supported to reflect upon and communicate their resilient responses to drought. Hypothesis: Collaborative arts-based methodologies, emphasizing site-specificity to examine human relationships with lived-in places, are appropriate vehicles for the generation and communication of group-based understandings of environmental risks and opportunities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Natural disasters, including those that arise from hazards such as drought, negatively impact upon the social, economic, and environmental systems that affect young people&apos;s mental health and wellbeing. The impacts of drought on young people are particularly severe in sub-Saharan Africa, where recurrent drought intersects with development challenges such as inequality, exclusion, poor education and a lack of employability skills. It is important therefore to understand what enables young people to withstand, adapt to, resist or challenge these impacts (i.e. to be resilient). Resilience is about beating and changing the odds. So, equally critical are how young people can be best supported to reflect on and communicate their resilient responses, and how adults (including local and national governments) can &apos;change the odds&apos; that place young people at risk.    To understand better the complex relationships between drought, social-ecological systems (e.g. family, school, government, the physical environment) and resilience, this proposal outlines an interdisciplinary study to explore the resilience of young people living in the drought-challenged Govan Mbeki municipality of Mpumalanga, South Africa. The study will adopt a social ecological approach, with a particular interest in how social and environmental systems enable and constrain the resilience of young people challenged by drought.  The study will address a series of questions. How has drought severity in the Govan Mbeki municipality changed over time? What do youth living in the municipality identify as their own health and wellbeing priorities? How do these young people define resilience in times of drought? Which characteristics of young people, and their families, communities, culture and physical environments, make them more resilient to drought-related stress? Are there gender and other socio-demographic differences in the way youth experience and adapt to drought? How can young people be best supported to reflect upon and communicate their responses to drought?  To answer these questions, we will use a blend of approaches from the sciences, arts and social sciences. First, we will use information from historical documents archived in South Africa (e.g. newspapers, colonial records), combined with rainfall data, to produce a time-line of drought severity for the study area back to the mid-19th century. Working with a community partner and local masters students, we will then encourage young people from Govan Mbeki to use arts-based activities to explore and communicate their personal, family, community, cultural, and environmental responses to times of drought. Armed with the timeline of drought severity, each young person will also be asked to talk to one adult to gather historical narratives of drought-related changes to their community and explore how the community coped with these changes.  The academic team, students, youth and community organisations will use the data generated from these activities to co-produce a strategy to support the resilience of young people to drought-related challenges. This strategy will use drama to share knowledge and develop collective approaches to environmental challenges and opportunities. The youth researchers will be supported in identifying a creative medium of their choice through which to communicate their emergent resilience strategy to relevant stakeholders. This might involve an exhibition, site-specific film and/or live performance event. The youth researchers will take centre stage in the dissemination. Together, the data generated will form an instrumental case study of the resilience of young people from Govan Mbeki, as well as that of their physical and social ecology. We intend to use the approach and findings of this study as the basis for a future large-scale investigation that will assess the relevance of our results to young people in other drought-stricken communities in South and sub-Saharan Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-31">110519.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-31">69409.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-31">179929.712</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to University of Brighton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P016057_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Brighton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FP016057%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
