<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N014006_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Community-led Upgrading for Self-Reliance in South Africa: Integrated Construction and Environmental Management Systems in Informal Settlements</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research seeks to make an important contribution in the field of sustainable urban transformations in South Africa (SA). The proposal fits mainly under the &apos;Land, Infrastructure and Sustainable Development&apos; topic, but also has relevance to &apos;Urban Economies and Livelihoods&apos; and &apos;Urban Politics, Citizenship and Participation&apos;. The overarching aim is to develop and test an integrated &quot;Collaborative Environmental and Construction Management Toolkit&quot; to enhance community self-reliance. The motivation for this research is therefore rooted in identifying the underpinning barriers and enabling drivers for up-scaling community-led, participatory upgrading approaches in informal settlements in Durban.  Overall, the research has four objectives, in order of priority, namely to:  Objective 1: To transfer knowledge to inform policy-making and tackle the specific barriers encountered in terms of scaling-up business models, upgrading skills and making efficient use of resources in the field of urbanisation. We anticipate knowledge being transferred across three levels: - other informal settlements in SA; - other African countries (the wider Africa); and, - the UK, thus enabling a two-way knowledge exchange.  There is the potential to share lessons from the UK Government Construction 2025 Strategy and Building Information Modelling (BIM) framework. BIM is a methodology to manage the essential building design and project data in digital format throughout the building&apos;s life cycle. Monitoring and evaluation is key in informal settlement upgrade mechanisms. The proposed research will explore the extent to which some aspects of BIM implementation that focus on collaboration, communication and data management can be transferred and integrated into participatory upgrading of informal settlements, given the unique context-specific governance, planning, institutional, and construction characteristics. However, the project findings can also impact on the UK practice, given the debate around decarbonisation of energy systems, community projects, and the impact of the Localism Agenda in urban planning.  Objective 2: To uncover gaps, barriers and drivers of bottom-up construction and environmental management in informal settlements in Durban.  Objective 3: To develop and test integrated business models for environmental management building on the drivers for &quot;self-reliant&quot; bottom-up upgrading.   Objective 4: To identify the skills developed and enhanced through collaborative upgrading and provide comprehensive training in the field of construction, project management and procurement, sharing transferrable lessons from the BIM framework in the UK.   These four objectives will be explored under the following set of sub-questions. - What is a comprehensive definition of &apos;self-reliance&apos; in informal settlements upgrading?  - Which are the barriers and drivers that affect in-situ participatory approaches in informal settlements upgrading in Durban? What are the &apos;best available practice&apos; approaches? What is the right balance between the needs and values of local populations and those of local authorities? - Would closed-loop environmental systems promoting re-use of wastewater be acceptable to local residents? What processes, partnerships and business models for &apos;frugal innovation&apos; are required to promote user-centric and resilient infrastructure provision in informal settlements? How can environmental management systems be designed to be user-centric to increase longevity? - What are the construction and project management skills required for local populations to be involved in participatory upgrading? Which elements of the BIM platform can be transferred and integrated effectively into this collaborative approach?</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project focuses on &apos;informal settlements&apos; in South Africa (SA), which are often characterised by the lack of basic services and infrastructure (eg safe sanitation, reliable electricity), poorly performing building materials (eg wood, cardboard, metal sheets, mud) without any building plans approved and often on illegally-accessed and hazardous land. The idea that the communities in informal settlements should be involved in improving their homes and neighbourhoods is often discussed in the international development community. However, the tools and processes needed to ensure a successful upgrade of environmental and construction management are poorly understood, and top-down policies used by central and local government in SA have not been successful to date. If communities can improve their neighbourhoods through participatory techniques, enhancing construction skills and using available materials, then there could be local, regional and national environmental, social and economic benefits. The research seeks to explore the underpinning barriers and enabling drivers for communities to upgrade their informal settlements in SA.   The central question for this research is how can participatory approaches be utilised in an environmental and construction management strategy to achieve self-reliance in informal settlements in Durban. This question will be investigated under six discrete project phases. Phase 1: Local Context and Gap Analysis (UKZN) -Examining factors that have helped communities in Durban upgrade their housing and communities, and barriers to upgrading. Phase 2: Mapping Urban Transitions through Community Participation (Westminster) Through a participatory action-research methodology, the project team will produce findings on bottom-up construction and environmental management in Namibia Stop 8 (NS8) with the involvement of the community living there. NS8 is a good practice case study in Inanda, Durban.  Phase 3: Integrated Closed-Loop Environmental Management Systems (UCL with UKZN) - Exploring the potential of closed-loop systems where wastewater generated from NS8 can be reused for agriculture.  - Investigating the processes, partnership models and business models required to ensure resilient infrastructure is provided. Phase 4: Skills Enhancement in Construction (Westminster) - Mapping the skills developed and enhanced through the &apos;self-build&apos; approach adopted in NS8.  - Transferring lessons from the UK Government Construction 2025 Strategy. Phase 5: Developing and Testing an Integrated Collaborative Toolkit (Westminster and UKZN) - Bringing together the key findings of individual Phases 1 to 4, this toolkit will take the form of a dynamic decision-making model, which will map potential ways for communities, businesses, and policymakers to collaborate. It will also identify the resources required, skills developed, and the business models created for mobilising private sector involvement and economic growth.  Phase 6: Project Management, Communication and Dissemination (Westminster with UKZN) - Allocating around 10% of the total cost of grant to communicate and disseminate findings to a varied audience. The dissemination strategy will include: project website, branding, social media, dissemination material, and dissemination events (UK and SA).  The research findings are intended to impact on SA government policy and practice in the field of sustainable urban transitions, building on best practice from the UK. However, this does not negate the potential to transfer knowledge from SA back to the UK or elsewhere. The intended target audience includes local communities seeking to enhance their quality of life and well-being and local authorities enhancing their planning. The research outputs can be also utilised by international agencies (eg UN), policy-makers and practitioners working on upgrading programmes, plans and policies, particularly under the SDG post-2015 development agenda.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-28">32862.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-28">131708.1</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-28">132747.9</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-28">66766.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
