<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P002609_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unraveling complexity: Understanding the land-water-food nexus in Elgeyo-Marakwet, north-west Kenya</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The communities of Elgeyo-Marakwet, northwest Kenya reside across the ecological continuum of the temperate Cherangany Hills and arid Kerio Valley. Heavily reliant on the land-water-food nexus, they offer a well-studied example of resilience in the face of multiple environmental changes over the last 200 years (Davies and Moore 2016). Earlier research by the PI, CoI and team has focused on management of water through a network of built water channels used for agricultural and domestic purposes; the sophisticated management of agricultural soils through complex patterns of tenure and fallowing; management of botanic resources including diverse indigenous and imported crops; and the importance of forests which serve hydraulic functions and as reserves of gathered medicines and foodstuffs.  However, recent work indicates growing apprehension of the impact of new ecological changes, including general concerns over climate change, as well as a shift towards water-intensive mono-cropping, the introduction of new crops, and the installation of piped-irrigation which is exacerbating unequal access to water resources. While these latter changes were meant to help mitigate food insecurity, research suggest that they may have had the opposite effect by increasing soil degradation, introducing unfamiliar weeds and crop diseases, and placing pressure on existing water sources. Related to this are concerns about the loss of traditional natural resource management, the loss of culturally valuable biodiversity, and the implications for food security. Compounding these tensions are land-use changes within the Cherangany Forest catchment, especially deforestation resulting from increased agricultural and pastoral activities. This has raised concerns of fertilizer runoff, land degradation, biodiversity loss, and decreased water quality and quantity across the upland-valley ecological continuum.   There is pressing interest among local communities and the County government, to understand the implications of these new challenges and develop practical solutions. We focus on disentangling the complex and interdependent land-water-food nexus across the Cherangany Forest reserve and the semi-arid Kerio Valley. Using ethnography, interviews, botanic survey, aerial photography, GIS mapping and building on existing collaborative strengths, we will effect these aims along two axes: 1. Forest Management and 2. Agriculture. We will collate, review and extend existing data to understand the land-water-food nexus in relation to both historic and potential future environmental changes. We will also examine existing literature on regional climatic change and collate local weather station data to produce a practical understanding of how these key axes (forests and agriculture) have and may respond to climatic fluctuation. Production of more highly resolved analyses of potential climate induced impacts seems especially important since current predictions for Eastern Africa are spatially heterogeneous and often of low certainty.   To produce localized and grounded knowledge for practical policy making we will partner with Elgeyo-Marakwet County Council, nearby Eldoret University (UOE), the Marakwet Research Station (MRS), British Institute in Eastern Africa (BIEA), National Museums of Kenya (NMK) and Kenya Forestry Service (KFS) to produce research to be directly incorporated into new county-level environmental and conservation planning. We have undertaken preliminary meetings with County officials and established MOU&apos;s with UOE and MRS. This work will advance longer-term goals of developing local research capacity, encouraging appropriate resource management, and devising policy frameworks that track and address emerging climate change and other ecological impacts by bringing together experts, civil society, and policy makers.  Davies, M.I.J and Moore, H.L. 2016. Landscape, time and cultural resilience. Journal of Eastern African Studies 10:67-87</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We draw together interdisciplinary experts, policy makers, and local community members to explore the land-water-food nexus in Marakwet, Kenya. We seek to build a comprehensive picture of how communities in two linked but environmentally contrasting locales have managed resources over time and have adapted to changing climate, water availability, deforestation, land degradation, and biodiversity loss and how they are and will continue to adapt to environmental, policy and governance issues in the future. Alongside desk study of climatic and rainfall records, we will achieve this via two research axis and four programmes of field work:  1. Forest resources, history and management 2. Agricultural practice, history and management   1.1. The forest and water management The Embobut Forest is a gazetted national water tower, but it is under threat from encroachments for farming and grazing, potentially resulting in a loss of water catchment and/or increased run off and erosion. Building on the UOE&apos;s ongoing research in biodiversity, we will GPS map forest encroachments and extend pilot ethnographic work with communities living in and around the forest concerning the reduction of forest cover and biodiversity. Using Ordinance Survey of Kenya (OS) aerial photographs from 1964 and recent satellite imagery, we will GIS map forest cover changes over the last fifty years - quantifying area and composition change and relating this to policy and hydrological impacts e.g. reduced water sources and/or increased soil loss.   1.2. The forest and food security Building on ethnobotanic work at UOE, we will focus on forest food resources and their possible depletion. This work will include botanical transect and quadrant survey and the collection and preservation of wild plant food and medicinal specimens. We will extend interview work with local communities to assess current and historic use of plants and perceived distribution changes.  2.1. Agriculture and water management Our research has already documented the dynamics of Marakwet farming in the arid Kerio Valley, especially the network of indigenous irrigation channels totaling 300 km in length. Irrigation relies on water from the Embobut Forest catchment but local farmers indicate a decline in volume. Flow rates were recorded in the late 1970s - our Civilian Science team will re-measure flows in select irrigation channels and rivers to create a baseline for measuring future change. We will conduct interview work with the cohort  of farmers we have been following, concerning perceptions of environment change with focus on water volume and conflict. We will collect these views as farmers shift to utilising a recently installed piped irrigation infrastructure and thus compare perceptions of water availability across the two systems. We will interview farmers excluded from the new scheme to understand the diversity of consequent impacts and conflict.  2.2. Agriculture and food security Agriculture provides subsistence for Kerio Valley communities and surrounding pastoral and urban populations via formal and informal networks (Pollard et al. 2015). Our team, will continue to record crop yields from our study cohort and collect data on crop varieties in the face of changing water allocations and rainfall. We will focus on the balance of hybrid vs landrace varieties. Formal botanic collections will be made of key landraces and wild plant foods and we will document their characteristics. Crop strategies will be examined in light of hybrid maize mono-cropping under the modern irrigation scheme. Using the 1964 OS photographs and we will map changes to agricultural areas and broad scale deforestation and erosion.  Outputs:  Botanic collections curated at UOE and NMK, ethnobotanic gardens at UOE. Synthesized data will contribute to county-level policy planning via dissemination workshops and co-authored policy/climate action plan. Presentations, web-posts and peer reviewed articles.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">25117.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-28">50235.07</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/P002609/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">22758.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P002609_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FP002609%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
