<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Effective Prevention and Inclusive Responses to SGBV in Humanitarian Crises: The Healthcare Needs of LGBTI People in the Great Lakes Region of Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1) To strengthen the interface between research, policy and advocacy by bringing together researchers from studies in Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity (SOGI), Sexual and Gender-based Violence (SGBV), Humanitarian Crises, Peacekeeping, Global Governance, Development and Global Health with research users from Europe and Africa and beyond, thereby combining cross-disciplinary expertise with practical knowledge. This will be achieved by fostering collaboration between researchers and research users in all network activities and in the research design of subsequent projects arising from the network&apos;s activities. 2) To identify and respond to the healthcare needs of lesbian, gay, bi-sexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTI) people in situations of humanitarian crises across the Great Lakes Region of Africa (GLR), specifically the Democratic Republic of Congo, Rwanda, Uganda and Tanzania, including populations displaced internally and across borders. 3) To produce research agendas with practical application to the healthcare needs of LGBTI people, which are based on ground-breaking ideas and supported by robust evidence. 4) To develop research methods and methodologies that include LGBTI people in the process of data collection and analysis and engage LGBTI participants as both co-producers of knowledge and potential service users. Thus, research methods and methodologies developed will include both robust quantitative methodological tools to generate accurate, up to date data and qualitative methods, including interviews, focus groups, and community-based methods, better suited to uncovering personal experiences and perspectives and social, cultural and other contextual factors pertinent to the research. 5) To develop ethically sound ways of identifying LGBTI people who are victims/survivors of SGBV, paying due regards to human rights and remaining cognizant of the ethical issues, political risks and possible legal consequences in exposure for such groups.  6) To acquire a better understanding of cultural attitudes and other contextual factors that shape attitudes to SGBV and SOGI, in order to better respond to the immediate health needs of LGBTI people by recommending effective measures to extend health services to these communities - within the boundaries imposed by the practical observance of laws in conflict settings and among displaced populations. 7) To develop effective strategies to promote change in social and cultural attitudes to LGBTI people which will have a positive impact in lessening SGBV and discrimination and thus improve access to health services for LGBTI people over the longer term. 8) To better understand the relationship between SGBV and HIV specifically, and with respect to LGBTI people. This will be achieved through a discrete programme of work which builds on existing knowledge of the complex relationship between SGBV and HIV and which identifies the risks of HIV infection to LGBTI people in situations of humanitarian crises.  9) To improve the training of UN peacekeepers. This will be done by undertaking a discrete programme of work assessing existing training materials and identifying gaps in regard to SGBV, SOGI and health, including HIV risks and prevention, and recommending practical measures to improve training. 10) To disseminate best practice and policy recommendations to those on the front line of implementation and the operational delivery of health services in the Great Lakes Region and to further disseminate the recommendations of the research network to influential change drivers at local, national and international levels. 11) To contribute to academic knowledge by identifying gaps in research at the nexus of studies in SOGI, SGBV, Humanitarian Crises, Development, Global Governance and Global Health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sexual and gender-based violence (SGBV) in conflict situations and humanitarian crises has reached epidemic proportions, yet the international community&apos;s response is inadequate. The UK Government (2010-15) played a leading role in challenging the culture of impunity attending SGBV, but the House of Lords Report on the Preventing Sexual Violence in Conflict Initiative (PSVI) (2015) noted that legal remedies were insufficient; a survivor-centred approach was required, including strategies to promote social and cultural change (2015: 68). This report further noted that health needs must be paramount in holistic responses (Ibid: 66). The UK Government has been asked to commission research on the effectiveness of its responses in regard to LGBTI people (UK FCO, 2015: 14).  This strategic network confronts and responds to the incidence of SGBV against lesbian, gay, bi-sexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTI) people in situation of humanitarian crises across the Great Lakes Region in Africa, paying specific regard to health, including HIV infection, and access to health services. With reference to HIV specifically, the United Nations (UN) Global Fund, a multi-million dollar fund dedicated to the fight against infectious diseases, recognises the need to address marginalised groups, including LGBTI people and sex workers in combating HIV (2012). The UN Security Council has long recognised HIV risks factors in conflict-affected settings (UNSCR 1983, 2011). UN peacekeepers might be perpetrators of SGBV yet there is little dependable data on the levels of HIV in troop committing countries and inadequate training on SGBV, sexual orientation or gender identity (SOGI) for deploying troops. SGBV has implications for human rights and gender equality. However, the dominant framing and language in which SGBV is couched very often casts only women and girls as victims and so compounds the invisibility of people who do not conform to heteronormative expectations and who are, consequently, stigmatised and often criminalised.   The network focuses on the needs of marginalised and stigmatised LGBTI people, impacted by conflict and humanitarian crisis in Democratic Republic of Congo, Rwanda, Uganda and Tanzania. This includes populations who have been displaced, internally and across borders. Participants in the network will work at the interface between research, policy and advocacy. Thus, the network will bring together a range of expertise in conflict and humanitarian crisis, peacekeeping, human rights, SGBV, SOGI, global governance, global health, and HIV specifically, with policy-makers and non-governmental organisations (NGOs) who operate on the front line of implementation. It will generate ground-breaking ideas, supported by robust evidence, to inform practical, effective policies.   The network will build on existing research, identifying gaps in current evidenced-based knowledge  and pin point areas where there is a need for further research, specifically with respect to marginalised groups. It will tackle methodological issues and confront the legal, political, ethical and practical challenges attendant on meeting the healthcare needs of LGBTI people. It will contribute to the development of effective training programmes on SOGI, SGBV and health, including HIV, for UN peacekeepers deployed across this region. It will also disseminate research findings, including initial guidance on workable strategies, to legislators, policy-makers and to other change drivers, at local, national and international levels, in respect to affected and at risk LGBTI communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-15">24935.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-15">99944.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">24935.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">24935.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">24935.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">24935.69</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">25137.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">-45749.23</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">-13642.97</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P006469_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
