<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T038683_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Non-invasive biomarkers of stress in mothers, fathers and infants in urban and rural Malawi: a feasibility study</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is known that health in early life is a key determinant of later life risk of a number of important diseases including high blood pressure, diabetes and heart disease. Changes in stress hormones are thought to be important underlying mechanism. Stress hormones can be collected in biological samples collected in non-invasive ways - such as in saliva, hair and breast milk. However, this has only really been tested in high income settings and it is not known whether collection of these samples will be acceptable and feasible in Malawi. It is likely that there are local cultural and technical issues - for example, length of hair, views on collecting samples in infants, difficulty with collecting samples at home, challenges with storing samples at home.  Two large population studies have been funded to look at the relationships between health in early life and later life disease in Malawi.  Malawian infants are growing up in one of the least developed countries in the world and are at high risk of infections in childhood and heart disease, diabetes and high blood pressure in young adulthood. There is a huge opportunity to link to these studies and conduct more detailed studies in smaller groups of participants to look at potential underlying mechanisms, such as changes in stress hormones.  Therefore in this funding application we wish to determine the feasibility and acceptability of collecting non-invasive biological samples for measurement of &apos;stress&apos; hormones from mothers, their partners and their infants. We will ask 50 women and their partners, to collect samples of saliva at home from themselves and their infants. Our trained research staff will also seek permission to collect hair samples and we will ask women to provide breast milk samples. We will find out whether it is feasible to do these collections, ask the participants and the research staff for their views about the sample collections, and look at the quality of the samples collected and whether the protocols need to be changed in any way.  The findings will pave the way for a future funding application for a nested study within the larger studies. This will add value to the existing studies through exploration of underlying biological mechanisms linking early life development with later life disease. The proposed seed-funding will also build local capacity and expertise in use of non-invasive biological samples, which we identify to be of wider relevance for other work in Malawi.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-08-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="MW" type="MALAWI"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">24191.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-05">72575.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This is a feasibility study aiming to assess the feasibility and acceptability of implementing repeat non-invasive biological sampling for markers of stress in parents and infants in rural and urban Malawi.  The feasibility study has the following objectives: 1. What is the absolute number and throughput (recruitment) of eligible women and men who agree to collect the non-invasive biomarkers (uptake)? 2. What is the proportion of women and men who are retained in the study (retention), who can collect the samples from themselves and their infants (adherence) and provide outcomes data (sample quality)?  The results will inform the design of a future mechanistic study nested within: a) The new co-funded Generation Malawi birth cohort to test the hypothesis that fetal exposure to stress (glucocorticoid) hormones is a key pathway linking size at birth to later diseases including susceptibility to infection in childhood and later life cardiometabolic disease b) The linked Healthy Lives Malawi population study, to test the utility of glucocorticoid measures as biological markers of maternal and paternal psychosocial stress in this setting."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
