<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N005031_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development of alternative sustainable fish feeds to promote human health using novel non-conventional indigenous ingredients</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Omega-3 (n-3) long-chain polyunsaturated fatty acids (Omega-3), eicosapentaenoic (EPA) and docosahexaenoic (DHA) acids, are essential dietary nutrients with key roles in neural development, immune and inflammatory responses, and beneficial effects in several pathological conditions, including cardiovascular and neurological diseases, and some cancers. Many national and international bodies recommend a daily intake of up to 500 mg of Omega-3 for optimum health. It is known that in countries with low economic status the availability of Omega-3 in the food supply is low and often below the minimum recommended intake. It is now appreciated that improvement of human nutrition in terms of fatty acid composition is an important goal and so the primary objective of the project is to address this nutritional deficiency in poor populations in India, Kenya and Tanzania.  Almost all long-chain Omega-3 is produced by microalga in marine and freshwater ecosystems and thus fish are the predominant source of these nutrients in the human diet with farmed fish now accounting for around 50% of consumption. However, the only sources of Omega-3 for feeds for farmed fish are fishmeal and fish oil that are also finite and limited resources derived from wild fisheries. Projecting recommended dietary intakes for Omega-3 to a population of 7 billion shows a large gap between supply from fish/seafood (whether wild or farmed) and demand. Therefore, supply of Omega-3 for optimal human nutrition is a global problem that transcends geographical and political boundaries. Conventional plant proteins and vegetable oils do not contain long-chain Omega-3 but their precursor, ALA (short-chain omega-3), can be abundant in terrestrial and freshwater plants. In addition, many freshwater fish species including common carp and Nile tilapia have the metabolic capacity to convert dietary ALA to EPA and DHA. Therefore, one potential option for increasing the amount of Omega-3 available to human populations is to exploit the endogenous ability of freshwater fish species to produce EPA and DHA from ALA. Fish farming in India and Africa is dominated by carp and tilapia production - the species of greatest interest for the production of Omega-3 in farmed fish. Intensification of carp and tilapia aquaculture with associated increased use of supplementary and manufactured feeds provides the opportunity to enhance nutritional quality of the farmed products through higher Omega-3 contents derived from dietary ALA. This must be done sustainably and thus without the use of finite and/or expensive global commodities or competing with existing human food resources or animal feedstuffs represented by current agricultural crops.     The aim of the present proposal is to improve Omega-3 status of farmed carp and tilapia in India and Africa (Kenya and Tanzania) for the benefit of poor local populations using indigenous, non-conventional feed ingredients. In this context, we aim to apply and expand current knowledge of nutrient and fatty acid compositions of a range of local, indigenous materials including freshwater plants, microbes and seaweeds and assess their availability, feasibility and potential as feed ingredients in terms of nutritional quality, supply level, and socio-economic viability. Selected novel ingredients will be tested in carp and tilapia feeding studies for ability to support growth, development and health of farmed fish and to enhance nutritional quality through increased the Omega-3 content. The potential of the novel feed ingredients for further widespread application and industrial and commercial scale-up will also be assessed in order to facilitate their exploitation as novel indigenous feed ingredients.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-10-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-23">268298.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-23">270471.8</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-23">170413.93</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-23">68165.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Our contention is that the nutritional quality in terms of the content of beneficial n-3 long-chain polyunsaturated fatty acids (LC-PUFA), most specifically EPA and DHA, of carps and tilapia farmed in India and Africa can be improved through the use of novel indigenous non-conventional feed ingredients. These ingredients must be sustainable and thus cannot include expensive global commodities or compete with existing human food resources or animal feedstuffs represented by current agricultural crops. Therefore the overall aims of the study are to identify indigenous, non-conventional feed ingredients in terms of supply and nutrient content, determine their utility in fish feeds in terms of production and, especially, n-3 LC-PUFA and antioxidant content of farmed products, and thus to assess their ability to improve nutritional quality of locally farmed fish and therefore their potential to improve the health and quality of life of poor populations including assessment of feasibility for commercial application and industrial scale-up.  The specific, measurable project objectives are: Objective 1. To review existing knowledge of nutrient content and composition of a range of non-conventional ingredients and assess their utility as feed ingredients for fish.  Objective 2. To assess the availability and feasibility of potential novel non-conventional feed ingredients in terms of supply.   Objective 3. To characterise the nutrient content and nutritional quality including fatty acid compositions of selected novel feed ingredients.  Objective 4. To investigate the ability of selected novel feed ingredients to support growth, development and health of farmed fish and to increase the n-3 LC- PUFA content of the harvested fish and thus their potential to improve health of local consumers.  Objective 5. To assess the socio-economic viability of the non-conventional ingredients as components of fish feeds and provide an analysis of cost-benefit to the local populations.  Objective 6. To provide the information required to determine the potential of the novel feed ingredients for further widespread application and industrial and commercial scale-up.   The major overall outcome of the project will be the development of new value chains for carp and tilapia culture in India and Africa with new cost-effective feeds based on indigenous, locally produced and sustainable ingredients that can deliver health benefits to both the fish and, especially, the local populations consuming the farmed products. The training and knowledge transfer components of the project are vital for its success being key in defining feasibility and viability and so other major outcomes will include socio-economic assessments vital to the successful uptake and acceptance of the new ingredients and feeds. These outputs via simple brochures/pamphlets/fact sheets/guidance notes in local languages targeting the key stakeholders (farmers, consumers etc.) will be as critical to the success of the project as the biological outcomes. Transfer of knowledge will include raw ingredient compositions, fish feed formulation, fish dietary trials, and analyses of trial outcomes (fish composition, health and nutritional quality). Specific publications in the peer-reviewed scientific literature will include a comprehensive review of existing data in the literature on macrophytes, microbes and macroalgae and their potential use as feed ingredients for fish including a database of the nutrient, fatty acid and amino acid compositions of novel ingredients; Nutrient compositions of fish grown on novel ingredients with particular reference to n-3 LC-PUFA content and possible beneficial health effects for local consumers; Effects of novel feeds and ingredients on fish metabolism."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
