<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_T007141_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project ThaiPASS: Thailand-UK Python+Astronomy Summer Schools 2020 and 2021.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Project ThaiPASS (Thai-UK Python+Astronomy Summer School) is a human-capacity building STEM-outreach project involving 3 UK universities (Warwick, Hull, UCLan) and 2 Thai partners (Naresuan and NARIT).  The core activity of ThaiPASS is a 5-day workshop aimed at Thai secondary school students age around 16-18. Students will receive hands-on training in scientific computing in Python, one of the world&apos;s fastest growing open-source programming languages and one of the most desirable from an employability perspective. Students will learn to use Python to mine, analyse and visualise data. This will be done via the medium of astronomy, which is one of the most inspiring and high-impact STEM enablers. Professional astronomers from the UK will guide students through a series of lectures and hands-on tasks involving handling astronomical data and producing visual output such as astronomical images and graphs. Students will leave the summer school with a new perspective on the role of data science in modern scientific research, and will be inspired to continue to learn coding beyond the scope and time-scale of the summer school. Each summer school concludes with a &quot;university and career&quot; day to inform students on how STEM subjects can be taken further at university level and as a career.  The ThaiPASS project will address many of the challenges in science and ICT education in Thailand, which has fallen far behind other countries emerging out of the middle-income trap. At ThaiPASS, we will bring STFC-funded science to new audiences who may not have the opportunity to access such training otherwise. The skills developed at ThaiPASS are current, relevant and easily transferable to a wide range of industrial and academic applications.   Our experience with delivering ThaiPASS in 2018 and 2019 has informed us that our workshop is unique from other locally organised &quot;summer camps&quot; which are geared towards Olympiad-style training. Feedback over the past 2 years have been overwhelmingly positive, with many previous participants going on to higher education in various STEM areas. For the 20/21 schools, we will deliver bigger events (doubling the number of participants), cover more topics in astronomy, and provide separate teacher-training sessions.  In recent years, Thailand has established itself as an emerging player in astrophysics research thanks to a new generation of internationally recognised researchers at NARIT, Chiang Mai, Naresuan. Chulalongkorn, Suranaree etc. Investment in the ThaiPASS project will be an important step towards forging a strong and lasting Thai-UK synergy, which can easily spin off into future collaborations in astrophysics research and further outreach activities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We propose to organise two STEM-outreach summer schools entitled: Thailand-UK Python+Astronomy Summer School (ThaiPASS) in 2020 and 2021. This builds on the success of ThaiPASS&apos;18 and 19, also funded by STFC and NARIT. Our proposal addresses human-capacity building with focus on the &quot;STEM Outreach&quot; theme of the call.  ThaiPASS is primarily aimed at Thai secondary-school students age around 16-18, who will be trained in basic data handling skills using Python via the medium of astronomy. ThaiPASS 20/21 is a collaboration between 3 UK universities (Warwick, Hull, UCLan), and 2 Thai institutions (Naresuan &amp; NARIT). Our primary objectives are: - To develop competency in scientific programming via Python-based activities. - To introduce students to contemporary topics in astronomy via lectures from UK professional astronomers.  - To train students to mine, analyse and visualise data (e.g. producing astronomical images or videos) either individually or in small groups. - To educate students in the modern interlink between astronomy and data science. -       To encourage critical thinking and problem solving with the aid of computer programming. -       To motivate students to continue learning coding and astronomy beyond the scope and time-scale of the summer school.  - To inspire students to take up STEM subjects at university, and to take up careers in science and technology.   New to 20/21 is the addition of Python training sessions for secondary-school teachers, running in parallel to the student sessions. Our teacher-training programme will give participating teachers not only Python fluency, but also inspiration to continue learning Python after ThaiPASS, with the ultimate goal of becoming Python trainers themselves.  STEM knowledge and data-handling skills are transferable to many different sectors and underpin economic advances in health systems, education and infrastructure. The kind of training offered at ThaiPASS will support the development of a knowledge-based high-tech economy that Thailand strives to be.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-03">45223</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-03">21453.76</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-03">66676.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC Newton STFC - ODA Award to University of Warwick</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST/T007141/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Warwick</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FT007141%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
