<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P002439_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton RCUK - TUBITAK Innovating the Turkish supply chain for services in humanitarian aid</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">For decades the humanitarian sector has mainly relied on providing material assistance to beneficiaries during disaster relief. These days there is a growing importance in the provision of services, not only by means of replacing the distribution of relief items by cash &amp; vouchers that can be exchanged for goods as needed but also in the provision of supporting services such as health or education. These services can help stimulate local market activity and restart livelihoods.   In this project we aim to design and implement the supply chain for two key services to beneficiaries: cash &amp; voucher distribution (as a replacement for distributing core relief items) and the provision of educational services. The project has been split up into three phases. In the first phase we aim to analyse the current refugee situation in Turkey, conduct interviews with agencies in the field on the current refugee situation in Turkey and on disasters in Turkey in the past (we have contacts with local agencies for this purpose - amongst others UNHCR and Turkish Red Crescent, both of which were unfortunately not able to provide a letter of support in time for this proposal). We furthermore perform desk research to collect information on the specifics of the refugee situation in Turkey and on past disasters.   In phase two we focus on the development and application operations research models to identify where and how to locate these services in order to provide optimal support to beneficiaries. In the design of cash and voucher supply chains we develop guidelines and tools on how to set up cash and voucher distribution points dependent on in-kind distributions while reducing travel times, waiting times, yet guaranteeing sufficient security. We furthermore develop guidelines and tools on supporting timely scale-up of cash and voucher distribution. In the part focused on integrated models for refugee camp location and mobile public services we develop a decision making methodology and supporting guidelines and tools for the camp site selection problem while considering the level of public services around the potential areas. With the help of this methodology, the selected camp sites will be in places where the city can accommodate public services when the need arises.    In phase III we aim to integrate the findings of both sub-projects and test the models on the Turkey case. We develop a framework how to monitor, measure and assess the impact of our findings on stakeholders, including ao. beneficiaries, local suppliers, donors, banks and other system providers, logistics services providers, government.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-06-30"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="TR" type="TURKEY"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EUROPE, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">89</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-14">41885.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-14">84111.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-14">48215.15</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall goal of the intended project is to increase access of refugees to services while increasing efficiency and effectiveness for humanitarian organizations and government involved in setting up supply chains for these services. We aim to provide guidelines for the design of the supply chains for two specific services: cash and voucher distribution services and mobile services (such as health or educational services). By doing so we aim to achieve the following (in decreasing order of priority) - Increase access for refugees to key services and in particular to education - Increase local ability in Turkey (government but also NGOs) to cope with natural disasters and refugee situations by being able to set up and deploy services networks quickly and efficiently - Support beneficiaries in building up a local market and develop livelihoods by offering access to services - Be able to quickly decide on refugee site locations and the appropriate supply chain setup for cash and voucher services as well as educational services  We aim to fulfil these aims by providing a: - Report on state of the art design of supply chains for cash &amp; vouchers and on the state of the art of provision of education services to refugees.  - Decision making framework for cash and voucher distribution - Stakeholder KPI monitoring, measurement &amp; impact methodology and model. - Decision support system for planning distribution points and cash needs for cash and voucher distribution systems, supporting scale-up. - Mathematical model on refugee camp location and mobile facility routing.  - Implemented solution algorithm for planning the location and schedule of mobile education facilities. - Guidelines for planning the location and schedule of mobile education facilities to serve refugee camps in Turkey. - Pilot test project to assess the cash and voucher decision framework, monitoring measurement and assessment methods, and cash and voucher distribution planning tools."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
