<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R019541_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early-life origins of brain resilience to mental illness and cognitive impairment across the life-course</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing mental illness and cognitive decline are priorities for the Indian government. The proposed research is designed as four objectives that will inform preparation of a large scale grant to investigate the hypothesis that early life environment affects future risk of mental illness and cognitive ability. It will also begin to create a platform of enduring value for future population research. Through collaboration with established cohorts in Holdsworth Memorial Hospital (HMH) Mysore, and the Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology (CCMB), Hyderabad, South India, we will address the following objectives:  1. Pilot collection of brain magnetic resonance imaging in subsamples of the Mysore Parthenon Cohort (current age 20-21, N~500) and Mysore Birth Records Cohort (current age 51-83, N~750), to investigate relationships between early life socioeconomic circumstance, brain complexity and cognitive and mental health outcomes in a rapidly developing population. Effect sizes will inform power calculation for a future large-scale study.  2. Develop awareness of health informatics through public engagement with participants and researchers in Mysore. Explore attitudes and potential barriers to creation of secure data linkage between imaging, laboratory, health data and outcomes for Mysore cohort participants and potentially in future for the children of mothers in the Mumbai Maternal Nutrition cohort (current age 5-11, N~1,600) to facilitate future linkage studies. Understand what is required for interoperable, secure data storage and plan future biorepository as a resource for researchers that will build over time.  3. Collect new cognitive data using existing tests of cognitive ability and depressive symptoms and investigate feasibility, with cohort participants and Mysore research staff, of collecting new navigation ability data using Sea Hero Quest game on iPad. Collect new bio-samples (blood and buccal samples where possible and saliva as an alternative) from Mysore cohort participants and transfer to Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology (CCMB), Hyderabad.   4. Host a two-day Computing Sciences Workshop at the University of Aberdeen for Indian Co-Investigators and UK team members that will explore the feasibility of utilizing big data approaches, including multi-dimensional data capture and storage, machine learning analysis techniques and other data analytics applied to the brain imaging, cognitive and epigenetic measures collected in as part of objectives described above.           The proposed work will allow research that addresses Sustainable Development Goals: i) Goal 3-to ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages; ii) Goal 4-to promote lifelong learning opportunities for all; iii) Goal 10-to reduce inequalities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research in children in North America using brain scanning has shown that the brain develops less well and has a smaller surface area in children of families with less income. This result was not found in a study from Norway, where there is greater socioeconomic equality. Our own research has shown that being poor as a child is associated with more brain abnormalities in later life, which are associated with depression and dementia. Countries such as India are experiencing a rapid rise in what were considered &quot;Western diseases&quot;, such as diabetes, combined with an increase in older people. In addition, there remain significant disparities in socioeconomic circumstance, access to education and healthcare. Researchers in the UK, in Mysore and in Mumbai have established groups of normal people (cohorts) at different ages and from different socioeconomic circumstances that have already provided much evidence on the early life origins of later life diseases, such as heart disease and diabetes. Here we will carry out work that will pave the way for a future large-scale study of mental health and thinking (cognitive) abilities in these groups. Concentrating on the Mysore groups in this application, we plan four projects that will help us design our future project to include people in Mysore and Mumbai.   1. We will invite a small number of the younger and older Mysore cohorts to have a brain scan first to find out how acceptable scanning is for them and secondly as a pilot study to test whether early life circumstances influence measurable changes on brain scans. We will investigate what factors in early life (such as your father&apos;s job, your birth weight) predict brain scan appearances.   2. By speaking with participants we will find out what people who are part of these informative cohorts think about volunteering for brain scans, blood tests and new computer tests of their thinking (cognitive) abilities. We will ask them how they view keeping information about them on a computer and their opinions of combining this information with other health and education information about them. We will also take account of local permissions, participants&apos; and researchers&apos; views on creation of a future database that allows their information to be securely stored, transferred between institutions in India and anonymously available to future researchers. Such a collection of information would grow over time and allow future research to answer our question about the impact of early life environment on important mental health outcomes.  3. Provided participants agree, we will collect blood samples, cheek scrape samples, repeat tests of thinking abilities and depressive symptoms to add to existing research records and to allow us to calculate how many scans and tests would be needed in a future large-scale study to provide meaningful information. We will also take account of local permissions, participants&apos; and researchers&apos; views on creation of a future database that allows this information to be securely stored, transferred between institutions in India and anonymously available to future researchers.   4. We will host a workshop at the University of Aberdeen for investigators from India and Aberdeen to discuss and plan analysis of the extensive information available in these participants and how we best design a data analysis plan, based on pilot data, existing expertise on &quot;big data&quot; approaches and meaningful statistical analysis for a future large-scale application to address our research question.  The work we propose here will provide the preparatory work for a future study to discover what aspects of early life environment can be modified to reduce mental illness and cognitive decline in India. This addresses three of the Sustainable Development Goals: i) Goal 3-to ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages; ii) Goal 4-to promote lifelong learning opportunities for all; iii) Goal 10-to reduce inequalities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-01">193797.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Rapid Response Research Grants Award to University of Aberdeen</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/R019541/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Aberdeen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">186589</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R019541_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Aberdeen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">1635.34</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R019541_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Aberdeen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FR019541%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
