<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003818_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Co-developing a method for assessing the psychosocial impact of cultural interventions with displaced people: Towards an integrated care framework</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stories of displaced people, migration and immigration continue to occupy headline news here in the UK and abroad. Less well documented are the huge efforts being made by displaced people and associated relief agencies to deal with the challenges of displacement and migration. There are a host of temporary &apos;pop-up&apos;, as well as more established arts, heritage and cultural programmes which are aimed at displaced people who are currently in transition, for example in camps, and those refugees who have reached their resettlement destination. The impact of these programmes on participants&apos; health and wellbeing has often been overlooked in relation to their overall health and how such cultural programmes contribute to recovery, adjustment and other challenges associated with displacement. By working in collaboration with a UK based arts and mental health charity and a Palestinian refugee camp in Jordan, we wish to better understand the role of creative arts and cultural activities in improving the health and wellbeing. We will also explore the potential for the arts to play a central role in improving issues associated with resettlement, employability and learning new skills, and consider how this could feed into relevant policies such as those related to immigration.  New research shows how damaging displacement is for people&apos;s physical and mental health, overall wellbeing and opportunities to flourish, such as employability. Along with issues such as the loss of a sense of belonging, identity and isolation, research shows that refugees and displaced people are more likely to experience mental health problems, such as major depression and Post Traumatic Stress Disorder. These problems arise from the trauma associated with exposure to violence and difficulties encountered in the migration journey, as well as migration-related difficulties in their countries of resettlement such as issues with immigration, employment and income.    Jordan hosts the highest number of Palestinian refugees of all five fields of United Nations operations. Those 1.95 million registered Palestinian refugees constitute over 40% of all registered refugees in the Near East. The first Palestinian refugee camps in Jordan were established almost 60 years ago following the 1948 Israeli-Arab war. Since then, the refugees had to craft their lives away from their homeland and traditional support systems. The current situation of refugees is complex as the new generations suffer limited access to resources, poverty and poor environmental conditions while at the same time continue to live a non-ending temporary situation inside camps. The frustrations of alienation and poverty have led to depression, anxiety and frustration. This has been addressed through interventions in camps, usually partnering with local organisations, addressing mental health through arts or culture. However, these activities are usually conducted without a systematic assessment of process or impact. Similarly, in European camps and refugee organisations, the impact of arts programmes has not been assessed in relation to overall health and wellbeing.  To understand the impact of creative and cultural activities we will collect evidence from displaced people by working closely with them and charities and organisations in the UK and Jordan. We will use this information to inform the development of a new method for collecting evidence which takes into account the health and wellbeing of displaced people and we will co-produce a toolkit which has a more integrated and holistic approach to care. This toolkit will be made widely available and will have relevance for anyone working with vulnerable audiences. We will also create a range of other outputs, including a short film to be produced by displaced people and refugees, which will provide an opportunity for them to decide which stories are told and to take back ownership of their own journeys of displacement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal seeks to understand the value and impact of creative and cultural activities for displaced people, in relation to their overall health and wellbeing. The project has the following objectives: - The main objective of the research is to co-design and co-develop a new method for assessing the impact of creative and cultural activities (to include music, art making, film, theatre, dance, museum and heritage activities) with displaced people and other relevant stakeholders, taking into account the impact of other interventions such as physical and psychological support (including talking therapies, drug treatments).  - In co-designing the methods framework we will engage participants and stakeholders in two geographically defined locations (1) Helen Bamber Foundation (a charity in London supporting refugees and asylum seekers who are survivors of torture and extreme human cruelty); (2) Talbieyh Refugee Camp in Jordan (a Palestinian refugee camp established in 1968 under UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East, UNRWA). - We will use quantitative and qualitative methods from social sciences, psychology and health sciences to understand the value and impact creative and cultural activities on participants (displaced people) and stakeholders (including providers of arts/cultural activities; health/social care/third sector staff; relief workers; volunteers; policymakers), incorporating psychosocial mental wellbeing measures, arts and museum wellbeing measures, transcribed interviews, arts practices, standardised questionnaires and participatory methods. - We will test the use of participatory methods as an approach for co-design and co-development of psychosocial methods in the context of arts and health.  - We will use a range of co-production methods to design and develop a new, interdisciplinary, method for assessing the impact of creative and cultural engagement on health and wellbeing, with a focus on psychosocial mental health, including: film production, arts and other creative or making activities, singing, focus groups, workshops, interviews, questionnaires. - We will co-produce the methods framework in an easily accessible &apos;how to, best practice guide&apos; toolkit which will be made available electronically in English and Arabic. - We will co-produce a toolkit which has a more integrated and holistic approach to care which can be widely applied in diverse settings, and which will have application for a range of vulnerable audiences. - We will use the learning derived from the study to understand the role and potential of creative and cultural engagement to mitigate the negative health and social challenges associated with displacement and to help ameliorate issues associated with the migration and settlement process, including skills acquisition (language, teamwork, creative), resilience, employability and confidence building. - We will feed new learning into relevant policy material via for example Arts Council England, UNRWA, UN Refugee Agency (UNHCR) and the World Health Organisation via our knowledge outputs. - We will co-produce other knowledge outputs to raise awareness and encourage wider impact and engagement in the project by: co-producing a short film; Film making skills exchange residency hosted by Talbieyh Refugee Camp, Jordan; two knowledge exchange workshops (UK and Jordan); conference presentations and scholarly publications; a website, blogsite and social media activity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="MIDDLE EAST, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">63033.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">74544.62</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">11701.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003818_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">51222.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003818_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">51222.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003818_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">55376.44</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003818_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">54563.91</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003818_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
