<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P028519_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">WISER-Water Infrastructure for Schistosomiasis-Endemic Regions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Schistosomiasis, also known as bilharzia or &apos;snail fever&apos;, is a parasitic disease carried by fresh water snails that are infected by one of five varieties of the pararasite Schistosoma. Schistosomiasis is transmitted by human contact with contaminated fresh water that are inhabited by snails carrying the parasite. Larvae, known as cercariae, emerge from the infected snails and swim in the water until they come into contact with an individual and penetrate the skin. The transmission to humans can occur through a range of normal water contact activities such as collection of drinking water, bathing, washing clothes, swimming or fishing. Once inside the body the larvae develop into worms which live in the blood vessels for years. Female worms shed eggs which end up in urine and faeces; if infected individuals urinate or defecate into freshwater bodies, the eggs migrate to snails where they hatch and begin the cycle again. The symptoms of schistosomiasis can include frequent painful and bloody urine, abdominal pain and bloody diarrhoea, inflammation and scarring of the bladder, enlargement of the liver or spleen, and where infection persists, bladder cancer may develop. In children it leads to anemia, malnutrition and learning difficulties, thus dramatically impairing their future quality of life and productivity.  It is estimated that 258 million people are infected in 78 countries worldwide, though 90% of the infections occur in Africa. Schistosomiasis kills an estimated 280,000 people annually and ranks second only to malaria as the most common parasitic disease. Praziquantel is the primary form of treatment, with a single dose of the drug having been shown to reduce the burden of infection and severity of symptoms. However, re-infection will quickly occur when people are re-exposed to contaminated water. Education campaigns about the risks of exposure to contaminated water and improved water supply and sanitation should in theory break the life cycle of the disease. Universal sanitation coverage should prevent the passage of urine and faeces into contaminated water bodies, however there is always a danger of transmission by infected people visiting from elsewhere and urinating or defecating into the water body, or occasional lapses in the usage of sanitation facilities. Mollusciciding has also been suggested as a solution, however there are concerns regarding potential unintended consequences of dosing molluscicides into water bodies and the long-term effectiveness and sustainability of this strategy is questionable, since the snails could return at some point in the future. In some cases there may be alternative water sources (e.g. boreholes) which can be accessed, however often there are no alternative safe water sources available to meet the full water needs of communities in endemic regions. In such cases, therefore, the immediate focus for cutting schistosomiasis transmission must be treating the contaminated freshwater body to provide a safe alternative supply.  Unfortunately however, there is very limited and incomplete information available regarding the effectiveness of water treatment processes at removing or inactivating cercariae of different Schistosoma. Also, there are no rapid means for detecting cercariae in water samples and determining their viability, which makes assessing the risk and degree of contamination of a water body and testing the effectiveness of water treatment processes as barriers against cercariae very difficult.  This three-year research programme aims to address these gaps in critical knowledge through a collaboration between water engineers, synthetic biologists, parasitologists, and social scientists in the UK, Ethiopia and Tanzania, in the hope of developing invaluable new knowledge to guide the design of sustainable water infrastructure for schistosomiasis-endemic regions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The research objectives are to: 1. Determine the effectiveness of water treatment processes at removing or inactivating cercariae in water samples collected from endemic regions of Ethiopia and Tanzania, capturing a range of water quality conditions (e.g. pH, temperature, turbidity, colour). The treatment processes will be chlorination, sand filtration and ultraviolet disinfection, the latter by low and medium pressure mercury arc discharge lamps, light-emitting diodes, and solar disinfection. The processes will be tested individually and in combinations. 2. Develop and validate a rapid and cheap biosensor for detecting cercariae in water samples using synthetic biology. Apply this to measuring cercariae in water samples collected from the study regions and in the water treatment trials described in the first objective to aid in the assessment of cercariae occurrence in water bodies and removal/inactivation effectiveness.  3. Using the treatment data gathered by addressing the first two objectives and considering the relevant non-technical, i.e. social and economic factors (e.g. costs, maintenance requirements, local education/training needs, gender and class equity issues), develop design guidelines and recommendations for appropriate, sustainable/affordable, and equitable water infrastructure for communities in schistosomiasis-endemic regions of Africa.  Further goals of this collaborationare to: 1. Disseminate the resulting recommendations to as wide an audience as possible, including as many relevant stakeholders and end users in the two partner ODA countries (Ethiopia and Tanzania) and beyond, including regional ODA countries that are schistosomiasis-endemic.  2. Grow the existing research capacity at Addis Ababa University through bespoke training in research and transferable skills, and develop curriculum for new modules relating to water and wastewater engineering. 3. Communicate the research findings in UK schools and to the public via the Imperial Festival and Fringe events, as outreach activities to promote the importance of STEM subjects in addressing global challenges.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">498916.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">502957.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">485398.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-26">1487272.062</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to Imperial College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_P028519_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FP028519%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
