<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P016219_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building Bhutanese Resilience Against Cataclysmic Events (BRACE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BRACE is a transdisciplinary project that will forge new relationships among geoscientists, engineers, social scientists, historians, and policy makers to address seismic risk and develop resilience-building strategies. This will be achieved through collaborative research and outreach between UK and US researchers and academics and government officials in the Himalayan Kingdom of Bhutan, an ODA recipient country. This novel attempt to develop a multi-pronged approach will reduce earthquake disaster risk, and bring geological, geomorphological and seismological work into conversation with both historical records held in Bhutanese archives and with research into contemporary Bhutanese governance, disaster preparedness, and effective communication strategies for risk reduction. By merging new research in these fields with close consultation with in-country policymakers and engineers, our long-term aim is to develop a sustainable framework for improving Bhutanese resilience to earthquakes and their secondary effects. We will combine expertise in tectonics, seismology, geomorphology, engineering, cultural history, environmental decision making (governance), development, and education to investigate the links between historical records of seismicity, seismic hazards, and the impact of earthquakes on environmental issues, infrastructure and populations. The aim will be to develop resilience and research capacity within Bhutan to cope with earthquakes and their cascading effects on environment, infrastructure, and society. The underlying drivers of disaster risk are currently poorly understood. The Himalaya are highly seismically active (highlighted by the 2015 magnitude 7.8 Gorkha earthquake in Nepal), but Bhutan appears to represent a region of relative seismic quiescence. There is currently little understanding of seismic hazard in Bhutan, and therefore of the potential disruption to landscape and infrastructure, and the consequent impacts on access to food, water, energy, and impact for the health and wellbeing of society. In addition, the regional tectonics and poorly known fault network appear structurally complex and present challenges to assessing future earthquake potential. Bhutan is a rapidly developing country in which traditional modes of life and architecture are being challenged by moves to urban areas where population density has increased. Urban areas are rapidly expanding but building standards are not sufficient to withstand future seismic events, thus presenting a clear call to action. Strengthening resilience to earthquakes and their secondary effects presents transdisciplinary and multi-stakeholder challenges. The interaction between social systems and physical processes results in layers of complexity, which challenge businesses, governments and policy makers, particularly at times of rapid change or shock after a natural disaster. This project will bring a transdisciplinary perspective in which the knowledge of geoscientists, engineers, historians, social scientists, policy makers and practitioners, as well as local knowledge and lay views, are considered. Scientific research identifies pathways and opportunities available to society in times of shock, and combined with a social science perspective can identify the pathways to resilience and rebuilding. Historical archives provide rich data on past seismic events that can help to build an understanding of seismic hazard. However, little work has been done to investigate the potential of Bhutanese historical records to collect and constrain information about past earthquakes. Such data are critical to our understanding of today&apos;s seismic hazard as well as the structural makeup of the tectonic plate boundary in the eastern Himalaya. We will assess the availability of documentary data on past earthquakes using selected archives to develop a catalogue of historical seismic activity and vulnerability, as well as indigenous response and coping mechanisms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation phase objectives: 1. Build resilience against cataclysmic seismic events through a transdisciplinary and multi-stakeholder approach By working with Bhutanese scientists, engineers, historians, and government organisations, we will co-develop a methodology to integrate geological and historical research into seismic hazard assessment. Estimates and uncertainties will be examined with policy makers, emergency responders, government departments, and businesses to assess cascading seismic hazards and risks and to inform resilience strategies. 2. Foster collaboration between researchers in the UK, Bhutan, the USA for analysis of seismic hazards and historical records A methodology for building resilience requires collaboration across disciplines, professions and countries. It also requires a combination of indigenous historical knowledge and current geological assessment. We will work with geoscientists at the Department of Geology and Mines (Chief Seismologist Dowchu Drukpa), and engineers and archaeologists at the Royal University of Bhutan (Raju Sarkar and Kuenga Wangmo). These collaborations will result in new knowledge generation and increase the visibility of UK research in Bhutan and elsewhere. 3. Develop knowledge exchange activities between research, policy, civil society, and business that feed into research and impact activities Through 4 knowledge exchange meetings, 2 in the UK and 2 in Bhutan, we will facilitate cross-disciplinary and cross-sector knowledge exchange concerning seismic risk and disaster planning. Full details are included in the Justification of Resources. 4. Work closely with Bhutanese partners and stakeholders to explore ways to co-develop a resilience plan for Bhutan to address seismic risk With our project partners in the Royal University of Bhutan, the Department of Geology and Mines, and the Shejun Agency for Bhutan&apos;s Cultural Documentation and Research, along with stakeholder organisations such as the National Environment Commission we will assess the cascading impacts of earthquakes and develop resilience strengthening measures. 5. Develop a transdisciplinary approach that combines geology, history and social science Our project brings researchers with diverse disciplinary backgrounds together with policy and practice to determine research questions and develop methodologies at the intersection of work under NERC, AHRC, and ESRC. We will identify good practice that has wide international applicability across different subject areas. Longer-term goals: 1. Test the applicability of resilience strategies in Bhutan for other vulnerable regions. While this project is centred on the distinct tectonics and risk prediction of Bhutan, the policy and governance decisions that stem from it will be transferable to other regions. 2. Extract and collate comprehensive historical data on medium-to-major seismic activity in Bhutan. Analysis of historical archives will bring a new perspective to earthquake research in Bhutan, illustrating the value of indigenous knowledge available within in-country archives. 3. Combine modern seismic data with historical records of seismicity to produce a comprehensive assessment of present-day seismic hazard in Bhutan. 4. Investigate the unique sustainability and wellbeing policy focus in Bhutan (e.g. emphasis on Gross National Happiness rather than Gross Domestic Product) and how it can allow alternative approaches to risk and resilience that focus on flourishing rather than purely economic measures. 5. Work with Bhutanese policy makers, engineers and architects to improve national building codes. Bhutan uses the Indian building code, which is not adapted to Bhutanese construction styles or materials. We will survey existing buildings to assess their vulnerability to earthquake shock, combine this with our historical and modern seismic data to assess seismic hazard across Bhutan, and advise the government on revisions to the national building code.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BT" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bhutan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-16">59971.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-16">102555.46</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-12-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-16">162526.894</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P016219_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FP016219%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-09"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
