<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_V006088_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sources, Sinks and Solutions for Impacts of Plastics on Coastal Communities in Viet Nam</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The 3SIP2C project is focused on quantifying the types and amount of plastic waste entering the coastal margin of Vietnam, and understanding the pathways and destination of that plastic into the wider environment and marine life, and how this plastic impacts upon business activities such as aquaculture, fisheries, tourism and coastal communities. Vietnam&apos;s 3260 km coastline stretches across 28 coastal provinces and supports rural livelihoods that are engaged in coastal tourism, fisheries and aquaculture industries that are between them worth more than US$17 billion per year.  These industries are themselves contributors to the plastic waste problem, but are also impacted by that waste, such that it represents a risk to civil society and business performance, health and safety.  Our project will focus on plastic waste comprised of large (&gt;50 mm), macro- (5 - 50 mm) and micro-plastics (&lt;5 mm). The project is organised into five work packages, with Capacity Building and Engagement acting as the unifying theme throughout our proposed science, policy and governance programme. Our work packages flow from a fundamental understanding of the physical processes that transport plastics into coastal areas using 3 dimensional particle tracking models that account for seasonal changes in transport processes, and that account for the effects of tides, waves and freshwater inundation on these processes. We will couple this with a broadscale sampling strategy designed to gain insight into the characteristics and quantities of those plastics and the contaminants that are transported into the coastal system. This will be linked to a work package focused primarily on understanding the impacts and causes of large plastics on businesses and civil society associated with coastal communities, which will involve engaging citizens in collection of data on the distribution of large plastic through &apos;fishing for plastic&apos; and the use of App technology. We take a deeper dive into the pathways by which macro and micro-plastics interact with the environment and interact with organisms, particularly those relevant to businesses such as fisheries and aquaculture. We will use experiments to understand how those plastics and their associated contaminants relate to health and disease threats in e.g. coastal aquaculture systems. We will interrogate the existing national and international legislations and policies that address the issue of plastics in supply chains and investigate where shortcomings in the integration of policies leads to shortfalls in their successful implementation. Finally, using a broad suite of techniques such as discourse analysis, focus groups, round-table discussions, gamification and citizen science, we will greatly increase awareness of the issues associated with plastic pollution and the effective solutions that could reduce its occurrence or its impacts on society. This engagement will interface with citizens at local, regional and national levels, and with managers and Government officials in relevant ministries. This proposal is ambitious with a multidisciplinary team from 8 research institutions and 7 partners in Vietnam covering all regions of the coastline, and HWU in the UK. Our engagement, impact and delivery are further strengthened by strategic partnerships with the wider non-academic collaborations through retailers (The Cooperative, UK; Sainsbury&apos;s), major seafood importers and processors (Labeyrie Fine Foods - Lyons Seafood) and a Vietnamese business consortium (IDH-Vietnam) and Vietnamese NGOs Centre for Marine Life, Conservation &amp; Community Development (MCD), and global NGOs the Global Ghost Gear Initiative (GGGI) and Global Aquaculture Alliance (GAA). These partners provide the necessary access, expertise and impact translation to realise potential solutions that deliver demonstrable reductions in the causes and consequences of plastic waste in the environment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Vietnamese coastline supports rural livelihoods at local and national scales through tourism, fishing, and aquaculture industries. However, this unique coastline is under pressure from plastic pollution, squeezed between two major sources - the land and the sea. Dealing with this pollution is complicated as Vietnam&apos;s water ways, that span multiple countries, require coherent strategies to reduce and mitigate plastic waste and current estimates suggest that up to 730,000 tonnes of plastic waste are transported to the marine environment. While much of the visually observable plastic waste is large in size (&gt;50 mm), with the potential to impact the fishing and tourism industry, much of the plastic waste consists of macro- (5 - 50 mm) and micro-plastics (&lt;5 mm), a proportion of which finds its way to the coastal system, impacting the environment, ecosystems and, potentially, food quality and human health. The economic impact of this plastic pollution to commercially important fisheries and tourism is currently unknown but threatens a combined business of US$17.1bn. The aim of this ambitious proposal is to understand and assess the impact that plastic pollution, in its various forms, has on civil society and coastal business operations, and how it could affect human health and safety. Importantly, we will undertake a policy analysis that will highlight where effective interventions to mitigate the causes and effects of plastic pollution will have most effect, and will deliver reductions in plastic waste through a comprehensive programme of engagement at the local, regional and national level. We will bring together a multidisciplinary team from 8 research institutions and 7 partners in Vietnam, covering all regions of the Vietnamese coastline, and linked through HWU in the UK.   The project proposal&apos;s specific objectives are: 1. Quantify the flow of plastic materials into the coastal environment and the factors that affect this flow, uptake by aquatic organisms, and deposition to the sea floor.  2. Establish rates of macro- and micro- plastic formation from larger intact plastics 3. Identify key plastic particle types and associated contaminants of potential concern (COPC) and pathogens of risk to ecosystem and human health. 4. Establish a ground-truth plastic particle transport model to improve assessment of management and climate mitigation policies and strategies. 5. Engage governments, civil society and relevant businesses to quantify scale and economic risk of plastics in the coastal zone. 6. Establish an equitable, transparent and collaborative platform for knowledge exchange for the responsible utilisation of resources that reduces plastic production and consumption. 7. Build a core capacity of Vietnamese and UK teams able to assess, mitigate and recommend current and future strategies for plastic waste management in the Vietnamese coastal zone. 8. Develop a lasting circle of expertise through engagement with strategic partnerships between academia, Government institutes and non-academic organisations, including retailers (The Cooperative, Sainsbury&apos;s), seafood importers and processors (Labeyrie Fine Foods - Lyons Seafood), a Vietnamese business consortium (IDH-Vietnam), a Vietnamese NGO (Centre for Marine Life, Conservation &amp; Community Development), and global NGOs (Global Ghost Gear Initiative and Global Aquaculture Alliance).</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="VN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Viet Nam</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-09-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-09-02">3559126.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to Heriot-Watt University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE/V006088/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heriot-Watt University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FV006088%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-01-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
