<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N013255_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sustainable Agricultural Intensification and the Nexus in Brazil (SAIN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil is an important player in the international debate about food security, food production and the need to develop production methods that minimise climate impacts, land use changes and loss of tropical forests and biodiversity.  These sometimes competing objectives and the damaging role of some forms of livestock production in particular, have led some commentators to suggest that a process of sustainable agricultural intensification is necessary to produce more outputs from less inputs, especially land, which has traditionally been abundant in Brazil. This new sustainable intensification agenda is an important element of a wider green growth debate in the UK and increasingly in Brazil and other emerging economies. This project considers the nexus of trade-offs inherent in the need for Brazil to sustainably intensify agricultural production to avoid local and global external costs in terms of greenhouse gas emissions from livestock production and direct and indirect land use change (by deforestation) and associated loss of biodiversity and ecosystem services. The wider context for this imperative is the increasing global demand for food production and Brazil&apos;s ambition to maintain its pre-eminent status as a global food commodity exporter, while maintaining domestic food security and social equality. Global climate change creates an additional stressor, with a need for Brazil to understand impacts and to make incremental or transformative adaptations to allow the agricultural systems to be more resilient to climate scenarios.  The project adopts a quantitative approach to understanding the interaction between these elements. We identify a number of sustainable intensification measures that can be accommodated within farming systems of different scale across the variety of Brazilian environments (or biomes). These measures include livestock feeding, grassland improvement and housing options. We then develop a numerical optimisation model that describes different production systems and allows us to illustrate the economic and environmental trade-offs in a way that helps to inform the design of policies such as those focused on greenhouse gas emissions from agricultural production and land use change (including deforestation). The project addresses the more general question of where production is appropriate and where it is not, by modelling the responses in each biome. We will also be able to address more contentious issues such as the consequences of reducing global demand (or consumption) for livestock products, which is increasingly discussed in academic and policy circles.  The project combines expertise from key agricultural research institutions in Scotland (SRUC) and Brazil (Embrapa), and a key civil society organisation (Imaflora) focussed on agricultural development and sustainability in Brazil.  Our proposal builds on an existing collaboration between the scientific team members and an existing model framework that we aim to improve using additional data and qualitative research of smallholder systems.  A range of different stakeholders from the public, private and civil society will be involved to help develop our model structure and comment on results.  The work builds on existing experience of providing evidence to the Secretary for Agricultural Policy for the Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Supply (SPA/MAPA). This advice has been used for policy development for Brazil&apos;s offer as Nationally Appropriate Mitigation Actions (NAMAs) from the agricultural sector. NAMAs are voluntary emissions reduction commitments to be offered under the United Nations Framework on Climate Change. Finally the project will target significant knowledge exchange to facilitate Brazil&apos;s ambition to inform the intensification debate in other countries in the global south.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project proposes to develop a quantitative policy model to optimise the environmental and economic trade-offs that define our co-constructed conceptualisation of the Nexus as it applies in relation to agricultural production, sustainable intensification and the minimisation of global external cost from production and consumption.  We focus principally on Brazil&apos;s global role in livestock and soya production and consumption, considering the national and international consequences of intensification pathways.   We aim to use the model to develop a cost-benefit appraisal of alternative policy ambitions including the need to deliver mitigation and adaptation that is economically efficient and to provide a quantitative basis to the rhetoric on land sparing and sharing and the likely unintended consequences of reduced livestock consumption.  The project will develop an existing optimisation model used to characterise livestock production and land intensification in the Cerrado biome. Working with project partners and a combination of existing and new data, we aim to extend the analysis to characterise sustainable intensification in other biomes including the Amazon, using measures that form part of much of Brazil&apos;s national ambition in terms of land use change mitigation and the reduction of deforestation.  The model is based on a constrained linear optimisation approach to represent broad scale production choices. In this project we aim to add elements to characterise mixed and smallholder systems and to parameterise the models using qualitative input from smallholder surveys on behavioural intentions. We also add an uncertainty element to the modelling.  The project aims include: - to deliver credible and substantive policy advice on how and where Brazil can meet several of its international obligations and national aspirations in terms of emissions mitigation and adaptation and food production;  - to contribute to the debate on the likely impacts of reduced livestock (product) consumption; - to co-construct a model between UK and Brazilian researchers, building on an existing collaboration and adding new partners and supply chain stakeholders from private and public sectors; -             to engage with key stakeholder groups in both the public, private sectors and civil society to foster discussion and a shared conceptualisation of the Nexus and the development of shared policy scenarios that can be tested with the model;  - to facilitate knowledge exchange about the role of different measures that constitute sustainable intensification in the UK and Brazil; and  - to assist Brazil in its ambition to develop South-South influence in the sphere of agricultural development and sustainable intensification in particular.  We aim to undertake extensive knowledge exchange activities including offering direct advice to the government of Brazil in relation to the continuing refinement of agricultural Intended Nationally Determined Contributions (INDCs) to be tentatively offered as Brazil&apos;s emissions mitigation offer at COP21.  Further output will be through academic publication in high impact multi disciplinary journals, policy and industry briefs and project meetings.   We are specifically responding to the requirement under &apos;Measuring and modelling the Nexus&apos; in the call text. The proposal also addresses the topic of sustainable transformations (in agriculture) and political economy.  Under modelling we are developing a robust quantitative evidence base to define the Nexus in the Brazilian context.  We further respond to other text elements including metrics and tools for mapping trade-offs, ecological and economic modelling for representing Brazil&apos;s global (agricultural and food) position, strengthening the integration of  quantitative and qualitative methods in Brazilian social science, and analysing the role of evidence in policy formulation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-05-09" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-05" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-22">133513.92</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-22">169042.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-03-22">41624.39</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
