<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N00762X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Behavioural Compatibility between Individual Choice and Collective Action</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are many instances in economic and social life where good individual choices add up to poor choices for society. The financial crisis of 2009 can be understood in these terms: an individual banker may expect it to be profitable to grant a loan to a risky customer, but bankers collectively granting risky loans leads to systemic market collapse and a loss for all. A similar story lies behind the accumulation of atmospheric carbon dioxide where it makes sense for each firm or individual to burn fossil fuels but it does not make sense at global level. There are traditional economic models of these situations but recent research, including work at the Institute of Quantitative and Technical Economics (IQTE) and at the Tax Administration Research Centre (TARC), has shown the importance of psychological and cultural factors in guiding decisions. The emergence of behavioural economics, and the changed perspective on individual choice that has resulted, gives a pressing need to re-examine the links between individual choices and social outcomes within the new paradigm.  The application for funding will support workshops, masterclasses, visitor exchange, and a joint research programme of a partnership between the IQTE, China, and TARC, UK. The activities of the partnership are designed to merge the expertise of the two organisations. TARC has considerable expertise in applying computer simulations of individual behaviour to model social outcomes. It also has specialized capability in experimental economics with ready access to a large body of experimental subjects and capability in using online experiments to target specific sectors of the population. TARC is also developing competence in computable general equilibrium. IQTE is one of most important departments in the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. It acts as a &quot;think tank&quot; to support state decisions on fiscal (tax) and financial policy-making. It is highly skilled in the mathematical modelling of economic problems and also has extensive capabilities in computer simulation and experimentation. In both research institutes the focus of research has been exploring real policy problems to enhance economic development and social welfare.   The research programme will develop the experience of IQTE and TARC in applying a range of research methods to policy problems. The underlying theme of an improved understanding of the social, or &quot;macro&quot;, outcome by better modelling of individual, or &quot;micro&quot;, decisions will underpin the individual research projects. The selected research projects have policy relevance in both China and the UK and include implementing VAT in the financial sector, poverty reduction and the reduction of inequality, and investor behaviour and emergence of capital markets. The results of the research will be communicated to policy-makers in China and in the UK so that policy impact is achieved, and to academics worldwide so the international impact is obtained.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2015-08-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-21" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-20" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="CHINA (PEOPLE&apos;S REPUBLIC OF)"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-08-23">14101.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-08-23">28316.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-08-23">28546.22</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-08-23">7165.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The application is for financial support for a partnership between the Institute of Quantitative and Technical Economics (IQTE) of CASS, China, and the ESRC/HMRC Tax Administration Research Centre, UK. The partnership will undertake a programme of academic activities and research projects that deepens our understanding of economic behaviour when heterogeneous agents interact within social and economic environments. The insights generated will be applied to the formulation of tax administration policy in China and to policy-making and policy evaluation more generally. Dissemination activities will ensure that the results are communicated to policy-makers in China and in the UK so that wider impact is achieved.  The common core of the research conducted by the partnership will be the behavioural compatibility between individual choices and collective action. It is often observed that the aggregation of individually rational choices can lead to collective outcomes that are not satisfactory. Similarly, externalities between individuals - such as environmental effects or social interaction - can lead to poor collective outcomes. The consequences of interaction increase in significance when process dynamics are considered. Existing research, including work at TARC on tax compliance, has shown the importance of psychological and cultural factors in economic decision-making. Behavioural models of choice with risk and uncertainty have justified departing from expected utility theory, and social norms are evidently important in guiding individual behaviour. The funding will support workshops, masterclasses, a visitor exchange programme, and a joint research programme that explore these ideas.  TARC has developed considerable expertise in applying agent-based modelling and specialized capabilities in experimental economics. It has ready access to a large body of student experimental subjects and has pioneered the use of online experiments in collaboration with market research companies to target specific sectors of the population. TARC is also developing competence in computable general equilibrium. IQTE is one of most important departments in CASS and acts as a &quot;think tank&quot; for supporting state decisions on fiscal (tax) and financial policy-making. It is highly skilled in studying realistic economic problems using mathematical and interdisciplinary analysis and other relevant methods. There are some research areas, such as agent-based modeling (ABM), experimental economics, and game theory, that have risen to prominence in IQTE in recent years. The application of these methods has been focused on economic development and social welfare enhancement.   The research programme follows the experience of TARC and employs a range of research methods including agent-based simulation, computable general equilibrium, economic experimentation, and theoretical analysis. The underlying theme will be an improved understanding of the social, or &quot;macro&quot;, outcome by better modelling of individual, or &quot;micro&quot;, decisions. There is considerable research looking at individual choice but much less that considers the aggregate consequences of behavioural choices. In particular, there are open questions about the extent to which aggregating &quot;behavioural&quot; individuals will lead to stable macroeconomic phenomena or to equivalent anomalies at the macroeconomic level.  These methods will be applied to five research projects: 1. Implementing VAT in the financial sector 2. Consumption externalities in social networks and macroeconomic outcomes 3. Poverty reduction and the reduction of inequality 4. Public goods and public services 5. Investors&apos; behaviour and emergence of capital market All of these research projects have policy relevance in both the UK and China."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
