<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00580X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhancing resilient deaf youth in South Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Around 6,200 per year are born in South Africa with a significant degree of permanent deafness and many more become deaf through childhood illness. Over 95% of deaf children are born into hearing families with no prior experience of deafness. Deafness presents a major risk to the acquisition of language with poor literacy and very low educational attainment. For many families deafness also attracts unwelcome stigma, discrimination and society as a whole has low expectations of deaf people&apos;s potential despite a normal range of intelligence. The consequences for personal self actualisation, autonomous citizenship and contribution to broader society are far reaching with the majority of deaf adults struggling for employment, access to education and opportunities to lead a normal life. We will develop a series of social interventions using film and visual media to combat current and future public health burden that arises from these consequences.  Our project is focused on building resilience amongst deaf youth through enhancing self esteem, supporting hearing parents to develop their repertoire of emotions based (rather than merely functional) communication and developing practical keep safe resources in a context where deaf young people are especially vulnerable violent crime and abuse. Our chosen medium to achieve these goals is community based participatory film making because the visual is a highly accessible medium for both knowledge acquisition but also knowledge production for those for whom articulation, whether in spoken, signed or written languages, may be severely delayed and because of its non-dependence on the written word.  The project will work with deaf children/young people and their families to explore, produce and edit short films that demonstrate personal potential and ambition with the scope to influence wider public attitudes and act as an educational resource. In working with deaf and hearing filmmakers through workshops and community events the children will also acquire new social-relational skills, have the opportunity to restructure challenging daily experiences of being deaf into potentially inspiring futures through sharing and raising their ambitions of what is possible for them and having access to deaf adult role models through these processes.  Deaf mentors and parents of deaf children will co-create a new emotions-based workshop curriculum to inspire parental confidence in communication about the non-functional aspects of life so emotional worlds and concepts open up to deaf children/young people as resources to enable them to understand their own development and read the emotional reactions of others - both vital aspects of resilience building.  We will create with deaf children/young people a series of interactive films designed to explore keeping safe strategies, prevent abuse, reduce risk and provide deaf young people with a means of knowing of how seek help and support. The community context through which the potential film scenarios are explored, created, filmed, edited and responded to are also learning opportunities for those who will take part in growing their personal and social strategies to combat abuse, neglect and discrimination.  All products will be made freely available in multiple languages, including South African Sign Language, through a Web Doc that will be fully update-able and accessible through a variety of low cost digital means.  The deaf and hearing team working together combine internationally leading expertise in visual anthropology, deaf studies, social research with deaf people and on the ground NGOs providing family centred intervention free at the point of need, parent-led support groups, deaf film makers and supported by the public health office of Gauteng province. The project is process-evaluated by students in deaf education and Deaf studies in South Africa.    The delivery of the project cements a new partnership ready for further research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-12-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ZA" type="SOUTH AFRICA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1029</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-13">83289.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-13">83289.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="This project concerns deaf children, young people and their parents (carers) in South Africa.  It is focused on the delivery and evaluation of social interventions as public health initiatives to offset the long term developmental, socio-economic and health burden of growing up deaf in Low and Middle Income Countries.   Specifically, this proposal focuses on:  The development of resilience building interventions through the medium of participatory filmmaking and visual methods in order: -   to enhance self esteem at an individual level -   offset discriminatory attitudes that impede actualisation at a societal level -   combat the high rates of abuse experienced by deaf children and young people at a community level.   To these ends there are two work packages whose objectives are:   Work-package one:  Inspiring Futures  1.1 Through a child and community authored method, to involve deaf children/youth in the making and production of a series of &apos;this is me - this is my future&apos; films which serve: a) to enable deaf young people to participate in creative exploration of potential futures which expand their horizons of what might be possible b) to develop film making skills supported by deaf and hearing filmmakers c) to produce a legacy of interactive and inspirational short films that can be used for the wider promotion of a positive vision of deaf youth in society to start to nudge attitudinal change.  Work-package two:  Keeping Safe  2.1 To support the work started by the NGOs THRIVE and Hi Hopes to develop parents&apos; confidence in communicating with their deaf children specifically from the perspective of socio-emotional development incorporating linguistic and para-linguistic strategies and visual methods to engage their deaf children in interactions about feelings, growing up, bodily changes and sexual safety. 2.2 To work with a range of partners including parents, deaf young people, schools, the deaf community and business to develop a series of &apos;growing up and keeping safe&apos; films aimed specifically at deaf young people.    In terms of output and legacy, additional objectives are:  To evaluate the effectiveness of exploratory, participatory film making with deaf children/young people as a process, participation in which brings its own opportunities for social learning, personal/collective reflection and resilience building through the acquisition of new skills and positive restructuring of challenging life experience.  To provide deaf mentors and parents of deaf children with enhanced training in the delivery of an emotions communication curriculum designed to enhance socio-emotional development and provide deaf children/young people with new conceptual resources to understand personal and social experience as part of a safeguarding preventative intervention.  To build, using WebDoc technology an update-able, sustainable repository for socio-developmental resources that are accessible to deaf children/young people and their families.  To cement the new multi disciplinary partnership between the academic centres in SA and the UK and the NGOs and other delivery partners in SA as the basis for expansion of ethnographic visual methods as the medium for personal development and social change through its visual suitability and accessibility to deaf children and adults."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">27688.43</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00580X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">55600.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00580X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">41644.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00580X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">41645.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00580X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">-1.83000000000004</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00580X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
