<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP_P015506_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton Fund (Invitation Only): DISASTER RESILIENT CITIES: FORECASTING LOCAL LEVEL CLIMATE EXTREMES AND PHYSICAL HAZARDS FOR KUALA LUMPUR</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Recent natural disasters in Malaysia, such as the wide-spread floods in 2014/15 and the flash flooding of Kuala Lumpur in 2007, have revealed that improvements are required in the prediction of damaging natural hazards and in the capacity to manage the associated risks and consequences.    Appropriate to the theme of &apos;future cities&apos;, the focus of this project is the prediction and management of physical risks relevant to Kuala Lumpur, which is the Malaysian capital and the most populated city in Malaysia with around 8 million inhabitants. The particular hazards to be targeted in this project, that are common in Kuala Lumpur,  are floods, landslides, sink holes, strong winds, urban heat and air pollution.  A consortium of 16 research and business partners from the UK and Malaysia has been assembled for this project. The basic strategy is to adapt and combine existing technologies to enhance hazard forecasting ability, and the main objective is to develop a prototype multi-hazard information platform suitable for communicating risks. The primary beneficiaries will be risk managers and decision-makers in Malaysian local government and the insurance sector. The project objectives relate to the Malaysian Science to Action initiative, which has an aim of mobilising science for societal well-being.   University College London is one of the main UK academic partners and contributes to WP2 on both the simulation urban flood risk and urban heat islands in Kuala Lumpur. With relation to urban flood risk, UCL&apos;s role is to contribute to the determination of rainfall scenarios in the hazard assessment, and to propose and test approaches for loss estimation from the rainfall and urban flooding scenarios. This work will be carried out in close collaboration with JBA and Met Malaysia.  In the context of the urban heat island simulations, UCL will modify an existing software platform to account for the specifics of tropical climates and better characterise the effects of varying building materials on the heat absorption and heat storage of the built environment. The new version of the software will be used to assess the susceptibility to heat-related hazards of several pilot areas in Kuala Lumpur, selected to have different land use features and urban characteristics. This work will be carried out in collaboration with CERC and Met Malaysia, and will involve field investigations.  Benefits of the project will include improved information regarding the risks of occurrence of natural hazards that will enable Malaysian local authorities to make better contingency plans to mitigate the effects of such hazards. This will in turn provide economic benefits and improve the quality of life for Malaysian citizens. Improved information about geophysical and atmospheric hazards will also aid the development of insurance services.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The goal of the project as a whole is the development of a prototype geophysical multi-hazard forecast system for the Malaysian region, in particular for the largest city, Kuala Lumpur. The system will improve contingency planning and risk management, and reduce the economic and societal impacts of the hazards. The main focus is on short-range (hours to days) and high-resolution (city-scale) capability, regarding hazards such as flash-floods, landslides, heat waves, air pollution. There is also a long-range (weeks to seasons) component of the meteorological package, aimed at providing early warning regarding the activity of various meteorological events. The project consortium contains 16 Malaysian and UK academic and commercial participants.  The objectives of the main University College London component of the project workplan are:  1.Contribute to a set of input precipitations for the study of surface water flooding in WP2.1  2. Development of a set of loss functions for asset components under flood events in WP2.1  3.To evaluate the heat induced risks in different pilot areas of Kuala Lumpur by means of urban heat island simulations WP 2.6-8  4.To contribute to an appraisal of the resilience of Kuala Lumpur to water and temperature related hazards in collaboration with Malaysian partners  5.Disseminate the outcomes of the research</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-29">22783.6</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-29">91318.97</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-29">59710.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-29">12313.25</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-29">198041.94</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-EP/P015506/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FP015506%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-03"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
