<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029900_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Integrated Deprived Area Mapping System (IDEAMAPS) Network</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Introduction:  The UN estimates that 2.5 billion people will be added to the planet over the next 30 years. A large portion of these populations will reside in deprived neighbourhoods including slums, informal settlements, and areas of inadequate housing and face a range of challenges from insecure tenure, to unplanned housing, pollution, environmental risk, and social exclusion. Spatial data on such neighbourhoods are commonly not available. On the occasions that they do exist, they quickly become out-dated. Without up-to-date information on the geography (location and extent) of deprived neighbourhoods and the specific social and physical environmental conditions faced by their inhabitants, the impact of these on health and social outcomes are not traceable and the development of effective interventions is not achievable. However, there is currently no systematic, scalable approach to map deprived neighbourhoods across cities, particularly in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs).    Methodology:  The project will design an Integrated Deprived Area Mapping System (IDEAMAPS) that will push the boundaries and overcome the weaknesses of each of these current approaches to mapping slums, informal settlements, and areas of inadequate housing. This will be accomplished by joining up a multisectoral and transdisciplinary network of researchers, technologists and societal stakeholders who will collaborate to co-design the IDEAMAPS approach to map and address neighbourhood deprivation and perform pilot studies in Nairobi, Accra, and Lagos, where we have existing strong partnerships and access to existing data (see details below). This approach will consist of an innovative combination of three components: (a) engagement of stakeholders in different scales; (b) modelling and data infrastructure techniques that aim to integrate and leverage the accuracy of field-based maps; (c) an integrative framework, which defines assessment criteria for characterising neighbourhood deprivation in connection with sustainable development.   Work Groups:  WP1. Stakeholder Engagement- This work package (WP) leads engagement of stakeholders across sectors (e.g. EO, demography, community, policy) in both established and innovative ways to further develop understanding of urban neighbourhood deprivation, and to create enabling environments in which a deprived area mapping system can be implemented.  WP2. Integrative Frameworks- This will be dedicated to the synthesis of key requirements and a shared agenda for the IDEAMAPS approach. It will begin with collating existing literature reviews from current and past projects of the research team: specifically, the Improving Health in Slums Collaborative, Surveys for Urban Equity, Million Neighborhoods Initiative, Modelling African Urban Population Patterns, Accra women&apos;s health study, and Standardizing City-Level Data-Gathering in Lagos and Accra.   WP3. Modelling and Data Infrastructure Techniques. This WP3 collate existing data and methods to test potential IDEAMAPS approaches. Based on the domains of deprivation framework developed in WP 2 with input from stakeholders of WP1, we will develop new area-level environmental (e.g. flood risk) and social datasets (e.g. open sewers), and evaluate modelling approaches that can capture domains of deprivation individually, as well as an overall deprivation &quot;slumness&quot; index. WP2 will also investigate different visualisation targeted at end-users in different scales. The evaluation criteria developed in WP 2 will be used to assess and compare model outputs.  Expected Output:  The work packages will create a foundation of stakeholder engagement approaches, frameworks, and techniques to scale-up over the next three years to flesh out an integrated deprivation area mapping system (IDEAMAPS) with a capacity to generate more accurate and usable maps and integrate them into community upgrading and advancing progress toward sustainable development goal.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To: 1. Establish strong networks of key stakeholders within three cities ready to carry forward implementation of an Integrated Deprivation Area Mapping System (IDEAMAPS) in the following three-year project. 2. Achieve scalable proof-of-concept frameworks and techniques to map deprivation in these and other LMIC cities and a shared agenda to be pursued in the following three-year project.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-23">144595.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">36148.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029900_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Population and Health Res Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">36148.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029900_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Population and Health Res Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">36148.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T029900_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">African Population and Health Res Centre</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
