<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002160_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening health system promotion of maternal and child health through medical travel</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objective of work conducted for this proposal development grant seeks to identify ways in which we can assess the effect of medical travel on the health system and maternal and child health in South Africa and influence its development.  The research has three linked specific objectives each corresponding to one of the research questions set out in the case for support.   First, the research aims to understand how inbound medical travel affects the maternal and child health of the resident South African population. Focus will be on if and how domestic patients are &apos;crowded out&apos;. This includes attention on whether the quality of services suffers or improves, and the effects on population level indicators of maternal and child health. Research will examine if effects differ between medical travellers who access services through formal referral agreements when compared to where they travel for treatment informally. Focus will also be on whether and how health systems adapt over time. If there is indeed evidence and examples of this, do they offer potential could this be transferred to other countries to assist health system adapt and develop &apos;coping&apos; strategies?   Second, to identify and analyse current agreements between South Africa and neighbouring countries which govern and affect patients traveling. This is with the aim to ultimately develop policy recommendations on how to better use such agreements to improve maternal and child health. This includes agreements on cross-border healthcare, referral agreements between countries and those under the WTO General Agreement of Trade in Services (GATS). Analysis will focus on whether these give specific attention to health more broadly and effects on maternal and child health specifically. Based on the impact observed (objective 1), analysis will assess the extent to which these agreements cover and engage with the challenges of medical travellers. Through these initial steps in the analysis research will then seek to identify how maternal and child health can be fostered through existing and future agreements pertaining to medical travel.   Third, to establish what kind of indicators and data are available at national and sub-national level to monitor health systems and impact of medical travel on MCH at population level. As a proposal development grant a key objective of the work will be to identify and test available data to establish its suitability for the measurement of impact of medical travel on maternal and child health. A focus here includes investigation of whether new data will be required, or whether a review of existing data will reveal that this would be sufficient to monitor such impact over time (and during a larger research proposal). Given the novelty of the research, an initial step here is to understand the kind of data required based on the initial qualitative work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This 12 month grant focuses on strengthening health system promotion of maternal and child health through medical travel. It concentrates on South Africa and the effect on resident population of patients traveling to South Africa for treatment from neighbouring countries. It is a collaboration between the University of Cape Town and the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine.   The main objective is to identify how to assess and influence the effect of medical travel on the health system and maternal and child health in South Africa. There are three linked specific objectives. 1) To understand how inbound medical travel affects the maternal and child health of the resident South African population. 2) To identify and analyse current agreements between South Africa and neighbouring countries which govern and affect patients traveling. 3) To establish and review what kind of indicators and data are available at national and sub-national level to monitor health systems impact of medical travel on MCH.   Research employs quantitative and qualitative methods. To assess effects on resident South African MCH, it examines indicators and experiences of health workers, patients and other actors in areas where health facilities are seeing a large number of medical travellers coming in and compare these with areas and facilities who do not. These will be identified through initial key informant interviews. Interviews will be in five communities/facilities where large numbers of medical travellers are received and five where there are not. Quantitative work will evaluate usefulness of core indicators for MCH and health systems access which are publicly accessible. Research will include the analysis of agreements governing medical travel between South Africa and neighbouring countries to identify policy recommendations on how such governance arrangements can best support health systems&apos; promotion of maternal and child health.   Findings, including reflection on methods, will inform a larger comparative research proposal with researchers in India and Thailand.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-EDU-133903" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-10">22170.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-10">44341.32</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-07-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-07-10">88682.63</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/M002160/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">2096.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002160_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">-4854.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M002160_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133903">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FM002160%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
