<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_P004091_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Informal Finance in China: Risks, Potential and Transformation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China&apos;s rapid economic growth in recent decades has been attributed to its reliance on informal contracting and trust-based relationships.  This claim is a reflection of the absence in China of some of the more formal legal and regulatory institutions of the market economies of the global north.   Although the claim that China lacks formal legal mechanisms of market governance may have been somewhat  overstated, it is the case that informal finance, particularly in the form of trade credit,  family lending and communal investing, has played a major role in supporting China&apos;s growth.  The prevalence of informal finance constitutes a significance source of flexibility for China&apos;s economy given the limitations of the formal sector, which remains dominated by state-owned banks lending largely to state-owned enterprises.  Informal finance is also evolving quickly and is converging with the use of internet technologies to deliver finance (&apos;fintech&apos;) through such mechanisms as crowdfunding.    However, there are downsides to the reliance of the Chinese economy on informal finance and significant risks arise from its convergence with fintech.  The large shadow banking sector, by virtue of its positioning outside most of the regulations applying to mainstream banks, adds to systemic risks.  The formal and informal sector coexist in an uneasy relationship: they may substitute for each other, or provide complementary modes of finance, but they can also operate to reinforce and magnify systemic risks, as in the case of the crisis in Wenzhou after 2011.    Similarly, the rise of fintech is a double edged sword.  On the one hand, cloud computing and big data may be facilitating new forms of social credit and collective investment schemes which have the potential to meet the needs of the growing social credit sector.  Crowdfunding may provide a new and flexible form of financing for start-ups and innovative ventures. However, these new forms of finance also have the potential to undercut or render otiose regulations designed to maintain market transparency, and to intensify the risks facing investors.      Against this background, we propose to conduct a multiple methods research project which will explore the phenomenon of informal finance in China, identify the risks and potential associated with it, and assess how regulation can best respond to the risks while not sacrificing the innovations and flexibility associated with it, particularly in the context of &apos;fintech&apos;.   The projects will be organised in four work packages which correspond to three of the five themes identified in the ESRC-NSFC Call:  WP1 [theme 1]: Understanding the limits of informal financing  WP2 [theme 2]: Regulating shadow banking  WP3 [theme 5]: The potential of new technology to promote financial innovation and development (&apos;fintech&apos;)  WP4 [theme 2]: Building a social credit system</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We propose to conduct an interdisciplinary research project to explore informal finance in China, the risks it is generating, its potential to support economic growth, and its transformation in the light of new technologies and a developing regulatory agenda.  Our specific aims are the following:  (i) To understand the potential, but also the limits, of systems of informal financing in China  (ii) To analyse the relationship between formal and informal finance in China  (iii) To examine the risks posed by China&apos;s shadow banking system  (iv) To study the emergence in China of new forms of financing using big data and cloud computing to drive financial innovation, including P2P lending, crowd funding and similar collective investment schemes   (v) To explore the scope for the development of social credit systems in China   The work will be carried out by a cross-disciplinary team of lawyers and financial economists based at the Universities of Cambridge and Sheffield (UK) and Hunan and Renmin Universities (China).  The team is highly experienced in conducting fieldwork and econometric analysis of law and finance in China.  The British and Chinese members have a strong record of existing collaborations. The lead investigators also have extensive experience of research dissemination and impact activities. Thus we expect to be able to make a core contribution to the realisation of the objectives of the ESRC-NSFC Call.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China (People&apos;s Republic of)</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-08">52250.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-08">209423.9</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
