<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00360X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Designing a resilient relief supply network for natural disasters in West Java Indonesia using optimisation-via-simulation: Relief-OpS</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this project, we will develop methods that optimise the delivery of essential relief items following a natural disaster. These include optimising warehouse locations; inventory management strategies particularly for perishable relief items; and robust routing for post-disaster distribution. The optimisation will make use of an agent based simulation model that we will build with input from key decision-makers, designed to mimic the complexities of post-disaster relief efforts.  The Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction 2015-2030 puts a strong emphasis on Disaster Risk Management, acknowledging the importance of risk management and strengthening resilience against disasters. Based on the Sendai Framework, the Indonesian government produces a national plan for disaster risk management which highlights the needs for Indonesia to improve its preparedness and response to natural disasters. To execute the plan, Indonesia has established the national board for disaster management overseeing several regional boards for disaster management.  DRM activities span four phases: mitigation, preparedness, response, and recovery. Based on the Indonesian national plan, we focus our research on the preparedness phase (activities performed prior to disaster to allow more efficient response activities such as pre-positioning inventory of relief items) and the response phase (activities following a disaster to reduce its impact). The majority of research in DRM solves the preparedness and response phases of DRM separately, leading to suboptimal solutions. Furthermore, the solutions tend to be based on just one type of disaster. Another gap is that most research assumes that relief items are non-perishable, relief distribution is well coordinated, and demand and damages are known immediately after a disaster. Our focus on multi-disaster situations incorporating all of the complexities of multiple organisations providing relief support will result in more realistic models, filling the gaps in the literature in DRM and resulting in more impact. The research also extends previous Optimisation-via-Simulation methodology to multi-objective, multi-level problems.  In this project, we will work with West Java regional board from specifying the requirements for the decision support system to developing realistic scenarios to evaluate our methods. West Java province is chosen because it has the highest multi-disaster risk in Indonesia due to the population size, population density, high contribution to Indonesian GDP and being the centre of rice production in Java island (rice is the main staple food in Indonesia). As we will implement the national standard procedures for disaster preparedness and response, the decision support system can be customised by other regional boards to suit the characteristics of their regions by changing the parameters (for example, map, demography, infrastructure). Therefore, we will also organise a practitioner workshop to present our findings and to provide training for all regional boards to use the decision support system. The decision support system can also be used for training purposes which will strengthen the preparedness of the regional board officials.  Finally, this project will build capacity in this vital area of research. The research assistants in the UK and Indonesia will gain from regular project meetings, interactions with investigators and the scientific advisory board members, and relevant training in Southampton, Padjadjaran or other places in the UK and South East Asia. We will also organise a research workshop for Indonesian researchers who are interested in OvS, ABS and Operational Research in DRM</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of this project is to develop an optimisation-via-simulation (OvS) method to solve a multi-objective Integrated Stochastic Disaster Risk Management (ISDRM) problem. The method will find optimal warehouse locations and replenishment policies for the perishable relief items needed following a natural disaster subject to practical and operational constraints (e.g. use the existing infrastructure whenever possible) as well as an optimum routing for relief distribution when a disaster strikes. We will consider multi-disaster scenarios, practical constraints and multi-criteria objective functions that are relevant to West Java province, which has the highest multi-disaster risk in Indonesia. While we will work closely with the model users from three government units in West Java, research outcomes will be shared with model users from all provinces in Indonesia.   We divide this overall objective into five research objectives and two dissemination and capacity building objectives.  1. Gather and analyse data from model users. This includes data on multi-disaster risk, transportation (e.g. network, capacity and vehicles), inventory (e.g. existing warehouse locations, potential new locations, capacity, existing replenishment policy), and standard operating procedures for disaster preparedness and response. We will also set the key performance indicators (KPIs) with the model users.  2. Develop an Agent-Based Simulation (ABS) for relief distribution which includes route-optimisation for a given set of warehouses and replenishment policy. Most existing relief distribution models assume that the relief distribution operation is well-coordinated, and demand and damages are known immediately post-disaster. Our ABS model will model the interactions between organisations involved in relief distribution, and the information on demand and damages will made known in stages.   3. Develop an efficient OvS to find the optimal solution to the ISDRM problem. We describe the problem as a multi-level, multi-objective stochastic optimisation. This is the most ambitious part of the project because the focus in the OvS literature has traditionally been on single-level, single-objective problems. Here, we incorporate combinatorial optimisation with ranking and selection via simulation for multi-objective optimisation. We extend using an approach in which a multi-criteria optimisation problem is simplified by optimising only the most important KPI and introducing chance constraints on secondary KPIs that ensure they are above/below a threshold level. Our research will result in new mathematics applicable across a much wider range of problems.  4. We will work with model users to define scenarios for the OvS algorithm based on past disasters, likely future disasters and extreme cases. The results of the scenario analysis will be used to get buy in from the main policy maker in Indonesia (National Board for Disaster Management) so that our research outcomes can be disseminated to other regional boards to maximise the impact of our research.  5. Make the OvS algorithm and ABS accessible to model users and other potential users. The generic part of the algorithm and model will be distributed as Python libraries to the public. We will also implement a decision support system (DSS) that is tailored for the model users in West Java using these Python libraries.   6. Disseminate research findings and the DSS developed in WP5 to model users from West Java and potential users from other provinces in a national symposium which includes training to use the DSS. Indonesian government has set standard procedures for disaster preparedness and response. Hence, the DSS are applicable to all provinces.   7. Develop the capacity of the two research assistants (in the UK and Indonesia) and two named-researchers(Indonesia) in the application of OR in DRM. We will also deliver a workshop for researchers in Indonesia on OvS and ABS for DRM.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-08-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-08-29">305087.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Southampton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T00360X/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">37982.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00360X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">37982.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00360X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">37982.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00360X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">37982.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00360X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">38289.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T00360X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT00360X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
