<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P024270_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Tick Cell Biobank - a UK and international biological resource</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The main objectives of the proposed project &quot;The Tick Cell Biobank - a UK and international biological resource&quot;, in order of priority, are as follows: 1. To secure the future of the Tick Cell Biobank (TCB) by establishing it at the Institute of Infection and Global Health, University of Liverpool, thereby enabling it to continue to underpin UK tick and tick-borne disease research. The Tick Cell Biobank (TCB) is the world&apos;s only dedicated culture collection and repository for cell lines derived from ixodid and argasid ticks and other arthropods. As well as supplying tick cell lines (TCL), the TCB maintains and disseminates expertise in the generation and maintenance of cell lines from ticks and other arthropods that is of particular value in current and future research on a wide range of vector-borne diseases. It was originally established at the University of Edinburgh in 2009 , and moved to The Pirbright Institute (TPI) in 2012.  However, TPI is unable to fund the TCB after March 2017, so this project will provide a new home for the collection and associated research. A new home is essential to safeguard the long-term future of the TCB and preserve and pass on the expertise in arthropod cell culture to younger scientists to ensure that these resources will continue to be available to support ongoing and future research activities both in the UK and worldwide.  2. To expand the existing cell line collection through addition and generation of new cell lines from ticks and other arthropods. Arthropod cell lines are tools essential for studying many aspects of vector biology and vector-pathogen interaction; while they cannot totally replace the whole organism, they provide many research groups that lack arthropod rearing and handling facilities with the opportunity to examine pathogen replication and vector cell responses at the cellular and molecular level. Some tick species are well-represented in the TCB while others, such as European Dermacentor and Hyalomma spp., and vectors of emerging diseases such as Haemaphysalis, are lacking. Cell lines are currently available from several species of mosquito, while biting midges and sand flies are poorly represented. Moreover, there are no continuous cell lines from many known and putative arthropod vectors of veterinary and/or medical importance such as blackflies, trombiculid and gamasid mites, sea lice, head or body lice, fleas and large biting flies such as tsetse and stable flies. Cell lines are also lacking from pollinators and their parasites such as Varroa mites, and many agricultural pests such as aphids and locusts. Expertise used and disseminated by the TCB will facilitate generation of novel arthropod cell lines and expansion of their uptake and application by UK scientists.    3. To give added value to the TCB through cell line characterisation, cell cloning and genome sequencing. All existing TCL are phenotypically heterogeneous; most or all of the component cells in most TCL are of unknown tissue origin. Characterisation and cloning of different TCL will greatly increase their applicability and contribute to better understanding of tick-pathogen interactions, tick biology and mechanisms of action of acaricides and alternative tick control methods. Compared to whole ticks, TCL provide a plentiful, accessible and relatively homogeneous and microorganism-free source of material for genome sequencing. Selected TCL will be sequenced to complement and expand existing tick genome resources and to facilitate tick- and tick-borne disease-related &quot;-omics&quot; research.  4. To support the GCRF component &quot;GCRF-BBR: The Tick Cell Biobank: outposts in Asia, Africa and South America&quot;. This 3-year workpackage will complement the new TCB by expanding its reach and coverage into lower and middle-income countries where ticks and tick-borne diseases are important, and where TCL are under-utilised but have huge potential for contributing to in-country research and development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ticks are bloodfeeding arthropods which, as well as causing direct damage to their hosts, transmit many diseases of livestock, companion animals and humans. Research into prevention and cure of these diseases, caused by viruses, bacteria, protozoa and filarial worms, is greatly assisted by the use of cell culture systems to study both how tick cells function, and how and why they transmit disease-causing pathogens. Such culture systems, called cell lines, have been developed for many disease-carrying ticks, but they require special skills and much time and patience to establish and maintain. Seven years ago a central collection, the Tick Cell Biobank (TCB), was created for all the tick cell lines available now and in future. The TCB distributes tick cell lines (TCL) on request to research scientists all over the world and provides essential training in their maintenance. The TCB also carries out characterisation studies on TCL, as very little is known about most of them, and is creating new cell lines from species of ticks not already represented in the collection. This proposal requests funding to secure the long-term future of the TCB as an essential resource underpinning UK and international tick and tick-borne disease research, to expand the resource to include cell lines derived from other important arthropods such as biting midges, mites and honeybees, and to give added value to the cell lines through characterisation, cloning and genome sequencing, thereby ensuring that these unique and invaluable biological resources continue to be available to the scientists who need to use them in biomedical, veterinary and agricultural research.   Since the TCB was established in 2009, the crucial role played by TCL in research into ticks and the diseases they transmit has become increasingly clear. Indeed, interest in TCL and the methods used to generate them has spread to encompass pathogens transmitted by other arthropods such as mites, fleas and lice. With environmental and climate change driving the emergence of new vector-borne diseases, the demand for cell lines derived from ticks and other arthropods is likely to continue to increase in the future. This proposal includes generation of novel cell lines from ticks, mites and insects such as sand flies and midges both in-house and through dissemination of the required expertise to scientists in laboratories specialising in these arthropods.   Establishment of TCL takes many years and requires specialised expertise, much patience and, importantly, a stable background of laboratory support. The TCB has brought together almost all the TCL available worldwide into a single repository and point of contact for supply of TCL and training in their maintenance (essential for successful transfer of TCL to recipient laboratories). The TCB has been enormously successful over the past 7 years, generating 18 new TCL, supplying TCL to 71 recipient laboratories and training 80 young scientists representing 27 countries in Europe, Asia, Africa, North and South America. This proposal includes a workpackage specifically aimed at raising the profile of, and improving access to, TCL and training in lower and middle-income countries, by establishing outposts of the TCB in Malaysia, Kenya and Brazil. TCL from the TCB have already facilitated a wide range of studies, but much remains to be done. UK and global research has only scratched the surface of knowledge of these economically important and biologically fascinating parasites, their microbiota and the pathogens they transmit. Continued maintenance and expansion of the unique resource represented by the TCB, including genomic and molecular characterisation of TCL and generation of new arthropod cell lines, is essential to support this research now and for many years to come.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">118611.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">172921.81</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">178926.46</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">85327.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">40833.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">40834.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-28"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-28">840640.936</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF BBR Scheme Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P024270_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FP024270%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
