<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_N009320_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Belle Epoque  Cairo Museums Itinerary  (BECAMI)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The success of the conservation and rehabilitation process of Egyptian heritage requires a rethinking of how this cultural heritage is perceived by local communities and how it can play a role in sustainable human development through education and access to knowledge. During the difficult years following the uprising of the Arab spring in Egypt in 2011, intolerance and the exclusion of others, created a controversial discourse about Egyptian history and heritage and its diverse cultural identities. For more than a half of a century, a narrow vision of the Egyptian history, culture and heritage was promoted, denying particular aspects of its modern dimension and its belonging to the wider Mediterranean civilisations. The development of memory and emotional appropriation by the young generation of Egyptians and social empowerment through education and active public participation are key to mitigating the threats for a sustainable future of Egyptian heritage both tangible and intangible.   This network  focuses on re-establishing a balance in the current dominant discourse on Egyptian heritage by engaging the public with unknown museums echoing various aspects of a collective memory of the &quot;Belle &#xC9;poque&quot; era.  These museums will be used in this project as catalysts of a new type of engagement with the tangible and intangible heritage of the  liberal age, with its flourishing art, music, technological innovations, political issues and modern way of life and consumption. This project will engage university students and school children in the re-discovery and emotional appropriation of eleven Cairo museums,  all housed in buildings of high architectural and historical significance. They connect tangible and intangible cultural heritage such as: iconic Egyptian singers in the Arab world (such as Abdelwahab and Umm Kulthum); literature (such as Taha Hussein and Ahmed Shawki); transport and communication (such as Cairo railway and post); and political figures (such as Mohammed Ali and Saad Zaghloul).  The main objectives of the Belle &#xC9;poque Cairo Museums Itinerary (BECAMI)  network are as follows:  1. To establish a multidisciplinary collaborative project between UK and Egypt academics to increase the visibility and accessibility of eleven forgotten &apos;Belle Epoque&apos; museums by the creation of both physical and virtual itineraries, hence bringing them into a cluster. 2. To engage, physically and virtually, local communities and tourists with these museums through the development of an itinerary, sign posts, art installations and an interactive website  3. Engage university students and school children in the creation of a walking  itinerary of 3,6 km and a narrative connecting seven of these eleven museums hence allowing a greater visibility and an increased number of visitors from a variety of backgrounds.   4. To establish twinning Cairo museums with two UK  museums through a interactive website platform.  The Oum Kaltoum and Abdelwaham museums will be twinned with the Liverpool Beatles Museum and the Cairo Railway Museum with the National Railway museum in York in the UK. The virtual twinning will allow sharing good practice in education and community engagement as well as cultural exchanges.   5. To co-produce art installations and publicity material for each of these museums by engaging school children and university students through workshops, hence facilitating emotional ownership for these museums.  6. To promote communication and exchanges between the cluster of eleven Cairo museums by linking them via a virtual itinerary platform through which they can sustain collaboration in educational and community engagement   projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will engage university students and school children in the re-discovery and emotional appropriation of eleven forgotten and unknown Cairo museums established in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, an era known as the &quot;Belle Epoque&quot;. These museums have the potential to reconnect the young generation of Egyptians with an important historical era during which Egypt was leading a renaissance in the Arab world. They represent three types of Egyptian cultural heritage: their tangible architectural heritage of high historical significance;  their tangible exhibited content; and their intangible heritage linked to socio-economic, cultural and political conditions of the Arab renaissance era. They also represent an important part of the memory of the Egyptian nation as depositories of the history of iconic figures in politics, music and literature that have shaped the whole of the Arab world. Despite their cultural and historical importance in Egypt, and the Arab world, these museums remain unknown to the vast majority of the Egyptians, particularly the younger generation. Furthermore, their location in down town Cairo and within walking distance from three metro stations  means that they are highly accessible but not necessarily visible. The main objectives of the Belle &#xC9;poque Cairo Museums Itinerary (BECAMI ) are as follows: 1. To establish a multidisciplinary collaborative project between UK and Egypt  academics to increase the visibility and accessibility of these eleven forgotten &apos;Belle Epoque&apos; museums by the creation of both physical and virtual   itineraries, hence bringing them into a cluster. 2. To  engage, physically and virtually, local communities and tourists with these museums.  3. To engage university students and school children in the creation of a walking  itinerary of 3,6 km and a narrative connecting  seven of these eleven museums, hence allowing a greater visibility and an increased number of visitors from a variety of backgrounds.   4. To co-produce art installations and publicity material for each of these museums by engaging school children and university students through workshops hence facilitating  emotional ownership for these museums.  5. To promote communication and exchanges between the cluster of eleven Cairo museums by linking them via a virtual itinerary platform through which they can sustain collaboration in educational and community engagement projects.  6. To create  twinning of some of these museums with UK museums of similar themes. As such the Umm Kaltoum and Mohamed  Abdelwahab museums will be twinned with the Liverpool Beatles museum, and the Cairo Railway museum will be twinned with the National Railway museum in York. These virtual twinnings will allow the sharing good practices in education and community engagement and increase their international visibility.  7. To engage school children and multidisciplinary teams of university students in a competition to design physical sign-posts for the museums itinerary and the production of a connecting narrative that will weave the tangible and intangible components of these museums.   The project will be facilitated through three workshops (two in Cairo and one in Sheffield) bringing together a multidisciplinary team of architects, human geographers , artists . The project is led by two principal investigators : Dr Magda Sibley, Senior Lecturer and Director of Humanities at the School of Architecture at Sheffield University and Professor Galila Elkadi, Head of Architecture at the French University in Cairo.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-12" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Egypt</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="189" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-26">31723.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/N009320/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FN009320%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-02-12"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
