<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V028480_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF_NF106 Entrepreneurial resilience &amp; recovery during and after covid-19 crisis: firm- &amp; community-level responses in Wuhan, Malaysia, and Thailand</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Moscarini and Postel-Viney (American Economic Review, 2012) showed that entrepreneurs are central for economic resilience during an economic crisis and for kickstarting recovery as the crisis attenuates. However, we know little about how this potential can be best harnessed during a covid-19 -style economic emergency, which not only causes a sharp demand shock, but also, requires businesses to radically reconfigure their operations to comply with social distancing. This knowledge gap is particularly acute for low- and middle-income economies, as most studies of entrepreneurial resilience have been conducted in high-income countries.  In harnessing entrepreneurs for economic resilience and recovery during a crisis, governments have to deter a &apos;race to the bottom&apos; response and encourage a &apos;community pulling together&apos; response. The first is a &apos;dog-eat-dog&apos; race to secure as many of the dwindling resources for oneself as possible. In the second, the community pulls together to buffer its members against the shock. We currently know little about how to promote sustainable responses and discourage unsustainable ones.  We address the above knowledge gaps. Collaborating with Wuhan University, UN Economic and Social Commission for Asia (Bangkok), Asia School of Business (Kuala Lumpur) and Asian Development Bank (Manila) we study entrepreneurial firm- and community-level responses and business model practices for resilient adjustment to covid- 19 crisis and for robust post-crisis recovery. We will conduct 20-25 longitudinal case studies to induct firm- and community -level process models of entrepreneurial resilience and recovery to inform policy and entrepreneurial practice in lower and upper middle income economies in Asia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The unique challenges of the global economic and social crisis triggered by covid-19 highlight four major knowledge gaps concerning entrepreneurial resilience and recovery in lower and upper middle income economies: (1) most resilience studies have been conducted in high-income economies; (2) most studies have focused on firm-level responses, ignoring community-level ones; (3) previous studies have treated crises as low-probability &apos;one-off&apos; events of limited duration; (4) previous studies have focused on financial and demand shocks and overlooked situations that require a more wholesale re-configuration of business operations. The overarching objective of our is to address these gaps and produce practice-relevant insight for entrepreneurs and policymakers in lower and upper middle income economies, particularly in Asia.  Drawing on longitudinal case studies of entrepreneurial businesses in Wuhan (China), Malaysia, Philippines and Thailand and using London as a comparison point, our objective is to create the following deliverables:  1 Process model of entrepreneurial resilience and recovery strategies in the face of covid-19 crisis in low- and middle-income countries (firm level)  a. Elaboration of insights relevant for female entrepreneurs  b. Elaboration of insights relevant to product-, service- and platform    businesses 2 Process model of entrepreneurial resilience and recovery strategies in the face of covid-19 crisis in low- and middle-income countries (entrepreneurial community level)  a. Elaboration of insights relevant for female entrepreneurs  b. Elaboration of insights relevant to product-, service- and platform businesses 3 Framework of factors increasing the likelihood of &apos;race-to-the-bottom&apos; versus  &apos;community-pull-together&apos; responses 4 Identification of effective business model adjustments to improve resilience (with specific focus on digitally enhanced adjustments and product-market adjustments) 5 Elaboration of policy insights to facilitate resilient firm- and community  (entrepreneurial ecosystem) -level responses and recovery strategies</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-04465125" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-09">152201.94</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-09">153023.82</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-09"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-09">305225.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to Imperial College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/V028480/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">50733.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V028480_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">50733.98</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_V028480_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FV028480%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-08-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
