<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P005179_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building Futures: Aspirations of Syrian Youth Refugees and Host Population Responses in Lebanon, Greece &amp; the UK</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching aim of this research is to generate and analyse original, rich and pertinent empirical data on the experiences, skills, needs and aspirations of young Syrian refugees through a face-to-face survey, and on the corresponding attitudes and belief structures of host populations through public opinion surveys in three receiving states: Lebanon, Greece and the UK. We will analyse this data to derive a list of training and skills needs which answer to individual refugees&apos; own aspirations for their future social and economic roles, whether that is for reintegration in Syria or integration in their host nations. We will also apply the tools of philosophical analysis to understand and compare the ethical frameworks underlying both migrants&apos; and host populations&apos; thinking about their needs, rights and duties. From these, we will formulate impactful recommendations that balance protection and assistance to refugees with the claims and needs of (often deprived) host populations. By answering to the reasons implicit in concerned parties&apos; ethical perspectives, we will show how these policy recommendations can be communicated and provide the basis of an overlapping consensus in a context of strained resources and increased inter- and intra-national tension. To meet this ambitious interdisciplinary aim the project has the following specific research objectives:  1. To analyse the lived experiences, skills, training needs and aspirations of forcibly displaced young Syrians in a comparative context and explore the extent to which their reception in host communities equips them with the knowledge and confidence to begin to plan for their imagined futures; 2. To understand the ways in which young refugees develop &apos;modern&apos; navigation skills, or conversely what prevents them from developing new life management skills, in order to help them to integrate economically in host communities or prepare for reintegration in Syria; 3. To explore the implicit structures of ethical thinking underlying young Syrians&apos; self-understandings of their current predicament, how they impact upon their longer term intentions regarding repatriation or settlement in their host countries, and how they compare to the way that members of the host population think about the rights and wrongs of migration policy; 4. To analyse the drivers of public attitudes of the host populations towards young Syrian refugees and the extent to which these are shaped by materialist considerations such as the social and economic context of the receiving state or socially constructed frames that draw attention to a subset of political and normative considerations; 5. To increase critical thinking and public awareness on the refugee crisis and strengthen collective consciousness by identifying and emphasising needs and ethical frameworks that are shared between refugees and members of the host populations; and 6. To synthesise theoretical insights from migration studies, education, philosophy, political behaviour and sociology, so as to develop a new interdisciplinary framework to study refugees&apos; opportunities for skill development, integration and/or repatriation, which are attuned to the existing opportunity structures in their home and host countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is an innovative interdisciplinary study of the experiences, skills and aspirations of young Syrian refugees, who have been forcibly displaced by the conflict in their home country, and the corresponding attitudes and belief structures of the host population in three receiving states: Lebanon, Greece and the United Kingdom. We will conduct surveys with these young refugees, exploring their aspirations and giving centre stage to their own perspectives on their needs. We will also survey members of the host populations, some of whom may be analogously disadvantaged, to identify their attitudes to refugee&apos;s training needs. We will then compare the responses of both groups to reveal contrasts and points of convergence in the underlying ethical frameworks that shape their understanding of the needs, rights and duties involved in this complex situation.  This research will advance our theoretical understanding, and promote important social and political ends, in a number of ways. First, our data on their aspirations will allow us to formulate policy recommendations to meet the training and skills needs of young refugees, with a view to facilitating either reintegration in Syria or integration in their host nations. Second, our comparative approach will give guidance on how such policy should be framed and advocated in a context of strained public resources and anti-immigration sentiment. By focussing on shared ethical commitments, we will offer ways to develop training and skills policy which builds consensus and cross-community understanding.  We will disseminate this research by producing five academic articles in journals across a number of relevant fields. We will also engage in an ambitious programme of knowledge exchange and public engagement, through concise publications aimed at policymakers and general audiences in all three countries, and through a series of six public events. We will make our data available for sharing through the UK Data Archive at the end of the project, following an embargo period that will allow for publication of key outputs.   By drawing on our research expertise in the social sciences and the arts, we seek to influence both the content of training and skills policy, and also the public discourse surrounding such policy. By focussing on the ethical perspectives of both migrant and host populations, we will promote social cohesion and welfare for both groups: the former can have their training and skills needs met in a more supportive social context, and the latter can be reassured that the principles governing the distribution of scarce resources are ones which resonate with reasons they also share.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LB" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lebanon</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="MIDDLE EAST, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">83907.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-24">126132.01</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">18040.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P005179_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">59994.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P005179_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">59994.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P005179_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">59994.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P005179_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">60380.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P005179_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">55686.86</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P005179_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Glasgow</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
