<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R000123_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing Challenges of Coastal Communities through Ocean Research for Developing Economies (ACCORD).</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Addressing Challenges of Coastal Communities through Ocean Research for Developing Economies (ACCORD). The coastal and marine environments of South East Asia and the Western Indian Ocean (the regional foci of ACCORD) are rich and diverse, possessing high levels of biodiversity and productivity. These regions also have hydrate-bearing seafloor sediments and seafloor mineral resources. Coastal ecosystems and the services they provide are under threat from growth in human activities, including the demands of increasing population size (globally, 2 billion people live within 100km of the coast) and global markets, the desire for economic growth, and the less direct impact of global climate change. This affects both the resilience of living resources to pressures and the ecosystem services we derive from them. Many coastal communities depend on nearby coastal and marine resources for their livelihoods and welfare yet lack alternatives when these services deteriorate due to over-exploitation or adverse effects of climate change. A the same time coastal developing nations are looking to the ocean to provide opportunities for sustainable economic growth through resource exploitation (e.g. mineral extraction) and livelihood diversification (e.g. tourism, aquaculture, and blue carbon initiatives) and to support food security (e.g. fisheries and aquaculture).  For developing coastal nations the ocean is also an opportunity for diversification of their economies through the production of clean, renewable and unconventional energy and resource exploitation, yet these opportunities need to be balanced carefully against the need to protect habitats and preserve the total value of national resources. The concept of Blue Economy integrates ocean-based economic activities with conservation and sustainable use through effective marine planning.  We identify two overarching development challenges: a) Sustainable growth of, and resilience to change for, the blue economies of partner countries and b) Resilience to natural hazards including impact-based, climate-proof coastal flood warning systems.  Our aim is to deliver high quality science outcomes required to improve the environmental information available to support these challenges in coastal states on the Development Assistance Committee (DAC) list of Official Development Aid (ODA) recipients. Identifying and protecting critical habitats from overexploitation, and degradation is the cornerstone of the integrated ocean management required for sustainable blue economies. ACCORD will achieve this firstly by understanding the mechanisms and processes that determine the potential sensitivity or resilience of marine ecosystems to both globally and locally induced environmental change. Secondly, we will use this understanding to determine the environmental and societal consequences of ecosystem change to inform risk assessment, adaptive spatial management and mitigation strategies. Our approach will provide partner countries with an improved capability for integrated and sustainable management of marine activities. This capability will help partner countries to build a resilient marine and coastal socio-ecological system, and support their growing Blue Economies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objective 1: to promote the welfare and economic development of DAC list countries in SE Asia and the Western Indian Ocean; Objective 2: to develop techniques by which the multiple impacts of climate change on the health, function and value of key Blue Carbon habitats can be quantified and managed alongside local sourced anthropogenic stressors; Objective 3: to develop and provide novel tools and approaches that improve the ability to quantify and predict the impacts of environmental stress (natural and man-made) on ecosystem function, identifying asset vulnerability and resilience; Objective 4: to provide a consistent national and regional framework for holistic analysis of coastal flood hazard and understanding future flood risk in the study regions; Objective 5: Understand and quantify the impact of climate change and local stress on the viability and value of commercial shellfish and fin fish resources; Objective 6:  Increase the efficiency and cost-effectiveness of seabed mapping to quantify the potential for exploitation of both living and non-living seafloor resources and identify the processes that underlie the maintenance and sensitivity of those resources; Objective 7: to understand the contrast between direct anthropogenic and climatic pressures across the two study regions and identify where adaptive management of local activities and impacts can ameliorate the impacts of climate change on key ecosystem services and maximise sustainable use of marine resources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">NOC (Up to 31.10.2019)</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-07" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-08">741750</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-08">1217000</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-08">1445000.26</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-08">3651000.26</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed (Research Programmes) Award to NOC (Up to 31.10.2019)</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R000123_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NOC (Up to 31.10.2019)</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FR000123%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-04-03"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
