<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S009000_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF Urban Disaster Risk Hub</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overarching Aim: To reduce disaster risk for the poor in tomorrow&apos;s cities, by making urban development in low and middle-income countries resilient to multiple disasters.  The Hub will co-produce new understanding of the multi-hazard context in four target cities around specific, ongoing policy development and implementation programmes, catalysing a transition from crisis management to risk-informed planning in these cities, and globally through collaborating International governance organisations.  The Hub will strengthen national, city and community capacity to implement and track the SDGs by building resilience of the poor (1.5) including strengthening gender equality (5C), to reduce human and economic losses in cities (11.5), through disaster management (11.B and 13.1) and climate change adaptation plans (13.2) with strengthened communication and capacity building for climate change adaptation integrated into broader development activities (13.3). Objectives: 1. Carry out forensic examinations of urban risk, exposing physical and social root causes and drivers of historical multi-hazard crises, understanding the decision-making context and identifying opportunities for more inclusive processes, including those enabling gender equity. 2. Set up Partnerships, including researchers and stakeholders, with a City Hub Office, in each target city. 3. Refocus physical science from concentrating on process to quantifying controls on human disaster risk reduction in a multi-hazard environment.   4. Quantify and model physical and social vulnerability and exposure at unprecedented resolution. 5. Integrate high-resolution layers of multi-hazard disaster risk into the Global Risk Model by developing new techniques for nested risk modelling within the main UN platform for global risk analysis. 6. Co-develop decision support tools to bridge the gap between currently existing large-scale analyses and the scale of city management intervention. 7. Combine the new multi-hazard risk models with detailed analysis of social and physical vulnerability and decision-making contexts into a framework for action-oriented community and city disaster risk planning. 8. Use multi-hazard scenarios in this new framework to examine future development choices and stimulate engagement and innovation to generate and enact risk-reducing options.  10. Build capacity for integrated planning through mentoring of junior professionals, exchanges between practice and academic partners and the training of PhD students funded by partners. Outputs and Outcomes (for high level city and international outcomes see Theory of Change), technical outputs are: 1. High-resolution validated models of multi-hazard risk in its societal context at the correct precision and scale to reflect individual experience and inform urban development planning. 2. Precise descriptions of exemplar multi-hazard risk contexts leading to recommendations for risk and development planning policy to mitigate risk accumulation in future development. 3. Tools and methods for citizen-led and city-level monitoring, evaluation and audit of disaster risk and futures planning, aligning city risk assessments with the Sendai Framework and targeted SDG indicators, facilitating city leadership in - and direct engagement with - the global policy agenda. 4. City Partnerships to facilitate new governance relationships between city authorities and relevant sectors to deploy Hub methods and tools and to champion city leadership in knowledge exchange. 5. A national and international legacy of active research and policy groups with strong inter-connections and links to UK science and international governance organisations to amplify the urban voice in future international risk governance. 6. Legacy vehicles: risk assessment and action planning tools owned by city and international partners to fill strategic technical gaps that will be modified and deployed during and after the Hub.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Hub will reduce disaster risk for the poor in tomorrow&apos;s cities. The failure to integrate disaster risk resilience into urban planning and decision-making is a persistent intractable challenge that condemns hundreds of millions of the World&apos;s poor to continued cyclical destruction of their lives and livelihoods. It presents a major barrier to the delivery of the Sustainable Development Goals in expanding urban systems. Science and technology can help, but only against complex multi-hazard context of urban life and the social and cultural background to decision-making in developing countries. Science-informed urbanisation, co-produced and properly integrated with decision support for city authorities, offers the possibility of risk-sensitive development for millions of the global poor. This is a major opportunity - some 60% of the area expected to be urban by 2030 is yet to be built. Our aim is to catalyse a transition from crisis management to risk-informed planning in four partner cities and globally through collaborating International governance organisations.  The Hub, co-designed with local and international stakeholders from the start, will deliver this agenda through integrated research across four urban systems - Istanbul, Kathmandu, Nairobi and Quito - chosen for their multi-hazard exposure, and variety of urban form, development status and governance. Trusted core partnerships from previous Global Challenge Research Fund, Newton Fund and UK Research Council projects provide solid foundations on which city based research projects have been built around identified, existing, policy interventions to provide research solutions to specific current development problems. We have developed innovative, strategic research and impact funds and capable management processes constantly to monitor progress and to reinforce successful research directions and impact pathways. In each urban system, the Hub will reduce risk for 1-4 million people by (1) Co-producing forensic examinations of risk root causes, drivers of vulnerability and trend analysis of decision-making culture for key, historic multi-hazard events. (2) Combining quantitative, multi-hazard intensity, exposure and vulnerability analysis using advances in earth observation, citizen science, low cost sensors and high-resolution surveys with institutional and power analysis to allow multi-hazard risk assessment to interface with urban planning culture and engineering. (3) Convene diverse stakeholder groups-communities, schools, municipalities private enterprise, national agencies- around new understanding of multi-hazard urban disaster risk stimulating engagement and innovation in making risk-sensitive development choices to help meet the SDGs and Sendai Framework.  Impact will occur both within and beyond the life of the Hub and will raise the visibility of cities in global risk analysis and policy making. City Partnerships, integrating city authorities, researchers, community leaders and the private sector, will develop and own initiatives including high-resolution validated models of multi-hazard risk to reflect individual experience and inform urban development planning, tools and methods for monitoring, evaluation and audit of disaster risk, and recommendations for planning policy to mitigate risks in future development. City partnerships will collaborate with national and regional city networks, policy champions and UN agencies using research outputs to structure city and community plans responding to the Sendai Framework and targeted SDG indicators, and build methods and capacity for reporting and wider critique of the SDG and Sendai reporting process. Legacy will be enabled through the ownership of risk assessment and resilience building tools by city and international partners who will identify need, own, modify and deploy tools beyond the life of the Hub.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-05-12" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">434567.21</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">3483577.74</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">2635620.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">2656968.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">1788064.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">3118182.75</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-02-08"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-02-08">17657278.776</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_S009000_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Edinburgh</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FS009000%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-13"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
