<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P027989_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Global Network for Neglected Tropical Diseases</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is estimated that ~1 in 6 of the world&apos;s population suffer from a Neglected Tropical Disease (NTD) representing a significant challenge to global human health and well-being and this has been recognised by the United Nations (UN).  One of the primary aims of the UN&apos;s Sustainable Development Goal on &quot;Health and Well-Being&quot; is to &quot;ensure health and well-being for all&quot; and with 1.7 billion people in 185 countries requiring treatment for at least one NTD in 2014, advances in the development of new medicines for NTDs is critical. Indeed, the target set by the UN is &quot;By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases.&quot; Supporting the delivery of this goal are many world-wide ventures directed towards the treatment of AIDs (e.g. The Global Fund), tuberculosis (e.g. The Global Fund) and malaria (e.g. Medicines for Malaria Venture) but there is currently no corresponding world-wide sustained effort for NTDs. It is this gap that our global NTD network will fill and, in doing so, will contribute to the delivery of the UN&apos;s goal on &quot;Health and Well-Being&quot;. Within the spectrum of NTD pathogens, insect-borne parasites represent a major threat to human health across the developing world. In particular, leishmaniasis and Chagas disease represent a significant challenge for developing nations with lower levels of research investment and infrastructure exacerbated by a lack of suitably trained personnel capable of developing much needed solutions. With over 350 million people world-wide considered at risk, more than 1.7M new cases each year, 12 million people currently infected and an economic cost that can be estimated in terms of 2.4 million Disability Adjusted Life Years (DALYs), the health challenge of leishmaniasis is undeniable. A similar situation exists for Chagas disease where there are currently 10M people infected and, in Latin America alone, Chagas disease leads to approx.700,000 (DALYs), nearly six times the socioeconomic toll of malaria in the region. Globally, the total annual economic effect of Chagas disease is estimated at over $7 billion. The challenge presented by these disease states is heightened by the fact that the few efficacious drugs currently available often exhibit serious, potentially fatal, side-effects, and have difficult and prolonged modes of administration leading to poor patient compliance within developing nations. Moreover, reports of resistance to even the most modern drugs are beginning to emerge.  We will establish a &quot;Global Network For Neglected Tropical Diseases&quot; which will bring together over 50 academics and more that 500 researchers at 14 institutes around the world all working towards the common goals of delivering scientific advances that will help to combat Leishmaniasis and Chagas disease</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We will establish an interdisciplinary global network of researchers working collaboratively to develop new knowledge, capacity and capabilities, both within DCs and the UK, to ultimately deliver new therapies for Neglected Tropical Diseases. The Network has four key broad objectives all of which are of equal importance to deliver the aim of enhancing capacity and capability in NTD interdisciplinary collaborative research both within the UK and in ODA countries. O1) Expand the global effort for NTD research of pivotal importance to world health, prosperity and equality and increase the capacity in interdisciplinary NTD research well beyond the 500 partner researchers currently directly linked to the Network enhancing UK/ODA collaborative ties.  O2) Deliver a new generation of highly skilled interdisciplinary researchers world-wide by providing a focused, interdisciplinary, state-of-the-art training programme in NTD research and a wide range of collaborative opportunities across the science base to both ECRs and established workers from S. America, S. Asia and the UK.   O3) Deliver world leading research that has a positive impact on the fundamental global challenges presented by leishmaniasis and Chagas Disease that benefits the economy, health and well-being of populations in S. America and S. Asia. Target validation, assays for compound screening, new leads and delivery methods for the next generation of NTD therapeutics will be enabled by the multi-disciplinary skill base of the Network. O4) Enrich the academic community and prospects of a new generation of ECRs through their participation in an exceptional, interdisciplinary, global research programme by ensuring that UK and Network funded research students fully participate in all multidisciplinary exchange, training and research opportunities available throughout the network.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">716350</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">3354828</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">3416538</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">2927206</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">2133965.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-20"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-20">6764938.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF RCUK Award to Durham University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P027989_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP027989%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
