<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_T004959_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gender and Intersectionality on India and its Diaspora&apos;s (GRID) Heritage</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our aims and objectives are to: - forge a GRID Heritage network that focuses on ensuring that gender and intersectionality are central to issues pertaining to India and its Diaspora&apos;s heritage - provide a connected  forum in the UK and India to consolidate and amplify such efforts, and drive new perspectives that can regularise gender and intersectional discussion - focus on how changing contexts to  do with internal and external migration have led to changing understandings of and practices in heritage  - bring to the fore &apos;hidden heritage&apos; that might otherwise not be valued as it has been associated with marginalised people. In this way, the network will not only have artistic and scholarly value, but can also help to improve lives, build capabilities, foster resilient systems and contribute to the individual&apos;s social and economic advancement. - organise exhibitions and performances of the works so as other scholars, practitioners, specialists and members of the general public can directly engage with the heritage work  - develop an online exhibition and curated archive of the objects and practices for long-term legacy - work with findings, outcomes and evaluation of network activities to develop a GRID Heritage roadmap including an executive summary to send to stakeholders, consolidate further partnerships and, after the network programme, develop a larger UK-India research application</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Valuing and conserving our diverse heritage is an important endeavour for our presents and our futures. Recognising how certain aspects of heritage are prized over others, and how such imbalances can be mitigated are equally significant. In an adaptation of George Orwell&apos;s famous lines from his book, 1984, those who control the past control the future, and those who control the present control the past. Experiences and practices of discrimination and inequity in the current era has repercussions for whose, and which kind of heritage continues for future generations.  Our vision is to develop and consolidate a UK-India network that highlights and deepens a framework of analysis that is conscious of social and institutional discrimination when it comes to valuing heritage. Our framework is informed by gender and intersectionality on Indian and Diasporic (GRID) heritage  so as those people and practices discriminated along the intersecting lines of gender, caste, class and/or ethnicity along with their heritage work are fully appreciated, engaged and supported at the national and transnational level.   We  plan to consolidate the GRID Heritage network through the organising of two workshops, linked exhibitions and musical performances in New Delhi and London, a project  website with an online exhibition of case studies and digitised archive along with other more long-term strategies. The network will include academics, researchers, curators, heritage practitioners, managers and other specialists in three main areas:  (i) Craft: paintings, illustrations  and three dimensional objects (co-ordinated by Parul Dave-Mukherji, Principal Investigator, India), (ii) Threads: embroidery and textiles (co-ordinated by Raminder Kaur, Principal Investigator, UK),   (iii) Echoes: music and performance (co-ordinated by Navtej Purewal, Co-Investigator, UK).  Each of these components will be developed by network participants, and supported by free public events in New Delhi and London  to which the general public including local Asian, heritage, arts and youth groups will be invited.   We encourage network participants to apply a gender and intersectionality lens to heritage issues and cases by asking the following questions:  - How do we develop a context-specific understanding of gender and intersectionality as they apply to Indian and Diasporic heritage? In what ways have practitioners felt discrimination with respect to their identity and heritage? What are the implications of this for the individual and the community/ies with which they self-identify in changing contexts?  - To what extent is the value assigned to forms of heritage used to include some groups and the devaluation of other forms of heritage used to exclude others? How are categories such as &apos;art&apos; and &apos;craft&apos;, &apos;artisan&apos; and &apos;artist&apos; applied for work that draws upon an individual&apos;s heritage? - How do we make sense of heritage objects and practice located across diverse caste-class, religio-ethnic and regional contexts? How does this influence an understanding of their various homes, whether they be in India or in UK? - How can we use gender and intersectionality lenses to empower individuals and communities to build upon their heritage? - How can we place what might be off-the-grid or hidden heritage associated with marginalised people on a platform where they can be valued now and in the future?  The network activities will lead to a project website with digitised case studies, visual and audio-visual recordings of public events, open access working papers, reports, a GRID Heritage roadmap including an executive summary to send to stakeholders, teaching material for undergraduate and postgraduate courses, interim and final network reports including a comprehensive evaluation report for participants&apos; and partners&apos; own networks. This final report will later inform the development of a firmer focus, aims, objectives and partners for further international research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-30" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-30">11947.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-30">23894.31</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
