<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_V008684_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using the arts to mitigate the impact of Covid-19 among India&apos;s indigenous and nomadic communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed research aims to document, create awareness, and ease the short and long-term impact of Covid-19 among India&apos;s most precarious indigenous nomadic communities through multiple arts activities; and by researching and communicating community appropriate responses to the pandemic. To do so, it brings together researchers, development practitioners, policy makers, artists and activists. The project builds on a pilot GCRF grant at the University of Leicester, which is successfully trialling a community arts podcast to document and spread information about Covid-19 in indigenous languages and art forms.   India counts one of the largest indigenous populations in the world also known as adivasis, a term of self-reference that literally means original inhabitant. More than 80 million people are officially classified as Scheduled Tribes (STs) and around 110 million people as DeNotified Tribes (DNTs) - communities that were &apos;notified&apos; as born criminals during British colonial rule under the 1871 Criminal Tribes Act. India&apos;s ST and DNT groups are among the most precarious populations in the subcontinent working as manual labourers, agricultural and construction workers, performers, sex workers and street entertainers at the margins of India&apos;s informal economy. Their economic poverty is further compounded by the stigma associated with their identity.  For DNT groups in particular, the brand of criminality continues to drive their interaction with the state and negatively affects their ability to access basic state provisions from schools to, to food and health services (Renke et al. 2008; Devy 2006).   The project has been co-designed in partnership with Bhasha Research and Publication Centre, Budhan Theatre and the Adivasi Museum of Voice - a research NGO, a grassroots theatre group and a community museum with a track record of working for the rights of India&apos;s indigenous and nomadic groups by linking art and rights-based campaigns. A team of twelve indigenous artists, curators and researchers will undertake an extensive project of documentation of the specific lockdown and post-lockdown experiences of DNT and ST communities in the western India region (also the worst affected by the pandemic), through mobile digital technology; and produce a series of community arts podcasts in local indigenous languages aimed at addressing the health, socio-cultural and politico-economic dimensions of the pandemic. Podcasts will be disseminated through community social media networks and through an exhibition at the Adivasi Museum of Voice. They will also be accessible with English subtitles for international audiences through a dedicated project website.   The project will develop transferrable methodologies for socially engaged arts practices in the context of the pandemic. This includes translating theatre forms through socially distant and virtual platforms; and further reconceptualising the role of community museums as key agents that can assist societies in times of crisis. The research undertaken as part of the project will also inform a policy intervention and report in collaboration with development consultant Dr. Khanna aimed at strengthening indigenous rights and social accountability mechanisms, and at devising public health interventions based on communities&apos; needs. The policy intervention will focus on the relationship between precarious citizenship, mobility and rights, challenging the sedentarist bias in approaches to welfare and human rights. This is especially crucial in the context of the two intersecting urgencies posed by Covid-19 and India&apos;s new citizenship bill, which threatens to make many indigenous groups (especially mobile STs and DNTs) stateless. As Covid-19 exposes and deepens existing inequalities, this project will contribute to alleviating the effects of the pandemic on highly vulnerable populations by employing the arts and culture as mechanisms for community building and resilience.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-09-28"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-27" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-04">77290.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-04">33124.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The proposed research aims to understand and mitigate the effects of the Covid-19 pandemic on India&apos;s indigenous and nomadic groups (especially mobile Scheduled Tribes and DeNotified Tribal groups) by employing the arts and culture as mechanisms for community building and resilience. The research has been co-designed with Bhasha Research and Publication Centre (BRPC), the Adivasi Museum of Voice and Budhan Theatre - a research NGO, a community museum and a grassroots theatre group with a track record of working for the rights of India&apos;s indigenous groups by linking art and rights-based campaigns; and with Dr. Khanna, a lawyer, medical anthropologist and development consultant who has worked extensively on the HIV/AIDS epidemic India and on the rights of DNT transgender groups. The project will employ arts and humanities methodologies, in particular film, theatre and the work of a community museum to:   1) Document and understand - The specific vulnerabilities of India&apos;s indigenous and nomadic groups relating to Covid-19. This includes understanding the incidence of pre-existing conditions; the impossibility of social distancing and hygiene measures in overcrowded areas with poor sanitation facilities, and alternative protection measures; livelihoods linked to migration. - Community responses to the pandemic. This includes understanding specific belief systems and the role of traditional healers in community responses. - The specific vulnerabilities of mobile indigenous and nomadic groups in relation to lockdown and post-lockdown measures. This includes understanding the immediate economic impact of lockdown for highly precarious and mobile workers; the long-term impact of lockdown following the introduction of new deregulated labour laws and the crackdown on certain occupations (including sex work, street vendors and performers).   2) Spread information about Covid-19 among India&apos;s indigenous and nomadic communities, with a focus on health measures, rights and social accountability mechanisms. To do so, artists belonging to Budhan theatre will produce a series of community arts podcasts drawing on the documentation mentioned above as well as on interviews with experts; and train other groups to do the same (specifically indigenous curators associated with the Museum of Voice). The podcasts will deliver factual information and employ traditional forms of expressions including lyrics and song composition, solo theatre performances, poetry and storytelling to spread information. The pieces will be disseminated in local languages on community social media platforms (especially WhatsApp), in a project exhibition at the Museum of Voice, and feature on a project website with English subtitles for international audiences.    3) Strengthen indigenous rights in the context of the pandemic and beyond, especially in relation to the issue of precarious citizenship; and review the link between mobility, citizenship and human rights through a policy paper and intervention delivered by Dr. Khanna. The policy document will be disseminated to and inform discussions with the Indian Human Rights Commission, the National Commission for DNTs, the Gujarat state, and the police (in particular the Sauraksha Setu project for community policing). It will both contribute to scholarship debates; and to the framing of new flexible public health interventions that account for the needs of groups who rely on highly precarious and mobile livelihoods.   4) Develop replicable methodologies for socially engaged arts practices in the context of the pandemic by translating theatre forms through socially distant and virtual platforms; and further reconceptualising the role of community museums as key agents that can assist societies in times of crisis.   5) Produce a feature length documentary film directed documenting the effects of the pandemic on India&apos;s indigenous and nomadic groups and reflecting on the research intervention itself."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
