<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S00341X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Located Making: Unlocking the Potential of Cultural Heritage by Design</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AIM: To develop a practical framework for unlocking the potential of cultural heritage by design. The framework, for use by policymakers, heritage sector organizations and academics, will include a robust methodology suited to the Chinese context, a step-by-step pathway for identifying principal goals and developing feasible strategies, as well as real world examples and insights. Application of the framework will enable cultural heritage-based making practices in China to benefit economically and socio-culturally from design expertise.  RESEARCH QUESTION: How can design expertise increase the visibility and perceived value of heritage-based making practices in China in ways that accord with sustainability, decent jobs, economic growth and community?  OBJECTIVES: OB1: Undertake a series of place-based case studies of cultural heritage making practices in China to assess historical, contextual and stakeholder priorities. OB2: Co-create strategies that will increase the visibility and perceived value of heritage-based making practices in ways that stimulate the economy while valuing people, place and community. OB3: Synthesize research insights into generalizable forms that can be adapted to a variety of contexts and elicit feedback to maximize adoption, implementation and impact. OB4: Develop a practical framework for the Chinese context that includes a step-by-step pathway for identifying development opportunities for heritage-based making practices, principal goals and effective strategies for their achievement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is increasing recognition today, through initiatives such as UK&apos;s Radcliffe Red List and UNESCO&apos;s Intangible Cultural Heritage Programme, of the contemporary value of heritage-based maker practices. Heritage-based material culture is often strongly rooted in community, place, materials and traditions. They express local knowledge and contribute to a deeper sense of identity and belonging. As such, they offer a stable counterpoint to our fast-changing, digital lifestyles.  While there is a renaissance of interest in heritage making in both the UK and China, there needs to be a better understanding of how this translates into growth in the creative economy that is respectful of cultural legacy. The application of design research expertise offers a way of unlocking the potential of such traditional material cultures by helping ensure they are relevant and meaningful to contemporary needs. Investigating the ability of design to reveal the potential of this cultural heritage provides the catalyst for this collaborative research in the creative economy - between academics in design, fashion and ethnology, businesses and policy makers.   The aim of Located Making is to develop a practical framework for unlocking the potential of cultural heritage by design. This framework, for use by policy-makers, heritage sector organisations and academics, will include a robust co-developed methodology suited to the Chinese context, a step-by-step pathway for identifying principal goals and developing feasible strategies, as well as real world examples and insights. Application of the framework will enable cultural heritage-based making practices in China to benefit economically and socio-culturally from design expertise.  The project will investigate how design expertise can increase the visibility and perceived value of heritage-based making practices in China in ways that accord with sustainability, decent jobs, economic growth and community. To do this, UK and Chinese researchers, in conjunction with private and public sector partners and advisors will: 1) Undertake a series of place-based case studies of cultural heritage making practices in China to assess historical, contextual and stakeholder priorities; 2) Co-create strategies that will increase the visibility and perceived value of heritage-based making practices in ways that stimulate the economy in ways that value people, place and community;  3) Synthesise research insights into generalisable forms that can be adapted to a variety of contexts and elicit feedback to maximise adoption, implementation and impact; and 4) Develop a practical framework for the Chinese context that includes a step-by-step pathway for identifying development opportunities for heritage-based making practices, principal goals, as well as effective strategies for their achievement.  Located Making will generate benefits for academics and non-academics through fostering innovative partnerships among researchers, businesses, makers, sector organisations and policy advisers, extending understanding of how design expertise can increase the visibility and value of heritage-based making practices, and enhancing strategic  development capabilities in the heritage-based maker sector in China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-03">32888.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-03">66043.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-03">66578.1</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-03">33423.34</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-09-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-09-03">198932.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to Lancaster University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH/S00341X/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">16711.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S00341X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-07-01">16711.67</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S00341X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Lancaster University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FS00341X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
