<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P016049_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CreativeDrought - Creative experiments for building resilience to future drought in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Drought events cause severe water and food insecurities in many developing countries. In many of these countries resilience to drought is low for a myriad of reasons, including poverty, unequal political and social structures, limited access to information, and problems adapting traditional knowledge to changing situations. In the CreativeDrought project we aim to increase drought resilience by combining local indigenous knowledges with scientific methods. With a multi-disciplinary research team, we developed an interdisciplinary approach that: i) collects existing drought narratives (i.e. stories about past drought events) and other useful local knowledges, ii) develops hypothetical future drought scenarios with a hydrological model (verified with local communities), iii) organises creative experimentation workshops in which communities build future drought narratives based on the narratives and model scenarios, and finally, iv) embeds the outcomes of these workshops in local water management.   This new approach needs to be tested in a pilot project. The pilot study area we have selected is the Mzingwane area in southern Zimbabwe, a very poor rural area, with a dry and irregular climate, traditional dryland farming systems, and limited effective water management. The region is currently experiencing a severe drought, related to below normal rainfall in two consecutive rainy seasons, and leading to major impacts on local communities in terms of food and water.   We will conduct interviews and group sessions, based around narrative elicitation, with various groups within local communities in the Mzingwane area. In this way we will learn about the experience, perspective and cultural significance of drought events. We will build on this knowledge to develop hypothetical future scenarios with a hydrological model by extrapolating the narrated droughts to outside their historic range. The communities can then use their own experience and the modelling scenarios to experiment with stories about possible future drought events and possible effective ways of responding to them. Through this experimentation they can build up experience of dealing with droughts that are outside the range of previous drought events. This way of increasing resilience to drought is regarded as robust because it uses scientific methods, is culturally embedded and bottom-up. It also ensures that the perspectives of different members of the community are heard and incorporated. Finally, we work with local authorities to make sure the future drought narratives that the communities have developed will feed into official decision-making processes.  The team of the CreativeDrought project consists of experienced academics from different backgrounds. While some have collaborated before, the project also creates new links and allows team members to apply their work outside the UK. We actively build on recent and current projects of the team members. The team builds bridges between different disciplines (natural and social sciences, arts &amp; humanities), between countries (UK, Zimbabwe), and between scientists and local stakeholders (community members, NGOs and authorities). To increase success of the project, we will link up with existing projects in the same area and have an international scientific steering committee.  The outcomes of this research are diverse, including meetings and workshops with local stakeholders, high-level scientific publications, a website to disseminate results and archive collected data, and a proposal that aims at applying our new interdisciplinary approach to other case study areas in Africa and around the world. With the CreativeDrought project we hope to lay the foundations for new ways of increasing the drought resilience of rural communities in developing countries, by combining strengths of local knowledge and cultural expressions with scientific methods.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our goal is to increase drought preparedness, adaptive capacity and resilience of rural communities in Low and Middle Income Countries. With the CreativeDrought project we aim to lay the foundations for this by setting up the research community and methodology for application in potential future larger scale projects.   The objectives of the CreativeDrought project can be sub-divided in research objectives and project objectives. Our project objectives relate to the outcomes of the &apos;Building Resilience&apos; call as follows:  - testing an innovative interdisciplinary method that combines arts &amp; humanities with natural and social science;  - strengthening existing partnerships &amp; development of new collaborations between academics of different disciplines (in UK and global south) and between academics and users; and  - preparation of a follow-up proposal in which the methodology will be extended to other ODA countries.  We will apply our novel interdisciplinary methodology in a pilot study area in southern Zimbabwe, with the aim to realise both scientific and development impacts locally. The research objectives therefore relate to three of the themes of the &apos;Building Resilience&apos; call, namely &apos;cultural implications in building resilience&apos;, &apos;understanding of and ability to forecast environmental hazards&apos; and &apos;improving effectiveness of research engagement and uptake&apos;. Our research objectives are formulated as:  - understanding past droughts by collecting existing information from local communities, i.e. drought narratives of past events, IK about water &amp; climate;  - scenario modelling with input of existing information and iterative process with local communities;  - building new narratives of hypothetical future droughts, using creative experimentation based on local cultural expressions and model scenarios; and  - improving local cultural context in decision making by including future drought narratives into integrated water resources management.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-25">111241.54</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">57745.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P016049_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">47641.59</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P016049_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
