<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V002481_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Pollution and Climate Smart Agriculture in China (PaCSAC)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Agriculture is a substantial contributor to emissions of greenhouse gases (GHGs) such as carbon dioxide, methane and nitrous oxide but is also impacted by the climate change caused by increased atmospheric concentrations of these GHGs. This situation has led to the &apos;climate smart agriculture&apos; (CSA) approach that identifies agricultural management practices and technologies to reduce emissions, whilst simultaneously enhancing productivity and improving farmers&apos; livelihoods. However, agriculture also contributes substantially to air pollution through emissions of nitrogen oxides, ammonia and aerosols in addition to the more well-known GHGs. Together these emissions contribute to air pollutants of which secondary ozone and aerosols (PM) are arguably the most important, damaging both human health and arable crop productivity.  These agricultural emissions contribute to substantial air quality problems in China. Poor air quality (due to elevated PM) is estimated to be responsible for between 0.35 to 1.2 million premature deaths per year in China. Ozone pollution has also been estimated to induce wheat yield losses of between 3 and 12% per year. However, the nature of these environmental challenges also offer opportunities for innovative solutions, specifically to extend the CSA approach to include air pollutant emissions and impacts and apply this in China. This will be explored in PaCSAC within four key research areas: The first will involve stakeholder engagement with farmer representatives and organisations to gain a better understanding of the feasibility of implementing alternative agricultural practices and technologies to reduce emissions. The second will translate this knowledge of feasible measures into quantified estimates of emissions associated with these different interventions; here we will partner with colleagues in Laos to explore the transferability of methods developed in this project to support agricultural burn assessment and subsequent air quality. Thirdly, we will combine existing models (TOMCAT and WRFChem), remote and in-situ observations to estimate the atmospheric ozone and aerosol concentrations, with a focus on Eastern China where agriculture is particularly important. Finally, impact assessments of the consequences of pollutant concentrations and associated climate variables, for a range of agricultural emission reduction scenarios, on crop productivity (namely rice and wheat) and PM effects on human health will be assessed using two existing tools - the DO3SE-crop model (for crops) and the LEAP-IBC tool (for human health and crops). These scenarios will be developed in partnership with IIASA who are supporting policy makers in China on low emission development. Importantly, these estimates of emissions, concentrations and impacts will incorporate new satellite, aerial and in situ observation monitoring technologies coupled with the expertise of our Chinese partners to improve modelling and ultimately, the identification of the sustainable solutions for agriculture.  To enable transfer of these new methodologies for application in other countries, PaCSAC will further develop and apply the LEAP-IBC tool. This is a decision support tool and represents a simplified, consolidated tool that incorporates the emissions, concentration and impact estimates that are provided by the combination of the more complex models used in this project. LEAP-IBC is currently used by countries around the world to develop low emission development pathways, supported by the international &apos;Climate and Clean Air Coalition&apos; organisation. This offers an exciting opportunity for the results of our project to be disseminated to a large number of countries supported by the CCAC. In the first instance we will work closely with Bangladesh to ensure that the improvement of the LEAP-IBC tool (and specifically the agricultural emissions associated with different interventions) is relevant outside of China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The ultimate aim of PaCSAC is to identify feasible emission reduction options and scenarios for the Chinese agricultural sector aimed at reducing GHG and air pollutant emissions, and to quantify the impact of each scenario in terms of its ability to reduce the adverse effects of agricultural emissions on arable crop productivity and on human health. The following objectives will deliver this ultimate project aim:-  - Engage with farming organisations and other agricultural stakeholders to deliver a series of feasible emission reduction options for NOx, NH3, CH4, primary aerosol, N2O and CO2. This will explore the intended and unintended consequences of current agricultural farm management practices (e.g. agricultural burning) and barriers to the adoption of solutions for more sustainable agriculture.  - To establish improved agricultural emission inventory methods, to embed these into all-sector inventories, and to develop emission scenarios for agriculture sector management practices and technologies. These interventions will be specifically tailored to inform Climate Smart Agriculture (CSA) approaches that consider both GHGs and air pollutants. This will be achieved through close collaboration with Chinese partners, accelerating and enhancing research collaborations, and with application to third countries where current knowledge on key emissions sources (e.g. agricultural burning) is extremely poor (e.g. Laos).  - To demonstrate the practical benefits of space-enabled and in-situ technologies to support the Chinese agricultural sector - specifically the development, evaluation and application of the atmospheric chemistry-aerosol transport models TOMCAT and WRF-Chem 3-D in estimating i) pollutant concentration profiles across China and ii) impacts of aerosols on photosynthetically active radiation (PAR).  - To develop and deploy the O3 deposition and crop growth model DO3SE-crop for Chinese wheat and rice varieties to assess the effect of multiple stresses and feedbacks (i.e. O3, aerosol and climate variables such as temperature and precipitation) on the productivity of arable agriculture across eastern China. To engage and deliver benefit to other ODA countries (focussing on Bangladesh for proof of concept) through improvements made to agricultural emission inventorying and ozone concentration estimates of the LEAP-IBC model. This will enhance end user engagement, which will benefit from the project&apos;s results and key findings</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-26">186665.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-26">43018.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-08-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-08-26">229683.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC Newton STFC - ODA Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST/V002481/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FV002481%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
