<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009832_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Politicised Provision: Development and Welfare under Latin America&apos;s New Left</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latin America has in recent decades witnessed a dramatic political shift to the left. Numerous leftist political parties have achieved and retained power, primarily through the ballot box, in what scholars have described as a &quot;Pink Tide&quot; sweeping the continent. Central to the political platforms of many of these governments have been a range of novel social programs and welfare initiatives oriented towards the most disadvantaged members of society. In a continent where inequality remains staggeringly high, these forms of poverty-reduction program have been a central basis of the popularity achieved by the governments of the &apos;new left&apos;. Despite the centrality of these social programs to the political projects of &apos;new left&apos; governments, we know little about how they are understood and experienced by the people at whom they are targeted. Much has been written about the policies and politics of the &apos;new left&apos;, but this commentary has often been polarised and contradictory. For some, the emergence of redistributive social programs after a period of neoliberalism has been welcomed and celebrated, and measurable improvements in well-being among impoverished beneficiaries have been emphasised. For others, the programs appear to be bound up with a rising tide of populism that threatens to undermine democracy and weaken liberal institutions across the continent; trends which are understood to be contrary to the interests of the poor majority. Focusing on the Nicaraguan case, this fellowship aims to move beyond these polarised debates by exploring the perspective of the people whose lives these social projects affect most directly. Because one thing is clear: it is not just scholars who express strong feelings about this range of highly-politicised social programs. Participants themselves (along with potential participants) hold powerful opinions regarding the value and purpose of the projects. Indeed, in many of the countries which comprise the &apos;Pink Tide&apos;, the projects have become a focal point for intense political activity among the rural and urban poor. Based upon close ethnographic study of the experiences of project beneficiaries, the fellowship will seek to promote understanding of how these intense political hopes and aspirations invested in the social projects of the new left impact upon their successes and failures. The key idea to be pursued here is that there is much to be gained from understanding the ways in which welfare provision overlaps with the forms of political subjectivity revealed by close ethnographic investigation. If participants in &apos;new left&apos; social projects invest those programs with powerful desires for political inclusion and recognition as citizens, understanding why projects have the results they do requires that this complex dynamic be understood and taken into account. By making steps in this direction, the fellowship aims to promote the improvement of the design, delivery and evaluation of &apos;new left&apos; social welfare programs in Nicaragua and beyond.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Latin America&apos;s left-leaning governments have been rolling out novel programs of social provision for over a decade now. But little is known regarding how the highly politicised nature of these programs plays into their success or failure. Based on close ethnographic study of programs such as Hambre Cero and Plan Techo in Nicaragua, the overarching objective of this fellowship will be to improve the state of knowledge regarding Nicaragua&apos;s current mode of social provision for scholars, policy-makers and development practitioners. By making ethnographic knowledge about the way social projects play out in politicised contexts available to those responsible for these initiatives, the fellowship aims to enable improvements to project design and delivery. My doctoral thesis comprised an extended ethnographic study of a rural Nicaraguan community&apos;s engagement with state and NGO development and social projects, focusing in particular on the ways in which rural involvement with such projects has come to be bound up with the current political context of &apos;New Left&apos; politics in the country. The analysis I undertook there was primarily oriented towards a social anthropological audience. I am convinced, however, that the work has the potential to offer concrete and useful insights into the dynamics of development project reception and delivery. The main objective of the fellowship will therefore be to develop the practical and theoretical implications of my findings for a much wider audience and in relation to a broader scholarly literature, with the primary aim of making an impact on the design and delivery of comparable development programs across rural Latin America and elsewhere. In addition to developing two articles on the topic (see impact plan for details) and publishing them in high-impact academic journals, a central priority will be to ensure that my work comes to be known about among development practitioners and policy-makers in Nicaragua. This will be achieved primarily through collaboration with individuals and organisations working in the implementation of projects throughout Nicaragua. By working closely with local stakeholders I will facilitate the development of a network of specialists capable of sharing knowledge and insight. I will do this by organising and facilitating a series of workshops in Nicaragua itself, which will enable both the dissemination of my own findings to this group, and ongoing knowledge exchange among the network of specialists the workshops establish. Further to the workshops in Nicaragua aimed at development practitioners, I will also convene a one-day conference at UCL, to be held towards the end of the period of the fellowship. Provisionally titled &apos;Development and Welfare under Latin America&apos;s New Left&apos;, this will carry the objective of facilitating dialogue between scholars across a range of disciplines who are studying the dynamics of development and social welfare in countries comparable to Nicaragua socially and politically; for example, in Venezuela, Ecuador or Bolivia. By designing the meeting to be quite thematically specialised, the intention will be for the conference to be the first step in an ongoing collaboration between the scholars involved, leading to the publication of an edited book (see case for support for details). While visiting Nicaragua for the purpose of undertaking the workshops, I will also undertake a small amount of additional research required for the successful publication of the journal articles. My research so far has been primarily based upon close ethnographic study of a single community. Gaining access to data regarding state and NGO projects nationally (of which only limited amount is available in the public domain) will be necessary. By conducting a short series of interviews with government officials and NGO leaders, I will both develop the ties necessary to gain access to this data, and gain valuable material through the interviews themselves.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-21" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="NI" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Nicaragua</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="389" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Post Doctoral Fellowship Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009832_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP009832%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-12-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
