<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_N012542_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BIOmes of Brasil - Resilience, rEcovery, and Diversity: BIO-RED</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of BIO-RED are to:  (i) Determine the biome-wide relationships between target ecosystem functions and biodiversity based on data from the RAINFOR and associated vegetation census networks; (ii) Obtain a detailed mechanistic understanding of the link between biogeochemical cycling, plant nutrient use and species composition and diversity in primary and regenerating systems at the local scale in 3 study landscapes; (iii) Examine tree species&apos; ecophysiological sensitivities to key climate-linked stressors - drought, heat &amp; fire - via real-time monitoring of vegetation functioning and comprehensive trait assessments; (iv) Develop and apply a UAV-based imaging spectroscopy platform to map canopy chemistry and functional diversity at tree, plot &amp; landscape scales, and explore the relationships between ecosystem properties &amp; functional diversity; (v) Establish the extent to which biome transitions are already occurring, including forest invasion into cerrado, using both local and satellite-based monitoring; (vi) Determine the ability of recovering ecosystems and ecosystem management to protect biodiversity &amp; provide key ecosystem services in Brazilian biomes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal spans the three largest biomes in Brazil, the Atlantic and Amazon Forests, and Cerrado savanna. Together these cover &gt;85% of Brazil&apos;s territory and include many of the most diverse ecosystems on Earth, but all have seen large losses in extent. While the value of their vegetation is increasingly recognized it is unclear to what extent these systems can regenerate or resist the increasing environmental stressors associated with climate change, particularly heating &amp; drying. The motivation of BIO-RED is to understand how these changes affect the ability of intact &amp; regenerating ecosystems to deliver societal benefits. This requires addressing these key questions: (i) How resilient are old-growth &amp; regenerating ecosystems to the key stressors expected from future environmental changes? (ii) Is the destruction a reversible process on time-scales relevant to human society? Thus, will vegetation recover to a similar state as the original and provide similar services? (iii) Will the increasingly hot climate affect the recovery of forests and will modified forests be more vulnerable to future environmental change than intact forests?   Answering these questions is only possible with a sound understanding how these systems function and what their sensitivities are. To respond to this need, BIO-RED will apply a multi-scale approach to evaluate the relationships between functions, biodiversity, resilience and regeneration potential in Brazil&apos;s three largest biomes in the face of deforestation and climate change threats. Our objectives are to: (i) Determine the biome-wide relationships between target ecosystem functions and biodiversity based on data from the RAINFOR and associated vegetation census networks; (ii) Obtain a detailed mechanistic understanding of the link between biogeochemical cycling, plant nutrient use and species composition and diversity in primary and regenerating systems at the local scale in 3 study landscapes; (iii) Examine tree species&apos; ecophysiological sensitivities to key climate-linked stressors - drought, heat &amp; fire - via real-time monitoring of vegetation functioning and comprehensive trait assessments; (iv) Develop and apply a UAV (&quot;drone&quot;)-based imaging spectroscopy platform to map canopy chemistry and functional diversity at tree, plot &amp; landscape scales, and explore the relationships between ecosystem properties &amp; functional diversity; (v) Establish the extent to which biome transitions are already occurring, including forest invasion into cerrado, using both permanent plots and satellite-based monitoring. (vi) Determine the ability of recovering ecosystems and ecosystem management to protect biodiversity &amp; provide key ecosystem services in Brazilian biomes;  BIO-RED builds on existing observational networks all led by PIs of this proposal: RAINFOR, GEM, ForestPlots.net (&gt;500 old-growth forest plots), ECOFOR &amp; BIOTA, and others contributed by Brazilian project partners. Most activities will be focused on 3 focal-landscapes, in W Par&#xE1; (Amazon forest), E Mato Grosso (cerrado), &amp; E S&#xE3;o Paulo (Atlantic forest), each with a complex mosaic of old-growth &amp; regenerating systems that is already well sampled by our plot infrastructure and so ideal for intensive work to probe processes &amp; to scale-up via hyperspectral imaging.   BIO-RED will improve understanding of the extent to which Brazilian forest &amp; savanna are resisting climate extremes, the extent to which destruction is reversible, &amp; the vulnerabilities of intact &amp; modified vegetation to climate extremes. It will identify the factors that control resilience &amp; recovery of biodiversity &amp; provision of key ecosystem services to people. These will be used to inform ecosystem management &amp; policy options such as REDD+, the Brazilian Forest Code, &amp; Brazilian ecosystem recovery plans. We therefore expect to lay a stronger scientific basis for future regeneration &amp; protection of these systems, and so to improve benefits for human society.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-02">125132.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-02">175657.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-02">150788</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-05-02">2000</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
