<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Performance of EArly Retinal Laser (PEARL)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Diabetes, an illness in which the body cannot manage blood sugar safely, is often thought of as a disease of wealth. In fact, over 80% of diabetes occurs in poor or middle-income countries, where rates are growing very quickly. In China, there is ten times more diabetes now than there was 30 years ago, and rates (12%) exceed the US. Over years, diabetes damages blood vessels and vision cells in the eye, and can cause blindness. Most diabetic blindness can be prevented with laser if caught early, but only 10% of rural diabetic persons in China receive care.  A major reason is that standard treatment of diabetic eye disease (&quot;DR&quot;) calls for patients to return for examinations until their eyes reach a late stage called &quot;PDR&quot;, which may take many years, before any treatment is given. This can be very difficult for rural patients, who are often less educated and poorer, meaning they drop out before receiving care.  We have completed a review of papers written about earlier treatment of DR, at a stage called &quot;No PDR&quot; or &quot;NPDR.&quot;  This review showed studies are needed to prove that this approach is safe and beneficial, but evidence suggests that early treatment could be better to preserve vision, and easier for patients who might otherwise drop out of standard care. To fill the gap in evidence, we designed a study where patients with disease at an earlier stage (&quot;NPDR,&quot; the Early Group) get laser treatment right away in one eye chosen by chance and the other eye only get laser if  &quot;PDR&quot; develops later, which is the current standard. We will compare eyes treated at NPDR and PDR stages for several outcomes important to patients: vision, developing more serious &quot;PDR&quot; disease, and damage to the eye from treatment. An important goal of this study is to find out if patients who get early treatment are less likely to drop out of follow-up. Since one eye of a patient can&apos;t &quot;drop out,&quot; we will also have a second group of people who will get later treatment in both eyes only if PDR develops (&quot;Standard Group&quot;). We will compare the rate of dropout between the Early and Standard group. The cost of Early versus Standard treatment will also be examined.  An equal number of urban and rural patients will be recruited, because our early work shows that rural patient are at special risk for dropping out, because of their lack of understanding of their disease, but we want to understand patients from both settings. Our study will have two main aims:  1. This kind of study, a &quot;trial,&quot; is expensive and hard. We want to first do a small &quot;Pilot&quot; (100 patients each in Early and Standard groups, versus 300 in each for the main trial) to show that we can find enough patients, convince them  to join the study, give them the treatment as selected by chance, follow them for 1 year and collect necessary data.  2. Care of DR in rich settings often depends on expensive tests or advanced training to define the stages (&quot;NPDR,&quot; &quot;PDR&quot;) and complications of treatment that require further care. Such tests and training may not be practical in poorer settings. In our study, trained local doctors will define stages and find complications using simple, cheap examinations. We will compare their results against more expensive tests and photo grading by experts to find out how well this simpler and cheaper approach works.  Finding out if these locally appropriate ways work is very important for diabetic eye are in poorer areas, and will be an important part of our Pilot study.  Our team includes Chinese and UK experts in diabetic eye care, statistics and trials such as this one. Patients will be recruited at the First Affiliated Hospital in Guangzhou, which has one of the largest diabetic clinics in China, and treated at Zhongshan Ophthalmic Hospital (ZOC), China&apos;s largest eye hospital. The main investigator, Prof Congdon, is an eye doctor based now in the UK, who has worked in China at ZOC for many years, is fluent in Chinese, and will help to link teams</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-09-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">36432.52</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">73160.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">18363.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="A Pilot Trial  I. Objectives relating to preparation for Main Trial:  -Identify methods and rate of recruitment to the trial and test hypothesis that monocular treatment in the early treatment wing will be sufficient to overcome possible resistance to early treatment in what may be a                      pre-symptomatic phase for many patients -Test randomization procedure -Test trial data collection procedures, accuracy of forms, usability of images -Gather data necessary to confirm assumptions on which power calculations for main trial are based in this setting -Identify rate of fidelity of intervention delivery (target &gt; 90%) -Identify rate of attrition (target &lt; 15% at 1 year) -Test feasibility of gathering data for cost-effectiveness analysis  II. Independent objectives of Pilot Trial:  -Assess accuracy (sensitivity/specificity) of clinical diagnosis of severe non-proliferative diabetic retinopathy (NPDR) by local physicians using our simplified definition (based only on micro-aneurysms and haemorrhages) compared to photographic grading using the standard definition (which includes more difficult-to-ascertain findings: venous beading and IRMA) -Assess accuracy (sensitivity/specificity) and cost-effectiveness of local physicians&apos; clinical diagnosis (compared to &quot;gold standard&quot; studies) of:       o Outcome of laser: Progression to Proliferative Diabetic Retinopathy (PDR), compared to assessment by fluorescein angiography       o Complications of laser: Macular oedema, as compared to Optical Coherence Tomography.  B Main Trial  -Determine whether laser treatment for Severe NPDR will reduce progression to PDR compared to standard care (no immediate treatment) (Main outcome) -Determine whether laser treatment for Severe NPDR will improve visual acuity compared to standard care (no immediate treatment)  (Secondary clinical outcome) -Determine whether laser treatment for Severe NPDR will increase complications (macular oedema) compared to standard care (no immediate treatment)  (Secondary clinical outcome) -Determine whether laser treatment for Severe NPDR will improve patient compliance with recommended visits compared to standard care (no immediate treatment)  (Secondary qualitative outcome) -Determine whether laser treatment for Severe NPDR will reduce patient vision-related quality of life (Chinese version of VFQ-25)  and general quality of life (Chinese version of EQ5D-5L) compared to standard care (no immediate treatment)  (Secondary qualitative outcome)"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">36432.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">18216.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">18216.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">18363.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">18363.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">18363.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">17921</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021037_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen&apos;s University of Belfast</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
