<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N501876_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Joint Centre for Cancer Biology &amp; Therapeutics</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is little scientific understanding of the mechanisms that normally maintain  cellular and molecular homeostasis in epithelial tissues, or how derangements in these mechanisms foster carcinogenesis. However, there is remarkable potential that better understanding of these mechanisms will engender novel methods for early diagnosis, risk stratification and cancer therapy. Therefore, translational research in this important area is an urgent strategic priority in India, at a time when epithelial cancers are already a major cause of morbidity and mortality, and their importance is increasing sharply with changing disease demographics.  The proposed Joint Centre seeks to create a synergistic strategic partnership in this important area between the MRC Cancer Unit (CU) in Cambridge, and NCBS /  inStem in Bangalore. The CU seeks to advance understanding of the earliest steps in  epithelial carcinogenesis, and to exploit this knowledge in new approaches for early diagnosis and improved therapy, through innovative enabling technologies. The CU&apos;s internationally recognized programmes led by clinicians and scientists closely complement those of multiple NCBS and inStem faculty leading outstanding basic science programmes investigating epithelial tissue homeostasis, receptor signalling, inflammation, stem cells and regeneration, and mathematical biology. Notably, an extensive collaboration between the institutions has been led since 2011 by Ashok Venkitaraman, the Director of the MRC CU, and Satyajit Mayor, Director of NCBS  and inStem. They attracted significant DBT funding to establish in 2013 a new Centre for Chemical Biology &amp; Therapeutics (CCBT) in Bangalore that complements MRC- funded research at the CU, with the support of Cambridge University and the MRC.  The proposed Joint Centre will harness this powerful existing collaboration to open important new opportunities to extend and enhance the partnership between NCBS/inStem and the MRC Cancer Unit in the areas of cancer biology and translational cancer research. Over the first 3 years, the Joint Centre will focus primarily on collaborative research exploring the chemical biology of intracellular signaling pathways altered in cancer. We will aim to deliver a palette of selective chemical tools that modulate these pathways by targeting phosphopeptide recognition via three structurally-distinct protein domains, with an appropriate assay cascade plus information on structure-activity relationships and binding mode required to deliver validated leads. This activity will nucleate the establishment of joint research projects between a wide network of Cambridge &amp; Bangalore faculty in cancer biology and translational cancer research. These joint projects will focus on three priority areas (Maintenance of homeostasis in epithelial tissues, Mechanisms underlying the pre-neoplastic to neoplastic transition, and Knowledge-directed interventions for early diagnosis, risk stratification and cancer therapy) and aim to extend the breadth and depth of collaboration between the participating institutes. Conversely, it will enhance the potential impact of MRC-funded work in Cambridge through the application of recently established platforms to new research projects.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There is little scientific understanding of the mechanisms that normally maintain cellular and  molecular homeostasis in epithelial tissues, or how derangements in these mechanisms foster carcinogenesis. However, there is remarkable potential that better understanding of these mechanisms will engender novel methods for early diagnosis, risk stratification and cancer therapy. Therefore, translational research in this important area is an urgent strategic priority in India, at a time when epithelial cancers are already a major cause of morbidity and mortality, and their importance is increasing sharply with changing disease demographics. However, few institutional efforts in India currently address this need.    The proposed Joint Centre will exploit a timely opportunity for a synergistic strategic partnership in this important area between the MRC Cancer Unit (CU) in Cambridge, and NCBS / inStem in Bangalore. The CU seeks to advance understanding of the earliest steps in epithelial carcinogenesis, and to exploit this knowledge in new approaches for clinical intervention, through innovative enabling technologies. The CU&apos;s internationally recognized programmes led by clinicians and scientists closely complement those of multiple NCBS and inStem faculty leading outstanding basic science programmes investigating epithelial tissue homeostasis, receptor signalling, inflammation, stem cells and regeneration, and mathematical biology. An extensive collaboration between the institutions has been led since 2011 by Ashok Venkitaraman, the Director of the MRC CU, and Satyajit Mayor, Director of NCBS and inStem. They attracted significant DBT funding to establish in 2013 a new Centre for Chemical Biology &amp; Therapeutics (CCBT) in Bangalore that complements MRC-funded research at the CU, with the support of Cambridge University and the MRC.    The proposed Joint Centre will build on this strong foundation to (a) further develop joint research on the maintenance of homeostasis in epithelial tissues, on mechanisms underlying the pre- neoplastic to neoplastic transition, and on knowledge-directed clinical interventions for early diagnosis, risk stratification and cancer therapy, (b) enrich in Bangalore a framework for translational cancer research leading to clinical intervention, and (c) provide a unique trans- national training environment to build capacity in India for researchers and clinicians in translational cancer research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-27" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-26" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-13">1151978.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Access to Research Grants Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N501876/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN501876%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-04-27"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
