<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N01037X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Unveiling the protein landscape of the African trypanosome cell surface and chasing down potential targets for therapeutic intervention</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human African trypanosomiasis, and the related diseases of American trypanosomiasis and leishmaniasis, threaten millions of people in some of the poorest regions across the globe. New approaches to disease control and treatment remain a priority. The overall objective of this proposal is to exploit the data I generated on the cell surface protein landscape of African trypanosomes to identify and validate essential and invariant parasite surface molecules that are potentially therapeutically exploitable, and identify cellular components that determine surface organisation. I have the experimental tools and preliminary data in place to tackle this aim by addressing the following specific objectives: 1. To identify surface-exposed molecules that are essential to parasite survival in culture and in an animal model of human disease. Recently I identified and validated a cohort of 175 parasite surface proteins. This objective will modify established library generation methods to create a surface protein-specific library of inducible mutants that can be selected for loss-of-fitness both in vitro and in vivo.  2. To identify the determinants of parasite cell surface architecture. With an exclusively extracellular lifestyle, African trypanosomes rely on sequestering many invariant surface antigens into a protected membrane domain. The barriers that segregate those proteins on the surface are key to the success of the parasite. A genome-wide gene silencing analysis will be performed to detect those membrane barrier components necessary for surface membrane protein segregation. 3. To test parasite-specific, surface-exposed invariant proteins for their potential as vaccines - firstly in a piloted in vitro assay to test for visibility/accessibility to host immune defences, and then in a vaccinated animal model of human disease. The proposed work will significantly increase our molecular understanding of the host-parasite interface in African trypanosomes by establishing which components of the parasite surface are essential in a disease-relevant model and identifying the mechanism(s) that keep them correctly localised - both of which may identify new routes to therapeutic intervention. The studies outlined will also shed new light on the biology of cell surfaces that may be of widespread significance to many other areas of biology and medicine that fall within the remit of the MRC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Neglected tropical diseases are a diverse group of diseases that thrive mainly among the poorest of the world&apos;s populations. Three of the World Health Organisation&apos;s 10 most significant neglected tropical diseases - African trypanosomiasis (also known as sleeping sickness), leishmaniasis, and Chagas&apos; disease - are caused by closely-related single-celled parasites. Human infection with African trypanosomes is brought about when an infected tsetse fly takes a blood meal. Without treatment the disease progresses through general ill health to coma and death. Current drugs in use against trypanosomes are old, toxic and failing due to emergence of resistance. Urgent new research is needed to identify potential new therapeutic options. An unusual aspect of African trypanosomes is that they multiply in the human blood in full view of the body&apos;s defence systems. They do this by periodically changing their cell surface to escape recognition by the host. However, many molecules on the parasite surface perform essential functions and cannot be changed. Trypanosomes place these in a special, protected domain on the cell surface. Identifying surface-exposed invariant molecules and understanding how this protective segregation is maintained are of major scientific interest, as well as of practical utility in uncovering ways in which trypanosomes may be vulnerable to new therapies. Using a combinatorial approach funded by the MRC, I have previously identified the composition of the African trypanosome cell surface. I now aim to exploit this knowledge to single out those invariant surface molecules that are essential to the survival of the parasite during infection. For this, I propose to harness some of the power of modern DNA sequencing technologies to test which cell surface genes, when silenced, cause the parasite to die inside the host. A similar method will be used to identify not only cell surface genes, but any genes that the parasite uses to maintain the cell surface organisation, which is so critical to escaping the host immune attack.  Finally, I propose to test those surface-exposed molecules for their potential as vaccines. My pilot experiments show that I can use genetically-modified parasite to screen for molecules on the parasite surface that are accessible to the immune system. I propose to develop this assay and test the most promising candidates in an animal model of human disease. The proposed work will increase our understanding of the fundamental biology of a significant human parasite, and also, by exposing essential surface molecules, provide the first steps in developing new treatments.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="298" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-21">83821.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-21">112440.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-21">113351.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-21">85644.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-21">395258.858</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N01037X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FN01037X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
