<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P006876_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A comparative trial of seasonal vaccination with the malaria vaccine RTS,S/AS01, seasonal malaria chemoprevention and the two interventions combined</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of the proposed clinical trial are to - a. Determine whether vaccination of young children living in areas of seasonal malaria transmission in the Sahel and sub-Sahel of Africa with the malaria vaccine RTS,S/AS01 at the beginning of the malaria transmission season is as effective as seasonal malaria chemoprevention (SMC) with sulphadoxine-pyrimethamine and amodiaquine in preventing clinical episodes of malaria. b. Determine whether a combination of the two interventions would provide useful and cost effective added benefit in preventing malaria in young children over the use of either intervention alone. c. Determine whether a fractional dose (1/5th) of the standard dose of RTS,S/AS01 would be more effective at preventing clinical episodes of malaria than a full dose when given as the third priming dose and as a fourth and fifth subsequent injection. d. Determine the safety of the two interventions, with a focus on the incidence of meningitis and cerebral malaria which were identified as safety signals in the previous phase 3 trial of RTS,S/AS01.  e. Compare the pre-and post vaccination tires of anti-circumsporozoite protein (CSP) antibodies before and after priming and subsequent doses in each of the groups of children who receive RTS,S/AS01, including comparison of tires in children who receive either a full or a fractionated doses. f. Measure the comparative costs of seasonal vaccination with RTS,S/AS01 and SMC and of the additional costs of combining the two interventions. g. Determine the preference of the target populations for injection with RTS.S/AS01 or oral administration of SMC and the views of health staff on the ease of implementation of the two interventions.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There has been substantial progress in the control of malaria during the past decade, but it is estimated that in 2015 there were still 438 000 deaths from malaria, despite widespread deployment of insecticide treated bednets and an increase in access to diagnosis and effective treatment: new tools and approaches are needed. In the African Sahel and sub-Sahel, the risk of malaria is concentrated in the few months of the rainy season, although some transmission continues during the rest of the year.  The seasonality of malaria in this part of Africa has allowed the development of a control measure called seasonal malaria chemoprevention (SMC), which involves treatment of young children, regardless of whether they have any symptoms, with the antimalarials sulphadoxine-pyrimethamine (SP) and amodiaquine (AQ) at monthly intervals on four occasions during the malaria transmission season, a regimen which is very demanding on health care givers and recipient children.  The malaria vaccine RTS,S/AS01 has been in development for over 20 years. A recent trial conducted in 15,439 children showed that when three doses of the vaccine were given to children aged 5-17 months, followed by a fourth dose a year later, the vaccine provided 37% protection against clinical attacks of malaria over a period of 4 years, and a similar level of protection against severe malaria. The vaccine caused febrile convulsions in about 1% of children and there was a small, unexplained, increase in the incidence of meningitis in  vaccine recipients.  These findings were reviewed by the European Medicine Agency in July 2015 and, based on the balance of benefits and risks, the Agency gave the vaccine  a positive opinion. WHO has subsequently recommended that several large pilot implementation studies should be done before the vaccine is deployed more widely and that alternative approaches to its delivery should be explored.  A characteristic feature of the vaccine is that it produces high levels of protection in the first few months after vaccination but that this subsequently wanes. Vaccine efficacy of 86% (26/30 subjects protected) was obtained in a recent trial in USA military volunteers challenged shortly after three doses of vaccine had been given,  the last dose at a lower concentration than usual. The aim of this study is to take advantage of the high initial efficacy of RTS,S/AS01 to investigate its potential to provide protection to children exposed to malaria for just a few months each year.  A three arm trial is proposed which will compare  (a) administration of three doses of RTS,S/AS01 to young children followed by a fourth  and a fifth dose at the beginning of two subsequent malaria transmission season (b) administration of SMC with SP + AQ  as recommended by WHO (c) the combination of these two interventions. The main objectives of the trial will be to determine  whether  RTS,S/AS01  provides a similar level of protection to that of SMC and is equally cost effective as SMC but is easier to administer and whether combination of the two interventions provides an added, cost effective benefit. The trial will be conducted in 6,000 children (2,000 in each arm) in Hounde, Burkina Faso and Bougouni, Mali where a trial of adding the antibiotic azithromycin to the anti-malaria treatment regimen used for SMC is currently under way and due to finish at the end of 2016.  The study team and many of the techniques needed for the new trial are, therefore, in place.  The main end-point of the new trial will be the incidence of episodes of clinical malaria severe enough to warrant treatment. Other end-points will be the incidence of severe malaria, hospital admissions with malaria and anaemia. The safety of the two interventions will be monitored, with a focus on meningitis. The costs of the two approaches and of the combination will be measured and the preference of the local populations for each intervention will be determined.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BF" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Burkina Faso</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-17">208528.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-17">837472.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-17">953729.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-17">1070040.7</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-17">213606.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-08-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-17">3491906.3642</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P006876_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP006876%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
