<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003800_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Interrogating the value of theatre-based methodologies as a research tool for addressing the effects of violence on young people&apos;s education pathways</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overview Brazil faces excessively high rates of violence, with homicide rates similar to conflict zones. These extreme rates of violence impact on everyday interactions and relations, and on all public institutions, including schools. This network therefore explores how violence restricts education pathways/access, in ways that reflect localised patterns of inequality, such as gender, race, class, and sexualities. Members share a concern for the emotional and physical well-being of young people affected by extreme levels of everyday violence, and a curiosity in the potential role of theatre methods in deepening our understanding of how people live with exposure to everyday violence. The network will incorporate a pilot study in a high school in North East Brazil, where violence rates are exceptionally high, in order to focus and deepen the discussion on the value of using applied-theatre methods to create safe spaces for pupils and teachers to express their experiences.  This collaboration between academics and practitioners, between arts and humanities research and practice, and development and education policy and research will therefore road-test and refine a theatre-based model for researching everyday violence as an urgent and persistent challenge.   The issue Latin America has the highest homicide rates in the world for non-conflict zones, which are focused primarily in cities. High levels of interpersonal violence go largely unreported, and rates of violence against women are high. Different groups of people face different sorts of threats and levels of vulnerability. Young people have to deal with the fear, threat and reality of violence, in the home, at school, on the street, and in their relationships with authorities.  Evidence suggests that all forms of violence have negative consequences for educational experience, but also negative school experiences are an indicator for future involvement in violent crime. This multidirectional relationship between violence and education, as well as the disengagement this can produce among teachers, is an issue in need of urgent responses.   Why theatre? This problem emphasises the need to foster creative and safe spaces that allow young people to express emotions, bodily responses, and social practices that can otherwise get missed in the precarious environment they inhabit. The arts have a long tradition of working for non violence and exploring the ways in which people are impacted by politics, power and discrimination. Moreover, there is a parallel between the expressive use of the body in theatre-based activities, and the body as the target of violence. This convergence offers a creative route for understanding the way people experience violence, physically and emotionally.   Activities and outcomes This work will provide methodological innovation, and fresh insights into the impacts of violence on education. The network will come together to discuss plan, deliver and evaluate a pilot, exploring the value of theatre-based approaches as a research methodology. In particular, the network is interested in unpacking the precise insights produced by theatre methods, and their suitability for investigating such a sensitive and complex topic.   The network aims to produce learning that can be shared with professionals and practitioners in the worlds of policy and practice in addressing the impact of the protracted crisis of everyday violence on young people&apos;s (YP) education pathways. Secondly, the network will develop a research proposal to build on the knowledge and practices developed, to explore the potential use of theatre approaches in other settings, and the potential of these methodological tools to function not only as tools for research, but also to provide future solutions to these issues.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-13" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-11">54795.49</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The network&apos;s primary aim is to provoke and facilitate an extensive process of coordinated dialogue focused on road-testing and refining a theatre-based model for researching everyday violence as a situated, urgent and protracted challenge. The network will assess the model for its ability to offer meaningful insight into the impact of violence on school communities, students and teachers, and thereby on education pathways/access; in ways that illuminate localised patterns of inequality (gender, race, class, sexualities). Exploring the potential of emerging applied-theatre methods to create safe spaces for body politics to emerge (the way in which bodies are the site of struggles, via policies, practices and ideas), we bring methodological innovation to this specific exploration of theatre as a research tool. The purpose of the pilot is to bring together the existing team of partners with a wider group of stakeholders from different sectors to provide a focus point to discuss in depth the methodologies in context and move towards common understanding and a shared research agenda.  Objectives -To engage in cross-disciplinary and international boundary crossing, connecting scholars and practitioners working on violence, education, development and theatre methods, who will form a sustainable, inclusive, international &apos;community of enquiry&apos;  -To mobilise this network to examine one element of applied theatre methods: their specific use for offering meaningful research findings on the emotional and bodily impacts of everyday violence on young people (YP) in education settings; and interrogating the methodological value of this process as a research tool  -To draw up criteria for assessing theatre-methodologies, for their ability to uncover and deepen understanding of the effects of violence on YP  -To pilot selected methods in a selected High School in Recife (aged 15-17) to unpack what theatre methods tell us about the impacts of widespread violence on education experience and engagement in this site  -To enable the meaningful participation of teachers and students in this process of dialogue and methodological development - privileging their voices through their participation in provisional network discussions, contribution to Youth and Staff Fora and attendance at network meetings  -To develop a research agenda that has the potential to: o Develop a large scale bid that builds on the knowledge and practices developed through network discussions to explore: other geographical areas and school contexts; the potential of theatre as a solution-focussed, context sensitive method; and its ability to account for intersecting inequalities in experiences of violence affecting education settings; o Work with the outcomes of this network phase to investigate the prospects for the network to contribute to both education and public health practice, building on the refined methodology to develop grounded solution-orientated tools; o Incorporate the needs of the policy community, through their engagement in this agenda-setting stage, to develop policy and practice appropriate guidance for addressing the impact of the protracted crisis of everyday violence on YP&apos;s education pathways.  -To engage in team-based learning and development o Supporting and mentoring the development of 2 early career researchers (Fernandes and Raw) through leadership roles in an innovative research network that draws directly on their unique strengths as emerging researchers o Familiarizing teachers in the pilot school with a methodological approach using theatre-based techniques to work with affective skills."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">34247.18</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003800_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">20548.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003800_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">-8790.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003800_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
