<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018240_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Malaysian GestatiOnal Diabetes and prevention of DiabtES Study (MY GODDESS)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Gestational diabetes is a condition that occurs during pregnancy when the blood sugar is higher than it should be. After the baby is born, the blood sugar returns to normal. The number of women in Malaysia that develop gestational diabetes is about 50,000 each year and these numbers are increasing with the worldwide epidemic of obesity. Around half od the women with gestational diabetes are likely to develop either type 2 diabetes or pre diabetes within 10 years. In other words, these women who are child-rearing and who may also be working outside the home, are developing diabetes in their 30s and 40s, almost 20 years before the average person. Gestational diabetes leads to further health problems and the baby can be born big-for-dates which increases his/her chances of developing type 2 diabetes later in life. Malays, Indian and Chinese Malaysians are all at high risk  for getting diabetes. The chances of getting type 2 diabetes could be significantly reduced if women made lifestyle changes to lose weight and increase their physical activity. This can be very difficult with modern lifesyles and demands. Also getting gestational diabetes is usually a very upsetting experience because the mother feels guilty and also worrying about the health of her baby. There have been trials, mainly in North America, testing different types of lifestlyes but the findings from these trials are not clear cut. There have been no trials reported in Malaysia. We still do not know what kind of support women would find the most helpful. King&apos;s Health Partners has one of the largest clinical and research units for diabetes. We have been developing new approaches to supporting women with gestational diabetes (led by Prof Angus Forbes and Pro Helen Murphy). Our interviews with women with gestational diabetes showed that women in the UK have a poor understanding of their risk of developing diabetes and we think this might be the same  for women in Malaysia. They also did not know how best to lower their risk and worried that exercise and different diet might harm their baby. We also found that women became very upset, guilty and burdened after they were told they had gestational diabetes.    This project is called MY GODDESS and we aim to share the ideas and experiences of women in the UK and Malaysia. In the first set of studies, we will review the research already published and find out what works and what doesn&apos;t. We will focus on studies that uses digital technology such as apps, websites from the smartphone or computer. We will then interview women with a history of gestational diabetes and ask what was difficult about making lifestyle changes and what helped. We will then use use our shared knowledge as researchers and as patients to design a new treatment to support lifestyle change. We will consider ideas such as group sessions, lifestyle coaches text messages, and wearing devices that measure our step counts and heart rate. We will develop the MY GODDESS app which can be downloaded onto a smartphone. We believe that if we understand better how to harness the &apos;health power&apos; in digital technology, we will produce stronger support systems to help women with GDM lead healthier lifestyles.   The second project is to test our new treatment, MY GODDESS, in a small study to see if we could test our new could be conducted at a largerthat it does help women to make lifestyle changes. We will recruit about 50 patients. We will study how many women we could identify, who will be interested in participating and who will stay in the treatment to the end. We will ask women for feedback about their experience, what worked and what did not and any suggestions about improvement. By the end of the project if our findings are in the right direction, we will submit a proposal to conduct a full scale trial to test whether MY GODDESS works in a much larger sample of women across Malaysia.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Objectives The overall aim is to develop and test the feasibility of an innovative, culturally appropriate digitalised diabetes prevention intervention (DPI), MY GODDESS, for women with gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) in Malaysia. We are proposing 2 workstreams with the overall objective to reduce the risk of type 2 diabetes (T2D) in women with gestational diabetes (GDM) in Malaysia. In addition we will be developing an innovative smartphone app. We will also be developing training and public engagement programmes. The specific objectives are: 1. To systematically synthesise the process evaluations of RCTs of DPIs for women with current or history of GDM stratified by those that have a digital component versus those that are only face-to-face in order to understand the strengths and limitations in contributing to effectiveness (Study 1a) 2. To qualitatively describe the different i) implementation processes (reach, format of delivery, fidelity); ii) nature of content; iii) mechanisms or theory of action iv) impact of the cultural, social, religious contexts, in order to identify those processes that are more likely to be effective (study 1a) 3. To inform the development of the logic model which outlines the key aspects of our new DPI (study 1a) 4. To explore perceptions of need, importance and acceptability of DPIs from the perspective of women with GDM (study 1b) 5. To describe the barriers and facilitators to uptake of DPI from a) the Malaysian woman with GDM and b) healthcare provider perspectives (study 1b) 6. To generate solutions for optimising the processes in a digitalised DPI for GDM (study 1b) 7. To integrate the findings from Study 1a and Study 1b in order to model and finalise a manualised digitalized DPI for Malaysian women with GDM (study 1c) 8. To develop the MY GODDESS interactive smartphone app with the aim of supporting culturally appropriate lifestyle changes in the context of motherhood for women with GDM (Study 1d). 9. To conduct a feasibility randomized controlled trial (study 2) to: a) describe the screening, recruitment and data collection methods and rates . b) estimate the statistical parameters to inform sample size calculation for full scale RCT c) conduct a process evaluation to identify mechanisms of action, extent of reach, implementation methods to optimize these for the full-scale intervention. 10. Develop a protocol for a full scale definitive effective RCT of the DPI 11. Transfer of knowledge by deliver training in: a) complex interventions b) women&apos;s health in context of GDM c) training in mixed methods  d) developing quality assurance processes such as introducing standard operating procedures, supervision, ensuring database management, interim report writing c) build capacity in skills in behaviour change techniques, namely motivational interviewing and skills from cognitive behaviour therapy, counselling skills d) training the trainers; training in collecting and coding dietary data; training in developing and evaluating complex behaviour change programmes. e) support the development of a patient public involvement in research 12. Dissemination To submit to the most appropriate and high impact journals. 13. Raise awareness with the public using social media and collaborations with diabetes patient networks such as journalistic reports, clinician and patient testimonials of being involved in research.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">42218.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">126998.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">42560.69</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-26">8817058.848</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T018240_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT018240%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
