<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_S020950_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK-China Agritech Challenge- CITRUSAFE</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposal addresses China&apos;s development priorities to eliminate waste and improve food safety. The project will exploit complementary Chinese and UK research and industrial expertise to valorise waste from large scale (&gt;10 million tons of waste) Chinese mandarin canning manufacturing for food safety applications. Efficient green technologies will be optimised to extract and refine food grade hydrocolloids and citrus bioactives from both solid and liquid waste streams. The focus will be on improving extraction efficiencies and solubility of the compounds to ensure compatibility with foods and packaging matrices. The exploitable outputs will be well defined biomaterials with downstream processing applications in two manufacturing sectors: (1) food additives and (2) food packaging. Food and packaging prototypes will be developed and selected according to optimal antimicrobial and antioxidant properties against key spoilage pathogens in high risk foods (e.g. meat and fish products) and consumer acceptability. This project will utilise China sustainable materials, provide commercial opportunities to Chinese and UK industries with benefits to the environment and the safety of consumers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The proposed project fits within the remit of this call under technical challenge 3 (agricultural products processing) by addressing China&apos;s priorities to reduce or eliminate waste and improve food safety. This project will support China&apos;s sustainable development ambitions to: (1) deliver improvements in environmental quality by reducing or eliminating unavoidable waste from food processing streams (2) achieve food safety and reduce risk of food borne disease by developing food ingredients that can replace high-risk animal products and extend shelf life of commodity products and (3) provide new sources of employment and income to people in traditional agricultural communities. The proposal addresses several technical challenges: (1) improved efficiency, recovery and shelf-life of well defined, foodgrade high value materials from both liquid and solid citrus waste streams using green technologies; (2) the application of these materials to food production with emphasis on improved food safety and nutritional health properties; and (3) the functionalisation of food packaging using citrus extracts for shelf-life extension of high-risk commodities. The research program has been divided into 4 technical work packages (WP2-5), in addition to WP for management (WP1), exploitation (WP6) and dissemination (WP7). This is a multisciplinary project with 6 partners in total, involving exchange of know-how, information and materials that will be managed to deliver the project within 24 months. WP2- Solid waste treatment: the objective will be utilisation of mandarin peels for production at semi-industrial scale (1 ton/h) of food-grade microcellular and refined hydrocolloid powders and citrus. Drying and micronisation milling technologies will be applied to the peels to reduce moisture &lt;15%. Powders will be further refined to extract mandarin pectins and citrus flavonoids. Optimisation of solvent extraction and co-precipitation chemistry will be applied to maximise water solubility and compatibility of materials with food and packaging matrices. WP3- Liquid waste treatment: the objective will be the recovery of well-characterised food-grade hydrocolloid powders and citrus bioactives from viscous, high COD canning water. Sonication will be applied to improve filtration recovery (canning water is highly viscous) of water soluble hydrocolloids and citrus flavonoids, which will be recovered by co-precipitation (as above). Albedo segments from the filtrate will also be recovered and micronised providing an additional source of functional biomaterials. WP4- Food prototypes: microparticle powders (peel and albedo) and refined hydrocolloids will be used to reduce or replace gelatine and animal fat to produce a range of prototype foods, focusing on Chinese and UK stables that are likely to benefit large sections of the population. This WP will also develop biofilm formulations that exploit both hydrocolloids and citrus actives for the purpose of coating high-risk foods including meat, chicken and fish. Demonstration of extended shelf-life and LCA will be carried out and consumer acceptability will be tested using sample consumers both in China and the UK. WP5- Packaging prototypes: citrus bioactives with antioxidant and antimicrobial properties will be used to functionalize packaging materials to extend shelf life of high risk foods including pork, chicken and fish. The bioactive molecules will tested for their compatibility with packaging materials will be studied at the laboratory scale at UoL. The composition of packaging material will be optimised for antimicrobial and antioxidant properties and a pilot trial production will be out at industrial facilities at PKS. Packaging properties will be assessed using commercial UK chemical and safety standards. LCA and consumer acceptability of packaged products will be carried out. There will be strong emphasis on knowledge-transfer and technical training in China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-14">63876.99</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-14">229010.77</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-14">92390.73</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-12-14"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-14">422328.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/S020950/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FS020950%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
