<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S011641_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Learning from Multicultural Amman: Engaging Jordan&apos;s Youth</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Communities and especially the younger generation in Jordan are poorly engaged with their multicultural heritage, both in formal education and at touristic heritage sites and museums which do much for the Jordanian economy but little for its social development.  Our project is designed to tackle this challenge, by training museum staff, teachers and university lecturers to take advantage of the rich educational resources of Jordanian museums, and to consequently create better opportunities for their pupils and students to value Jordan&apos;s rich past. Some key principles underpin our mission: undertaking our research in a rigorous, critical and ethical manner; working with the past for the benefit of present-day and future generations of Jordanians; celebrating the multicultural heritage of Jordan&apos;s diverse communities; highlighting the educational value of museums and their collections; identifying, sharing and adapting best professional practice for the Jordanian museum and education sectors; creating and working in new partnerships that connect not only some of the best scholars and heritage professionals in the UK and Jordan, but also museums, schools and universities, for mutual benefit; and persuading influential policy makers that, by adopting these transformative principles, museums and their users can make a positive and lasting difference to Jordan&apos;s economy, culture and society. We do not yet have all the answers. Despite over 40 years of academic and professional research and debate over community engagement in heritage globally, we still need to understand much more about the Jordanian museum situation, including the professional and social barriers to fully exploiting their educational potential. We also need to find out - by systematically asking and listening to people in the heritage and education sectors - what developmental changes might work best in the Jordanian context. We are certain that high quality training of our collaborating museum staff and educators will make a difference. But we also want to experiment as a team with new ways of teaching and learning in museums, to figure out what approaches work best, both for teachers and for young learners. Ultimately, we want to pass on what we have learnt to other stakeholders, ranging from decision makers in Jordan to scholars and museum professionals globally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objectives of our timely and innovative research and development project are: 1. To identify good practice for engaging school children and university students in learning about their multicultural pasts through Jordanian museums - to ensure that their rich and diverse heritage plays a meaningful part in the future social development and cohesion of Jordan; and to identify good practice in creating and sustaining successful working partnerships between museums, schools and universities - to underpin the sustainable professional and economic development of Jordanian museums;  2. To develop and deliver a tailor-made museum education training programme for Jordanian museum staff, school teachers and university lecturers on the use of museums and their collections to engage young people with their cultural heritage, and on working in professional partnerships for mutual benefit; 3. To develop and implement a set of educational activities and events (including the application of digital technologies to cultural heritage), led by museum staff in collaboration with school teachers and university lecturers, intended to engage Jordanian school children and university students with museums and with their multicultural past, and to enhance those young people&apos;s knowledge, skills and employability in the important Jordanian tourism and heritage sector; 4. To evaluate these activities and events and to use the results to create and share museum learning guidelines on how to make effective use of museum and heritage resources to engage young people in learning about their multicultural past;   5. To use the project&apos;s outcomes to advocate to policy makers the benefits of museums and heritage for community engagement and education, and the value of professional partnerships to support such engagement within the museum and education sectors. In sum, by achieving these objectives, we will affect a step-change in how museums in Jordan engage not only with large numbers of tourists but also with their local communities and with each other, and in how the next generation of Jordanians understands and values their own multifaceted cultural heritage, for the economic and social benefit of the country as a whole.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-24">24019.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-24">96273.11</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-24">72642.56</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-24"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-24">4051641.552</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC Newton Development Grants Award to Durham University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-AH_S011641_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Durham University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FS011641%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
