<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Impact of Rapid Expansion of the Estrategia de Saude da Familia in Rio de Janeiro: Mixed Methods Evaluation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The United Nations has recently set a target for countries to provide comprehensive healthcare at low cost to all citizens. While this is a welcome development, there are concerns that strengthening Primary Health Care (PHC) is not prioritised enough within national and international plans to achieve this. These concerns are grounded in knowledge that health systems with stronger PHC tend to have greater population reach, can respond better to local health needs, and provide a comprehensive set of benefits at lower cost. One potential reason for the lack of priority given to PHC is that most previous research in this area has been conducted in North America and Europe.  Brazil has invested in PHC over the last 20 years through the Estrategia Saude da Familia (ESF). The focus of the ESF is to re-orientate the Brazilian health system to PHC through the delivery of community based health care by multidisciplinary teams. The ESF is much less developed in large cities than rural areas, with poor populations living in favelas (urban slums) being especially underserved. ESF coverage was low (7% in 2008) in Rio de Janeiro until recently, but this has increased substantially since 2011(to 50% in June 2016) reflectings political ambition to achieve universal coverage in the city. The impact of ESF expansion in Rio de Janeiro on health outcomes and costs has important implications for how health systems in large cities in Brazil and internationally should be developed.  Our project will be conducted by a multi-disciplinary team of researchers and policy makers from Brazil, UK and USA, including doctors, health planners, mathematical modellers, and social scientists. It involves quantitative analyses of a unique database that has linked information from patients&apos; medical records (both primary care and hospitalisation records), data on eligibility for state welfare benefits, and deaths in the city. This component of the project will examine whether public investment in ESF in Rio de Janeiro has produced better health outcomes, including a lower likelihood of being admitted to hospital for chronic conditions and a lower risk of death during infancy. It will examine whether individuals dually enrolled in the ESF and a major conditional cash transfer programme derive health benefits above those obtained from each programme in isolation. The project will also explore whether certain groups of patients, including from different race/ethnic groups, benefit more from the ESF than others. We will observe practices in health clinics and undertake interviews with health managers, clinicians, and patients to understand success in the implementation process and barriers to programme expansion. We will undertake mathematical modelling to estimate the potential benefits from further expansion of the programme in the city and whether comparable benefits may accrue if the ESF is expanded in other major Brazilian cities.  Our project aims to influence the development of PHC in Rio de Janeiro, other large cities in Brazil, and internationally by generating and actively disseminating timely evidence to policy-makers especially in a period of economical crisis. We will achieve this by including policy-makers and programme implementers from Rio de Janeiro in our research team. We will jointly host dissemination events with the Pan American Health Association in Rio de Janeiro and Brasilia with policy-makers from cities across Brazil to share the findings in order to inform policy development in the country and internationally. Our evaluation will provide important information to other countries seeking to achieve UHC in major urban areas and large cities, such as Colombia and India. By fostering links between academics and policy makers from Brazil, UK, and USA with extensive experience in analysing linked datasets, microsimulation modelling and qualitative research, we will build research skills and research translation capacity among all team members.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-01-02"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="BR" type="BRAZIL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">217754.34</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">182527.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-12-20">22214.79</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Examine whether rapid expansion of primary healthcare (PHC) (the Estrategia Saude da Familia - ESF) in the city of Rio de Janeiro has improved health outcomes;  Examine the implementation process for ESF expansion, and the barriers and facilitators to programme success through observation, semi-structured interviews, and focus groups with programme administrators, team managers, health professionals, and patients;  Explore how ESF is performing against key domains of PHC (access, continuity, co-ordination, comprehensiveness, quality, equity, and efficiency) from both a system and individual patient perspective;  Examine whether key domains of the ESF are driving improvements in health outcomes;  Explore whether some population groups are benefiting more from ESF than others and why they are doing so;   Explore whether there are synergistic health benefits from dual coverage of ESF and a national conditional cash transfer (Bolsa Familia) programme;  Employ robust methodologies including propensity score matching, and multi-level regression analysis to maximise casual inference and granular understanding of the data from the study;   Create a unique linked longitudinal database covering health care contacts (primary and secondary care), welfare benefit eligibility, and mortality in the city of Rio de Janeiro for on-going use by health care administrators and researchers;  Utilise dynamic micro-simulation models to explore the effectiveness (both in terms of health outcomes and cost) of further expansion of ESF in Rio de Janeiro and in selected other Brazilian cities with low ESF coverage at present e.g. Sao Paulo and Salvador;  Utilise micro-simulation to model potential policy-scenarios reflecting the economic and political challenges in maintaining ESF funding, and explore the impact on health of reduced funding and ESF coverage;    Work as an integrated team of researchers (both qualitative and quantitative), policy-makers, and programme implementers to ensure relevance of research questions, high potential impact from the research, and timely feedback of results to decision-makers;  Organise dissemination events for city, state and national level policy-makers in Brazil with the aim of promoting our research findings and informing the development of PHC in the country and internationally;  Engage with project partners - the Ministry of Health in Rio de Janeiro and the Pan American Health Organisation (PAHO) - to maximise impact of the work alongside traditional routes such as academic publications and conferences;"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">47671.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">125835.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">22124.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">22124.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">117051.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">21825.45</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">21825.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">21825.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">22214.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P014593_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-04465125">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Imperial College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
