<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T022787_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Adapting the health system in Ghana to reach the urban poor</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In rural areas, Ghana has a well-established programme of community-based nurses, community health officers and volunteers working with rural communities to improve maternal and child health. The approach is called Community Health Planning and Services (CHPS) and evaluations in rural areas have shown that the approach has halved all maternal deaths and with increased access to family planning, reducing by one the number of children a woman gives birth to. While successful in rural areas, the approach has not yet been extended to urban areas. Ghana is urbanising rapidly and inequalities between the rich and poor are unacceptably high, with children under the age of 14 in poor urban communities five times more likely to die than the general urban population. Extending CHPS to poor urban communities is now a top government priority. This proposal has been put together by health systems researchers and policy makers embedded within Ghana&apos;s health services (GHS) and the national CHPS programme. Our aim is to conduct the foundation work needed to scale-up CHPS so that the poorest, marginalised urban residents can benefit from the approach.  We will engage closely with three urban communities, each with different variations of urban poverty, for example informal settlements or more mixed, well-established neighbourhoods. Our team includes senior GHS staff, including the head of CHPS, head of nursing research and a strong team of health systems researchers. Ghanaian public health registrars who have worked throughout GHS, with expertise in research methods, will work alongside UK public health registrars (at no salary cost to the project). They will conduct two focus groups in each of the 3 areas. Participants will include women with children facing a variety of challenges to accessing health care. We will conduct approx. 24 interviews with marginalised groups and also community leaders.  The registrars will conduct a desk review of urban community health initiatives. We will collect details of current services provided in the 3 areas and their costs. Key decision makers from within the CHPS programme and GHS will come together for a workshop to design a prototype urban CHPS model and identify all materials, guidelines and training that need to be developed. Our team will develop the practical tools and revise them based on learning throughout the project.  CHPS staff and volunteers will be trained to deliver the new model and will begin implementation in the three areas. Our team will facilitate participatory action research groups with the CHPS staff, community members in each of the areas. The groups will identify issues, agree on and implement solutions and then observe the results. This will lead to a continual cycle of learning and development. The registrars will document this process, collect cost and service data to estimate cost and increase in utilisation and qualitative data with marginalised groups to inform improvement. This will provide valuable new knowledge on how to engage communities and develop an urban health system to reach the most vulnerable. We will draw on a theoretical framework that spells out  different components to consider in community engagement. This will ensure that the model we develop considers all aspects of creating a successful and sustainable community engagement model. Our findings will also allow us to propose modifications to the framework which is currently based on evidence from high income countries. A final workshop with CHPS and CHS decision makers will enable the detailed development of a plan to scale-up the model across urban Ghana. It will also enable us to plan for future large scale evaluation.  By the end of the project, a full suite of policy and practice documents will be available to enable scale-up across urban areas. We will establish a centre of excellence for Urban CHPS to maintain the culture of research to continually evaluate and improve urban CHPS as it is scaled up.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">To answer our primary research question, &quot;How can the health system in urban Ghana be adapted to engage the poorest and respond to their needs at community level?&quot; we will use participatory action research (PAR). PAR has at its core the aim of creating social change, and can be seen as having two parallel and mutually supportive aims, one to make real changes to practice, and one to generate knowledge of value to those engaged in the project, and those in other similar contexts in other communities, including the academic community, and other countries. Our aims are therefore: 1) To adapt Ghana&apos;s Community Health Planning and Services (CHPS) to reach and engage with the urban poor to effectively improve their health and well-being.  2) To understand the social structures, uptake of insurance registration and health seeking behaviour and needs of poor urban communities  3) To identify how to develop system-wide approaches, that synergistically address community engagement, human resource skills and service delivery to ensure that CHPS becomes an effective and scale-able component of the urban health system in Ghana.  Phase 1 - (6 months) Reconnaissance Phase Objective 1: To explore social structures of poor urban communities, identify excluded individuals and households and identify their current health seeking behaviour, including their uptake of the National Health Insurance System, using this information to adapt the CHPS model Objective 2: To review and critically analyse preceding efforts to implement rural and urban CHPS to understand what worked (or not), how and why and establish baseline service utilisation and costs. Phase 2 - (12 months): PAR  Objective 3: To design with urban communities, CHPS community team and health system managers, an adaptation of the current CHPS program and system to ensure relevance to the urban.  Phase 3 - (6 months): Evaluation and preparation for scale-up Objective 4: To evaluate early implementation processes, costs, and acceptability from the perspective of marginalized and vulnerable urban populations, including women and children, frontline health workers and health systems managers and identify the pathway for scale up. Objective 5: To make recommendations on contextually appropriate modification of the CHPS policy, program and implementation arrangements for urban localities as well as approaches to scale up.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSITY OF YORK</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="GH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ghana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1030" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-12-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-12-06">197910.44</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T022787/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">24639</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T022787_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT022787%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
