<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T023562_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Bangladesh D:CLARE Project (Diabetes: Community-Led Awareness, Response and Evaluation)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Conduct a systems analysis through engaging with sub-district, district and national level stakeholders to identify the barriers and enablers to PLA implementation at scale, identify optimal intervention delivery mechanisms, and develop strategies to strengthen scale-up systems; 2. Scale-up and evaluate the PLA intervention to cover a population of 215,000 to: a. Determine the scalability of the PLA intervention by replicating 18-month, salaried-facilitator led implementation across an additional rural population of 130,000; b. Assess whether comparable impacts can be achieved through the implementation of a shorter, lower-coverage PLA intervention delivered by incentivised volunteer facilitators over 12 months in the 64 villages that did not receive PLA in our aforementioned DMagic trial, covering a population of around 85,000; 3. Describe the sustainability and health impacts of 122 PLA groups that were implemented in 32 villages of our DMagic trial, explore factors affecting their sustainability after the withdrawal of direct support, and provide three mentoring workshops for nominated &quot;group champions&quot; over 15 months; 4. Conduct formative research, a pilot study and process evaluation to understand the feasibility, acceptability and adaptations to the intervention required for communities in the different, higher risk environment of urban Faridpur.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We recently completed a population health experiment in rural Bangladesh where we found that a diabetes-focused participatory community mobilisation intervention whereby ordinary community members themselves identify, prioritise and address threats to their health reduced the burden of diabetes and the risk of diabetes (known as &apos;intermediate hyperglycaemia&apos;) in these villages by more than 60% relative to villages where no intervention took place. Furthermore, among individuals who were at higher risk of developing diabetes, those living in community mobilisation villages were almost 60% less likely to develop the disease over two years compared to those who lived in villages where no intervention took place. These findings and our robust methods of evaluation give us confidence that exposure to the community mobilisation intervention caused this reduction in the burden of intermediate hyperglycaemia and diabetes. Furthermore, the low-cost, social intervention is cost-effective and can lead to savings in health care expenditure. Based on these findings, we wish to scale-up our intervention to cover a much larger population. Working with the Diabetic Association of Bangladesh, who will implement the intervention across a population of 215,000 people, UCL will apply epidemiological, economic, social and implementation science methods to better understand the processes, costs and impact of implementation at such a large scale. Further, we will evaluate the sustainability of groups when direct intervention from the Diabetic Association of Bangladesh is withdrawn and evaluate whether observed improvements in health last over a period of three years. Finally, a core component of our project will be engagement with governmental and non-governmental stakeholders in Bangladesh and globally to share our findings and to explore opportunities for longer-term, larger-scale implementation of the intervention.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BD" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Bangladesh</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-07">113213.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-07">340556.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-07">115054.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-07">115054.47</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-07">1369590.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T023562_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT023562%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
