<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007842_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Education, Justice and Memory Network (EdJAM)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">EdJAM&apos;s vision is to create an inclusive, international and interdisciplinary network that builds capacity, amplifies innovative practices, and generates new knowledge to contribute towards achieving Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) target 4.7 - ensuring all learners have the knowledge and skills to build a culture of peace and non-violence. EdJAM aims to reshape the discussion around SDG target 4.7 and to make a significant impact towards achieving it. To do this, our network will: 1) Build capacity of civil society organisations, educators and researchers in LMICs to shape research agendas and to create and share evidence around educative practices and outcomes for SDG target 4.7; 2) Identify, support and amplify innovative and creative approaches to teaching and learning about the violent past in order to build a culture of peace, both inside and outside of the classroom (with an attention to heritage sites, social memory construction, and transitional justice processes as other spaces for teaching and learning about difficult histories); 3) Develop and contribute evidence, partnerships, new approaches and indicators for achieving SDG target 4.7, sharing with key stakeholders including policymakers (national, regional and international), education in emergencies practitioners, and researchers in order to influence strategies for achieving SDG target 4.7. EdJAM works across three overlapping strands with the following objectives: STRAND I: Understanding promising practices, learning from knowledge exchange, and expanding our network 1. Understand and amplify creative practices for teaching and learning about the violent past through proof of concept work with civil society partners in Cambodia, Colombia, Pakistan and Uganda.  2. Map opportunities, barriers to, challenges of and gaps in our knowledge about each thematic area and their links to teaching and learning for a culture of peace and non-violence. 3. Strengthen partnerships, knowledge exchange and in-country impact through partner exchange visits and co-produced impact agendas and events in each country. 4. Expand our network within and beyond these four countries, building partnerships with policymakers, civil society actors, and researchers nationally and regionally.   STRAND II: Building research capacity and developing new knowledge  1. Generate new knowledge around: a. Creative and innovative practices for teaching and learning about the violent past in order to build a culture of peace and violence; b. Ways to amplify these creative practices so that they can change and support formal education policies and practices at national and international levels; c. Opportunities, barriers, challenges and gaps around education as a site of memory production, identified in Strand I. 2. Build research capacity in and beyond our countries of focus, with a priority on supporting the research agendas and development of global south researchers and UK early career researchers.  STRAND III: Synthesising learning for SDG target 4.7 and for partnership working The objectives of Strand III are to: 1. Enhance the impact of Strands I and II, disseminate their achievements widely in order to contribute significantly towards meeting and measuring SDG target 4.7  2. Assess and learn from the models of partnership working, North-South and South-South collaboration and co-creation of knowledge used by EdJAM and to share this widely.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Education, Justice and Memory (EdJAM) network comes together in order to contribute towards Sustainable Development Goal 4, which aims to ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and to promote lifelong learning opportunities for all. A crucial part of SDG4 is its target 4.7, which specifies the kinds of skills, knowledge and attitudes that education should develop in all learners and includes knowledge and skills to promote a culture of peace and non-violence. Current approaches to teaching about conflict and peace often fall short of meeting this challenge. Peace education often relies on generalised approaches that fall flat for learners since they do not enable connections between past and present injustice or violence that affect daily lives. Formal history education is often a space where violence is perpetuated, for instance when it promotes exclusive group identities; silences cultures and experiences; or legitimises conflict and injustice. Curricula often limit opportunities for students to develop knowledge and understanding of the specific historical, cultural, political and economic roots of the conflicts and violence that affect them, much less the skills to transform these conflicts. Where spaces do exist, teachers often lack training, resources and skills to support dialogue and difficult conversations. Existing research tends to concentrate on textbooks and curricula, meaning there is limited evidence of effective teaching and learning processes in schools and other spaces where learners apprehend the past. However, alternatives exist. Creative and innovative practices, pioneered by teachers, artists, community educators, museum curators, and young people themselves offer engaging ways to connect learning about difficult pasts with skills and commitment to realising better futures. EdJAM works to amplify, connect, develop an evidence base about and share these approaches, drawing on the disciplines and practices of transitional justice, memory studies, history, heritage studies, politics and education and working with leading civil society partners in Cambodia, Colombia, Pakistan and Uganda who are doing this pioneering work. This focus enables EdJAM to connect to other SDG challenges, particularly SDG 16 (just, peaceful and inclusive societies) and SDG 17 (global partnerships) and to ensure that learners in our focus countries have a chance to develop the skills and knowledge to build a culture of peace. EdJAM will support researchers in Cambodia, Colombia, Pakistan, Uganda and elsewhere in the global south, and researchers in the UK who are early in their career to develop their research capacity, to share new knowledge, and to shape future research agendas. It will commission research to identify and learn from creative approaches to teaching about the violent past through a series of small grants that will produce both academic and creative outputs (e.g. curriculum resources, museum displays, photo exhibits, online materials). EdJAM will also commission large grants to explore outcomes of creative approaches to teaching about the past, developing new ways of measuring progress towards SDG target 4.7. EdJAM&apos;s work will be shared on an interactive webpage, in English, Spanish and other project languages as demanded. It will also run a series of events to connect its work to policymakers, educators, civil society organisations and researchers in Cambodia, Colombia, Pakistan and Uganda to ensure that connections are made to national curricula, teacher training and other important policy areas. It will share its work widely with the international community, especially those who make decisions about how SDG target 4.7 can be measured and how progress towards it can best be supported. EdJAM is founded on partnership working and collaborative knowledge production across our network - we will share our methodologies, learning and ethical reflections from these experiences of working together.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2024-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">458506.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">186516.03</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">465964.16</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-06">745442.53</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">114626.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007842_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">114626.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007842_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">114626.54</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007842_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
