<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002797_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SITARE: Southampton-IUCAA Training for Astronomical Research and Education</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Provision of *Quality Education* remains a key challenge to sustainable global development. Quality education leads to economic progress through innovation, personal growth and well-being, and reduction of socio-economic inequalities (including gender). Developing countries often suffer the most in terms of this provision. Despite the formulation of miriad strategies to raise the basic education level of their populations, high quality education remains confined to a small elite minority. Targeted approaches addressing specific needs in the higher education sector remain sparse. In particular, the pure sciences are often neglected in lieu of applied subjects such as engineering and information-technology. Yet, blue-skies education and research is critical for driving innovation and development.   Here, we address the issue of pure science development in the low/middle-income country (LMIC) India and the least developed country (LDC) Nepal. We will focus on astronomy and astrophysics education and research activities as a means to encouraging Masters&apos; level university students to go on and pursue higher level research. The students will learn transferable skills in data analysis and critical thinking, allowing them to apply their knowledge well beyond astronomy.   There is a clear and definite need for such capacity building. India is on a path to constructing and operating major new infrastructure focused on astrophysics research. This includes IndIGO (the first gravitational wave LIGO detector outside the USA), the recently-launched AstroSat mission (a world-leading high-energy astronomy satellite), and their involvement in several major international projects such as the Thirty Metre Telescope (TMT) and South African Large Telescope (SALT) consortium. The UK has core expertise in all of these. However, there is also a shortfall of Indian expertise with the requisite advanced skills to fully develop and exploit the projects. Much funding at present is concentrated in the Indian space programme (ISRO) and in engineering schools (IITs), and both of these have demonstrated success. Yet, India is from being competitive in blue-skies research capacity. Both the AstroSat and the IndIGO teams are keen to recruit fresh young talent and bring in additional resources (IndIGO is currently heavily reliant on US contributions). Additionally, there is a need for young scientists to take the lead in developing TMT and SALT projects; India has a significant share in both which is currently underutilised for SALT.   Nepal&apos;s state is far worse. Despite having access to some of the clearest skies in the Himalayas, and a youth force with high aspirations, opportunities for development of pure science research are almost non-existent. Most Nepalese youth are never exposed to the excitement of research. In fact, many of them simply never get the chance to travel abroad.   Our approach will be two-fold: (1) We intend to host a series of workshops in four geographical regions of India, and one in Nepal. Up to ~80 students from a host university and surrounding colleges will be targeted, some of these being quite isolated from big cities. Each workshop will include lectures on a range of frontier topics in astrophysics and data science that the UK (and Southampton in particular) has core expertise in. One-on-one sessions with students will be held to encourage them and answer queries on career possibilities.  (2) Select students will participate in longer training camps in IUCAA and at Southampton, where they will carry out a short research project and will receive international exposure and interaction with their UK peers.   Our strategy includes capacity building through core learning, outreach activities, hands-on training and cross-border interactions. The aim is to allow the next generation of research stars (&apos;sitare&apos;) to shine brightly in these countries. Provisions are included for sustainability beyond the end of the project</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This proposal addresses global sustainable development goal 4 (Quality Education) in the LMIC India and the LDC Nepal, focusing on capacity building for astrophysics. India is constructing and operating massive infrastructure projects that are world-leading in this field: e.g. LIGO-India, AstroSat high energy satellite and more. Yet, the requisite (wo)manpower capable in the advanced scientific and technical skills required to fully exploit these projects remains meagre. This is symptomatic of the broader issue of chronic underfunding of pure sciences in these countries.   Despite having a large network of 400 recognised universities, each with tens of affiliated colleges, *high quality* education has failed to materialise. This is a result of isolation and (more importantly) a lack of resources and exposure to the latest research developments for many students spread across the sub-continent. Nepal sits in the lap of the Himalayas with some of the clearest observing sites in the world; yet, a lack of infrastructure and lack of economic development have meant that blue-skies research and teaching remain critically unprogressive.   The UK has expertise at the forefront of this field. In particular, University of Southampton is involved in the LIGO science project results on gravitational waves, and the UK is a world-leader in high-energy astrophysics.   Our aim is knowledge transfer, interaction with leading role models, and development of career aspirations of potential future research scientists (in astrophysics and any STEM subject) in India and Nepal, as follows.  1) We will hold a series of workshops in four geographically separate regions of India and in one university in Nepal. These will target upto 80 Masters&apos; level students for a series of focused lectures in astrophysics and data science over three days. About one-third of the time will be set aside for Q&amp;A and one-to-one interactions with international staff, with the aim of mitigating the psychology of alienation felt by many students in far-flung regions.   2) Selected enthusiastic and talented students will be rewarded with longer training camps at IUCAA and in Southampton, constituting a short research project, outreach activities and interactions with international peers. A selection process including learning tests and interviews is being built into the project. Gender equality will be a core part of this process. The aim is to give the students a flavour of the excitement of research, and to raise their self-confidence, allowing them to overcome suffering from &apos;imposter syndrome&apos;, which is an inevitable consequence of neglect. For many students (especially from the LDC Nepal), the UK visit is likely to be the first opportunity to travel abroad, and thus is likely to be a defining formative experience.   3) The programme will be sustained by asking the students to form study groups within the universities, and to feed back to their juniors. The career paths of the students under this project will be tracked and facilitated beyond the end of the project. Additionally, statistics will be compiled on the socio-economic and educational backgrounds of the students; this data will be used for evaluating the efficacy of the project, as well as refining and expanding it in future years.   In summary, SITARE is an ambitious project with an immediate reach of several hundred students at the grass-roots level across India and in Nepal. It disseminates the highest level of frontline science by researchers who are active in world-leading global astrophysics projects in which India is an emerging player and the UK has core expertise. Multiple activities beyond attending lectures (both in the LMIC/LDC and in the UK) will maximise learning and building of confidence. In turn, this project has the potential to seed the growth of the next generation of world-leading scientists in India and Nepal.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-02" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-05-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-19">100590.02</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">25147.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002797_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">25147.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002797_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">25147.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002797_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-01-01">25147.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002797_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">-14104.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002797_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-19">100590.02</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Southampton</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST/R002797/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Southampton</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FR002797%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-04-02"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
