<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_V003208_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Social innovations for equitable and climate resilient landscapes in Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In this project we bring together six existing networks and projects working independently at landscape scales across Africa, to build an international community of practice of stakeholders that will advance multidimensional understandings of the role, impact and effectiveness of landscape-level social innovations for climate action. We will compile existing evidence on, share experiences of, characterise and evaluate social innovations that support integrated risk reduction and resilience across different sectors, land uses and societal actors across African landscapes. This will generate new insights of particular relevance to the &apos;institutional capacity for decision-making across risk domains&apos; theme of this call. We will also identify knowledge gaps from which to develop a Network Plus bid to develop further knowledge and strengthen capacity across Africa

The specific objectives of this project are to: 
1.	Establish an international community of practice on social innovations to progress the sustainable development of equitable and climate resilient landscapes across Africa.
2.	Compile evidence on the role and impacts of social innovations across African landscapes to tackle climate change (mitigate climate risks, strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity) in the context of multiple interacting risks and high level of inequality.  
3.	Develop a framework to characterise social innovations and evaluate their effectiveness, considering multiple perspectives, innovation processes and outcomes, and multiple interacting risks.
4.	Identify knowledge, evidence, capacity gaps and new partners who can support fill them, and propose expansion of the scale of work across the continent in a Network Plus proposal. 
5.	Consolidate the findings to produce (a) a Network Plus proposal, and (b) an academic and popular publication on the role, impact and effectiveness of social innovations for tackling climate change among different actors at landscape scale across Africa. 

Considering past and current social innovations employed in landscapes across Africa we will answer the following research questions:
a)	What social innovations (autonomous and planned) have been, and are being, employed in African landscapes? (Obj. 2)
b)	How can these social innovations be classified and characterised in terms of the approach used, actors involved, and the outcomes they seek to achieve? (Obj. 3)  
c)	Considering multiple perspectives (academics, practitioners, policy makers and local communities), social innovation processes and outcomes - how effective are social innovations, what opportunities do they create and what challenges are faced for whom and why? What opportunities and trade-offs, in relation to other risks, exist and/or are emerging? (Obj. 3)
d)	In our assessment of the role, impact and effectiveness of social innovations in African landscapes to tackle climate change, what is missing and how can this knowledge be used to inform the development of better integrated, equitable and sustainable strategies, programmes and plans? (Obj. 4)</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will develop innovative approaches that strengthen institutional capacity to improve resilience of vulnerable groups to multiple interacting climate and non-climate risks in Africa. The project brings together six networks and projects, currently working independently at landscape scales across Africa. We will build an international, multi-stakeholder community of practice to advance multidimensional understandings of the role, impact and effectiveness of social innovations that promote climate action and reduce risk across landscapes.

Recurring climate change hazards and  shocks, alongside other stressors on livelihoods,  overwhelm marginalised communities&apos; abilities to cope and adapt to climate change, with significant repercussions for implementation of SDGs and poverty alleviation. To date, development and landscape management interventions and adaptation options typically neglect local inequalities and risk trade-offs and tend to be siloed and sectoral. There is a need for more innovative, relational and pluralistic collaboration for landscape governance to deal with conflicting interests, inequality and unequal power relations. In this project, we use the concept of &apos;social innovation&apos; to advance this knowledge base. 

We will identify, characterise, evaluate and share existing evidence and experiences of social innovations that support integrated risk reduction and resilience across different sectors, land uses and societal actors within African landscapes. By exploring different social innovations we will provide understanding of what works or not, why, and importantly for who, in landscape planning and governance. We will provide new ideas and perspectives to facilitate novel approaches for social innovation to tackle climate change in the context of multiple interacting risks. By learning from existing social innovations, we will identify new paths for practitioners to develop fresh collaborations, in order to find better solutions for climate risk reduction and landscape governance. 

Our  proposal is particularly relevant to the &apos;institutional capacity for decision-making across risk domains&apos; theme of this call. The knowledge gaps we identify will form the basis for development of a Network+ bid for further knowledge development and capacity strengthening across Africa. The longer term findings and multi-stakeholder collaborations established by this project will generate new understandings for integrated landscape level solutions that reduce multiple risks and that leave &apos;no one behind&apos;. By integrating interrelated climate and development challenges, we will be able to explore links and feedbacks between SDG13 (climate action) and other SDGs that act as barriers to SDG achievement. Goals 1 (poverty reduction), 2 (zero hunger), 3 (health), 5 (gender equality), 10 (reduced inequality), 15 (land), and 17 (partnerships) are particularly relevant. Such appraisal is key in supporting the longer term future envisioned in Vision 2063 agenda of the African Union, particularly aspiration 6, on people-driven development relying on vulnerable groups, 1 (sustainable development) and 3 (good governance). We will co-implement and expand on workshops co-funded by related landscape projects that put stakeholder engagement and impact at their core. In these workshops we will co-develop an analytical framework to evaluate social innovations at a landscape level in terms of their process and outcomes, considering equity across different disadvantage groups. We will use this to develop the Network+ proposal, craft an academic paper, as well as popular article and web content for wider audiences. 

Our team comprises UK and African researchers with expertise in landscape approaches, environment, gender, governance and wellbeing. The core African team members are based in Kenya, Ghana and South Africa and work more widely across Africa through the six networks that this project brings together.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">174773.29</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Leeds</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/V003208/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000658">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leeds</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FV003208%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
