<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T01010X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building an integrated data platform for early child development in Malawi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Like many low-income countries in Sub-Saharan Africa, Malawi is burdened with high rates of maternal, infant and childhood mortality and undernutrition. These are driven by multiple factors that interact over space and time. Coupled with economic and gender inequalities, factors that operate across early childhood (0-8 years) result in many children failing to achieve their educational potential. At a national level this impedes economic development and perpetuates a cycle of poverty.  A holistic, unified, approach to data acquisition of key factors impacting early child development, data sharing and linkage to existing datasets, statistical analyses and mathematical modelling, is required to identify which children are at greatest need of intervention. We aim to achieve this by building a new data platform for early child development in Malawi by harmonising geo-temporal data that already exists, courtesy of national surveys conducted by the Government of Malawi, with data from ongoing projects undertaken by our team of researchers and NGO partners, relating to early educational outcomes, maternal and infant health, and micronutrients in soil and crop samples taken from plots where food is grown for consumption in family homes. Integrating these datasets into a large-scale national data platform will enable secondary analyses to be conducted, that have hitherto, not been possible. This will transform early child development and learning outcomes in Malawi, and requires collaboration and cooperation of key stakeholders to bring about long-term, sustainable, change. Current policy for mothers and children in Malawi is covered by three separate government ministries. A lack of joined up planning, acquisition, and sharing of key data means that opportunities to intervene at an early stage may be lost. Currently, it is not possible to track individual children from pregnancy to 8 years and identify those most at risk of adverse outcomes. This leaves Malawi vulnerable to continued poor early child development and the long-term negative impact this has on the country&apos;s economic development and welfare.  Over the past year, we have established a multidisciplinary team of international researchers from psychology, biosciences, maternal, child, and public health, big data science, and international law on data protection and governance, with NGOs, policy-makers, and policy-enablers from key government sectors in Malawi, all of whom are committed to improving quality of life for young children and their families. We have identified the need for a unified data management system in Malawi, that is compliant with General Data Protection Regulation legislation, and will enable NGO and research data to be integrated with national government survey data.  Accordingly, in this project we propose to build a new data platform that will harmonise existing datasets from NGOs, the Government of Malawi, and ongoing research projects in Malawi, to enable secondary analyses to be conducted that will identify causal pathways of adverse outcomes in early childhood. Results from these secondary data analyses will enhance understanding of factors that impact early child development and learning and will be utilised by NGOs and the Government of Malawi to make strategic decisions based on scientific evidence to enhance the effectiveness of their programmes and policies. The new data platform will be hosted within the Ministry of Gender and will be an ongoing, sustainable resource, improving the capacity and methods for secondary data research in Malawi and will act as a demonstration of potential to other developing nations. This project is timely as it will increase high-quality, impactful and relevant research in Malawi and other ODA contexts on factors influencing early childhood outcomes. The results of the project will impact generations of children inMalawi and other countries in the region facing similar development challenges.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our vision is to enhance understanding of complex pathways that lead to adverse early child development (0-8 years) in low-to-middle income countries (LMICs). To address this global challenge, we propose to build a new data platform for early child development in Malawi, a low-income country in Sub-Saharan Africa, with a history of high infant mortality, poor early child development and low educational outcomes. We will combine existing geo-temporal data from the Government of Malawi, courtesy of regular national surveys, with data from ongoing projects undertaken by our team of international researchers and NGO partners, relating to early educational outcomes, maternal and infant health, and micronutrients in soil and crop samples taken from plots where food is grown for consumption in family homes. Integrating these datasets into a large-scale national data platform will enable secondary analyses to be conducted, that have hitherto, not been possible. This will inform effective interventions that target primary causes. This will be achieved over the course of the funding period by the following objectives:  1. Build on previous funding from this scheme by strengthening and broadening an established international, interdisciplinary, network of academics and external partners, including government ministries and NGOs in Malawi, with new NGO and international research partners, who will commit to the project long-term, provide robust governance and leadership, and co-design the new data platform to ensure it becomes a sustainable national resource.  2. Co-create a unique integrated data platform that harmonises existing data and encourages contributions from multiple sources, not only to investigate their impact on early child development but also to enable ongoing analysis across geo-temporal factors contributed over time by NGOs, government, and research projects.  3. Hold a design workshop in Malawi with in-country collaborators and stakeholders at the start of the project to co-create the new data management system that is compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation framework, and will enable data sharing, secondary analysis, and mathematical modelling of causal pathways, thus building capacity with in-country NGO partners and policy-makers. 4. Secure ethical approval in Malawi and the UK to gather data during the design workshop to quantify impact, and interview NGO and other data providers to understand design preferences and co-produce user access guidelines for the new data platform. 5. Register the project with the Open Science Framework and provide a link to the data platform hosted by the Government of Malawi, and open access to the aggregated NGO and research datasets by arching these datasets with the UK Data Service. 6. Raise capacity of a Malawian technical researcher by collaborating with experts in big data science, advanced statistical analyses, and mathematical modelling at the University of Nottingham, and mobilise this knowledge by embedding it within the Government of Malawi through the co-creation and prolonged usage of the integrated data platform. 7. Conduct secondary analyses of NGO and research data within the new data platform to produce high quality, impactful research, the results of which will inform effective NGO programming and government policies that target primary causes of early childhood adversity. 8. Hold a launch workshop towards the end of the project to showcase the capability of the new data platform for meaningful secondary analysis of NGO and research data and encourage other NGOs and researchers in the region to contribute data to enrich its capability. 9. Monitor the impact of the project by recording attendance at the design and launch workshops and the number of pledges signed by delegates attesting to their commitment to engage with the platform, contribute data to enrich its capabilities, and apply for further funding to support its sustainability.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malawi</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">58963.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">118403.99</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-11-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-11-05">177367.228</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T01010X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT01010X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
