<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S004270_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Optimising implementation strategies of the scale-up of a primary care psychological intervention: The Friendship Bench</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A randomised controlled trial showed unequivocally that the Friendship Bench (FB) is the first effective psychological treatment programme in primary care to be tested so far in Sub-Saharan Africa. The auspicious results persuaded the government to scale-up the FB to 72 clinics in and around Harare about one year ago. Additional scaling-up has been planned for later this year. Up until now, there has not been an evaluation of the results of this scaling-up initiative.  This study aims to evaluate the scaling-up so far but most importantly to identify the factors that have influenced the outcome of the implementation of the FB with a view to design an enhanced facilitation intervention to improve the implementation in clinics that have not performed so well. We will use two well-known implementation science frameworks (RE-AIM and CFIR) to guide our work. Whilst RE-AIM will provide us with a framework for the outcomes, CIFR will guide us through the process of exploring the &apos;core&apos; factors that determine the success or failure of the implementation of the FB. We will start with an evaluation of what has been achieved so far using all the data that has been routinely collected during the scale-up effort until now. This will be supplemented with additional data captured through a survey and other qualitative methods. The results will allow us to evaluate RE-AIM outcomes and classify clinics according to their implementation outcomes. Subsequently we will conduct a workshop with the main stakeholders to discuss and agree on the CFIR framework to use for the second phase of exploration. The main aim of the second phase is to identify key or core variables deemed to be key predictors of the successful implementation of the FB. In order to do this we will focus on comparing low and high performing clinics to identify those factors that might explain implementation outcomes. During the second phase, most research will be of a qualitative nature, through focus groups and semi-structured interviews, except for small surveys and the collection of additional economic data. At the end of this phase, we will invite main stakeholders again to review our results and conclusions and to help us identify the components of an enhanced facilitation intervention that we will test in those clinics whose implementation achievements fall into the lowest quartile. We will conduct a hybrid type 3 study to ascertain if implementation outcomes improve four months after this facilitation takes place in comparison with control clinics. The information generated in this study is vital to continue the successful expansion of the FB and to consolidate the implementation currently underway. Besides it will provide essential information for other neighbouring countries in terms of using implementation science methodology as well as learning about potential problems in the route to implementation as well as possible approaches to improve their implementation efforts.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall goal of this proposal is to systematically identify and test promising implementation strategies to maximise the Reach, Effectiveness, Adoption, Implementation, and Maintenance of Friendship Bench program in Zimbabwe. Specific aims include: Aim 1: Use the RE-AIM model to evaluate the current scale-up of the evidence-based Friendship Bench primary care psychological intervention, assessing the program&apos;s real-world and pragmatic Reach, Effectiveness, Adoption, Implementation, and Maintenance across 72 primary care clinics. Sub-aims include measuring: 1a) Reach: Proportion of health facilities and population in Harare reached by the Friendship Bench intervention and the representativeness of those reached by age, gender, socio-economic status, HIV status, and ethnic group so that we can have a preliminary assessment of the distribution of the implementation across different population sub-groups (equity). (target: 90% of facilities and 80% of individuals with CMDs reached). 1b) Effectiveness: Scores on Shona Symptom Questionnaire (SSQ) pre- and post-treatment (target: recovery rates of 60%). 1c) Adoption: Proportion of clinics that have adopted the intervention, and those with future intention to try and numbers/proportions of CHWs who are delivering the intervention (target: 80% adoption; 50% of CHWs delivering). 1d) Implementation: assessing usability (ease-of-use and perceived usefulness), feasibility (perceived fit with organizational goals/priorities, infrastructure, existing resources, and culture), and process fidelity (the degree to which providers implement Friendship Bench according to protocols). 1e) Maintenance: Proportion of clinics and CHWs sustaining implementation over time (target: &gt;90% at 12 months, &gt;80% at 24 months, and &gt;65% at 36 months). Aim II: Use the Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research (CFIR)22 to understand better the factors influencing the implementation of the FB. The constructs of CFIR chosen to be included in our assessment model will be decided through a participatory process that includes main stakeholders. More specifically to: 2a) Guide examination of implementation process. 2b) Define core elements of the Friendship Bench program. 2c) Describe determinants of success and failure found across RE-AIM outcomes in implementing facilities. 2d) Systematically identify promising implementation strategies to optimize RE-AIM outcomes 2e) Learn about the factors that influenced the decision to scale-up the programme. 2f) Estimate the costs of the implementation across clinics and the cost-effectiveness with which resources are being used. Page 5 of 15 2g) Classify the clinics into high, medium, and low performing clinics in terms of achieving implementation placing emphasis on outcome measures. Aim III: 3a) To identify promising implementation strategies (based on information gathered through achieving previous aims) to improve the implementation outcomes in low performing clinics. 3b) To conduct a Hybrid Type 3 study in which we will randomize low performing clinics into two arms 1) improved implementation strategies or 2) usual strategies and to compare RE- AIM outcomes across the two arms 4 months later after completing this intervention. 3c) To explore if there were changes in the main CIFR constructs identified through AIM 2 in those clinics receiving the new strategies. 3d) To propose and disseminate a set of strategies for the good implementation of the FB that can also be tried for other similar interventions in Zimbabwe and other LMIC settings.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-10">125284.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-10">252091.64</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-10">123122.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-10">59973.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-10">743061.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_S004270_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FS004270%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
