<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_N015126_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding Buddhist Nationalism</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In the context of Myanmar&apos;s political opening since March 2011, Buddhist activism has made headlines over the past two years due to outbreaks of communal violence across the country marked by religious difference, that threaten to derail Myanmar&apos;s once-promising transition. Many see a connection between these violent episodes and the rise of new Buddhist networks and organizations, including the 969 and MaBaTha movements. However, aspects of the conflict connected to religious identity are poorly understood and research on this topic needs to carefully address the ways in which anti-Muslim actions are difficult to separate from pro-Buddhist impulses. Equally important is the intersection between religious identities and gender, as much of the nationalist discourse focuses on the protection of women as a way of protecting both Buddhism and the nation. A critical aspect of this approach is to take seriously the fears and perceptions of different groups to understand how they shape attitudes towards others and towards religious and national identity.  This 2.5 year research project seeks to critically assess and disaggregate the category of &quot;Buddhist nationalism&quot; in Myanmar by focusing on two complementary aspects of the phenomenon: the production, dissemination, and resonance of narratives that potentially justify violence by positing a Muslim threat to Buddhism and the Burmese nation; and the gendered discourse of nationalism, produced through nationalist rhetoric and both reinforced and contested via the perspectives of women who, respectively, support and oppose it. First, what is the rhetorical and ideational content of this discourse of Muslim threat, driven especially by monks? Which political, religious, and cultural narratives (at local, regional, and global levels) do they employ and how do these resonate with Buddhists in Myanmar? How do these discussions reconfigure categories such as &quot;Buddhist&quot; or &quot;patriot&quot;? What are the potential counter-narratives that monastic and civil society actors are and should be putting forward in response?  The second component of the project considers the complex gendered elements of this discourse. Buddhist nationalist agitation in Myanmar has often focused on the protection of women and concerns regarding women&apos;s role as re-producers of the nation have motivated laws to protect them from the presumably predatory actions of non-Buddhist men. However, the narratives from women themselves present a more nuanced picture of their threat perceptions and how they see their role(s) vis-&#xE0;-vis the religion, the nation and nationalist groups. In drawing on women&apos;s narratives, the project will also identify alternative articulations of religious, ethnic, or national identity that might challenge or complicate the current dominant anti-Muslim sentiment.  These research questions will be explored through assembling a database of sermons, speeches, and written materials from Buddhist and nationalist groups; monitoring media reporting on religious conflict; interviews with key actors in the Myanmar government, religious hierarchy, and civil society; and more detailed ethnographic study in particular places to better understand the production, resonance, and evaluation of nationalist narratives.  In the rapidly-changing political environment of Myanmar, the project will make immediate and regular contributions in the form of bi-annual policy briefs distributed to and discussed with religious and civil society actors, governments, foundations, and other international actors supporting these groups. By also analyzing the rhetoric and methods of those working to reduce religious violence, this study can gauge the effectiveness of their work and assist them in crafting campaigns that respond directly to the logic employed by those who are spreading inter-religious strife.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project has academic objectives, policy objectives, and capacity-building objectives. The academic objectives are:  1. To develop a more comprehensive and nuanced understanding of the narratives supporting anti-Muslim activities in contemporary Myanmar, their resonance among the population, and the role of various actors in producing and disseminating them. This will be accomplished through the creation of a database of sermons from Myanmar monks and materials produced by religious organizations. Analysis of this data will identify and distinguish the narratives that anti-Muslim arguments draw on (religious, cultural, political), gauge the ways that they resonate with different populations, explicate the varied and sometimes conflicting roles of state authorities in reinforcing them, and inform policy responses to counter dangerous rhetoric.   2. To study the ways in which gendered discourses are deployed in the promotion of Burmese Buddhist and Burmese nationalist ideals and identities and understand women&apos;s varied responses to these discourses. This will be accomplished by studying the ways in which groups produce and promote idealized gender images such as the &quot;good Buddhist woman&quot; and the &quot;violent Muslim man&quot; through sermons and other media and by conducting extensive interviews with differently-positioned women regarding their relationship to and perceptions of these categories as well as the role of religious groups in protecting Buddhist women and the Burmese nation.   3. To contribute to theoretical development in the areas of religion &amp; politics and civil society. This will occur through the publication of a monograph, academic journal articles, and papers shared at academic conferences. The three primary areas of contribution will be in disaggregating the category of &quot;Buddhist nationalism&quot; by considering specific contexts in which that category and its constituent components are constructed and contested through public discourse; developing the concept of the &quot;ortho-cultural,&quot; an area of meaning and symbolism between orthopraxy and orthodoxy that highlights the cultural bases of religious authority; and refining existing understandings of civil society, especially its nature in the non-Western world, its relationship to democratic values and practice, and the dynamics of religious civil society groups.  The policy objective is:  4. To support and inform domestic and international responses to religious and communal violence in Myanmar. This will be accomplished through sharing research findings through regular policy briefs, media contributions, journal articles, an edited volume, and a book and by conducting regular consultation meetings with civil society groups, religious groups, NGOs, the Myanmar government, and foreign governments (including the FCO, DFID, and the EU) to help them shape their responses to religious violence and discrimination.  The capacity-building objectives are:  5. To support the academic and professional development of Myanmar researchers. This will be accomplished through the support and training of two post-docs and an RA from Myanmar over 2.5 years (including research methods, networking, and co-written pieces) and by building the research and analysis capacity of Myanmar partner organizations through consultation meetings and seminars.  6. To further develop networks of scholars, civil society practitioners, religious actors, and government representatives to share understanding of the dynamics of religion, nationalism, and violence. This will be accomplished by eliciting input and critical feedback from relevant actors in Myanmar at regular stages of the project, sharing research findings at multiple academic conferences and consultation meetings over the course of the project and by convening an international workshop on Buddhism, nationalism, identity, and violence at the University of Oxford.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MM" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Myanmar</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-02">180374.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-02">241959.95</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-06-02"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-06-02">482945.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/N015126/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">60124.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_N015126_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">60124.73</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_N015126_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">60611.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_N015126_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">60611.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_N015126_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">60611.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_N015126_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">379.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_N015126_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FN015126%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
