<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008652_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Development and potential reversal of type 2 diabetes: How critical is vitamin A in the regulation of insulin responsiveness and lipid homeostasis?</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Although recent clinical and pathophysiological studies have shown that type 2 diabetes is caused by excess, yet reversible, fat accumulation in liver and pancreas, there is convincing evidence that impaired vitamin A signalling and metabolism contributes to this condition.  However, the underlying mechanisms responsible for this remain to be established. The proposed project plans to investigate the importance of vitamin A in the development of type 2 diabetes in the Philippines. We hypothesise that the rise in liver fat associated with a long term positive energy balance will subsequently increases circulating retinol binding protein 4 (RBP4), and that high circulating RBP4 further enhances de novo lipogenesis in the liver. The aim of the project is to test that hypothesis by investigating how increased RBP4 augments liver de novo lipogenesis via a range of mechanisms, and to determine whether energy restriction breaks this potential vicious cycle.    Objective 1: To determine whether high circulating RBP4 combined with low retinoic acid serum concentrations correlate with greater liver fat, and if these markers could be used to determine the risk of developing advanced type 2 diabetes, thus replacing the need for expensive MRI scans in the on-going National Nutrition Survey 2018-20 in the Philippines.  Objective 2: To determine whether raised RBP4 and liver fat promote insulin resistance in adipose and muscle through suppression of insulin signalling via STRA6, STAT3/5 and SOCS3 followed by de novo lipogenesis in the liver, thus inducing a vicious cycle of liver fat accumulation and development of diabetes. Objective 3: To examine if elevated serum RBP4 in diabetes patients with high fat diets shift retinol from the liver to the adipose tissue, thereby creating a tissue specific retinoid deficiency in the liver (inducing de novo lipogenesis through reduced PPARalpha expression) and hypervitaminosis A in the adipose tissue (inducing increased NEFA production).  Objective 4: To determine whether: i) diet-induced weight loss among diabetics in the Philippines (who have relatively  low BMI) achieves the same pathophysiological changes as in Causcasians in Newcastle; ii)  a low energy liquid diet is culturally acceptable; and iii) if substantial weight loss can deliver a clinically superior overall outcome at 6 months compared with management by current best practice guidelines from the Ministry of Health in the Philippines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The rapid increase in number of people affected by type 2 diabetes is matter of grave concern. Diabetes is a world-wide problem and has risen from 108 million in 1980 to 422 million in 2014.  In the Philippines, one out of every six Filipino has either pre-diabetes or diabetes. Recent studies have shown that type 2 diabetes develops by excess, yet reversible, fat accumulation in liver and pancreas. There is also some evidence suggesting that vitamin A may contribute to this condition, but the underlying mechanisms are not yet fully understood. Furthermore, it is not yet clear why some people develop type 2 diabetes faster than others, even with a similar liver fat content.  The proposed study therefore aims to understand if vitamin A increases the metabolic stress that is caused by a fatty liver, and if changes in vitamin A metabolism could contribute to an increase in liver fat, therefore inducing a vicious cycle of liver fat accumulation and acceleration of the development of diabetes.  The study will finally evaluate if diet-induced weight loss among diabetics in the Philippines could improve all aspects of diabetes control, and if a low energy liquid diet is culturally acceptable.  Finally, the project may help to develop new prevention strategies to enable the Ministry of Health to reduce the burden of diabetes and its complications in the Philippines.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-08-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="PH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Philippines</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-04">28505.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-04"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-04">43855.254</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to Newcastle University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008652_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FT008652%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-08-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
