<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P010849_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF-COMPASS: Capacity-building in Eastern Neighbourhood and Central Asia: research integration, impact governance and sustainable communities</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Global trajectories of development embedded in core Western notions of &apos;good governance&apos;, economic progress and democracy promotion, are being increasingly challenged by the rise of smaller states, emergent new orders and their counter geopolitical configurations. In their perception, the western approach still remains essentially &apos;unilateral&apos;, predicated on the &apos;universalism&apos; of western norms and their seeming &apos;exceptionalism&apos; rooted in a historic success and post-colonial discourses of Europe (Nikolaidis 2015). Therefore it comes as no surprise that &apos;good governance&apos; as a way to structure external relations, encounters defiance and resistance from a non-European outside, who feel that their way of being, belonging and believing is ignored, excluded and even &apos;threatened&apos;. COMPASS advocates for a new conceptual and practical approach to &apos;good governance&apos;, which would place more emphasis on local &apos;peoplehood&apos; by way of capacity-building, on &apos;othering&apos; as a way to de-centre and prioritise the needs of local communities, and on connectivity with all-level stakeholders, to ensure lasting and legitimate transformative effect, and dialogue.   The project thus seeks to set up the &apos;hubs of excellence&apos; at the leading HEIs in Azerbaijan, Belarus, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan. The chosen countries are former Soviet Republics, who share the legacies of the past including unreformed and heavily bureaucratised public sector, autocratic governance, outdated and inequitable education. Furthermore, they remain relatively inaccessible to the international community, and suffer from economic hardship, ongoing ethnic conflicts and Russia&apos;s geopolitical pressure. COMPASS does not only aim to address the societal challenges of facilitating sustainable governance, equitable education and resilient and conflict-free communities in the developing countries. It also sets to develop lasting research partnerships with hitherto closed regimes, seeking to bring about change by way of inter-disciplinary research integration in the UK and European research frameworks. In particular, drawing fully on our long-established contacts with the scholars of the region we seek to achieve 3 specific objectives: - promote internationally recognisable specialist excellence capacity for each partner - develop research synergies and joint projects - integrate and disseminate output activities to scholarly, policy and public communities, regionally and internationally To do so, we will establish knowledge platforms in the chosen countries, selected on the basis of their inter-disciplinarity, high research potential, specialist subject niche and connectivity with all-level stakeholders. They include: -  Azerbaijan Diplomatic Academy, Centre of Excellence for European Studies, specialising in European Studies, regional security and energy diplomacy - Belarusian State University, specialising in peace-building straddling History, Sociology, Economics and IR - Tajikistan International Shahidi Foundation, specialising in Cultural Anthropology, Identity and Social Psychology - Uzbek University of World Economy and Diplomacy, specialising in Eurasian economic relations and diplomacy practice By conducting a wide range of research workshops, pilot projects, learning and training activities, policy forums, and public events, we would seek to positively impact on the welfare provisions in the developing countries. Looking prospectively, established strategic partnerships and research networks would also greatly enhance the UK academia and the work of the consortium with a long-standing interest in the eastern region and Central Asia. This will be achieved by providing direct and privileged access into hitherto closed autocratic regimes, and insightful research opportunities and synergies. Additionally, it would greatly contribute to the UK and EU policy sectors, offering first-hand evidence on regional security, economic, cultural and diplomatic cooperation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project selects 4 ODA partners to represent a wide range of different environments, types of conflict/fragility and different scales and facets of poverty. Despite their diversity, they all face similar challenges associated with legacies of the Soviet past; inefficient governance structures; outdated and inaccessible Higher Education (HE) sector failing to support national transformation and integration into a global resource environment. While there is higher potential for capacity-building in each given case, they all suffer from &apos;weaknesses in organisational structure and research facilities, limited labour agility, underdeveloped gender perspective, and weak civil society participation&apos; (UNDP 2015: 158). These factors by far remain the prime contributors to enduring poverty, human insecurity and growth stagnation across the region. As such these cases do not only offer opportunities for facilitating lasting research synergies. Most of all, they may enable the development of a new sustainable and credible governance approach.   The project thus sets to address at a minimum three core development challenges, in full alignment with the UK Aid Strategy, UNDP and WB millennium goals for the selected countries. This focus would also meet the needs for more intensive internationalisation, and research partnership-building for the UK HE sector, crucial for a rapidly changing global environment. The core development challenges include:  - inclusive and equitable quality education - resilient and sustainable livelihoods supported by strong foundations for inclusive economic growth and innovation; inclusive of sustainable cities and communities - reduction of conflict and promotion of peace, justice and humanitarian action; reduction of poverty and inequality, including a gender dimension In addressing these challenges the project seeks to establish &apos;regional hubs of excellence&apos; across Eastern Neighbourhood and Central Asia to develop their specialist excellence capacity in three particular areas: 1) research integration and learning capacity by (i) identifying specialist research synergies and developing pilot projects to aid partners&apos; integration into the wider funding framework area; (ii) sharing &apos;best practice&apos; and knowledge for inclusive equitable education comprising staff skills training workshops, PhD learning schools, and UG/PG student high-impact research forums to facilitate linkages with wider stakeholders; (iii) developing internationally recognisable policy platforms (e.g. Caspian Energy Forum; Minsk Peace Dialogue; Eurasia Silk Road Diplomacy; and Tajik Cultural Diplomacy) to enhance the hubs&apos; specialist profiles and develop internal/external linkages     2) higher-impact governance capacity by (i) surveying needs of public administration, civil society and business sectors; (ii) developing Executive Education provision for all relevant sectors; (iii) offering networking and skills-development opportunities with key institutions in Brussels  3) sustainable community capacity by (i) developing engagement with schools via pilot projects; (ii) surveying community needs; (iii) organising citizen juries with local authorities to enhance outreach and raise critical awareness.  Project partners are selected on the basis of their inter-disciplinarity and specialisms to include EU Studies in Azerbaijan; History, Sociology and IR in Belarus; Peace Diplomacy and Negotiations in Uzbekistan; and Cultural Studies in Tajikistan.  Each partner also offers linkages with all-level national stakeholders to serve as a &apos;hub of excellence&apos; for knowledge production and transfer. EURAFFEX partner in Brussels would assist with skills training and integration into a wider European network. The principal aim is to enhance &apos;the hubs&apos; excellence capacity; integrate them into a wider research community and mobilise them to act as &apos;nodes&apos; for knowledge transfer across the region and beyond, in lasting partnerships with UK HEIs</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="798" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-19">394651.98</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-19">1463832</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-19">1472162</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-19">1461682.48</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-19">719201.72</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-19">114260136.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Kent</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P010849_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Kent</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FP010849%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
