<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R025444_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Affordable near-patient diagnostics to distinguish infectious diseases in the Philippines (AND2ID in Ph)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Acute fever may be caused by a range of pathogens, but clinical symptoms may be too non-specific to differentiate the causative organism, so correct diagnosis requires pathogen-specific diagnostic tests. These diagnostics are too expensive for routine use in resource-limited settings. This means that many patients are treated empirically with broad spectrum antibiotics, which may be unecessary, toxic, and increase the risk of antimicrobial resistance. Conversely delayed diagnosis and treatment may lead to poor outcomes.  A barrier to low-cost diagnostics in the Philippines, arises from a value chain that spans the world, without Purchasing Power Parity (PPP). If we could use technologies that can be manufactured locally, using local resources, then we have the first step to providing affordable diagnostics in resource poor areas, and delivering a sustained improvement in healthcare, while also developing the local economy.  We have made an enzyme (BOON-enzyme) that can do these tests and can be produced almost anywhere without special facilities.  We have made the enzyme pink, so that you can see that it has been produced and we have a way of making it stick to sand so that it is very stable.  We are going to use one of these enzymes - BOON-Taq in polymerase chain reaction (PCR) - to perform a clinical study in patients with suspected dengue and leptospirosis at the University of Santo Tomas in Manila, to assess the impact of the use of diagnostics on the patient pathway and the disease burden. As a result of these trials we will design a diagnostic kit that can be taken out to rural clinics and we will undertake clinical trials in such a clinic.  We will support the study by developing a healthcare economics model of the impact of diagnostics on the patient pathway.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The objective is: To provide an evaluation of the impact of affordable early diagnosis on the patient pathway of infectious disease in the Philippines using dengue and leptospirosis as models. Through: Providing a route to low cost nucleic acid tests (NATs) in the Philippines with global purchasing price parity. To achieve this by: 1. Overcoming the purchasing price parity for nucleic acid diagnostics by synthesising a nucleic acid polymerase (BOON-polymerase) that can be produced locally for minimal cost and isolated and &apos;self-packaged&apos; in one step on sand so that it is stable for some months. 2. Proving the BOON-polymerase in testing in the Philippines, UK and Malaysia using stored samples. 3. Undertaking clinical studies in the Philippines using a PCR protocol that incorporates the BOON-polymerase. 4. Developing a healthcare economics and impact model, taking into account both the burden of disease and a developing local economy emerging from a diagnostics enterprise. 5. Designing a nucleic acid diagnostic for use in a rural environment that can be produced in a low volume, by low resourced distributed manufacturing. 6. Undertaking clinical trials of a prototype diagnostic at a hospital and a rural clinic.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-08-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="MY" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaysia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">134803.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">289570.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">204393.62</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">115435.04</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-06-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-12">8127011.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R025444_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FR025444%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
