<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_T029579_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Harnessing natural product diversity to combat multidrug-resistant pathogens</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) constitutes one of the greatest threats to global public health. The leading AMR threats in South Africa (SA) reflect those on the WHO list of Critical/High Priority pathogens, which includes Gram-negative ESKAPE organisms, with growing levels of resistance to carbapenems and colistin. There is increasing concern over Sexually Transmitted Infections caused by resistant Neisseria gonorrhoea. There is a clear, unmet need for new agents to combat these bacterial pathogens. We will build on the extensive repertoire of SA and UK drug discovery expertise, with the aim of unlocking the potential resources contained in natural marine and terrestrial biota. In this work, we will have a strong emphasis on samples from SA, which is the 3rd most bio-diverse natural habitat on Earth and has the potential to deliver key natural product (NP)-derived antibiotics that are new to science and able to help meet the need for new antibiotics.  NPs are an unprecedented starting point for antibiotic discovery; NPs and their synthetic analogues are the sources of &gt;80% of all clinically-utilised antibiotics. They represent the only validated source of chemical diversity capable of delivering a sustained pipeline of novel antibacterial drug candidates.  Our project consortium is a complementary, multi-disciplinary and balanced team of international experts in clinical/medical microbiology, natural product discovery, medicinal chemistry, antibiotic evaluation, biophysical analysis, bioinformatics, metagenomics, in silico discovery and molecular biology. Team members have successfully delivered multi-partner, multi-national research programmes and there are already established collaborations between SA and the UK within our group. Working together on this project will strengthen the current collaborations, forge new long-term relationships and further develop AMR drug discovery by building capacity for future research to explore the NP diversity in samples from SA and other locations and provide an on-going supply chain of new antibiotic leads.  In the integrated research projects proposed in this Hub, we will deploy new approaches for NP discovery, with an emphasis on samples selected from the highly diverse SA terrestrial and marine biota, which has yet to be systematically screened for antibacterial compounds. We will examine NP extract libraries that have not been mined for antibiotic candidates and we will also explore the hidden potential of microbes by mining metagenomic datasets and the genomes of cultured isolates. This approach will overcome many of the previous limitations of NP discovery, mitigating risks to maximise the potential for delivery of new antibiotic candidate hits.  We will conduct exchange visits for post doctoral researchers in both directions between SA and the UK and we will deliver a series of training workshops in both countries for PhD students and early career researchers. This will include training in basic sample collection and antimicrobial discovery methods, through to specialist training in NP characterisation and analysis tools, bioinformatics, lead optimisation, preliminary in vivo evaluation, PK/PD and entrepreneurship.  Our integrated programme of research and training across the UK and SA will draw on our expertise and access to diverse resources across our transnational network. Through the Hub activities, we will establish new infrastructure, expanding cutting-edge research capacity and we will comprehensively rejuvenate the discovery of novel antibiotics from NP sources.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our consortium is committed to achieving our goal of identifying at least three characterised novel hit compounds that can be progressed to lead optimisation in future projects. We will target Gram-negative members of the ESKAPE group and Neisseria gonorrhoea, as these are among the leading AMR threats in South Africa (SA). Using a multidisciplinary approach, integrating research projects and training workshops across SA and UK centres of excellence in NP research, we will establish new infrastructure, expanding cutting-edge research capacity, especially at SA HDUs, comprehensively rejuvenating the discovery of novel antibiotics from NP sources.  We will achieve the Hub aims by delivering against the following objectives:   For cutting-edge antibiotic discovery research  1) We will establish a robust bioassay platform for use in screening validated NP libraries to identify novel antimicrobial small molecules 2) In parallel, establish a discovery pipeline of new NP extract libraries from diverse marine and terrestrial sources, including those sourced from the highly diverse SA biota that have not been extensively investigated for novel antimicrobial compounds. This work will be supported by (semi-)synthetic chemistry based approaches 3) We will conduct in silico mining of (meta)genomic libraries of taxonomically complex microbial communities from natural environments and explore opportunities for recombinant expression of novel loci encoding biosynthetic gene clusters 4) With these approaches, we aim to deliver at least three characterised novel hit compounds that can be progressed to lead optimisation in future projects  For capacity building and infrastructure development to support future antimicrobial drug discovery  5) We will exchange knowledge, skills and expertise through in-county training workshops in basic and specialist skills relevant to antibiotic drug discovery and development and entrepreneurship 6) We will support Postdoctoral Fellow (PDF) exchanges, in both directions to engage in immersive training in specialist skills for antimicrobial drug development and evaluation 7) We will establish an SA NP Research Network to develop an integrated, multidisciplinary discovery pipeline to address the challenge of AMR</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">1277980.9</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Plymouth</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/T029579/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Plymouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT029579%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
