<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_R013063_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using genomics to trace Salmonella transmission and antimicrobial resistance (AMR) in the poultry and swine food chains in the Philippines</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Salmonellosis, caused by Salmonella spp., is among the most commonly reported foodborne diseases globally, and has a high health and economic burden in both animals and humans. Salmonella enterica is a primary cause of cases and outbreaks of diarrhoea worldwide, including in the Philippines. While numerous potential methods of transmission exist, commercial chicken and pig meat have been recognised as crucial food vehicles for S. enterica. The forecasted increase in consumption and utilisation of swine and poultry products in the Philippines in the next 10 years to over 3 million metric tonnes per annum, increases the likelihood for exposure to the bacterium.  Previous studies from our Philippine team have shown that S. enterica is circulating in the chicken and pig food chains in Metropolitan Manila, and is a likely major and increasing cause of food poisoning. Notably, treatment options for salmonellosis are decreasing as the bacteria increase in their resistance to antimicrobial drugs. Due to frequent use of antibiotics, chickens and pigs are now realized as potential risks in disseminating drug-resistant S. enterica, with multi-drug resistant (MDR) strains now reported to be present in the Philippines.  For this study, we propose to compare at the genetic level of past and present samples of S. enterica across live animal and processed meat domains in the chicken and pig food chains in Metropolitan Manilla. We will perform whole genome sequencing (WGS) of historical and prospectively collected S. enterica bacteria isolated from these samples. WGS technology has become a rapid and affordable tool that is revolutionising the fields of genetics, microbiology, and ecology, as well as public health surveillance and response, including animal health. WGS analysis has enabled new and often unpredicted routes to disease by defining resistance genotypes and their historical generation, predicting resistance phenotypes and identifying similar isolate genomes that are part of a transmission chains. The resulting genomic variation will increase our understanding of transmission and drug resistance to permit more effective interventions. These genomic data will be correlated with laboratory determined virulence and drug resistance outcomes and other collected meta data to enable an important contribution in disease control and prevention, particularly in the design of diagnostics and interventions for Salmonellosis across the food domains (e.g. farms, markets).</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-08">112077.66</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-08">150344.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-08">151562.43</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overarching aim of the project is to understand the genetic diversity of Salmonella enterica in poultry and swine food chains in Metropolitan Manila, together with their antimicrobial resistance genetic markers to improve infection control procedures. The specific objectives of the project are to:    (1) Collect and process prospectively S. enterica samples across food domains and chains, including abattoirs (thereby informing on farm settings) and markets (n=3,200); (2) Characterize the genetic variation in historical (n=500) and prospectively collected (n=1,500) S. enterica isolates;  (3) Infer the phylogenetic relationship between strains and construct transmission chains;  (4) Infer mutations related to AMR and transmissibility, potentially informing downstream diagnostic tools or other control measures.    The objectives will use prospective routinely collected samples of S. enterica by the National Meat Inspection Service (Philippines Department of Agriculture) and processed by the Natural Sciences Research Institute (NSRI, University of the Philippines - Diliman). From these samples, we expect to culture more than 2,000 isolates of S. enterica based on our previous publications and most will have antimicrobial resistance. From these isolates we will select 1,500 for whole genome sequencing at the Philippine Genome Center that will be combined with 500 historical samples from the same locations that will be sequenced at LSHTM. This large-scale study of S. enterica will enable the first accurate understanding of the transmission dynamics and AMR developments in the Philippines. This data will enable new control measures to be implemented together with improved diagnostics. Through this project, a team of Philippine &quot;One health&quot; genomics experts will be trained who will have a long lasting impact on animal and human health. It is proposed that all outputs, including algorithms, methods, raw sequences and findings will be published and made available to the research community."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
