<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_T012412_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing nitrogen impacts in northern Indian cropping systems: realising production and environmental benefits</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A growing world population requires a growing food supply. The rise in crop yields resulting mainly from the production and application of synthetic nitrogen (N) fertilizer together with the selection of N responsive varieties sustained population growth throughout the 20th century. However, N fertiliser use is of global concern because it is associated both with high levels of energy use and greenhouse gas emissions that cause climate change, in addition to damage to fresh water and marine ecosystems.   N fertilisation is required for achieving high yield in cereal crops including wheat and rice. Increasing sustainability through a decrease in N fertiliser inputs has to date proved difficult due to the resulting fall in productive yield, farmer income and staple food supply. In addition, the current status of policy (and associated subsidy) intervention in fertiliser pricing in India (and other parts of the developing world) supports high application rates to drive yields. This leads to numerous outcomes, many of which are unfavourable for long-term sustainability. In addition this N demand drives the continual growth of synthetic fertiliser production (shown right), an energy intensive process resulting in additional emission and energy costs.  Our work on the N challenge to date has delivered major impacts to both UK and Indian cereal cropping through development of a new framework for optimising N use (UK) and through a direct intervention in farming practice to reduce N use in farmers&apos; fields in Bassian village (a colour-based method of determining optimal N rate called the PAU-LCC, India). We have provided important step changes in our understanding of the potential to reduce N fertiliser use without compromising productivity or economic returns to farmers.   This translational proposal builds on these outcomes to ensure that we realise their full value in terms of agricultural sustainability in India. We have established a solid foundational partnership with the social welfare NGO Atam Pargas and the farming community in Bassian village, which provides an important framework for focussing the delivery of impact and is a model for future system transformation in India. We will continue to base our work on this platform with the aim that all crop production in Bassian village makes use of the PAU-LCC for determining optimal N application. Additionally, this translational project will address two of the major gaps that we have identified based on our work to date. The first is a means to quantify and assess environmental benefits of reduced N fertiliser application at the local (village) scale allowing for the calculation of a full N budget to reflect the impact of simple interventions to reduce N use. The second is a framework for engaging in the Indian agricultural policy agenda around N reduction interventions. Agricultural policy in India is intricately linked to future agricultural sustainability and will largely determine how successful the practical interventions and monitoring in our project are so this framework will be crucial for realising the full impact of our work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to translate our current work on productivity-based interventions to nitrogen (N) fertiliser use in cereal cropping in northern India through establishment of a system to assess environmental benefits at the local (village) scale and to develop a framework for engaging in the Indian agricultural policy agenda around N reduction interventions.      Focused on northern Indian rice-wheat cereal cropping we have three core objectives:   Objective 1. Accelerating uptake of the Punjab Agricultural University Leaf Colour Chart (PAU-LCC) for wheat and rice production in Bassian village through:  - Continuing agricultural extension to work directly with the farming community in Bassian to support the full adoption of PAU-LCCs for determining optimal N fertiliser application and liasing directly with farmers on the benefits of reduced N fertiliser use. - Targeted dissemination events including on-farm visits and in-field demonstrations in farmers fields, and community workshops (co-hosted by partners Atam Pargas and PAU) to share results and advice, and to support the awareness and uptake of the proposed monitoring system for local quantification of environmental effects (see Objective 2). These events will also be used to inform the policy engagement framework (see Objective 3).  Objective 2. Development of a CINTRIN environmental dashboard for quantifying the environmental benefits of reduced N inputs in cereal cropping in Bassian village through:  - Development of village-scale methods to determine agricultural emissions from wheat and rice cropping in Bassian in partnership with Atam Pargas and the farmers of Bassian to allow for the quantification of temporal (seasonal) variation in emissions.    - Deployment of rapid testing capabilities for assessment of water pollution at key water drainage and access points in Bassian.  Objective 3. Scoping and development of a policy engagement framework relating to the current N subsidy system and minimum support pricing for grain in India through - Two Policy Workshops facilitated by the Centre for Science and Policy focused on identifying and bringing together stakeholders and hearing key perspectives and unpacking and considering policy implications from the project&apos;s findings. - Local scoping in Bassian village and the surrounding region  to ensure farmer perspectives and local needs are recognised and will inform both Policy Workshops and the final policy report</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UNIVERSITY OF ST ANDREWS</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-25">252766.85</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF Standard Grant Award to National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB/T012412/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">40109.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_T012412_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">40109.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_T012412_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">40109.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_T012412_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FT012412%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
