<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_V006428_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Systems Analysis Approach to Reduce Plastic Waste in Indonesian Societies (PISCES)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Context - Leakage of plastic waste into the environment in Indonesia is amongst the highest in the world. Only 39% of all waste is collected and 6 million tons of waste per annum is either burnt or dumped into the environment where it contaminates the air, soil, ground water, rivers and oceans damaging ecosystems and their services. In 2017, the Indonesian government introduced an ambitious target to reduce marine plastic debris by 70% by 2025. Yet social, behavioral, economic, political and infrastructural challenges hamper progress across the country&apos;s 17,000 islands. Production and consumption of plastic and plastic leakage are driven by multiple linked human decisions and practices that are not easily disentangled into specific, manageable problems. We need a better understanding of the nature of these individual aspects and that of the relationships that link them together.  Aims - To address this challenge, we will conduct a scientific research programme that brings political, environmental, economic, technical and social disciplines together to understand and address the causes of failures, rather than treating the symptoms.   Objectives -  1) We will research sources, pathways and fate of plastic waste in the environment, using state of the art modelling of plastic use, waste generation and littering to estimate the volumes of plastic flows reaching the land, rivers and seas around Indonesia. We will do this at national scale and in more detail at two case study sites in Pasuran, East Java and Jembrana, Bali. We will use this data to identify hotspots to prioritize sites for calibration and validation of the model and to inform government intervention programmes   2) We will calibrate and validate the models by doing litter surveys at a range of hotspot locations to count and categorize different items of waste and litter from the point of release into the environment and at increasing distances from the source to the sea.   3) We will examine impacts of plastic waste leakage on ecosystem services, ecosystem functions and social and economic structures.   4) We will use focus groups and surveys to increase our understanding of human behavioural and cultural factors associated with the consumption, use and disposal of plastic products   5) We will harmonise the collection of various mass and monetary data types under an analytical framework that seeks to assess the complex value of plastic flows positive (profit, benefit) or negative (cost, impact). Considering all environmental, economic, social, technical and political domains the framework allows for a whole-system assessment to support informed decision-making. Optimisation of the system not only facilitates the recovery of plastic resources but also ensures that impacts on society and the environment are fully considered. Using advanced modelling approaches within this framework, we will identify the most effective points to intervene, in order to create value from plastic waste and maximise the efficiency of identified solutions.   6). We will involve users and multiple stakeholders in &quot;living laboratory experiments&quot; co-creating, testing and observing new solutions and organizational structures. We will examine integrated sets of design interventions (at product, business model, behavior change, waste management levels), pproviding guidance as to where successful interventions can be made, and indicating how changes in the political and legal framework can be instrumental in the better management of resources at different levels of the economy.  Benefits - Our multi-stakeholder team includes action delivery partners who are designing and implementing change programmes on the ground and local and national governments. Our research is designed to inform and add value to these programmes, driving inter-connectivity between academia and government, established public-private partnerships, implementation programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Overarching Objective - To use whole systems analytical approaches to advance understanding of the nature of the interactions underpinning plastic waste leakage into the Indonesian environment and to co-design, trial and test adaptive solutions.   Research will concentrate on understanding and reducing the land-based sources of plastic waste leading to an associated reduction in near shore impacts of plastic emanating from urban environments. We will work closely with our project partners, NGO&apos;s and local and national governments to provide underpinning evidence to inform and support their intervention programmes on the ground as well as local and national changes in government policies.  There are 6 interconnected work packages (WP1-6) describing six main objectives (O1-O6) providing the core integrative requirements of a systems level approach to 1) understanding the problem, 2) co-designing interventions, and 3) delivering solutions.   Objective 1.  Conduct state of the art material flows modelling of the nature and volumes of plastic entering the Indonesian environment, mapping a) the entire Indonesian system to identify country-wide &quot;hotspots&quot; to inform future implementation of waste management programmes by our project partners and b) selected case study areas at sub-district level to inform design and implementation of specific interventions (described in Objectives 5 and 6)  Objective 2.  To calibrate and validate the models developed in Objective 1, establishing robust approaches to understand and monitor sources, distribution and fate of plastic waste generation and littering at a) Regency scale (to inform nationwide modelling) and b) sub-district scale, at each of two case study sites, to help inform the targeting, co-design and implementation of interventions (described in WP4,5 and 6)      Objective 3. Holistic assessment of environmental, social and economic risks and impacts of plastic at relevant spatial scales, and identification of appropriate metrics of marine ecosystem service impact that can be integrated into the plastic pollution calculator to determine the costs of inaction and the benefits that could be gained through the various interventions.   Objective 4.  Study of the behavioural and cultural factors associated with the consumption, use and disposal of plastic products and identification of social and behavioural changes needed to reduce plastic pollution.   Objective 5  Integration of the various modelling approaches to create state of the art interdisciplinary model of plastic material flows and their social, environmental and economic impacts (Objectives 1, 2 and 3). Extensive detailed mapping and systems analytical modelling to identify the most effective points in the plastics system to intervene unlocking system re-design and innovation   Objective 6.  To design and test innovations to prevent and reduce plastic leakage into the environment and drive a sustainable plastic economy.  Involving users and multiple stakeholders in &quot;living laboratory experiments&quot; co-creating, testing and observing new solutions and organizational structures. Adopting a systemic and cross-value chain approach, examining integrated sets of design interventions (at product, business model, behavior change, waste management levels) aimed at producing coordinated changes throughout the whole value chain to develop locally tailored solutions to specific (geographical, cultural, economic, regulatory, etc.) contextual conditions identified in Objectives 3,4 and 5.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-04" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-12-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-12-21">3561374.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to Brunel University London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE/V006428/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brunel University London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FV006428%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2021-01-04"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
