<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003567_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF: Dynamics of Health &amp; Environmental Inequalities in Hebei Province, China</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Provide the Hebei government with robust estimates of the spatial dynamics of poverty, pollution and health:    a. Estimate small area level deprivation indices for 2000 and 2010.   b. Estimate nuanced and robust measures of the spatial structure of poverty and segregation and how it has changed over time.   c. Estimate how the geography of pollution and health has changed between 2000 and 2010.    d. Estimate the relationship between air pollution, deprivation and health in Hebei, and give a clear picture of how this relationship varies both spatially and by &quot;Hukou&quot; household registration status.  2. Make clear steps towards achieving long-term impact through the development of data infrastructure, linkage and training, and by tailoring our outputs towards inclusion in decision support tools:    a. Link Census data, health survey data and pollution data at small area level.   b. Facilitate replication of our work by Hebei statisticians and encourage the take up of our analysis as best practice by other Provinces by making the computer code easily accessible and understandable, and by providing excellent training to government researchers.    c. Work closely with our collaborators in the Hebei Institute of Statistical Sciences (HISS) to make our outputs amenable for inclusion in existing decision support tools developed for the Hebei government.    d. Work with HISS to build a platform for future work that exploits individual level Census data. We shall do this by starting  the process of negotiating the release of individual level Census data which has the potential to be linked over time due to the inclusion of the unique identifier for every citizen. This will be a particularly important research resource for future research given that Chinese Census data includes questions on health and fertility as well as the usual demographic variables.  3. Provide world-leading methodological innovation:    a. Develop a new method for capturing spatial effects in multi-level models where the dependent variable is bounded. This will involve developing a method for estimating fractional logit spatial multi-level regressions by advancing the award winning Bayesian statistical methods previously developed by the research team.   b. Apply this method to explain the determinants of health using either: (1) self-assessed health from the Hebei Health Survey (this variable is bounded between 0 and 100); or (2) Aerial unit Census data on the % in good health.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Hebei province has some of the most polluted cities in the world. A key priority for the 74 million people who live there is to find ways of reducing air pollution and to address the associated social and health inequalities. It is crucial that the true cost of pollution is included in economic planning. The first step is to develop the necessary data infrastructure needed to provide the government a clear picture of how pollution, health and social deprivation are related and how they have changed over time.   Our proposal offers an outstanding opportunity to make a step change in the quality and richness of evidence available to decision makers in Hebei Province. The potential for impact is exceptional due to: (a) the scale and importance of the problem we are seeking to address, and (b) access to senior policy makers made possible through collaboration with the Hebei Institute of Statistical Sciences (HISS). HISS plays a vital role in generating data and developing decision support tools for the Hebei government.    Over the past year we have been forging a collaboration agreement with HISS. This is fortuitous in that it sets out a long-term vision for data access and research that will inform industrial restructuring and social policy in Hebei Province during a crucial phase in its development. The imperative for change has become all the more pressing since 2014 when the Premier of China declared &quot;war&quot; on air pollution. Because of Hebei&apos;s proximity to Beijing (Hebei essentially surrounds the capital), it has become a target for drastic measures to reduce air pollution. There is an urgent imperative, therefore, to provide an evidence base that will inform these decisions to make them as efficient and socially just as possible, maximising the benefits for the socially vulnerable.  So, our proposed project is both timely, and highly relevant to the development challenges facing Hebei.   The proposed programme of research will provide the Hebei government with robust estimates of the spatial dynamics of poverty, pollution and health. Ours will be the first attempt to construct deprivation indices for Hebei province and the first estimates anywhere in China of how the geography of deprivation has changed between the 2000 and 2010 Censuses. We will also provide a range of nuanced measures that capture how the spatial structure of poverty and segregation has evolved over time, revealing, for example, whether poverty has become less centralised in Hebei&apos;s key cities (an important trend in many Western conurbations but, as yet, an unexplored issue in China). We also want to help the Hebei government understand how pollution, health and deprivation are related by developing robust statistical models. This is vital if the true costs of pollution are to be included in economic and social policy decisions in a rational and systematic way.   These research plans are made possible by the unprecedented opportunities for data access afforded through the collaboration between SMI and HISS. Together with the pressing policy issues noted above the newly available data also opens up an opportunity for world-leading methodological innovation. Our research team has pioneered statistical techniques for incorporating the effects of both spatial proximity and hierarchical structuring (e.g. individuals nested within neighbourhoods) in geographical data. The health variable we plan to model has particular features (bounded between 0 and 100). This motivates a novel extension of our methodology that will yield more reliable models of the relationship between health and pollution exposure. Our project will also establish a platform for exciting ambitious research opportunities in future, paving the way for further data linkage and potentially leading to a world-class longitudinal dataset that links individuals from multiple Censuses over time.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-06">30472.53</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-06">110171.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-06">161225.52</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/P003567/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">30472.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003567_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">30472.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003567_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">30472.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003567_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">28644.16</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003567_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">20581.88</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003567_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">12486.53</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003567_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FP003567%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
