<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R001138_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Structure guided design of a transmission-blocking malaria vaccine targeting Pfs48/45</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaria is one of the most devastating infectious diseases to affect humankind. It kills around half a million people, mostly young children in Africa. It also places a huge disease burden on large parts of the world, leading to hundreds of millions of serious infections. As well as directly causing suffering and death, this limits the development of large parts of the globe, reducing productivity and maintaining inequality. Malaria is caused by a tiny, single celled parasite, known as Plasmodium. An individual contracts malaria when bitten by an infected mosquito. The parasites are injected into the blood stream as the mosquito feeds. These first develop and divide within the liver without causing disease. They next emerge from the liver and infect red blood cells, replicating and increasing in number and driving the symptoms of malaria. At the same time, a fraction of the parasites within the blood take a different developmental route, adopting a form known as the gametocytes. When a mosquito takes a blood meal from an infected person, they are likely to ingest some of these gametocytes. Within the midgut of the mosquito these develop into male and female gametes, and fuse together. This completes the infection cycle and the parasites move to the salivary glands of the mosquito, ready to be injected into another human victim. Development of a vaccine to prevent malaria has proved very challenging and it is likely that the vaccines of the future will simultaneously target multiple stages of the parasite life cycle, blocking both liver and blood cell entry. One component of such a vaccine is likely to target the gametes of the parasite and to stop them from fusing. This is known as a transmission-blocking vaccine component as it will prevent the development of the parasite within the mosquito and will therefore stop the disease from being passed from person to person through the action of this blood-sucking insect.  We study a molecule called Pfs48/45 that is found on the surface of the gametocytes and gametes of Plasmodium parasites. Pfs48/45 is essential for a male gamete to fuse with a female gamete and if the immune system of an animal is exposed to Pfs48/45, it produces molecules called antibodies that bind to Pfs48/45 and prevent gametes from fusing. This means that if we can include Pfs48/45 in a vaccine, it will trigger the human body to make antibodies that will prevent malaria from being transmitted to other people. This will reduce the prevalence of malaria in the community and will help to eradicate the disease. Despite this promise, Pfs48/45 is a challenging molecule to produce in a functional form and in large quantities. In addition, if we are to make vaccines that simultaneously contain multiple components, it will be important for each component to be as small and focused as possible, to make it easier and cheaper for them to be produced and distributed. For this reason we aim to understand the structure and shape of Pfs48/45 and also to understand the location and the nature of the sites where the gamete-fusion-preventing antibodies bind. This information will allow us to use the latest computational tools to design novel molecules which contain just the regions of Pfs48/45 that are needed to bind to inhibitory antibodies. We will then inject mice with these novel immunogens and study the antibodies that are produced in a mosquito-infection experiment. If mosquitoes are fed on human blood containing malaria parasites, gametes can fuse, leading to the formation of cysts in the gut wall of the mosquito. If gamete fusion is prevented, the cysts are no longer formed. We will therefore study the ability of the antibodies induced by our novel immunogens to prevent cyst formation revealing which of our designs is most effective at blocking gamete fusion and preventing transmission of the malaria parasite. These newly designed molecules will form part of the malaria vaccines of the future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to structural characterize the critical Plasmodium gamete surface protein, Pfs48/45 and to design novel variants for inclusion as transmission blocking components in a malaria vaccine. Pfs48/45 is essential for male Plasmodium gametes to fuse with female gametes and if antibodies that bind to Pfs48/45 are present in a blood meal taken by a mosquito, they prevent gamete fusion in the mosquito midgut. This blocks the sexual cycle of the parasite, stopping it from developing and making the mosquito non-infective when it takes its next blood meal.  While Pfs48/45 is an excellent transmission-blocking vaccine component, it has proved hard to make and induces the production of non-protective as well as protective antibodies. We therefore aim to conduct a structure-guided immunogen design program. We will make novel immunogens that present the key inhibitory epitopes of Pfs48/45 in small, focused and easily produced molecules that are suitable for inclusion in a multicomponent malaria vaccine. Firstly, we will use x-ray crystallography to determine the structure of Pfs48/45 bound to a monoclonal antibody that can prevent gamete fusion. We have made good progress towards this goal by successfully producing Pfs48/45, by raising a panel of monoclonal antibodies and by generating diffracting crystals. We will now determine the structure, revealing the architecture of Pfs48/45 and showing how and where an inhibitory antibody binds. To give broader view of antibody responses to Pfs48/45 we will map the epitopes of a panel of inhibitory and non-inhibitory monoclonal antibodies. We already have access to an antibody panel and will produce an additional set of antibodies, by immunizing mice and screening hybridomas to find those that prevent oocyst development in infected mosquitos. We will solve structures of complexes of Pfs48/45 bound to these antibodies and will use hydrogen-deuterium exchange mass spectrometry to map epitopes for those which do not crystallise, revealing their structure and nature of key epitopes. Secondly, we will use this insight to perform a detailed program of structure-guided immunogen design. We will make smaller regions of Pfs48/45 that contain key epitopes and can be easily produced. We will need to conduct extensive protein engineering to allow these molecules to fold correctly when removed from the context of the larger protein. We will use a Rosetta-based protein-modeling algorithm, PROSS to generate stabilized versions of these sub-domains of Pfs48/45. We will also use novel Rosetta-based epitope grafting tools to transplant key inhibitory epitopes onto smaller scaffolds, and to design stable variants that present these epitopes. We will test the ability of these immunogens to raise antibodies that prevent mosquito infection in a membrane-feeding assay. This will generate novel immunogens for inclusion in malaria vaccines.  Thirdly, we will initiate a structural program to study the complex of Pfs48/45 with its gamete surface binding partner, Pfs230. We will establish stable insect cell lines that produce different domains of Pfs230 and will test their ability to bind to Pfs48/45 using surface plasmon resonance. We will subject complexes to crystallization trials. We will also use Pfs48/45 reactive antibodies to immune-purify Pfs48/45:Pfs230 complex and will study this using our new electron microscopy facility, revleaing the architecture of the complex. This will provide the first structural insight into Pfs230 and will reveal how it binds to Pfs48/45 in a complex essential for the fusion of malaria gametes. These objectives will reveal the structure of Pfs48/45 and the nature of its interaction with Pfs230. They will show how key inhibitory antibodies bind to Pfs48/45. Finally they will allow us to use structure-guided design methods to produce and test novel immunogens that will be transmission-blocking components of the malaria vaccines of the future.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-17">78181.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-17">149860.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-17">143937.36</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-17">72258.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-17"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-17">444238.084</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_R001138_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FR001138%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
