<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024828_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">How to embed and sustain project-initiated improvements in research capacity: good practice recommendations</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UK government is committed to helping developing countries create their own solutions to the challenges they face rather than trying to adopt potentially inappropriate solutions from elsewhere. If developing countries are able to conduct high-quality research, they will be able to develop evidence-informed policy and practice, improve human capital and produce pro-poor products/technologies, all of which will accelerate social and economic development. Stronger research skills, systems, infrastructure and governance (i.e. research capacity) in developing countries will also benefit the UK national interest since poverty, migration, and epidemics, while concentrated in developing countries, impact globally. The UK is a world leader in supporting developing countries to strengthen their capacity for research and innovation. In recent years international development donors and governments have strengthened their spending on research capacity strengthening which has now become a cornerstone of international development assistance. Nevertheless, Africa in particular, lags far behind in global research capacity - in 1999-2008 African nations produced 27,000 papers/year, about the same number as The Netherlands. The &#xA3;1.5Bn GCRF supports collaborative, large-scale projects between UK and developing country institutions. Many of these projects directly or indirectly contribute to strengthening research capacity in their partner institutions in developing countries by, for example, introducing research skills courses, purchasing equipment and facilitating networks. However, much of this effort is wasted because these capacity improvements are not institutionalised or sustained in the long-term. This is because the institutionalisation of changes was not the main purpose of the project and sustainability can take decades to achieve.  In phase 1 we will identify strategies that have been used by GCRF and other UK-funded projects covering different research disciplines. We will collect data, initially through a survey, about what gains in research capacity were initiated by these projects and if, and how, these have been institutionalised, financed and sustained.  Through our cluster members we will access information from around 100 of these projects&apos; partner institutions in at least 20 African countries, including many of the poorest countries. This will provide information about what changes in research capacity have been initiated. To find out why and how these changes happened, why some succeeded and others did not, and to understand how the different contexts may influence uptake, financing and sustainability, we will undertake in-depth interviews with a range of key researchers, research managers, development funders and senior university officials in Africa and the UK. We will verify our findings by scrutinising the projects&apos; annual reports and evaluations.  All this information will be collated using a well-established framework that incorporates all the components that an institution needs to have in place to achieve world-class research capacity. From this information we will produce baseline data about research capacity strengthening changes that have been initiated through projects and which are common and independent of the research discipline. These will be accompanied by lessons and experiences about how and why these changes have or have not been institutionalised or sustained. We will develop draft guidelines about strategies that can promote uptake and durability of project-initiated improvements in research capacity, including how to promote equity in research opportunities and careers, to be tested during a subsequent project.  The members of our cluster comprise researchers, research managers, grant-making agencies, an NGO and an African research &apos;think tank&apos; with extensive convening power. The project will be led by the Centre for Capacity Research at the Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The long-term goal of our project is for developing countries to achieve self-sufficiency in capacity to generate research and innovation to accelerate socio-economic development. The eventual impact will be enhanced ability of developing countries to generate scientific and technological knowledge and translate it into new products or processes. This is essential for them to solve their own problems thereby accelerating economic growth and development, and for achieving the Sustainable Development Goals.  Many research collaborations already directly or indirectly support improvements in the research capacity of developing country institutions, but these changes are often wasted as they are not institutionalised or sustained. The aim of our project is therefore to identify (phase 1) and test (phase 2) strategies for institutionalising and sustaining project-initiated gains in research capacity.  Our objectives to achieve the aim of the phase 1 project will be jointly achieved by our cluster members and are: 1. develop methods and tools for obtaining comparable baseline data from across multiple research projects to describe and compare strategies for overcoming blockages in institutional research capacity and for promoting and financing sustainable improvements [success measures: methods and tools developed] 2. identify successful, scalable strategies for overcoming these blockages (focusing on institutions in DAC countries), explore why/how they work (or not) in different contexts [success measures: baseline data on strategies used to promote sustainable embedded change and their context, with description of common approaches]  3. derive transferable lessons and produce evidence-informed &apos;good practice&apos; draft guidelines on how to embed and sustain institutional improvements in research capacity beyond projects&apos; lifetime [success measures: preliminary draft guidelines for enhancement and validation in phase 2] Our objectives and goal align closely with the GCRF purpose which is to support cutting-edge, excellent research that addresses challenges faced by developing countries, while also contributing to the UK Aid Strategy to benefit the UK national interest.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">30221.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-06"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-06">483540.32</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T024828_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FT024828%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-06-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
