<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N014111_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Living the urban periphery: investment, infrastructure and economic change in African city-regions</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Targeting the funding call&apos;s first and second topics of &apos;Urban economies and livelihoods&apos; and &apos;Land, infrastructure and sustainable development&apos;, this project seeks to understand how transformation in the peripheries of African cities, (specifically related to infrastructural investments and economic change) is shaped, governed and experienced with a view to informing urban governance and strategies for urban poverty reduction. Life in urban peripheries is characterised by unevenness in economic and political terms, and challenges in terms of provision of, and access to, infrastructure, yet there is little understanding of how or why this occurs. Our project addresses this by mapping and detailing what changes are occurring, determining who in particular is driving these changes and why, and importantly, asking what the poverty implications of these processes are. In addition we identify a gap in understanding how life on the urban periphery is actually experienced by residents, thus we approach the issue of urban change through a &apos;lived experience&apos; approach, outlined below.  Our innovative approach will build on the small, but growing, research on African urban peripheries. Drawing on the expertise of the investigators, the project will examine seven cases within three African city-regions (Beall et al 2015): Gauteng, eThekwini and Addis Ababa. This choice of cases will ensure comparison across low and middle-income countries in Africa, but also between primary and secondary cities. These three city-regions display rapid but variable urbanisation, variable investment strategies, changing patterns of segregation and integration, and complex changes in governance structures. These processes offer us critical cases to develop urban theory, and to consider practical and policy outcomes to ensure poverty reduction. As is evident, our project uses two key ideas to structure our research, namely the spatial periphery of cities in Africa and, the idea of lived experience. Spatial peripheries are not necessarily places of economic, political or cultural marginality. They may be places of economic opportunity and innovation. They are however often poorly understood as attention has focused on more established and spatially central locations, or on edge-cities relying on American-based theories. Furthermore, case-based and comparative detailed empirical investigation is lacking. Our proposed research offers careful investigation into actual processes of change in specific cities in Africa. The focus on lived experience directs attention to the people who occupy the spaces along the spatial edges of African cities recognising that some residents live in these spaces out of choice, whereas others, however, have been coerced there through state or market actions. This idea of the lived experience of spatial change draws on significant intellectual threads in fields including urban studies, geography and planning theory, urban anthropology and sociology, and is concerned with how people live in places, including how they work, eat, parent (Meth 2013), love and die.  It uses a mix of qualitative methods (including interviewing, diaries and auto-photography) to understand everyday life on the periphery. In addition the project uses key informant interviews, surveys, document analysis and mapping to understand the characteristics and drivers of changes, and also the governance and poverty implications of these urban changes. This project draws on the expertise of staff at Wits and Sheffield University, as well as the GCRO in Gauteng, and EDRI and ECSU in Addis Ababa, and benefits from a strong existing collaborative relationship, outlined below. The project expects to deliver: 8 academic papers, 3 working papers, pamphlets and posters to inform dissemination events; present at a minimum of 4 conferences; hold 7 dissemination workshops; and develop and sustain a project website and other media platforms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project compares across cases within and between three city-regions and the specific objective is to understand how urban change in the peripheries of African cities, focusing on infrastructural investments and economic change, is shaped, governed and experienced, and how these processes then impact on urban poverty.  We pose six research questions to explore this objective:  1. What are the main characteristics of economic transformation and infrastructural change (with a focus on housing and transport) in the case study areas over the past fifteen years?  2. Which organisations, institutions and processes have driven and resourced these changes, how can these be explained and theorised and what is their significance for inclusive urban development?  3. What governance, economic and poverty-alleviation mechanisms exist to shape these infrastructural and economic changes? How robust are they? 4. How are these urban changes experienced by different residents of urban peripheries within the case study areas taking gender, age, class, ethnicity and national origin into account? 5. What are the comparative lived experiences in urban peripheries, particularly in terms of mobility, rootedness, prosperity and conflict, access to employment, welfare and services, and what are the consequences of these experiences for urban poverty?  6. What are the implications of such drivers and experiences of urban change for reducing urban poverty and improving urban inclusion and welfare for residents?</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-02-10" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-03">31748.38</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-03">160211.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-03">124150.24</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-03">84655.85</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-03">14026796.49</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_N014111_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sheffield</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FN014111%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-02-10"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
