<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R005397_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONNECTED - COmmunity Network for africaN vECTor borne plant viruses</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CONNECTED - COmmunity Network for africaN vECTor borne plant viruses     Director ~ Prof Gary D. Foster : University of Bristol Co-Director ~ Prof Neil Boonham : University of Newcastle/Fera   Sub Saharan Africa is the poorest region of the world and vector-borne diseases (VBDs) are one of the most significant constraints for production of staple and cash crops, for example cassava (CBSV and CMD), sweet potato (SPVD), maize (MLN) and potato (PVY). Limiting production causes poverty, food insecurity, malnutrition and prevents economic and social development. Emergence of new virus diseases in combination with climate change, resource limitations and a growing population will impact the region sooner and more significantly than other parts of the world and is of global significance. The network seeks to directly improve the food security and livelihoods of people in Sub-Saharan Africa by pump priming a large number of innovative research activities with the ultimate aim of growing the ones with greatest regional impact into larger activities within the three years of the project.    Objectives   1. To build a sustainable and long lasting Network of multi-disciplinary international scientists, to address the problems created by plant virus VBDs   2. To run a series of activities to promote and embed interdisciplinary working and to strengthen research capacity, capabilities and methodologies particularly focused on the vectors of plant disease   3. To use pump-priming funding for a range of innovative projects identified by the Management Board of CONNECTED ultimately leading to more competitive, collaborative, cross-disciplinary and integrative research proposals, as well as real impact   4. To capacity build, via improved communication and collaboration networks, seminars &amp; workshops, and training courses both in the UK and Africa   5. To develop early stage researchers, by focusing part of the pump-primed funding on proposals submitted by them, provide support to enable proposal development and delivery of projects.   6. To support collaboration between researchers in the UK and LMICs and engagement with end-users, stakeholders and policy makers   7. To provide legacy benefits from the network by facilitating the opportunity for further funding for the projects bringing the greatest impact to the region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We propose a network in Vector Borne Disease (VBD) Research focusing on improved control of Plant Viruses, namely &apos;CONNECTED&apos; - COmmunity Network for africaN vECTor borne plant viruses.  Our focus is Sub Saharan Africa, one of the poorest regions of the world and in which VBDs create highly significant constraints for production of staple and cash crops, for example cassava (cassava brown streak and mosaic diseases), sweet potato (sweet potato virus disease), maize (maize lethal necrosis) and yam (badnaviruses and yam mosaic virus diseases). Limiting production causes poverty, food insecurity, and malnutrition, which in turn prevents economic and social development. Emergence of new VBDs in combination with climate change, resource limitations and a growing population will impact this region sooner and more significantly than other parts of the world and is of global significance.  More effective agricultural research communities producing a pipeline of innovative disease control strategies are needed to increase agricultural productivity, improve incomes and market participation for smallholder farmers. &apos;CONNECTED&apos; seeks to improve livelihoods of people in Sub-Saharan Africa by, firstly, engaging with established networks, stakeholders and funders in the region to focus and refine the most pressing research targets, preventing overlap with existing activities and targeting the work of the network to ensure UK academic excellence has maximum impact. Secondly, &apos;CONNECT&apos; will pump prime a number of targeted innovative activities to generate tangible outputs in the short term, provide capacity building and training for virologists and other beneficiaries in the region. Finally, we will focus on growing &apos;CONNECTED&apos; beyond researchers and other practitioners, to policy makers, funders, extension services, and certification schemes to generate a forum for knowledge exchange and sustainable activity in the field of VBD, ensuring UK academic excellence targets its research to deliver regional development impact beyond the three years of the project.  CONNECTED has assembled an inter-disciplinary management board with an independent chair, an experienced management team and effective governance structure.  Every member has active collaborations in Sub Saharan Africa working on diverse but complementary aspects of VBD control, ensuring the work undertaken is relevant, novel and utilises academic excellence most efficiently. We have board members from five significant research institutes in East and West Africa (IITA, KALRO, KEPHIS, AATF and NARO), providing the focus for the network activities within three Lower Middle Income Countries as defined by OECD&apos;s Development Assistance Committee, namely Kenya, Uganda and Nigeria. We have leading experts on VBD as well as specialists in sustainability, social and environmental sciences, impact, learning, evaluation and inter-disciplinarity. Our board covers not just academic research organisations, but policy, extension and certification within the region, so as to not just focus on research excellence, but to deliver long lasting impact in the region. The board has identified five key areas where &apos;CONNECTED&apos; will benefit sustainable VBD control: 1. Control strategies, 2. Vector biology, 3 New Diseases, 4. Vector/Virus Interactions, 5. Diagnostics/Surveillance/Forecasting; as identified by the ODA relevance statement.  The board has decided to focus beyond specific single crop VBDs to include all VBDs of importance to African smallholders.  To date international investment has focused predominantly on specific VBDs (e.g. in cassava and sweet potato) with some neglected and emerging VBDs (e.g. in yams, maize and beans) remaining under-researched.  A major aim of CONNECTED will be to connect UK and African experts to pull together knowledge across crops, disciplines and regions to have maximum impact on food security from the mixed cropping systems important to smallholders.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-03" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Botswana</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-31">426403.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-31">571991.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-31">239583.35</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-31">192595.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-05-31"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-05-31">1719466.77</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF Standard Grant Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_R005397_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FR005397%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-07-03"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
