<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T037822_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Systems thinking approach to developing an integrated and patient-centred intervention model for multimorbidity care in primary care settings in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Multimorbidity is the existence of multiple long-term mental, physical, and cognitive disorders in one patient. These could include diabetes, hypertension, lung diseases, heart attacks, stroke, kidney failure, and liver problems or other conditions. Multimorbid conditions can share common disease causes and consequences. The rate of multimorbidity is rapidly increasing in low resource countries (low and middle-income countries - LMIC) such as India. Importantly, multimorbidity leads to reduction in quality of life, increase in use of health services and reduction in life expectancy. However, in management of multimorbidity, it is often considered as an assortment of disconnected diseases. Hence patients with multimorbidity receive less than optimal care.  A concerted effort from the health system for re-orienting the delivery of primary care is important in improving the quality of life of people with multiple chronic conditions. Our proposed study in primary care settings of Kerala, India will try to better understand the complexity of workforce strengths, system capabilities, human behaviours, link to social resources and their interactions most aptly framed from a health system perspective in developing an innovative and patient centred model for management of multimorbidity. We will adopt the following steps: 1. We will use different qualitative (discussions and observations) methods to investigate what is currently happening in our health facilities with services that multimorbidity patients receive. In this way we will understand the perceptions of health system managers, health care providers and patients in terms of the barriers and facilitators of provision of care for patients with multiple long-term (chronic) conditions.  2. We will identify successful models of interventions for managing multimorbidity in other settings by conducting a comprehensive review of available literature.  3. We will use this literature review and data from our research to develop context specific interventions for managing multimorbidity in primary care settings. Additionally, we will explore ways in which the care for people with multiple chronic conditions can be organised and integrated within the community through community health workers.  4. We will then use methods to visualise how different variables in a system are interrelated (causal loop model) and identify how changes in one variable affects others in the loop.  5. We will identify options for improving access to social resources (eg: accessibility for physical activity for females, rehabilitation services etc.,) for managing multimorbidity, which can then be incorporated into the intervention models developed in step 3 and 4.  6. Further, we will identify interventions that potentially have a more direct impact on patients, prioritise them and finalise them after incorporating comments from all stakeholders as in step 1.  7. Finally, materials and protocols will be developed for prioritised intervention items. Optimal involvement of clinical and health system leadership, engagement of all potential stakeholders including patients in the intervention development are unique to this project.  Finally, a detailed plan will be developed for formal evaluation of the developed intervention in a confirmatory study in future. The key lessons from this project may help to transform the current health-care delivery system into a patient-centered and coordinated system for managing multimorbidity in primary care.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Our main hypothesis is that in the context of recent expansion of the health workforce and re-organisation of primary care delivery in India, a better understanding of the complexity of workforce strengths, system capabilities, human behaviors and their interactions most aptly framed from a systems-thinking perspective may help to develop an innovative model for management of multimorbidity in primary care settings in India.   The overarching goal of the proposed study is to investigate how a systems thinking approach and causal loop modelling can support decision making in developing an integrated, patient-centred and multi-level intervention for managing multi-morbidity in primary care settings in India.  A casual loop model provides a real visual means of articulating our understanding of the relationship or connections between the most salient variables that affect a given behavior or problem (eg., re-organisation of primary care for management of multimorbidity). Additionally, the feedback loops (both positive and negative feeds backs, which acts as reinforcing and balancing forces in a system, respectively) in causal modelling provide the opportunity to explore the anticipated and unanticipated effects of intervening on these variables at different levels as well as the impact of change from one variable to another.   The specific objectives are as follows;  1. To identify potential interventions for integrated patient-centred and multi-level intervention for management of multi-morbidity in primary care settings through literature review.    We hypothesise that multi-level interventions implemented in other settings as identified in the systematic review may be relevant in primary care settings of Kerala, India.   2. To understand the perceptions of various stakeholders (providers, patients, care givers, health care administrators) in terms of the need and possibility of reorganisation of care for management of multimorbidity in primary care.   We hypothesise that positive and negative provider, patient, care-giver, health administrator and health system level characteristics, and practices, influence multimorbidity management in LMIC settings.   3. To develop a causal loop model to support prospective planning of intervention for optimal management of multi-morbidity.   We hypothesise that causal loop modelling will identify potential variables (facilitators/barriers) that improve quality of care and process outcomes of multimorbidity care in LMIC settings.  4. To prioritise interventions for managing multimorbidity in primary care settings and develop appropriate intervention tools for future evaluation in confirmatory trials.   We hypothesise that resource constraints, operational feasibility, and cultural issues of the identified interventions and their tools for implementation may hamper the delivery of some components of the intervention. We further hypothesise that prioritising the interventions based on the appropriateness of the identified intervention tools and health system context will influence management of multimorbidity.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-06-30"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-06-30">192173.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">FQ1 2021-2022 spend on Systems thinking approach to developing an integrated and patient-centred intervention model for multimorbidity care in primary care settings in India</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T037822_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-05-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-05-01">191921.58</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T037822/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT037822%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
