<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_P014674_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ultrafine and Submicron Particles in the Urban Environment in Thailand - Size, Concentration, Composition and Health Impacts</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">It is well known that particulate matter (PM) poses a significant health risk, especially to urban dwellers, with often the poorest in society most affected. Ultrafine particles (size smaller than 100 nanometres), as a component of PM, are increasingly implicated in disease and mortality. However, much of the research available in the literature is based on data from the developed world, especially for ultrafine particles, and without robust data it is not possible to determine trends in this important pollutant for Thailand and Bangkok in particular, and strategies for health protection therefore lack this vital information. In addition, aerosol particles provide the single largest source of uncertainty in most global climate models, and production of primary particles and gas precursors e.g. Volatile Organic Compounds (VOCs) from the transport and industrial sectors contribute significantly to this. Therefore, in order for the impact of these activities on climate to be assessed and reduced, determination of sources and levels of emission of both gases and particles much be undertaken. This study will to our knowledge be the first to report ultrafine particle (UFP) number concentration and size distributions in the submicron (smaller than 1 micrometre) size range in urban Bangkok, Thailand. Population in this megacity is expected to rise as urbanisation continues in Thailand, with more people exposed to higher levels of gas and particle pollutants. We will carry out an extensive experimental campaign combining particle concentration, size distribution measurement and sampling with precise laboratory analysis for the particle composition, state-of-the-art atmospheric tracer dispersion experiments and modelling and source apportionment techniques to establish the sources, emission factors, human exposures and inhalation doses for this important health risk. We will undertake work in the three main seasons in Thailand (cool dry, hot dry and rainy) to determine how the climate influences particle size distribution and properties. We will also examine other regional particle source events, such as agricultural fires, visiting rural areas in and out of season for these events to determine their impact on particle concentrations. We aim to provide methodological advances in using non-standard instrumentation for size-segregated airborne particle sampling and for estimation of submicron particle size distributions using cheaper devices than are presently available. By obtaining this new information on typical levels in a variety of microenvironments, in different regions and by identifying sources and emissions factors, direct public health advice on exposure reduction through interventions could be achieved, and first steps taken to engage regulatory bodies and government agencies to aid in their target of reducing particulate pollution to improve the health and quality of life of Thailand and Bangkok residents, and hence reducing the significant current economic cost burden to the Thailand government associated with adverse health impact of particulates.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The key research questions to be addressed are, in order of priority 1. What are typical particle number concentrations and size distributions in several relevant exposure scenarios (roadside, urban background, rural including during burning events, industrial, in transit via different transport modes) during each of the three main seasons in Thailand (summer, winter and rain)? 2. In which (submicron) particle sizes are potentially toxic metals found, and how will this influence received dose via inhalation (compared with other routes e.g. ingestion in diet or drinking water)? 3. Are models describing atmospheric dispersion on the ~ km scale in European cities valid for Bangkok, and if not what modifications are required? What are the implications for pollution dispersal (or deliberate release events) and human exposure? 4. What are typical atmospheric electrical parameters in Bangkok, and can they be used as a proxy for submicron aerosol concentrations? Target deliverables include: Quantification of the metal constituents found in particles of different sizes down to the ultrafine (&lt; 100 nm) range and determination of likely sources; Assessment of the relative importance of inhalation exposure compared with other routes of entry into the human body; Methodological recommendations for using Electrical Low Pressure Impactor or similar devices in conjunction with chemical speciation of samples; Comprehensive, new data set describing particle number concentrations in exposure and transport micro-environments within Bangkok; Comparison between co-pollutants in terms of personal exposures and by reference to static monitoring data; Recommendations to public and health protection officials on exposure reduction strategies; First experimental measurements of atmospheric plume dispersion in SE Asia megacity; Tailored model to Bangkok describing pollutant dispersal from point and line sources; Possible extension to first experimental assessment of OH radical concentration in SE Asia megacity; Novel measurements of atmospheric electricity parameters in a South East Asian city; Recommendation (or otherwise) for cheaper alternatives for ambient submicron particle monitoring.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-05-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="TH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thailand</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-03">116063.4</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-03">117003.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-03">8390407.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Newton Fund Award to University of Bristol</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_P014674_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FP014674%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-05-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
