<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004509_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Protracted Displacement Economies</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Around the world refugees and displaced people remain in limbo, unable to return home, unwanted where they are living and facing increasing difficulties to go anywhere else. The majority of refugees in the world have been in these situations for more than five years, a threshold usually referred to as &apos;protracted&apos;. As crises become prolonged, the limitations of the humanitarian response have long been recognised as insufficient and inadequate. Refugees and Internally Displaced People caught up in these protracted situations often speak of watching their lives &apos;draining away&apos;. The model of support offered to displaced people is known by the UN refugee agency (UNHCR) as &apos;care and maintenance&apos; but perhaps more accurately by advocates of a radical change to this policy as the &apos;warehousing&apos; of refugees. Global policy interest is shifting from short term humanitarianism to longer term development focused responses to protracted displacement. This was most recently indicated by the Global Compact on Refugees, in December 2018. The Refugee Compact introduces positive language around the long-term self reliance of refugees. This project responds to this renewed political will to find new solutions to protracted displacement and builds on a large body of research and advocacy work in this area. The project investigates the replacement of the care and maintenance model with a new approach: the protracted displacement economy.  The protracted displacement economy introduces two key innovations that will contribute to this original analysis as well the potential for impact. First, it is a whole of society approach. The focus is not just on displaced people but the &apos;displacement affected community&apos;, that includes the heterogeneous &apos;host&apos; population, amongst others. The second key innovation is a fundamental shift in the understanding of the transactions that drive the protracted displacement economy. Financial transactions are the stuff of most economic analysis, yet key human interactions and exchanges or gifts, collective organisation, care work and mutual aid are largely non-financial.  Research will involve ten countries, five pairs of countries each separated by an international border: The Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC)/Uganda, Ethiopia/Somalia, Lebanon/Syria, Myanmar/Thailand, Pakistan/Afghanistan.These ten countries encompass the most serious protracted displacement crises in the world. Research will be conducted with partners in one of each pair of countries and will be attentive to the cross-border dynamics of the protracted displacement economy. International partners are: The University of Kinshasa (DRC), The University of Addis Ababa (Ethiopia), the NGOs Basmeh &amp; Zeitooneh and Sawa (Lebanon), the think tank Covenant Institute (Myanmar) and the University of Peshawar (Pakistan). In each of these five countries, three locations will be selected for empirical research, including at least one urban neighbourhood and at least one camp in each country. Over three years, these 15 locations will be involved in community discussions, large scale surveys and qualitative interviews. Key stakeholders in this process from further afield will be involved in regular meetings so that every stage in the research is informed by relevant expertise. The project will introduce the completely new approach of video narratives, training groups of people in each location to produce five minute videos of the protracted displacement economy that will then be dubbed and shared across all research sites.  These films contribute to a wide range of innovative outputs that highlight the operation of the protracted displacement economy. Displaced people develop their own economic activities, including non-financial practices such as sharing and mutual aid as well as entrepreneurial activities. With time, community organisations begin to thrive. The project aims to support this process so that displaced people are able to look to the future with hope.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project responds to four of the key questions identified in the call:  1. How can refugees and/or IDPs become self-reliant and contribute to local economies and cultures and to the development of the communities hosting them?;  2. How can livelihood activities and socio-economic pathways for the protracted displaced be linked to local and national development priorities in host countries and regions to provide both viable economic opportunities for the displaced and development benefits for host communities and hosting regions?;  3. How can cities/urban areas where large numbers of protracted displaced people are arriving or residing, adapt their municipal planning systems to create opportunities for everyone?;  4. How does gendered access to services, economic and cultural opportunities and levels of power influence differently the experiences, opportunities and limitations of men and women?  These questions have directed our focus to the Protracted Displacement Economy. They structure the research objectives and the research design.  The project has four main objectives: a) The fundamental aim of the research is to define the Protracted Displacement Economy and explore the very different forms that it takes in different displacement contexts. This involves a detailed account of the main actors involved, the way financial flows are directed and managed, but also the opportunities for non-financial transactions, which typically account for the most important elements of sustainability. This requires a gendered analysis that is attentive to power dynamics at a variety of scales, and locates displaced people in the social and political context of the neighbourhoods they have lived in for at least the previous five years. Research will also consider the role played by the border within Protracted Displacement Economies for both refugees and IDPs.   b) Significant steps towards sustainability are already taking place in all of the research locations. Research will recognise these existing actions and highlight best practice examples which support long term solutions and ensure that the entire displacement affected community is able to benefit from the resources they attract.  c) Detailed research with displaced people and discussions with a wide range of stakeholders will help to identify and analyse the factors which encourage successful and inclusive activities and relations in Protracted Displacement Economies. This will lead to a consideration of the barriers to more sustainable practices. d) The final object is focused on impact. Examine and communicate how these barriers to more sustainable practices can be overcome using best practice examples and build capacity to ensure that members of displacement affected communities have the skills to communicate successes and difficulties themselves.   Research has been organised around impact, these four objectives lead to four related impact targets:  1. Recognise what is currently being done by displaced people. Much valuable development work goes unrecognised and unfunded, at least by international donors, and recognition may lead to support and programme to take account of this 2. Even years after displacement, a vital step is to improve connections between displaced people and &apos;host&apos; communities 3. Existing efforts to promote self-reliance are mostly focused at the market and are widely criticised as motivated more by a desire to save money. There needs to be significant change to existing market-based solutions, including genuine support for emerging initiatives and the more effective use of procurement to support emerging business and act as a &apos;humanitarian anchor&apos; 4. Finally, since most support is not financial, it is important to recognise and facilitate non-market activities, care work, emotional support and mutual aid. These four targets have informed the organisation of research, the framing of questions and the overall impact strategy.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Democratic Republic of the Congo</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-07">205143.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-07">433204.41</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-07">213805.79</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-07">406098.17</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-07">2545358.088</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to University of Sussex</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T004509_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT004509%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
