<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_R012865_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK-China partnership on Global Food Security: Combating avian tumor diseases for sustainable poultry production</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Infectious diseases result in direct and indirect losses at various steps of poultry farming and amongst them neoplastic disease caused by viruses is a major economic problem faced by the poultry industry worldwide. The oncogenic viruses causing neoplastic infection in chickens are herpesviruses comprising of Marek&apos;s disease virus (MDV) and retroviruses comprising of reticuloendotheliosis virus (REV) and avian leucosis virus (ALV). ALV is the most common naturally occurring avian retrovirus that can cause a variety of neoplastic disease conditions in chickens. In addition to causing neoplasia, ALV is known to be associated with reduced productivity and other production problems in affected flocks.  Based on the properties of viral envelope glycoproteins, ALV is classified into six subgroups: A, B, C, D, E and J.  Originally isolated by the Pirbright Institute in the late 1980s, ALV-J spreads widely and induces myeloid leukosis and a broad spectrum of additional disorders, such as histiocytic sarcoma, hemangiomas and erythroblastosis. The original strains have almost been eradicated from most of the commercial poultry flocks in Europe and the United States but in Asia, the virus evolved into a great variety and recently emerging Chinese isolates coarsely induce various tumours in both commercial laying hen flocks as well as native Chinese breeds of chickens. Defining the molecular background of the tumorigenesisis is needed to develop more effective control and eradication programmes in China. In this proposal, we aim to obtain detailed comprehensive picture on the molecular events to understand and predict the molecular pathways to ALV-J induced cancer. This includes non-coding RNA profiling for the role of non-coding RNAs in ALV-J induced oncogenesis, oncogene myc targetome identification and the role of myc-binding in maintaining the transformed phenotype and myc knockout by CRISPR/Cas9 system for the role of myc in maintaining the transformed phenotype. As the co-infection of ALV-J with other tumor viruses such as Marek&apos;s disease virus and Reticuloendotheliosis virus is very common and caused more serious pathogenic effects, we are going to elucidate the synergistic mechanism of ALV-J+REV/ALV-J+MDV co-infection in vitro and in vivo. The findings will be very valuable in developing new approaches for the eradication of ALV-J in China and control of cancers caused by oncogenic viruses. We also want to establish the resistant cell line by editing ALV-J receptor NHE1 using CRISPR/Cas9 system to explore genetic resistant to ALV-J. Finally, we will develop the rapid diagnostic kits to detect ALV-J infection in the field to aid the ALV-J control and eradication in China.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">23231.3</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">125288.33</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">137085.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">68958.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Avian leukosis viruses (ALV) are retroviruses associated with the induction of tumours of haemopoietic cells in birds. Although diseases due to ALV have largely been controlled in Europe and USA through successful eradication programmes, it continues to be a major problem in many countries including China, where it has caused serious economic losses in recent years. In particular, myeloid leukosis and other tumours due to ALV-J remains a major disease that threatens the Chinese poultry industry. A concerted approach is needed to better understand several aspects of the diseases that will lead to novel intervention strategies. Having reported the first isolation of the novel ALV-J subgroup and implemented the successful eradication programme in the UK, Pirbright has a long history of working with this virus. Pirbright also has extensive collaborations with a number of Chinese Institutes through Newton Funded UK-China Centre of Excellence for Research on Avian Diseases (UK-China CERAD) for developing effective strategies for controlling avian diseases. This proposal aims to bring the expertise together to further strengthen UK-China collaboration in avian disease research to develop novel sustainable strategies of control of this disease and aid Global Food security.   Our specific aims are to:  1: Dissecting the molecular pathways of ALV-J pathogenesis including &quot;The role of non-coding RNAs in host-ALV-J cross-talk in chicken macrophages &quot; and &quot;The role of Myc gene in ALV-J induced oncogenesis&quot;.  2: Inducing genetic resistance to ALV-J infection by generation of resistant cell line against ALV-J infection using CRISPR/Cas9 genome editing system  3: Mechanism of synergistic interaction of tumor virus coinfection including &quot;Mechanism of synergistic interaction of ALV-J and REV infection&quot; and &quot;Mechanism of synergistic interaction of ALV-J and MDV infection&quot;,  4: Development of rapid diagnostics tools on ALV-J including &quot;Development of gp85 antigen and antibody CGICS&quot; and &quot;Development of RPA for ALV-J detection&quot;."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
