<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S003274_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">[Indonesia] Extreme rainfall and its effects on flood risk in Indonesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia suffers from severe flood risk due to a combination of its climate (intense monsoon rainfalls), geography (steep mountains and rivers) and the mega-cities built at the outlet of rivers.  This risk is already severe and it is feared it will become worse as climate change takes affect and the population of the cities grows even larger with uncontrolled development.  When floods strike, they are often the combination of several sources: high river flows, intense rainfall on impermeable ground in cities and storm surges from the sea.  Even worse, they often affect several cities and towns at once - stretching emergency responses and disaster recovery even further.  The project aims to understand how these flood events happen so that planning and mitigation strategies can be developed. This understanding includes:  - when floods occur, and what warning can be given - what controls the spatial extent  (how many cities may be damaged at once) - how large the river flows can be and how often they happen - what effect land use (deforestation, urbanisation) has on the size and speed of floods - how the flood size and frequency of occurrence may change in the future  - how much damage is caused in cities by the floods Strategies to manage the flood risk will be informed by better understanding, and may take the form of: - better insurance cover - better warning systems for areas likely to be flooded - changing and controlling land use - building flood diversions, defences, or detention reservoirs The approach being taken for the research is to use computer models of rainfall, climate, river flows and cities, so that the effects of different floods and management strategies can be simulated safely. The project team is therefore made up of experts in meteorology, climate change, hydrology and computer modelling.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The project addresses the following Research Challenges: RC1. What are the key large scale atmospheric circulation and SST controls on rainfall: intensity, extremes, seasonality and spatial pattern?  RC2. What evidence is there for change (past and future) in rainfall and flood flows, and if the existing observational database of rainfall and floods is inadequate, how can this be improved using remote sensing and statistical methods?  RC3. What constitutes a representative extreme rainfall event set for multiple Indonesian cities/basins, which can be used for emergency planning as well as (re-)insurance purposes?  How does this relate to Area-Intensity-Duration-Frequency curves?  RC4. How well can we reproduce and understand large flood events affecting Indonesian cities using innovative, physics-based hydrological and hydrodynamic models?  RC5. What effects do land use change and management exert on this flood risk, and what structural and non-structural flood mitigation strategies are appropriate?  A number of objectives are identified: 1. To develop and make available a geospatial catalogue of selected extreme events and of extreme precipitation characteristics (IDF curves, area reduction information) for major parts of Indonesia, together with a supporting methodology, applicable for whole of Indonesia. 2. To generate a large storm event set (100,000 years) of daily (and 3 hour disaggregated) spatial rainfall fields for the whole of Indonesia. To carry out regional IDF and AIDF analysis based on this synthetic event set, with spatial joint probability for key cities for re-insurance assessment. 3. To develop validated catchment models for the significant basins in Indonesia; carry out simulations of major observed historic floods; use these models to generate a spatially dependent stochastic flood discharge event set (100,000 year equivalent) for use in flood risk assessment.  4. To develop inundation models for all major Indonesian cities, representing topographic surfaces and major flow effects from artificial management.   5. To estimate potential economic losses due to flood hazard for major cities. Example mitigation and adaptation strategies (structural and non-structural) will be developed for strengthening flood resilience and reducing flood risk</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-11-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">61533.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">123565.96</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">93299.54</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">31267.36</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-10"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-10">9677233.696</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed - International Award to Newcastle University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_S003274_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newcastle University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FS003274%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
