<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004177_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sri Lanka Research Network. Archaeology and Heritage in the North West.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research Network Objectives: 1 Bring together academics and representatives of the Sri Lankan Department of Archaeology (policy makers) in a series of meetings and site visits to explore the use of archaeology and heritage in new and challenging ways in Northwestern (NW) Sri Lanka  2 Use the network as the springboard for co-creating an archaeology and heritage project based in NW Sri Lanka 3 Meet with representatives from CSOs, NGOs, and community groups working in NW Sri Lanka to ensure issues of relevance to local communities are understood and given weight 4 Involve post-doctoral researchers and post-graduate students in meetings and sites visits and explore approaches to heritage training 5 Raise awareness of the potential of post-conflict archaeology and heritage have in wider academic and practical contexts    The aim of this Research Network is to bring together a core group of UK and Sri Lankan academics and practitioners from the related disciplines of archaeology and heritage to explore the use of archaeology in heritage initiatives.  Of particular relevance in the context of NW Sri Lanka is the need to find new methods for engaging post-conflict (often displaced) communities with local archaeology and heritage.  The challenge of the network will be to explore diversity in heritage that augments the current focus on monumental World Heritage sites of the early historic period. This heritage has national and international reach and sustains a substantial industry but over-rides more local, recent and everyday heritage.  A key objective is to use the network as a springboard to co-create a new research project based in the north western region of Sri Lanka, to be Co-directed by colleagues from UK and Sri Lanka. This project will build on the collaborative relationships created within the network and will address research and impact agendas that emerge from the network dialogues through field activities in the NW region focussed on the later historic period (c. 1200-1948).  Carrying out archaeological fieldwork in the neglected NW province will contribute to new understandings of the more recent past, and allow new heritages to be constructed by different communities as well as academics and heritage professionals.  Research questions and appropriate methodologies will be the result of discussions within the network.  Extending beyond the core academic group within the network, we recognise the critical importance of working with NGOs, CSOs and community groups to develop useful and appropriate methods to ensure that we engage with communities to identify their heritage understandings and needs.  Working with groups outside academia will allow us to explore effective methodologies for the process of heritage engagement with marginalised communities (which may be applicable in other post-conflict settings).  In turn,  local groups will be able to explore the potential of heritage for use in initiatives aimed at building stronger, stable and sustainable communities through greater understanding of multiple and shared heritages.   Our fourth objective is to offer new researchers and graduate students opportunities to be involved in the network.  In Sri Lanka, students from the Post-Graduate Institute of Archaeological Research (PGIAR, directed by the Co-applicant) will be included in meetings and site visits, allowing them to share their views and ideas with more senior academics and specialist from non-academic organisations.  Similarly in the UK, new researchers and students will be involved in meetings and site visits.   Post-conflict archaeology and heritage is an emerging area of interest, with considerable academic and practical value.  Finding ways to help re-build stable and strong communities after conflict is a major global challenge, and exploring ways in which archaeology and heritage can contribute to supporting understandings of diversity in heritages is a valuable tool in meeting this challenge.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We aim to create a research network between the UK and Sri Lanka to bring together archaeology and heritage academics and professionals, new researchers and graduate students, and representatives of NGOs, CSOs, and community groups, to develop dialogues that address challenges in the relevance and application of archaeology and heritage. This network will be a platform for building a new research project, allowing cross-disciplinary opportunities to co-create research that is relevant both to academics and to wider communities in Sri Lanka. Sri Lankan heritage is currently heavily oriented towards World Heritage sites of the early historic period, and a major challenge for the network is to explore ways to diversify this agenda. Of special interest to the network are heritages of the everyday and the more recent past, and finding approaches that value and privilege these in addition to the authorised heritage is a significant challenge. We believe there is space to offer different and multiple understandings of heritage in Sri Lanka, and want to use the research network to think through the value of working in the later historical period (i.e. 1200-1948) and exploring, recording and presenting heritages of everyday lives/people and places. This network is an ideal forum in which to discuss potential research themes within this framework, such as issues of contact and trade, the impact of movements and migrations, human-environment relationships and the ways these can be understood through material culture.   As well as discussing these issues within an academic context, we will use the network to build contacts beyond academia and extend the dialogue on the relevance of archaeology and heritage to a wider community. We believe this is particularly important in areas such as the Northwest of Sri Lanka (which will be the spatial focus for the Network), where post-conflict communities are working to find a sense of place and belonging.  Being able to network effectively with representatives from CSOs and NGOs that work locally means that the network will benefit from their ground-based knowledge and experience which will help shape approaches to understanding how archaeology and heritage could be important for communities, and support the creation of identity. This type of networking is also an excellent opportunity for non-academic groups to learn about what we do, and draw on it where useful to support and expand their own work. A good example of this from other contexts is work in London where psychologists have found that fine arts can be hugely helpful for recent refugees suffering trauma.    The network will hold two major meetings. The first in the UK to enable Sri Lankan participants to visit and experience venues that focus on everyday heritage of the more recent past and to meet heritage practitioners, teachers and academics. The second in Sri Lanka will extend the dialogue in an open forum meeting in Colombo and also spend time in the Northwest meeting local groups, sharing experiences and exploring potential research questions.  This network will include young researchers in discussions that have the potential to shape the ways in which archaeology and heritage are practiced in Sri Lanka. The Post Graduate Institute of Archaeological Research (PGIAR) is the only PG training institution in the discipline in Sri Lanka, and so has a pivotal role in training the university lecturers and practitioners of tomorrow. With the PGIAR as a partner in this network, their students will be able to join agenda-setting discussions with their primary partner, the Sri Lankan Department of Archaeological Survey, and help co-create an archaeology and heritage project that will put new principles and research aims into practice. Sri Lankan and UK researchers and students will also be able to participate in site visits and subsequent analyses in their respective countries, and network with senior academic and non-academic colleagues.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-29" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="LK" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Sri Lanka</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-10">16913.95</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-10">16913.96</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">16913.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004177_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">16913.96</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004177_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Leicester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
