<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_P003052_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton RCUK-CONACYT Cost-efficient and radiation-tolerant pixel detectors for ionising radiation based on thin-film technology</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Thin-film technology (TFT) has many advantages over classical techniques for single crystal growth and integrated circuit design and is today used in everyday appliances like computer/TV screens and solar cells. The idea of the proposed project is to put this technology to use in a new regime - large-area cost-efficient detectors for ionising radiation - and to ensure that Mexico is enabled to develop and produce such detectors for future high-profile projects in big science.  Up to now, tracking detectors for high-energy physics have been manufactured using non-standard silicon planar technology on small wafers leading to high cost and limited availability. The LHC upgrades require large areas (100s-1000s m2) of radiation-tolerant semiconductor detectors. Cost-efficiency is the key to being able to instrument large areas and volumes with the available budget - while higher granularity of detectors is instrumental to improving the physics reach of the LHC experiments in view of the large number of pile-up interactions taking place (up to 400 at any given bunch crossing).   Thin-film based detectors might be a way to accommodate both goals as the use of established low-cost, large-area processes known from solar cells is up to 2 orders of magnitude cheaper than state-of-the-art growth method for float-zone silicon wafers. As this approach for pixel detectors is novel, it is a unique opportunity for Mexico to establish world-leading expertise and lead future pixel detector construction efforts in big science projects such as the LHC upgrade.  Beyond thin-film deposition methods to create substrates in the photovoltaic industry, thin-film technology is also used to create field-effect transistors, e.g. in TFT screens. Recent developments in thin-film transistors suggest that it might be possible to manufacture the first pre-amplifier stage necessary for a charge-collecting semiconductor detector in thin-film technology &quot;on top&quot; of the charge collection volume - which has been created by thin-film technology as well. The concept of in-pixel amplification has been first established in so-called HV-CMOS detectors and allows the use of very thin sensor layers (down to about 20 um), which is advantageous for material budget, production cost and radiation tolerance.  The first step of this proposal is to design, produce, irradiate and characterise passive TFT-sensors that could replace today&apos;s planar silicon pixel sensors. In a second step, electronic circuits in thin-film technology will be studied and added on top of the pixels to amplify and possibly discriminate particle hits. The ultimate goal is to obtain monolithic active pixel sensors (MAPS). Base materials under investigation will be GaAs, GaN and c-SiTF.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-08-14"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-13" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="MX" type="MEXICO"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CENTRAL AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1032</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-03">101873.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-03">136656.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-08-03">68743.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The main objectives of the proposed research project are   1. To assess the suitability of thin-film processes for the growth of cost-efficient and radiation-tolerant substrates for tracking detectors for LHC upgrade projects in big science, utilising the expertise present with GaAs at Lancaster University, with GaN at CINVESTAV and with ZnO at BUAP.  2. To create passive sensors from such substrates and characterise them in the laboratory, connect them to LHC-compatible readout chips and characterise them in beam tests. 2.1 To irradiate such passive sensors to realistic LHC doses and fluences with different particles and re-evaluate their performance in the lab and in beam tests.  3. To investigate the suitability of thin-film transistors fabricated in GaAs, GaN and ZnO processes for charge-sensitive pre-amplifiers. 3.1 To irradiate such transistors and circuits to realistic LHC doses and fluences with different particles and re-evaluate their performance in the lab  4. To create active sensors using thin-film substrates and thin-film transistor based preamplifiers and characterise them in the lab and in beam tests 4.1 To irradiate such active sensors to realistic LHC doses and fluences with different particles and re-evaluate their performance in the lab and in beam tests.  5. To evaluate the possibility of transferring the know-how and process experience from the participating academic institutions to industrial partners from Mexico&apos;s growing electronics industry that is well-known for producing LCD panels."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
