<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007923_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Elephant conservation and indigenous experiences in Cambodia: Shaping environmental awareness through participatory filmmaking with young people</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The first and primary objective of the proposed project is to contribute to and build the capacity of a new generation of agents of change in Cambodia, in order to facilitate the delivery of creative arts-led impacts around urgent sustainable development challenges in Cambodia.  This will be achieved through a participatory filmmaking programme designed in conjunction with the Bophana Audio Visual Centre (&apos;Bophana&apos;), further developing the participatory methods developed in the Changing the Story GCRF Network Plus Grant to involve multiple layers of co-production with the individuals and communities engaged.  The filmmaking programme will involve training in storyboarding, visual story-telling, post-production and editing, co-productive filmmaking methodologies, engaging with conflict transitional and conservation, interviewing vulnerable subjects, and applying a gendered-lens to filmmaking.  As part of this programme, 12 students will be supported in the production of three films at the Elephant Valley Project site in Mondulkiri, collaborating with Elephant Livelihood Iniative Environment (&apos;ELIE&apos;), and in dialogue with relevant communities at the field site e.g. conservation practitioners and Bunong indigenous people.   The second objective of the proposed project is to promote awareness of the issues explored in the films in local, national, regional and international communities (e.g. Bunong community, young people, civil society and policy makers) through a series of events and outputs designed to amplify impact. These include: 1) Film screenings and dialogue events, including at the ELIE education centre and Sen Monorom provincial town in Mondulkiri, the Bophana Center in Phnom Penh, and at international thematic film festivals e.g. the International Green Film Network, the (online) Greenpeace Film Festival, and the Human Rights Watch Film Festival 2) An accessible briefing summarising the key issues highlighted in the students&apos; films to be disseminated amongst relevant audiences and stakeholders in Cambodia and beyond.  3) Bespoke social media training for the filmmakers to embed a long-term and sustainable dissemination The third objective of the proposed project is to build on the ethos of the Changing the Story GCRF Network Plus Grant by strengthening civil society networks in Cambodia for and with young people through genuine, equal and equitable collaboration with the Bophana Audio Visual Centre and the Elephant Livelihood Initiative Environment.  The fourth objective of the proposed project is to conduct an evaluation of the efficacy of the project through a &apos;making-of&apos; documentary, featuring excerpts from the filmmakers&apos; reflective video diaries, and a project brief reflecting on the value of participatory filmmaking as a methodology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project will deepen and extend the impact of our original research &quot;Participatory Filmmaking and the Anlong Veng Peace Tours&quot;, which was a &apos;proof of concept&apos; pilot developed and delivered through the Cambodia strand of the AHRC Network Plus grant &quot;Changing the Story: Building Inclusive Societies with, and for, Young People in 5 Post-Conflict Countries&quot;. The follow on funding for impact will apply the successful methods developed during the original project in collaboration with two new Cambodian partners, the Bophana Audio Visual Center (Bophana) and Elephant Livelihood Initiative (ELIE), to extend the reach of the original project to address urgent challenges for environmental conservation and indigenous communities in Cambodia. In the original research, we found that participatory filmmaking could empower young Cambodians as agents and beneficiaries of change by encouraging ownership of Cambodia&apos;s histories of war and atrocity, and building dialogue and empathy across divided communities. In particular, we saw young people using their own films as grassroots advocacy tools as they disseminated them across and within their own networks. While the original research focused on issues of post-conflict reconciliation for younger generations in Cambodia, our findings highlighted important outstanding relationships concerning legacies of conflict, transitions from war to peace, and harms inflicted on the environment, particularly in terms of deforestation and wildlife loss. Thus, the primary aims of this follow on funding project is to deploy our successful participatory filmmaking methodology to encourage young people to take ownership and actively engage with conservation issues, and to amplify awareness of environmental challenges across communities.          Cambodia&apos;s forty years of conflict have left a legacy of environmental harms, including wildlife reduction, deforestation and the loss of cultural heritage informing locally grounded approaches to forest management. Cambodia&apos;s transition to peace and subsequent development has witnessed unsustainable environmental exploitation and widespread environmental harms. Deforestation during and after conflict has caused further loss of rare and endangered wildlife and wild elephant numbers, in particular, have sharply declined as a consequence of the loss of their natural habitats. Indigenous communities, who have close cultural and spiritual relationships to elephants, suffer particularly as a marginalised group within wider Cambodian society and subject to unsustainable development pressures affecting the forests that they reside in. Conservation practice around elephant habitats, and issues facing indigenous communities who live alongside elephants, therefore offers a key site through which to encourage active engagement with wider environmental and development challenges in Cambodia.        The project has been designed in dialogue with the Bophana Center and ELIE to complement each partner&apos;s strategic objectives. The Bophana Center is committed to training a new generation of young Cambodian filmmakers, while ELIE&apos;s mission is to conserve the natural habitats of elephants while providing support for indigenous communities around them. Through the recruitment of 12 young people, who will be trained in co-productive and participatory filmmaking methods, the project will deliver 3 films that can be used as advocacy tools, highlighting exemplary conservation practice, environmental challenges, and issues facing marginalised indigenous communities through field visits to ELIE sites. These films will be constitute the centrepiece of an impact and dissemination strategy that will raise awareness of environmental challenges through screenings in indigenous communities, screenings facing conservation practitioners, submission for international film festivals, and a social media training program for the young filmmakers to disseminate their films as advocacy tools.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-13" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-12" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-07-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KH" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cambodia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">92933.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-22">92933.916</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Follow-on Funding Impact &amp; Eng Award to University of Bath</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T007923_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=AH%2FT007923%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
