<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014272_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">DRiSL: The Drought Risk finance Science Laboratory</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall objective of the Drought Risk Finance Science Laboratory (DRiSL) is to provide improved science and social science on drought risk to support the needs of humanitarian agencies for  transparent, accountable and defensible drought risk financing mechanism design.  Specific project aims 1. To provide an innovative &apos;due diligence&apos; assessment of globally applicable drought risk models and data, including the assessment of the assumptions and processes underpinning the Drought Finance Facility (DFF) model, recently developed by the Start NGO network. 2. To quantify and understand both the uncertainty in drought risk data and models, and the relationship of such proxies (and other risk drivers) to humanitarian food security, across a range a space/time scales and contexts.  3. To explore the potential for developing new indices to identify and understand the other risk drivers beyond drought that lead to humanitarian events, for application to operational drought risk and forecast based financing initiatives. 3. To provide guidance for the application of this new knowledge directly to two particular initiatives, namely the Start network Drought Finance Facility (DFF) and the Madagascar Drought Risk Finance project operated by Weithungerhilfe (WHH). 4. Document and demonstrate the innovative &quot;scientific due diligence&quot; approach, to support and promote its development and replication in disaster risk financing work globally.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Whether on television, newspapers, the internet or first-hand we have all seen the damage that floods, droughts and other weather hazards can have on people&apos;s lives and their livelihoods. It is a sad fact that such hazard events disproportionately impact developing countries and poor people.  However it is also increasingly evident that acting before a disaster occurs can save lives. For example, frontline humanitarian organisations and government agencies can themselves prepare by getting supplies and staff in readiness. More importantly, agencies can directly help the population prepare so that the impacts of a hazard are actually much reduced. Such actions depend on the lead time of a forecast but can range for example from distributing money, drought-resistant seeds, animal fodder to communities to ensuring evacuation procedures are followed. Acting before an event means they can also do this at a lower cost than the traditional &apos;late&apos; post disaster humanitarian response. As a result there is growing momentum within the humanitarian system to move beyond the current &apos;begging bowl&apos; funding model of post-disaster appeals, towards obtaining and distributing humanitarian funds before a disaster occurs. This change can enable humanitarians to mobilise more collaboratively, more predictably, and importantly in anticipation of crises. For this to occur requires trustworthy forecasts of hazards like storms, floods and droughts, and credible information on the condition of the people and systems exposed to them.     Forecast based financing and Disaster Risk financing initiatives, utilise information to anticipate potential disasters and set pre-agreed triggers for the release of disaster prevention finance. The advantage of this approach is that it is data-driven and objective. It thereby circumvents long debates around potentially conflicting early warning signs which tend to paralyse humanitarian action. It puts in place a robust predictable process to release funding or initiate action before a disaster occurs. Humanitarian agencies working on developing these systems face a problem, however. They are not scientists nor social scientists; but they need to use information from both realms of research to trigger the systems and have confidence in this information. They also must be accountable to the people that the system looks to support and the donors that finance it. The START Network Drought financing facility (DFF) and the Weithungerhilfe (WHH) Madagascar Forecast based financing project are both at this juncture of selection and development of scientific data to apply to these initiatives. The DFF having begun the design with a Global Parametric model and have a prototype model that requires testing and evaluation, whereas the WHH Madagascar Forecast based financing project is starting out from the beginning. However, currently no process, independent honest broker, or method to provide an independent review of the scientific (science and social science) credibility of these systems exists in an operational context. This is a stumbling point in the adoption of these ground breaking initiatives by other organisations. This project looks to meet the needs of humanitarian agencies. In particular it will provide &quot;scientific due diligence&quot; to the forecast and action components of these proactive schemes and hence ensure that the information going into them is as trustworthy as possible. It will assess a suit of global drought models in regard to their uncertainty and ability to depict emerging food security crisis. Global data products will be explored alongside data on the ground of drought and food security events in the three test sites associated of Pakistan, Zimbabwe and Madagascar.  It will help the humanitarian practitioners understand the limitations of the science for decision making and the fundamental risk of acting proactively when acting with forecast and monitoring information.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">41222.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">257623.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">70554.2</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-12-19"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-12-19">369400.612</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF NC&amp;C Award to University of Sussex</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_R014272_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Sussex</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=NE%2FR014272%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
