<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006183_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">World Heritage FOR Sustainable Development</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">There are currently 1031 sites on the UNESCO World Heritage List embracing cultural, natural and mixed categories. While it has long been recognised that sites require protection, conservation and management, they are increasingly implicated in wider programmes of social and economic development. A significant part of this is tourism-related which is widely perceived as a pathway to development particularly within developing countries where heritage and the wider landscape are important, if often fragile resources. Closely linked to this is the wider cultural and creative sector that animates places and supports tourism.   The United Nation&apos;s 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development recognises the role that the inter-connected sectors of culture, heritage, the creative industries and tourism can play in meeting the Sustainable Development Goals. The focus of this Network is specifically on the role that World Heritage sites can play in sustainable development as high profile actors in both cultural heritage and international tourism. In terms of the sites themselves and associated symbolic, &apos;brand&apos; value of UNESCO inscription, World Heritage sites offer significant development opportunities for ODA countries. However, there are clearly sensitivities around a more instrumental use of World Heritage that has long been immersed in the discourse of protection and preservation rather than as a lever for social, environmental and economic improvement within the context of sustainable development. Furthermore, there remains limited understanding of the ways in which World Heritage can actualise sustainable development through engagement with local communities and the embedded knowledge and creativity they hold.  This role of the community is recognised by UNESCO but mechanisms for harnessing this are not well developed. While clearly recognising the over-arching need to protect and maintain World Heritage, there is a need to re-imagine and re-structure the way that it is used; not simply as interesting and attractive places to visit but as highly visible and influential resources that can be used to achieve the SDGs.      Through a series of workshops, including those held in ODA countries, this project establishes and builds a Network of experienced and new researchers, policy makers and local stakeholders to share research, new ideas and examples of good practice relating to the ways in which World Heritage can be effectively and sensitively mobilised for sustainable development. Each workshop will focus on a World Heritage site and will act as a research activity and an opportunity to debate questions of practice and policy around concepts such as developing and managing sustainable tourism, working with the wider cultural and creative sectors and site management and governance. It will seek to better understand the conditions of working with World Heritage and the barriers to sustainable utilisation of the sites. The Network will recognise the multi/interdisciplinary nature of its objectives and its core partners and will seek to learn from the communities and stakeholders it engages with. In working with UNESCO&apos;s World Heritage Centre and specifically the sustainable tourism programme the Network will endeavour to shape policy and strategy and to disseminate its outputs and working methods beyond its immediate partners so as to engage with the other World Heritage sites in ODA countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This project is born out of a growing recognition by UNESCO - specifically the World Heritage Centre - together with emergent discussion within the academic community regarding the ways by which cultural heritage can underpin the economic and social development of local economies. In particular, it recognises the critical role of designated World Heritage sites as highly symbolic cultural resources with the potential for stimulating much needed sustainable development in countries in receipt of overseas development assistance. In the context of World Heritage (WH), while the protection of a site&apos;s &apos;Outstanding Universal Value&apos; remains paramount, there nevertheless exists considerable scope for developing strategies that employ cultural heritage (buildings, monuments and cultural landscapes) to stimulate sustainable tourism, the cultural and creative industries, related economic development and to foster social cohesion.   The aim of the proposed project is to establish and build an international network that will explore various pathways by which sites already inscribed on the World Heritage List in the developing world can be sensitively mobilised so as to contribute to the fulfilment of the United Nation&apos;s Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). The UN&apos;s 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development recognises that cultural heritage has a vital role to play in assisting countries and communities to meet the goals. The wider cultural sector along with tourism are strong allies in sustainable development and the Network will seek to examine how these sectors can work effectively and creatively with World Heritage at site and community level. Though the ultimate focus of the project will be to share innovation and best practice with and between developing nations, it will draw upon extant research and professional engagement relating to all World Heritage sites in order to interrogate and distil working principles, issues and practice. Through dialogue across academic disciplines and with direct engagement with stakeholders working with WH, the project seeks lasting impact beyond the period of funding and aims to create a platform for future projects that will inform policy and the development of innovative ways of using cultural heritage more generally as an important lever for sustainable development.  Specifically the key objectives of the project are:  To explore through a series of workshops, the issues raised by the use of World Heritage Sites in terms of their ongoing protection and management but also in terms of governance, wider cultural significance, local social and economic practices and effective implementation; To use the workshops to bring together academic researchers, policy makers and practitioners (site managers and non-governmental organisations) to develop a deeper understanding of the issues involved with the valorisation of World Heritage Sites; To specifically address the role that the tourism and cultural sectors can play at World Heritage Sites so as to meet several of the SDGs; To establish state-of-the-art thinking about the ways in which World Heritage Sites are able to function as catalysts for social and economic development and innovation within local communities; To develop research methodologies focused upon meeting development needs through cultural heritage that build upon current academic thinking, local sustainable development strategies and related policies; To stimulate discussions and share experiences amongst academics, local communities and non-governmental organisations regarding future research, education and capacity building; To develop and promote effective tools to capture and disseminate the outcome of network debate and examples of good and not-so-good practice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-01" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-09-29">39718.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">39718.09</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006183_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">-1202.62</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P006183_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-EDU-133784">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Birmingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
