<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00420X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Barriers to Women&apos;s Mobility</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A fundamental issue in sustainable development is enabling those who lives and well being are at stake to be involved in decision making and lead the way through collective action and engagement.  The centrality of gender equality, women&apos;s empowerment and the realization of women&apos;s rights in achieving sustainable development has been  recognized (for example in the Rio Declaration of Environment and Development, the Beijing Declaration and Platform for Action and the UN Conference on Sustainable Development). Women are critical agents in building more equitable, safer and sustainable societies.  Women in LMICs experience multiple levels of deprivation. They face constraints due to  socio-cultural norms that deny them equal access to facilities and opportunities . They have limited access to resources; restricted rights, limited mobility and a muted voice in shaping decisions. They are under-represented and under-utilised in the economy and labour market and tend to predominate as unpaid family workers in agriculture, and hold low paid, low skill jobs and at the lowest tiers of the industrial labour force in urban areas.  Pakistan ranks 128 out of 182 on Human Development Index (2010), 124 out of 155 on Gender Development Index (2009) and 132 out of 134 on the Global Gender Gap Report (2009). Malaysia ranked 111th (out of 145) on the Global Gender Gap Index for 2015, with an especially poor rating in the political arena. The UK, whilst in the top 20 (2016), is falling with women having 58% of the economic opportunity and 23% of political empowerment. Improving gender equality could add &#xA3;150 billion to UK GDP. Lack of access to basic opportunities is detrimental to women&apos;s social, economic and physical and psychological well being. A crucial element to reducing social exclusion is providing equitable accessibility (ease of reaching) to opportunities. A first step in this journey is to remove barriers to mobility (defined as the &apos;ease of moving&apos;). THE ILO stated that &apos;transport remains a neglected area among gender specialists and transport specialists are still reluctant to take on gender issues. Until this is done, the prospects for many women who live in areas characterized by poor physical accessibility and inadequate transport will remain poor&apos; . The overall aim of the proposed network is to provide a forum for knowledge exchange, training and cooperative working and learning: 1.to understand, using empathic design methods, the mobility barriers faced by women in Malaysia and Pakistan,  2 to co-design culturally sensitive solutions, policies and strategies to address these problems  3 to consider the usefulness of EU sustainable urban mobility planning processes in increasing consultation and user engagement in the design of master plans  4 to raise awareness of the effects of inaccessible transport on women and sustainable cities and communities.  Working together on these 4 issues in an 18 month project will provide opportunities for the network: 1. to grow and link to other national and international organisations,  2. to develop an understanding of cultural differences with respect to mobility 3. to test its ability to work together and provide evidence of co-operative activity to draw on for future bid applications  4. to transfer knowledge and best practice 5. to acquire data for joint publications  Empathic design methods will be introduced to Pakistan and Malaysia as a means of evidencing the lived experience of women. These will provide a basis for increased cultural understanding, and help in empowerment and presentation of clear evidence to policy makers. Network activities will culminate in co-design workshops with users, operators and policy makers as a means of exploring &apos;design led approaches&apos; to user engagement. These will be presented to transport operators, planners and policy makers, and used to inform course design.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The network addresses the GCRF challenge areas of sustainable health and well-being and sustainable cities and communities; UN Global Goals for Sustainable Development: Goal 11 (make cities inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable) and Goal 5 (achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls), and the AHRC cross cutting issues relating to urbanization, well being, equality and capacity building.   Access to affordable, safe and sustainable transport is a key component in achieving Goal 11. Since 1990s the gendered nature of transport has been recognized. Transport systems are not designed, operated, or planned by women. Current (public) transport does not take into account women&apos;s requirements or the journeys they need to make as employees, care providers and family members- even information about women&apos;s mobility patterns in census returns which are only concerned with (usually male) commuter journey.  Without access to safe public (or other forms of transport - even walking and cycling), women are denied access to resources and opportunities.This holds true for Western transport systems, but in LMICs, women face greater constraints due to the prevalent socio-cultural norms. At the lowest tiers of the industrial labour force in urban areas, they have limited rights and voices in shaping decisions, which makes them highly vulnerable.  Transport remains a neglected area for women&apos;s studies, yet it is crucial for achieving Goal 5. The network will look at how design research methods (co- and empathic design in particular) can improve user engagement of women in transport Therefore the overall objectives  are: 1. to raise awareness of barriers to women&apos;s mobility and the effects of this e.g. in terms of access to employment and other opportunities and in relation to quality of life 2. to foster research co-operation between Malaysia, Pakistan and UK in addressing issues relating to barriers to women&apos;s mobility in order to provide a foundation for future research applications 3. to share and exchange knowledge. Specifically   3a. to assess the applicability of empathic and co-design methods as a means of raising awareness, problem identification and solutions with respect to women&apos;s mobility  3b. to assess the extent to which the user engagement stages and philosophy of sustainable urban mobility planning might be used to address barriers to women&apos;s mobility 4. to act as a catalyst for integrating national work in each country, thereby adding value and weight to the voices of local,national and international organisations 5. to support early career researchers  The objectives will be achieved through: 1. Targeted workshops in each country. The Coventry team will provide information and training in relation to empathic and co-design and EU&apos;s Sustainable Urban Mobility Planning (SUMP) process.  2. Small scale empathic and co-design activities with female transport users in each country to provide culturally specific, authentic experiences of mobility problems faced by women and context specifics concept solutions and recommendations.  3. Development of information packs from 2) to extend the empathic horizons of transport planners, policy makers and service providers in each country and to provide a clearer basis for international and cultural understanding around mobility 4. Web site and social media as a repository of information for transport stakeholders, researchers and education providers</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">34666.14</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-07">14856.92</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">34666.14</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00420X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coventry University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">14856.92</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_R00420X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Coventry University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
