<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P02551X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A one health approach to the investigation and control of MERS-CoV among camel and human populations in Jordan as a potential model for the region</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Foundation funding will thus be used over an initial two-year period to address existing key knowledge gaps through multidisciplinary research leading to: 1) An improved understanding of the relative importance of transmission routes for MERS-CoV from camels to humans. There is a significant gap in global research knowledge regarding the accurate understanding of specific risk factors and routes of disease transmission from camels to humans. To date there has been no research aimed at identifying which aspects of camel husbandry, camel food products and human interaction with camels are of particularly high risk. However, without this knowledge appropriate control measures to minimise the risk of camel-to-human disease transmission cannot be accurately identified. This research will therefore seek to address these knowledge gaps by conducting a cross-sectional survey, involving both serology and virus isolation (nasal &amp; oropharyngeal swabs) together with the administration of pretested structured questionnaire to identify risk factors for infection among high risk Bedouin communities in the south of Jordan. 2) The identification of culturally acceptable measures to mitigate the risk of MERS-CoV transmission Camels occupy a unique and culturally iconic role in Islamic Arab society and culture. The Qur&apos;an and Hadith (Islamic texts) describe how camels reflect the wisdom and power of God, together with the believed healing properties of camels&apos; milk and urine. In addition, camels have until recent times represented the only means of surviving and maintaining a functioning society in the harsh desert environments such as the Arabian Peninsula - a fact which has also greatly elevated the status of camels in Arab culture, compared with other common livestock species in the region such as sheep and goats. With this in mind it is impossible to develop effective disease control strategies, including potential vaccination programmes, without an accurate understanding of these critical cultural issues.  3) The identification of knowledge gaps that should be the target of further research efforts and generation of key parameters for future disease transmission modelling. Objectives 1 and 2 listed above represent significant key knowledge gaps in the current understanding of MERS-CoV aetiology, epidemiology and control. However, as this study progresses new knowledge gaps will be generated. For example once key routes of transmission and their relative risk have been identified, the mechanism of these transmission routes is likely to require further investigation. Likewise the qualitative study, while addressing existing key knowledge gaps, will also inform future researchers in how best to target the specific issues raised. 4) The establishment of Jordan, through JUST, as a centre of excellence in MERS-CoV research, surveillance, control and training, able to serve the whole region. While the current MERS-CoV human epidemic in is largely centred on Saudi Arabia, MERS-CoV seropositivity has been identified in dromedary populations across the world. Jordan shares a long porous border with Saudi Arabia and research conducted by the RVC in collaboration with JUST and US NIAD / NIH, has identified high MERS-CoV endemicity among camel populations in Jordan and identified human pathogenic virus isolates from these same populations. Regional political tensions have given Jordan a unique position as a largely neutral, peaceful hub for regional training and dissemination of knowledge. This, combined with the existing OIE twinning initiative between RVC and JUST - and its associated collaboration with world experts in epidemiology and virology from LSHTM and US NIAD / NIH - provides a unique opportunity to develop JUST and Jordan as centre of excellence for MERS-CoV research surveillance, control and training, able to serve the entire region.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Middle Eastern Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus (MERS-CoV) is an emerging infectious disease that was first identified in Jordan and Saudi Arabia in 2012. Clinical cases present as an acute respiratory infection with rapid onset pneumonia and in many cases death. To date there have been over 1800 laboratory confirmed cases, with 643 deaths (as 2nd October 2016) spanning 27 countries. Camels have been identified as the primary viral host reservoir for infection in humans (although infection in camels is largely asymptomatic) with secondary human-to-human transmission also occurring. Individuals with co-morbidities (pre-existing medical conditions) are at particular risk of infection, with the majority of outbreaks occurring in hospital settings. Over 90% of confirmed cases have been in Saudi Arabia. There are current key knowledge gaps in the understanding of MERS-CoV - particularly the nature of disease transmission from camels-to-humans - that this project seeks to address. Through identifying specific risk factors for camel-to-human transmission the project aims to develop control measures to mitigate these risks. Such control measures must be culturally appropriate and developed in direct collaboration with high risk groups, to ensure they can be effectively implemented at a grassroots level. In addition the project seeks to identify key knowledge gaps in the understanding of MERS-CoV camel-to-human transmission that can form the target research efforts in the future. The project also seeks to establish Jordan, through Jordan University of Science and Technology (JUST), as a regional leader in international MERS-CoV research, surveillance, training and control.  With this in mind the project will adopt a &apos;One Health&apos; approach to achieving these aims, drawing on the expertise of a number of world expert from various fields including; veterinary public, human public health, epidemiology, virology and anthropology. The project will be coordinated by the Royal Veterinary College (RVC), London, working in strategic partnership with the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine (LSHTM),  JUST and the US National Institute of Health. Studies already conducted by the RVC in partnership with JUST and US NIH have already identified high levels of MERS-CoV infection among camels in the south of Jordan. Project field work will involve random sampling of high risk Bedouin communities in the south of Jordan, collecting blood samples, nasal swabs and sputum samples alongside a questionnaire to assess risk factors for infection. A routine health check will also be performed at this time. Where selected individuals are camel owners nasal swabs will be collected from these camels. All samples collected will be analysed for evidence of MERS-CoV infection, and this data then combined with the data collected from the questionnaires in order to identify risk factors for MERS-CoV infection. In addition an ethnographic study w ill be conducted to examine the role of camels in Bedouin Arab society and understand how potential control methods for MERS-CoV exposure can most effectively be implemented. Community health workshops will also be run among high risk Bedouin communities regarding the risk of zoonotic (animal-to-human) infections, including MERS-CoV, and give training and advice on how to reduce these risk.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Veterinary College</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="3"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="JO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Jordan</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="589" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-03">220399.88</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-03">260708.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-03"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-03">481107.984</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to Royal Veterinary College</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P02551X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Royal Veterinary College</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP02551X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
