<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004428_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Building trans-disciplinary partnerships for exploring the impact of population displacement on nutrition interventions in rural Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stunting affects nearly 30% of children in southern Africa, and leads to reduced human capacity, increased long-term risk of chronic disease and an inter-generational cycle of poverty. We recently conducted the Sanitation Hygiene Infant Nutrition Efficacy (SHINE) trial, which showed that stunting can be reduced by 20% through improved infant and young child feeding (IYCF). Despite this modest reduction, it is evident that current interventions are insufficient to eliminate stunting. Countries including Zimbabwe are therefore unlikely to achieve World Health Assembly targets for improving maternal, infant and young child nutrition by 2025. There is a clear need to test new and broader approaches for stunting through interdisciplinary partnerships aimed at tackling the multi-faceted determinants of this intractable problem.  Analysis of SHINE trial data has identified substantial gaps in infant nutrient intake despite an intensive IYCF intervention. Greater gains in linear growth can be achieved by enhancing the nutrient quality of infant diets. We have therefore recently broadened the disciplinary scope of researchers in this partnership to further build research capacity and capability. Having shown that linear growth can be modestly improved in the first 2 years of life with an intensive IYCF intervention, our partnership has been extended to include agricultural expertise in a follow-on randomised controlled trial. Collaborating with agricultural scientists and economists from the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Centre, the ultimate goal of this partnership is to further close the nutrient gap experienced by rural households in the immediate and longer term by integrating an enhanced &apos;IYCF-plus&apos; intervention with a sustainable intervention aimed at improving agriculture and animal husbandry practices.  As this call identifies, the long-term success of interventions such as ours depends on better understanding the cultural and historical contexts within which they take place as well as their reception by intended beneficiaries. This is acknowledged by the researchers involved in this partnership, who have an established track-record of working closely with the communities within which their work takes place. Despite this, important gaps in knowledge remain. Zimbabwe, like other southern African countries, has been subject to considerable population displacement in the past several decades, involving rural-urban, regional (e.g. Botswana, South Africa, Zambia) as well as overseas migration (e.g. Canada and UK). Population displacement is known to have multiple influences on household food security and relatedly agricultural production capacity.  In addition, the familial structure and support systems of rural households has been significantly impacted by the devastating legacies of HIV/AIDS. Of importance to nutrition interventions such as ours is the increase in the number of child-headed and elderly-headed households. It is widely acknowledged that child-headed households are especially vulnerable to food insecurity and households headed by elderly relatives are less likely to diversify crops and rely on growing cereal crops and other staples more vulnerable to adverse weather patterns (intensified with climate change) as they are less able to procure hybrid seeds and fertilizers.   In order to support LMIC countries like Zimbabwe in achieving WHA targets for improving maternal, infant and young child nutrition by 2025 it is vital that interventions take account of population displacement, changing household structures and the intersection with the gender-related and household dynamics that may shape household food security and agricultural capacity. This application seeks to achieve this by extending and more effectively integrating humanities and social science perspectives into an already existing partnership and by adopting a more radical approach to inter- and trans-disciplinary working.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We have shown in previous research in rural Zimbabwe that linear growth can be improved in the first 2 years of life with an intensive infant and young child feeding (IYCF) intervention, but that one quarter of children remained stunted. Data from this trial (SHINE) show that nutrient intake remained insufficient to meet both macro- and micro-nutrient requirements for most children. Follow-on research (CHAIN) will explore the hypothesis that the nutrient gap can be filled by a combined agriculture-infant feeding intervention.   However, as this GCRF call highlights, the long-term success of interventions depends on better understanding the cultural and historical contexts within which they take place. In order to better understand the potential for long-term and sustainable improvement to household nutrition in contexts such as those encountered in rural Zimbabwe it is vital that we take account of population displacement, changing familial structures and their intersection with gender-related dynamics shaping household food security and agricultural capacity. We will only achieve this by more effectively integrating humanities and social science perspectives into an already existing North-South/South-South partnership.   Our objectives in this proposal are as follows:  Objective 1: To identify inter- and trans-disciplinary partners  In order to achieve this objective we will undertake a comprehensive literature review exploring the intersection between population displacement, household food security and agricultural production capacity and conduct a social network survey of relevant non-governmental organisations (NGOs) based in Zimbabwe, neighbouring countries and from the UK-based Zimbabwean diaspora.  Objective 2: Building equitable and sustainable partnerships  We will work with the London International Development Centre-Migration Leadership Team (LIDC-MLT) and the African Research Universities Alliance (ARUA) to establish principles for equitable and sustainable working across our proposed inter- and trans-disciplinary partnership.  Objective 3: Building capacity and capability through participatory research  Working with Village Health Workers who are familiar with the rural Zimbabwean households we intend to engage with, we will design a pilot participatory research project to explore issues around near and far population displacement, household food security and agricultural production capacity and their potential to impact the effectiveness of the &apos;IYCF-plus&apos; intervention being tested in our CHAIN trial.  Objective 4: Develop future intervention strategies  Our core objective is to establish an enduring architecture for inter- and trans-disciplinary research partnership ensuring that the gains made during this project are not only sustained, but form the basis for future progress towards achieving WHA targets for improving maternal, infant and young child nutrition by 2025.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">89214.05</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">91145.03</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-15">180359.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">AHRC GCRF Development Grants Award to Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH/T004428/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">89214.05</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004428_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">44607.03</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_T004428_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=AH%2FT004428%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-12-31"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
