<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Child Health, Agriculture and Integrated Nutrition (CHAIN): a randomized trial to close the nutrient gap in rural Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Stunting (low height for a child&apos;s age) affects 155 million under-5 children around the world and leads to a higher risk of dying, poorer school performance and lower wages in adult life. Improving the quantity and quality of food for children under two years of age is the best approach we have to prevent stunting. We recently did a trial in rural Zimbabwe called SHINE, in which we showed that educating mothers about infant and young child feeding (IYCF) and giving the child a daily supplement (called Nutributter) to provide extra calories and vitamins, helped children grow taller. Despite this, many children still did not meet their daily nutrient requirements and over one-quarter remained stunted. In addition, the quantity of nutrients a child needs in developing countries is probably higher than in developed countries, because the gut is inflamed and less able to absorb nutrients. We therefore need to increase the nutrients children get and try to heal the gut, to help children grow better.   In this project, we will compare a new package of interventions against the SHINE approach, to see if we can close this nutrient gap. Almost 200 households with a 6-month-old child will be randomly allocated (like the flip of a coin) to receive the SHINE IYCF package (which we know reduces stunting) or the new package, which we call &quot;IYCF-plus&quot;. Households receiving the SHINE IYCF package will receive 6 visits from a Village Health Worker to provide a series of lessons in how to feed a young child a healthy diet, including daily Nutributter. Households receiving the IYCF-plus package will receive an agriculture intervention and a more intensive feeding intervention. Families will receive three new varieties of crops (fortified maize, which is more resistant to drought and pests; moringa trees, which contain high amounts of protein, vitamins and calcium; and sugar beans, which contain easily digestible protein, zinc and iron) and will receive advice during planting and harvesting seasons. We hope this will increase the family&apos;s food availability, provide a more diverse range of food choices for the child and improve the nutrient content of the diet. The nutrients contained in these crops may also help the child&apos;s gut to heal, which should improve absorption of the food. Village Health Workers will visit households 12 times to give Nutributter and to provide more intensive messages about how to feed a young child, including use of the new crops. Families will also receive powdered versions of the crops that can immediately be used (for example, by adding to the child&apos;s porridge) before the family becomes self-sufficient by growing their own.  We will compare children in the IYCF and IYCF-plus groups at 18 months of age. The main outcome will be how many children in each group meet their daily nutrient requirements, using a detailed questionnaire that recalls and weighs all food the child ate in the previous day. We think that more children in the IYCF-plus group will meet their daily nutrient requirements.  We will also measure their height, weight, blood count, the amount of muscle and fat in the body, and collect blood, urine and stool samples. We will use these samples to measure nutrient levels in the blood (such as iron and protein), to study the body&apos;s metabolism (how certain nutrients are broken down and used), and to test our theory that the children in the IYCF-plus group will have a less inflamed gut.  If we show that the IYCF-plus intervention leads to better nutrient intake, a healthier gut, and higher levels of nutrients in the blood, we would expect the combined agriculture-infant feeding approach to improve children&apos;s growth more than the SHINE intervention did. This approach has the advantage of being sustainable because families can grow and process their own crops for the child to eat, and health workers in rural areas can provide the advice needed to ensure infants receive the food they need to grow.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">We have shown in a randomized trial in rural Zimbabwe that linear growth can be improved in the first 2 years of life with an intensive infant and young child feeding (IYCF) intervention, but one-quarter of children remained stunted. Our data show that nutrient intake remained insufficient to meet both macro- and micronutrient requirements for most children. Our overarching hypothesis in the current proposal is that the nutrient gap can be filled by a combined agriculture-infant feeding intervention. Our objectives and accompanying hypotheses in this proposal are:  Objective 1. Deliver an integrated agriculture and infant feeding intervention (&quot;IYCF-plus&quot;) to households in a randomized, community-based trial in rural Zimbabwe  We hypothesize that more intensive behaviour-change communication by Village Health Workers, daily lipid-based nutrient supplements and provision of powdered fortificants (sugar beans, moringa and egg), together with a gender-sensitive agriculture intervention, will close nutrient gaps in young children better than the current standard of care IYCF intervention.  Objective 2. Evaluate the impact of IYCF-plus on nutrient intake and growth in young children at risk of stunting  We hypothesize that IYCF-plus will improve the intake of key nutrients (calories, protein, calcium, iron and choline) in 6-18 month old infants compared to the standard of care IYCF intervention (primary outcome). We further hypothesize that IYCF-plus will increase length-for-age, weight-for-age, weight-for-height, lean mass and haemoglobin more than IYCF.  Objective 3. Evaluate the impact of the IYCF-plus intervention on biological barriers to nutrient uptake and utilisation  We hypothesize that the IYCF-plus intervention will increase microbiota maturity, ameliorate environmental enteric dysfunction, reduce systemic inflammation and improve innate immune function in children aged 18 months, compared to the standard of care IYCF intervention.  Objective 4. Identify metabolic signatures of the IYCF-plus intervention in young children  We hypothesize that the IYCF-plus intervention will increase the concentrations of essential amino acids and choline at 18 months, which are required for child growth, and lead to a unique metabolic signature compared to the standard of care IYCF intervention.  To achieve these objectives, we have set the following milestones: 1. Write trial protocol and statistical analysis plan 2. Secure ethics approval and study sponsorship 3. Recruit and train research staff, Village Health Workers and Agricultural Extension Workers 4. Enrol 192 households, randomize to trial arms, and assess baseline characteristics. 5. Implement randomized infant feeding interventions (IYCF and IYCF-Plus) through home visits by government Village Health Workers with technical support from Zvitambo; assess intervention delivery fidelity through process reports. 6. Implement agricultural intervention to IYCF-Plus households through home visits by government agricultural extension workers with technical support from CIMMYT; assess intervention delivery fidelity through process reports. 7. Measure infant nutrient intake (primary outcome), anthropometry, haemoglobin and body composition (secondary outcomes) at 18 months of age.   8. Collect infant stool, urine and plasma at 18 months of age 9. Undertake social science, gender and economics assessments at 18 months using mixed methods. 10. Standardize laboratory methods in Zvitambo laboratory and finalize SOPs 11. Complete all laboratory work in Zimbabwe according to standard SOPs, with rigorous quality control 12. Ship samples to UK and undertake metabolomics and metagenomics work 13. Undertake &apos;future proofing&apos; work by evaluating growth of maize under future climatic conditions 14. Unblind, clean, lock, integrate and analyse data 15.   Interpret, publish and disseminate findings; engage with policymakers and programmers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-14">917664.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-14">710089.86</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">229416.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">229416.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">229416.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">229416.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">231274.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">231274.37</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">247541.12</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S013997_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Queen Mary University of London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
