<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T007958_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reimagining Infrastructure: how is marginalised people&apos;s food and nutrition security shaped by a continuum of urban infrastructure assemblages</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overall aim of this project is to reframe infrastructure planning, governance and participation in various city contexts in five low and middle income countries to better support the lives of their most marginalised residents. In particular our research will reimagine what infrastructure means in these contexts, where it is rarely experienced in the way envisaged by planners as the progressive realisation of access to a formal, city-wide &apos;grid&apos; (Pieterse et al. 2018).  We will focus in particular on infrastructure &apos;assemblages&apos;, i.e. the multiple arrangement of infrastructure access determined not only by physical infrastructure, but the social, ecological and political relationships, and ideologies operating and influencing access at multiple city scales. Our research will examine the interactions between five types of infrastructure assemblage: energy, water, sanitation, transport and communication. Whilst these infrastructures can be planned in silos, marginalised people&apos;s daily experience is instead of how infrastructure constraints can combine to add to their vulnerability to longer-term shocks and stresses and their inability to meet their basic needs.  We will concentrate on food and nutrition security as one set of basic needs which is significantly dependent on these infrastructures. Charting infrastructure interactions as these relate to food outcomes at multiple city levels provides us with an innovative methodology and a novel conceptual means to shine a light on such interactions, deficiencies and everyday means of coping. The five study cities: Tamale, Ghana; Epworth, Zimbabwe; Mossel Bay, South Africa; Bangalore, India; and Colombo, Sri Lanka were selected to present a deliberate typology of cities and a range of different grid access - from being completely &apos;off-grid&apos; to encompassing several hybrid types of formal and informal service delivery. The settings are well known to the research partnership and our methodology will pinpoint sites in which marginality and infrastructure poverty combine, so to allow us to chart the time and cost burdens to residents and their vulnerability to political, social and environmental disruptions which exist in such neighbourhoods. In involving marginalised people themselves in this analysis, as well as undertaking training, capacity building and targeted dialogues with urban planners, infrastructural managers and other urban decision makers, we will enhance the responsiveness of those actors to infrastructural needs of the most marginalised communities, within a city-wide and more systemic response.     Our objectives are therefore: #To reframe concepts of infrastructure interactions, drawing on critical literatures on urban infrastructure, socio-material assemblages, informality and food and nutrition governance. #To undertake quantitative and qualitative research in five diverse urban contexts which represent a variety of city and infrastructural settings with a focus on marginalised people who experience lives of precarity. #To pursue this research at multiple spatial scales in the city, using flows of food to understand infrastructure interactions in food provision, retail, storage, preparation and consumption as well as design, planning, management and governance, examining the implications for the food and nutrition security of the most marginalised. #To design new tools, training materials, maps and other forms of representing and understanding urban food and infrastructure interactions targeted at urban professionals and infrastructure practitioners, such as engineers and city planners, as well as those training them. #To build sustained capacity and multi-stakeholder processes to collaboratively identify and respond to issues affecting infrastructure access and food and nutrition security for poor, vulnerable and marginalised people in five cities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This research is designed to help improve the lives of the poorest residents of cities in Africa and Asia by focusing on how they are meeting their basic needs and accessing infrastructure, particularly when they are living &apos;off-grid&apos;. The research is led by a consortium including experts in urban research from Africa and Asia, brought together by the Institute of Development Studies. We will focus on five cities which represent different types of urban environment: Tamale, Ghana, Mossel Bay, South Africa, Epworth, Zimbabwe, Bangalore, India and Colombo, Sri Lanka.  They were chosen because, while planning and infrastructure design and provision is improving for some parts of these cities, such provision is not expanding fast enough to keep up with urban growth and provision is not evenly distributed for all. We focus on five main types of infrastructure - water, sanitation, energy, transport and communications. In most poor neighbourhoods people meet their needs in a variety of ways - informal access to formal grids such as illegal energy hook ups; &apos;off-grid&apos; forms such as latrines or bore-wells; hybrid forms such as reliance on water trucks when urban supplies run dry; or local vehicles providing &apos;last-mile&apos; connections to public transport. A particular concern in these cities is whether such critical infrastructure is sufficiently robust and stable to weather the multitude of human/political and environmental shocks and stresses facing cities, ranging from droughts and floods to political and financial crises which can literally &apos;turn off the lights&apos;.  In order to gain a better understanding of these systemic urban issues and how they are affecting the poorest and most marginalised, we focus our research on one key way of measuring whether basic needs are being met - whether people have stable access and availability of sufficient, diverse and nutritious diets - their &apos;Food and Nutrition Security&apos;.  This provides us with a way of researching how these various infrastructures combine at multiple levels, in order to achieve a more &apos;systemic&apos; understanding of infrastructure provision and the implications for people&apos;s lives. This has been little researched to date, but is critically important to understand for urban planners and infrastructure providers.  For example, water, energy and sanitation are essential for safe food preparation and disposal of human waste and also have a role to play in urban markets, alongside transport and communication. Inadequacies in access and supply can thus undermine the ability to safely cook, clean, store, supply, manufacture and grow food and add to the vulnerability of people to suffer consequences to their health, wellbeing, livelihoods and ability to care for others.  Our research starts at a city level to identify the most marginal and vulnerable settlements and how planning is envisioned in city-wide processes.  At a neighbourhood level, we will pursue statistically robust ways of capturing people&apos;s food and infrastructure interactions as well as capture deep and rich testimony of their lives through their own photographs and follow-up interviews. We will also train members of each settlement to &apos;audit&apos; their own infrastructure provision and present these results for discussion with local officials and providers.  A further stage will then &apos;follow the food&apos; by tracing how food reaches people, e.g. via street and municipal markets, or transport and warehousing, mapping the market infrastructure at each point.  Ultimately, our research will contribute to better decisions around infrastructure provision that can facilitate forms of infrastructure access. We will achieve this by engaging directly with urban professionals and infrastructure practitioners, such as engineers and city planners, as well as, importantly, those training the future generation of planners needed for African and Asian cities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2023-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">253915.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">138480.12</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2022-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2023-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">160590.06</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2023-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2024-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">139430.19</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">29565407.13</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF ODA Award to Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_T007958_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Institute of Development Studies</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=ES%2FT007958%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
