<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N004477_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Embrapa: Uncovering the genetic basis of the unique durable leaf rust resistance in the Brazilian wheat variety Toropi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The UK PI is Dr Lesley Boyd, NIAB. Boyd has led a research program on wheat-rust interactions for 20 years, being an internationally recognised expert on wheat-rust genetics and biology. Boyd is a member of the Borlaug Global Rust Initiative (BGRI) community and actively collaborates with this international community. In 2011 Boyd won the BGRI Jeanie Borlaug Laube Women in Triticum Mentor Award for her support and mentorship of young female researchers. Boyd has worked for many years with collaborators in Africa, being PI on the BBSRC - SARID project: Assessment of genetic biodiversity of durable disease resistance in African wheat genotypes, leading to the development of novel marker systems for wheat breeding, the BBSRC - SCPRID project: Implementing effective marker technologies into disease resistance wheat breeding programmes within Africa and the BBSRC-Flexible Interchange Program: UK partnership to support the uptake of new crop varieties by smallholder farmers and advancements in agricultural and dissemination technologies. Boyd is co-ordinator of a EU FP7 European Industrial Doctorate PhD Training Program joint with the University of Wageningen, The Netherlands: Max-CROP, and partner in European and International collaborative projects looking at translational aspects of Non-Host Resistance in wheat and barley.  The Brazilian PI is Dr M&#xE1;rcia Soares Chaves from Embrapa National Wheat Research Centre. Since 2002 Chaves has led projects that support the Embrapa wheat breeding programs. These research activities cover many aspects of the genetic resistance in wheat to rusts diseases: phenotyping, genotyping, histopathology, development of mapping population and functional genomics, and pathogen epidemiology and population dynamics. Among Chaves main achievements are the selection and in-depth characterization of sources of durable APR to leaf rust adapted to local and regional environments, including the leaf rust APR in Toropi.    Many of Chaves research projects are collaborative between Embrapa Wheat and the Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS). At UFRGS Prof. Jose Martinelli plays a significantly role in strengthening the interaction in areas such as plant breeding, plant pathology, genetics, cell and molecular biology. The cooperation between the two institutions led to the registration of the &quot;Research Group on Cereal Rusts&quot; on the CNPq database in 2009, which has its leadership shared by Chaves and Martinelli. Under this cooperation two PhD theses were developed, both aiming to investigate the histopathology of Puccinia x Gramineae interactions, with the goal to better understand the mechanisms involved in resistance of winter cereals to rusts. Chaves and Martinelli are both members of the BGRI.   At NIAB the consortium has access to extensive knowledge in wheat-rust genetics and biology, in particular the application of microscopy in the analysis of the biology underlying given wheat genotype-rust race interactions. NIAB has international expertise in wheat trait genetic analyses and genomic selection, and is host to the UK pre-breeding program on synthetic wheat production. NIAB also hosts high-throughput crop transformation, with the wheat transformation platform using the Japan Tobacco protocol. Embrapa Wheat has 284 ha that are used for experimentation and provides ideal conditions for field testing wheat-leaf rust interactions. In the UK leaf rust trials are difficult to carry out because of the presence of yellow rust, the major rust disease of wheat in the UK, which appears naturally in the field before the emergence of leaf rust. Embrapa Wheat also has extensive plant incubation rooms calibrated for wheat-leaf rust infection experimentation.  Other members from Embrapa who will be involed in the project are Drs Sandra Brammer and Sandra Mansur Scagliusi. Drs Renata Cruz and Fernanda Bered at UFRGS have recently joined the research consortium.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Toropi is an old Brazilian bread wheat variety that is seedling susceptible to all known Brazilian pathotypes of Puccinia triticina, the leaf rust pathogen, but has maintained a high level of field, adult plant resistance (APR) for more than 50 years[1]. Two recessive, additive QTL, trp-1 and trp-2 were identified by single marker regression analysis in a Toropi x IAC 13 F7 RIL population that together accounted for 71.5% of the phenotypic variation for leaf rust APR[2]. However, trp-1 and trp-2 are genetically poorly defined, lying within regions spanning more than 50cM, and were mapped using AFLP, a difficult to reproduce marker system. ToropiAPR has three objectives, the outputs of which will set the foundations of a full proposal to fine-map, with the view to clone and develop robust DNA markers for all the QTLs responsible for the durable, leaf rust APR in Toropi. The full proposal will also undertake to determine the biological role of each QTL and QTL combination, thereby prioritising selection of QTLs and QTL combinations within new wheat varieties to achieve durable leaf rust resistance.  Objective (1) To confirm the genomic locations of the Toropi leaf rust APR genes, trp-1 and trp-2.  Objective (2) To identify additional QTL regions contributing to leaf rust APR in the Toropi.  Objective (3) To determine the contribution of each QTL, individually and in combination to leaf rust APR through a microscopic study of Puccinia triticina development in selected genotypes.  Workplan:  To achieve Objs (1) and (2) the Toropi x IAC 13 RILs will be screened with a Core Set of SSR markers developed by Dr Renee Prins, CenGen, South Africa specifically for hexaploid wheat, and for SNP markers, using the Genotyping by Sequencing, DArTseq platform at Diversity Array Technology Ply Ltd, Australia. The SNP markers will provide a wide coverage of the expressed genome, while the SSR markers provide robust anchors that locate the SNP markers to chromosomes. Toropi and IAC 13, along with selected RIL from the population will be screened with diagnostic markers for the known slow-rusting leaf rust APR genes Lr34, Lr46, Lr67 and Lr68 to determine whether these genes are present in the cross (April-May 2015).  The Toropi x IAC 13 (94 F12 RIL) population has been phenotypes for APR to P. triticina in three independent experiments in Brazil (work of Ph D student Gerarda Beatriz Pinto da Silva). Adult plant leaf rust phenotypes include both percentage of the flag leaf covered in rust pustules and the reaction response of the plant, measured as necrosis and chlorosis. Gerarda will construct a genetic map of the Toropi x IAC 13 population using the SSR and SNP markers and carry out QTL analyses with the three phenotypic data sets using freely available software such as ICIMapping and R/qtl. Gerarda will be trained and carry out this work at NIAB, UK (May-June 2015).  The improved genetic identification of the APR QTL in Toropi will enable us to select lines with individual QTL, and QTL combinations for the biological study of the interaction between each source of resistance and the pathogen, P. triticina under Obj (3). Gerarda will carry out controlled inoculations of adult plants of Toropi, IAC 13 and selected QTL genotypes in Brazil. Flag leaves, inoculated with P. triticina will be sampled in a time course experiment. Gerarda will return to NIAB to undertake the microscopic examination of P. triticina development in this material (Sept-Dec 2015).   Objs (1) and (2) will confirm the 1AS and 4DS (or not) locations of the leaf rust APR genes trp-1 and trp-2, while also identifying additional leaf rust APR QTLs in Toropi x IAC 13. We will confirm that the APR is unique and not any of the known slow-rusting leaf rust APR genes. Obj (3) will provide a clearer picture of the biology behind the APR in Toropi, supporting wheat breeder&apos;s decision making when deciding which leaf rust resistance genes to use in new variety development.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-08-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-25">18145.8</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-03-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-03-25">24194.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC Newton Small Grants Award to National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB/N004477/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">National Inst of Agricultural Botany</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=BB%2FN004477%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
