<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015667_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Translating GeoNutrition (TGN): Reducing mineral micronutrient deficiencies (MMNDs) in Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mineral micronutrient deficiencies (MMNDs) affect the health and livelihoods of more than 2 billion people. Women and children in Low Income Countries are at greatest risks of MMNDs. Alleviating MMNDs remains a major challenge for meeting several of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), in particular SDG2 (eliminating hunger).  We shall translate research outputs, outcomes, and lessons learned from an existing programme of GCRF (and other ODA and institutional) funding, called &apos;GeoNutrition&apos;. This programme, which spans natural and social sciences, is focusing on understanding how to alleviate MMNDs. In addition, we shall also use this award to further strengthen research capacity and partnerships in SSA, which currently limits public and private investment, including for interventions to alleviate MMNDs.  Zimbabwe is the focal geography, where &gt;50% of the population are affected by MMNDs. Here, the Government of Zimbabwe (GoZ) plans to deploy their first full MMND survey in 2020/21. There is therefore an immediate window of opportunity to realise major impact by: (1) informing the design of this GoZ survey, specifically by translating GCRF-funded &apos;GeoNutrition&apos; work in Malawi, and (2) promoting new policy and commercialisation pathways through research capacity strengthening. This project has the highest-level support from the GoZ, including from the Ministry of Health and Child Care, and the Ministry of Higher Education. The project has been co-designed with the University of Zimbabwe (UZ).  Translating GeoNutrition Aims:  1. To co-design a national surveillance programme to establish baseline MMNDs in Zimbabwe.   2. To improve institutional and individual research capacity in Zimbabwe, including for testing policy interventions for alleviating MMNDs and for promoting private sector engagement.  Translating GeoNutrition Objectives (in delivery sequence):  1. Select pilot study participants from Enumeration Areas of Zimbabwe, representing a sample frame of ~10,000 households, with ~3,000 children under 5s. [Supports population-level inferences about MMNDs to inform the full national-scale surveillance programme]  2. Complete ethical approvals and standard operating procedures (SOPs); sample and analyse biomarkers from pilot households. [Supports lab./data management capacity strengthening]  3. Sample and analyse agricultural materials (soils, crops) using the Natural Region (NR) agroecological zone stratification design, including on-farm questionnaires. [Supports research capacity strengthening]  4. Statistical analysis of survey data to inform how the full national-scale survey should be designed for maximum economy, efficiency, and effectiveness, i.e. the &apos;3Es&apos; (e.g. sample size, the balance of survey effort between numbers of communities and households within communities) given requirements for precision, statistical power and logistical constraints. [Supports capacity strengthening in statistical analysis, design and survey planning]  5. Co-develop an implementation strategy for surveillance and alleviation of MMNDs, through a wider research capacity development plan spanning organisational, cultural, financial, and policy/private sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mineral micronutrient deficiencies (MMNDs) remain a global challenge affecting the growth, development, health, and livelihoods of more than 2 billion people. MMNDs are especially prevalent in Low Income Countries of sub Saharan Africa (SSA) and South Asia. Women and children are at particular risk of MMNDs due to unequal access to nutrient-rich foods within the home. Constraints to reducing MMNDs, especially in SSA, include: (1) baseline data on the distribution of MMNDs, especially within a country; (2) national research capacity to get the information needed to provide a sound evidence base, and potential solutions, for policy makers, private sector investors, and other interested parties (citizens, donors, public health professionals).  We have built up substantial knowledge on how to approach this challenge based on ongoing research, and lessons learned, from an existing portfolio of Global Challenge Research Fund (GCRF, and other ODA and institutional) funding, which seeks to, (1) reduce the impact of MMNDs by understanding local nutrition from the soil through to the person via complex food systems pathways (a &apos;GeoNutrition&apos; approach), and (2) strengthen research capacity in SSA.  The work will be undertaken with partners in Zimbabwe, where &gt;50% of the population are affected by MMNDs. The Government of Zimbabwe (GoZ) plans to embed a full MMND survey in a wider health survey in 2020/21. There is therefore a window of opportunity for impact by: (1) informing the design of this GoZ survey, specifically by translating GCRF-funded &apos;GeoNutrition&apos; research findings from Malawi, and (2) promoting new policy and commercialisation pathways through research capacity strengthening. This project has the highest-level support from the GoZ, including from the Ministry of Health and Child Care, and the Ministry of Higher Education. The project has been co-designed with the University of Zimbabwe (UZ).  Translating GeoNutrition Aims: 1. To co-design a national surveillance programme to establish baseline MMNDs in Zimbabwe 2. To improve institutional and individual research capacity in Zimbabwe, including to test policy interventions for alleviating MMNDs and to promote private sector engagement  Aim 1 will be delivered through activities in two (parallel) Work Packages (WPs), linking the Nutrition (WP1) and Agriculture (WP2) sectors. These can be scaled up as required.  WP1: Biomarker Survey Pilot, to support mapping of MMNDs, and to inform the design of the full MMND surveillance programme. The activity sequence includes: (i) design, (ii) area selection, (iii) data sharing, (iv) ethical approvals, (v) training and sensitisation, (vi) logistics/risk assessments, (vii) sample collection and processing (blood, urine), (viii) storage/shipping, (ix) lab. analyses, (x) data management, (xi) data analyses, (xii) communication.  WP2: Agricultural Survey, to link agriculture and nutritional policies, by mapping parts of the Food Systems which affect MMNDs, and to identify new market opportunities. Activities include those described above, with sample collection focusing on soils and crops.  Aim 2 will be delivered via WP3, which will be designed to include interim and final evaluations, within a Theory of Change. Of particular focus will be improving skills in data management, statistics, ethics, lab. analyses, finance systems, Higher Education curriculum development, and training-of-trainer (ToT) systems. An important component of research capacity strengthening is how research cultures and systems are developed; what works, for whom, when, and why, including how gender and social inclusion strategies are operationalised. Beyond the award, we shall use institute investment to co-develop a joint PhD programme between UoN and UZ, based on new UoN/Malawi models, which shall help to incentivise private sector engagement in the food, nutrition, and agri-services sectors.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZW" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Zimbabwe</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">342754</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">470546.18</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-09-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-09-26">813300.18</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF UKRI Award to University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T015667/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-10-01">120972</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015667_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-01-01">221782</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015667_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">201620</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015667_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">100810</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015667_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">101626.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T015667_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT015667%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
