<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_R006997_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">From the margins: Exploring Low-income Migrant Workers&apos; Access to Basic Services and Protection in the context of India&apos;s Urban Transformation</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Cities are marked by poverty, inequality and marginalisation, with numerous low-income migrants living and working precariously and denied basic amenities and fundamental rights. They depend on poorly-paid intermittent informal sector jobs, and can become vulnerable to abuse, extortion or bribery. Many low-income urban migrants lack documentation and registration, whether for basic services such as health care and schooling or electoral voting, and so are excluded from the promises of urbanisation. Moreover, they lack voice, representation, political recognition and citizenship; language and cultural differences expose many low-income migrants from interior parts of the country or across the border to harassment and political exclusion. The relationship between structural inequalities and poor access to justice, then, is a key project problematic.  Further, scholarship on migrants separates internal and international migration, although de facto political borders, legal arrangements and entitlements to services are ambiguous.  Internal and cross-border low-income urban migrants may have similar de facto citizenship experiences in regard to their entitlements and protection from violence.  Despite their ubiquitous presence, low-income migrants are mobile, dispersed and invisible and their precarious livelihoods, informality and invisibility keep them unnoticed in urban planning, in the work of civil society organisations and in social science research. So they present methodological challenges, especially for creating a sampling frame or mapping in a particular locality. When social researchers attempt to reach out to poor urban migrants, they often assume that slums are an appropriate entry point but such an approach often obscures the economic and social lives of people in informal economy e.g. domestic workers, rag pickers, those involved in petty trade or construction workers who do not necessarily live in one specific site, and therefore remain marginal in development/social interventions. The project&apos;s overall objective is generate evidence to advance the rights and protection mechanisms that must be planned and provided for low-income urban migrants. We shall examine what India&apos;s urban transformation means for low-income migrants, their inclusion and social justice by exploring:  1. Low-income migrants&apos; views on transformations in Indian cities, and the opportunities and challenges that confront them;  2. Low-income migrants perceptions of their entitlements, claim making processes and attempts to protect their own health in a context of poor living and working conditions;   3. The prevalence of violence and extent of exclusion experienced by low-income migrants and how they protect themselves from various forms of violence; 4. The legal, developmental, humanitarian and human rights responses to low-income migrants in Indian cities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indian cities attract a considerable number of low-income migrants from marginal rural households experiencing difficult economic, political and social conditions at home who migrate in search of livelihoods and security. These migrants come from around the country as well as across the border from Nepal, Bangladesh and Myanmar to work in low-income manual occupations in a range of small-scale petty trade, service sector work, transport and construction work. Low-income migrants live and work in precarious conditions and are often denied basic amenities and fundamental rights. Poorly-paid intermittent and insecure jobs make them vulnerable to abuse, extortion or bribery. Many such migrants, both internal and international, lack documentation and proof of identity, whether for basic services such as health care and schooling or electoral voting. Their marginal position entails poorer access to health care provisions and other determinants of health than general (non-migrant) populations, thereby enhancing their vulnerability to ill-health, abuse and ill treatment whilst simultaneously compromising their ability to access protection, legal support or redress, and forms of accountability. Language, appearance and cultural differences exposes many low-income migrants from interior parts of the country or across the border to harassment and political exclusion. Moreover, despite their ubiquitous presence, their precarious livelihoods, informality and invisibility keep them unnoticed in urban planning, in the work of civil society organisations and in social science research.  In this context, this collaborative project has been designed to generate evidence to advance the rights and protection mechanisms that must be planned and provided for low-income urban migrants. We shall examine what India&apos;s urban transformation means for low-income migrants, their inclusion and social justice by exploring:  1. Low-income migrants&apos; views on transformations in Indian cities, and the opportunities and challenges that confront them;  2. Low-income migrants perceptions of their entitlements, claim-making processes and attempts to protect their own health in a context of poor living and working conditions;   3. The prevalence of violence and extent of exclusion experienced by low-income migrants and how they protect themselves from various forms of violence; 4. The legal, developmental, humanitarian and human rights responses to low-income migrants in Indian cities.  Fieldwork based in Guwahati (Assam) and Jalandhar (Punjab), two of India&apos;s fastest growing cities, aims to enrich our understanding of access to health care, the social determinants of health, and experiences of violence, inclusion/exclusion and accessing justice, from the vantage point of diverse low-income migrant workers, from within India as well as cross-border. The project will focus on migrants&apos; perceptions and lived experiences and will generate evidence to advance the rights and protection mechanisms that must be planned and provided for low-income urban migrants. Low-income migrants are mobile, dispersed and invisible, so they present methodological challenges, especially for creating a sampling frame or mapping in a particular locality. A distinctive strength of the project is its innovative methods for accessing these &apos;hard-to-reach&apos; groups.  The proposed research will adopt a mixed methods approach. In order to unravel the nuances and complexities of low-income migrants&apos; experiences and situate these within the broader processes of urban transformation in Jalandhar and Guwahati, we shall combine ethnographic fieldwork with in-depth interviews, a brief survey, and participatory methods such as photovoice.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-05-15" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-21">132907.08</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-21">123721.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
