<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009794_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Understanding early child development in the context of socioeconomic adversity and maternal depression in Brazil and South Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Early child development is a complex process influenced by genetics, environment and socioeconomic factors. These interact from very early life (pregnancy) to shape multiple domains of development including growth, cognitive and language development and behaviour. My research so far has focused on disentangling some of these processes which affect early child development in both high income (UK and the Netherlands) and low and middle income countries (Brazil and South Africa) particularly in the case of adverse childhood experiences. More specifically, my work examines the effects of perinatal mental health on child development. Perinatal depression is prevalent, with about 10% of women experiencing significant depressive symptoms in high income countries (HIC) and 18-25% in low and middle income countries (LMIC). Depression during pregnancy and in the early years of life has been associated with an increased risk of delayed cognitive and language development, emotional and behavioural problems, lower academic achievement (maths) and higher rates of depression at 18 years of age. Parenting is one of the key mechanisms through which depression affects child development and more specifically inconsistent and unresponsive parenting. Children however, are not susceptible to the effects of maternal depression to the same degree. When facing socioeconomic adversity and lack of support, children born to depressed mothers are at increased risk of compromised cognitive development, behaviour and growth. As part of this fellowship I propose to extend some of my ongoing work to examine the impact of socioeconomic adversities on perinatal mental health and early child learning and behaviour. Brazil and South Africa are particularly interesting countries to extend this work to as they are both in rapid economic and social transition and both face high levels of inequality. Both countries face increasing levels of disparities amongst socioeconomic groups, which affect both economic and health outcomes. These transitions place high levels of stress on community and family life. Particularly in LMIC high levels of depressive symptoms are associated with poverty, lack of support and negative life events. Socioeconomic adversity and parental depression are both risk factors for poor development, which often co-occur. This, in combination with the higher rates of perinatal depression in LMIC, places children at increased risk of poor development.   The objectives of this fellowship are to:  1.Extend my current programme of work and examine how socioeconomic adversities in the context of rapidly transitioning societies impact on perinatal mental health and early child learning and behaviour in a sample of HIV-positive mothers in Soweto, South Africa. This cohort will provide data from a sample of socioeconomically disadvantaged women, where child development will be compounded by maternal mental health and maternal HIV-infection both of which are associated with caregiving difficulties (1 paper).    2.Produce publications from ongoing work with the Pelotas birth cohorts, a set of two cohorts set 11 years apart in an urban setting in southern Brazil (2004 and 2015, 2 papers) and on the feasibility of delivering an integrated treatment package of early child stimulation and depression treatment in a rural sample of HIV-positive women and their children in South Africa (1 paper).  3.Communicate these findings through two international conferences and publications as well as through workshops targeting community workers and local NGOs in South Africa.   4.Strengthen the current collaborations and explore opportunities for fellowship applications. Travelling to both South Africa and Brazil will enable me to meet with the teams and the cohort collaborators to discuss future work.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">My research has focused on disentangling some of the complex processes in play, which affect early child development in the context of adversity in both high (UK &amp; the Netherlands) and low and middle income countries (Brazil &amp; South Africa). I propose to extend this work to examine the impact of socioeconomic adversity in the context of rapidly transitioning societies on perinatal mental health and early child learning and behaviour. The aims of this fellowship are: 1.Conduct and publish new limited secondary analyses to examine the association between socioeconomic adversity, perinatal depression and child development (cognitive and socioemotional development) in a large prospective cohort in South Africa, using already collected longitudinal data 2.Produce publications from ongoing work with two large Brazilian cohorts on the role of socioeconomic factors on the association between perinatal depression and child development (analysis to be concluded by Nov 2016), and on the feasibility of conducting an intervention (containing a mental health and early child stimulation component) in rural South Africa with high prevalence of maternal HIV in the context of high levels of community stress (1 paper) 3.Communicate these findings in South Africa (impact plan)  4.Strengthen collaborations and scoping for fellowship applications in Brazil &amp; South Africa   My long term goal is to remain in the field of early child development in the context of adversity and contribute knowledge that can be used to strengthen early stimulation and mental health intervention programmes in LMIC with the aim of addressing inequalities which place children at risk of not reaching their full potential. The work I have carried out has the potential for wide impact and addresses specific development challenges for Brazil and South Africa and a number of sustainable development goals (ODA document).Both Brazil and South Africa are in the midst of rapid social and economic transition with high levels of inequality (GINI indices for Brazil:0.529 &amp; South Africa:0.634) and with increasing disparities amongst socioeconomic groups in both economic and health outcomes. These transitions place enormous stress on communities and family life. Studies from partner institutions have demonstrated the increasing effects of societal stressors on child development. In South Africa, higher levels of child behavioural problems were reported in families with higher partner conflict and family adversity. In Brazil, increasing levels of behavioural problems were reported across two cohorts from 1993 to 2004 with higher increases in children from families with fewer assets and less educated mothers. Perinatal depression is a prime example of such a stressor with a prevalence of about double in Brazil and South Africa compared to high income countries. This is compounded by extensive evidence indicating that the impact of depression on children is moderated by socioeconomic adversity. The higher prevalence rate of perinatal depression combined with socioeconomic adversity is likely to place these children at increased risk of sub-optimal developmental outcomes.  This fellowship would put me in an ideal position to extend the multi-method approach I have used as part of my doctoral training, will allow me to publish work resulting from my doctoral and postdoctoral work, will enable a strong publication record, help establish myself as an independent academic with international work and support fellowship applications. I propose to be based in the Dept. of Psychiatry under the supervision of Prof. Alan Stein and receive additional mentoring from Prof. Jo Boyden (Dept. of International Development). The Dept. of Psychiatry has a strong portfolio of work in LMIC particularly with longitudinal cohorts in South Africa, Brazil, Kenya, Guatemala, India and Philippines. Maintaining this link would contribute significantly to successfully achieving the objectives of the fellowship.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-23" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-23" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-22" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-22" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-11-15"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-15">0.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">ESRC GCRF Post Doctoral Fellowship Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES/P009794/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009794_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009794_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">0.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009794_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">-0.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P009794_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-UKPRN-10007774">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ES%2FP009794%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-01-23"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
