<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007856_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Popular print and reading cultures in francophone Africa</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">By 2050, it is estimated that 85% of the world&apos;s French speakers will be based on the African continent (Observatoire de la langue fran&#xE7;aise, 2014). There are expanding francophone African diasporic populations in North America, Europe, and China. With this future-oriented demographic context in mind, the proposed project will investigate popular writing and reading practices in post-independence Senegal, with a particular focus on magazines. The project addresses urgent issues concerning literacy and development, working with the National Women&apos;s Museum in Dakar and the Institut Fondamental d&apos;Afrique Noire at the University Cheikh Anta Diop in Dakar to develop professional capacity and promote engagement with historic print initiatives within Senegal through a pilot digitisation project and two related exhibitions (one in Dakar, the other in Bristol). Public engagement work and academic outputs (conferences/publications) will build connections to current creative and pedagogical work around reading. This work engages with research priorities in Modern Languages and the Arts and Humanities more broadly, namely the interpretation and preservation of cultural production in the Global South; changing ideas of the public sphere in an era of transnational mobility; and the materiality of post-independence local and national narratives.  From Onitsha market literature in Nigeria to recent online and print channels such as Chimurenga (South Africa) and Kwani? (Kenya), popular print cultures in Africa have to-date been studied in primarily anglophone regions of the continent. This research has highlighted the social worlds of everyday literacies, the emergence of new genres, and the kinds of textual and visual authority wielded by so-called &apos;popular&apos; print. Recent research on print culture in francophone regions of the continent has focused on inequalities in the global literary marketplace and the production of a francophone literary canon. This project will advance those findings by turning to the broader post-independence print archive found in popular magazines and investigating its significance for current and future ideas about reading, writing, and the materiality of the word in the Global South. The core focus will be on three magazines distributed across francophone Africa and its diaspora: Bingo, La Vie Africaine, and Awa: la revue de la femme noire. These magazines have been overlooked due to difficulty of access, leading to potentially narrow understandings of reading cultures in twentieth and twenty-first-century francophone Africa. They acted as vehicles for cultural translation across regions, between urban and rural milieux, as well as transnationally. They evoked a sense of individual and collective identity, themes of work and leisure, ideas of literature (the founding editors were published poets), political solidarity (whether national, or transnational, especially in the Cold War context), and acted as tools for generating future aspirations. The emergence of female writers and readers through these magazines is particular significant, pointing to active networks of female cultural producers that pre-date the canonical &apos;first generation&apos; of African women writers. A central research output of the current project will be a co-authored article analysing quantitatively and qualitatively over 2000 readers&apos; letters that appear in these magazines, based on quantitative and qualitative analysis. This work seeks to identify and analyse instances of reading for pleasure, as well as more instrumental reading practices. In their digitised form, these magazines will provide a rich archive of material for historians, political scientists, and social anthropologists working on this region. Using innovative collaboration between the UK, France and Senegal, the project seeks to collate, curate, research, and promote the archive of popular print production in francophone Africa for academic and non-academic audiences.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2016-11-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-08" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-14" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="SN" type="SENEGAL"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="WESTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1030</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-11-10">75114.83</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The project aims to build capacity for research on reading cultures in Senegal among a number of target groups (cultural practitioners, archivists, students, academics). Through this, it will seek to inform educational strategy by encouraging engagement with less-canonical elements of African print culture and the local print innovation, both past and present.  1. To develop deeper critical and public understanding of writing and reading practices in the context of global development agendas and address the uneven interpretation and preservation of popular cultural production in the Global South.   2. To enable network-building between academics, publishers, and producers of popular print in Senegal today.  3. To forge innovative transnational connections between academics, activists, and cultural institutions in Bristol, Montpellier, and Dakar and thereby advance approaches to knowledge exchange and collaborative dialogues between researchers, archivists, and the heritage sector in the Global North and Global South.  4. To pilot a digitisation project and web interface that will enable international access to popular print magazines (starting with Awa: la revue de la femme noire, the earliest francophone African women&apos;s magazine) and aid professional development in a historic, yet chronically under-resourced, research facility (Institut fondamental d&apos;Afrique Noire).  5. To develop public and scholarly engagement with popular print cultures emerging from francophone Africa in the post-independence period (1950 to present day) via two exhibitions, one held in Senegal and the other in the UK.  6. To relate reading practices/ideas of literacy to changing ideas of the public sphere in post-independence Senegal and in an era of transnational mobility (e.g. increased mobility; the growth of consumerism; increased visibility of female voices; tensions between urban and rural spaces; aspects of ethnicity, caste, social class, and sexuality).  7. With objective 1 in mind, to prepare and analyse a database of 2000+ readers&apos; letters from francophone African magazines published 1950-80.   8. To reflect on the production and reception of popular print cultures within francophone Africa as contributing to the materiality of post-independence history. This will entail a deeper engagement with the legitimacy of the term &apos;popular&apos;, exploring the relationship between form and content (both visual and verbal).  9. To enable discussion and debate around between &apos;popular&apos; literacy and ideas of work and leisure within the framework of international development agendas (with particular attention to the gendered division of labour).  10. To disseminate theoretical findings via a conference (held in Bristol) and study day (held in Montpellier); journal special issue; co-authored article by PI and CI on readers&apos; letters pages; and individual publications/follow-on funding bids authored by PI and CI."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q3">75114.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007856_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">-2957.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_P007856_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bristol</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
