<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T005009_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">MICA: The third, Intensive care bundle with blood pressure reduction in acute cerebral haemorrhage (INTERACT3) trial</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Key objectives of this clinical trial are: 1) To complete the study The patient recruitment target is 8621 from 80+ hospitals worldwide. With financial support from the Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital, and two pharmaceutical companies (Takeda and Credit, &#xA3;561,800), we have activated 45 sites in China and recruited over 2000 patients in the study to date. Further grant funding will allow completion of the project through activation of another 30 sites in China, and expansion to 35 sites in the low- and middle- income countries (LMIC) of Iraq, Nigeria, Pakistan, Vietnam, Brazil, Chile, Peru and Mexico, thus ensuring a reliable and generalizable assessment of the treatment effects. 2) To reduce the heavy burden of intracerebral haemorrhage (ICH) in LMIC The Disability-adjusted-life-years (DALYs) lost from ICH are much higher in LMIC than in developed countries due to higher rates in large, high-risk populations. ICH accounts for at least one fifth of all strokes in LMICs, compared with 10% in high-income countries. This study aims to reduce the burden of ICH in LMIC through conduct of a randomised evaluation of a quality improvement &apos;care bundle&apos; package of care. We assume that this intervention will provide a realistically modest, but clinically important, 5.6% absolute improvement in the proportion of patients avoiding a poor outcome after ICH. This effect size is based upon improving systems of care targeting physiological control: the number needed to treat (NNT) of 18 could have a large impact on outcomes from ICH, particularly in LMIC, but also in being generalizable to high income countries. 3) To seek effective acute management of ICH patients ICH is the most severe and least treatable type of stroke, without a clearly defined, proven treatment: early intensive blood pressure (BP) lowering has shown a moderate benefit but with an evidence rating of Class IIa. More robust and generalizable evidence of the role for specific physiological management strategies are urgently needed in ICH management, especially for low resource settings where the burden of this disease is high. We have based our study on the assumption that a combined strategy, intensive care bundle of BP lowering, glucose control, treatment of pyrexia, and reversal of anticoagulation, will provide a larger benefit than the individual components for ICH patients. The aims are to:  a. determine, as compared to usual care, the effectiveness of a care bundle of active management on poor outcome, defined by death and dependency, as well as physical function, health quality of life, days of hospitalisation and living circumstances, in patients presenting early after the onset of ICH; b. resolve ongoing uncertainties over the efficacy of early intensive BP lowering in ICH, especially in patients who were preferentially excluded from trials - those with severe ICH, large haematomas and requiring decompressive surgery;  c. provide reliable evidence for the updating of guidelines on acute ICH management and assist decision making by physicians, health professionals, and health policy makers.  4) To improve clinical practice of acute care in ICH patients across LMIC a. Understand the patterns of care of ICH patients through systematic data collection on local protocols, pathways and implementation issues, according to current national and international guidelines. This information and the knowledge gained are essential to addressing gaps in the management and treatment of ICH, the impact of the quality improvement strategies being assessed in this study, and stroke care more broadly, across LMIC countries.  b. To explore how complex service interventions can be implemented in LMIC hospitals, identify barriers and facilitators in fidelity to the protocol, and how evidence-based recommendations are adopted/integrated into routine health care practice in LMIC.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The context of the research Acute intracerebral haemorrhage (ICH) is the most severe type of stroke, which affects millions people in the world each year. The incidence of ICH is high in low- and middle- income countries (LMICs), particularly because prevalence of hypertension is high. ICH has a grave prognosis, with at least two thirds of the patients either dying or left with disability. Given the complex and serious nature of ICH, reliable evidence is required to guide health care delivery and policy making. However, the progress has been slow in established clear evidence of benefit for specific management strategies in this condition. However, there is good pre-clinical and observational data indicating that outcomes can be improved through early strict management of several key physiological parameters. Moreover, audits of hospital administrative data for stroke indicate there is widespread poor adherence to many evidence-based recommendations.   Aims and objectives INTERACT3 (The third, INTEnsive care bundle with blood pressure Reduction in Acute Cerebral haemorrhage Trial) is an investigator initiated and conducted, international, multicentre, randomised cluster clinical trial.  The study aims to determine the effectiveness of early intensive care bundle (BP lowering, glycaemic control, treatment of pyrexia, and reversal of anticoagulation).  The overall objectives include: (i) to solve persistent uncertainties of the most appropriate medical management of acute ICH; (ii) to understand the patterns of usual care for ICH in LMIC, in particular in relation to the use of local protocols, pathways and implementation of current national and international guidelines; (iii) to explore the barriers to implementation and adherence to a complex intervention; and (iv) to explore how best to adopt and integrate evidence-based recommendations into routine health care practice in LMICs.  Potential applications and benefits This study will provide reliable evidence on the acute management of ICH and assist decision makings by professionals, service developers, and policy makers in health sectors. Reliable data on ICH management and outcomes could improve quality of care and reduce the high burden of ICH in LMIC. Clinical practice in the care of stroke patients, particularly those with ICH, and adherence to guidelines, could improve outcomes through participation in a high quality clinical trial conducted across multiple hospitals in LMICs.  Moreover, the result could have a widely generalizable benefit, since evaluation of the intervention will be in a broad range of patients, including those severe ICH and/or who undergo surgery, who have been excluded from conventional individual patient randomised trials to date.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-16"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-16">2280496.56</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to George Inst for Global Health Australia</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/T005009/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">George Inst for Global Health Australia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">224257.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T005009_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">George Inst for Global Health Australia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">210395.84</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T005009_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">George Inst for Global Health Australia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">189603.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T005009_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">George Inst for Global Health Australia</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FT005009%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-03-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
