<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R022755_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strengthening the inclusion of persons with disabilities in the health system in Brazi</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Disability is extremely common - the latest Brazil census showed that almost one on four people (24%) had some type of disability, and 6.7% have &quot;severe&quot; disabilities. The prevalence of disability is expected to rise further as the population ages, health behaviours worsen and disabling chronic conditions prevail. People with disabilities are a vulnerable group, who are more likely to be poor and on average have higher healthcare needs. Although Brazil has an extensive and comprehensive health system, and Brazilian policy and law strongly supports the inclusion of people with disabilities in this healthcare system, the Zika epidemic revealed gaps in access. This restriction in access to healthcare is an infringement of the rights of people with disabilities, will lead to poorer health and more poverty and exclusion, and will make it difficult for Universal Health Coverage to be achieved in Brazil. Evidence on what we need to promote inclusion is still lacking, both in Brazil and internationally. We propose to conduct a comprehensive and multi-layered assessment of the health system in Brazil to investigate these issues and identify scalable solutions.  At the national level, we will conduct a policy analysis on the provision of healthcare for people with disabilities. This will include reviewing relevant policies and interviewing key stakeholders. Also at the national level, we will conduct a rehabilitation health system assessment to establish its current state and identify gaps through desk based assessment and interviews.  We will conduct in-depth investigations in three States, selected to cover diverse areas in Brazil: Northeast (Pernambuco), Central-west (District Federal) and Southeast (Sao Paulo). Within each state we will conduct a network analysis to map key stakeholders in the provision of healthcare for people with disabilities. We will use a case-study approach to collect facility-level information, selecting facilities from rural and urban areas, and different levels of health care provision (primary, secondary and hospital). We will collect data through observation, in-depth interviews with health professionals of different cadres, and interviews and focus group discussions with people with disabilities and their carers. The researchers will analyse the data to answer the key study questions, triangulating information across different sources.  A participatory stakeholder workshop will be held to formulate policy and programme recommendations to improve inclusion of people with disabilities in the healthcare system, which includes strengthening the provision of rehabilitation. These recommendations may include health system changes (e.g. restructuring curricula, improving accessibility) as well as proposals for how indicators can be collected to monitor the inclusion of people with disabilities in the health system. People with disabilities will have a central role in designing these interventions. This proposal draws upon three outstanding research groups in Brazil - with expertise in health systems (Pernambuco, Brasilia) and disability (Sao Paulo) - in partnership with disability and health systems researchers at LSHTM. It builds upon existing relationships, as joint grants are already in place between LSHTM and Pernambuco and Brasilia to investigate the healthcare needs of children with disabilities. These research groups are closely linked to key stakeholders in health policy and planning, both within Brazil (e.g. Ministry of Health) as well as internationally (e.g. WHO).  This proposal can help to substantially improve health service delivery for people with disabilities in Brazil, with important lessons learnt for other vulnerable groups in Brazil, as well as for people with disabilities worldwide. Strengthening the health system for these vulnerable groups will improve the service delivery for all, and therefore reap economic and social benefits across Brazil.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aim of this study is to assess the inclusion of people with disabilities in the health system in Brazil to inform how this can be improved.  To achieve this aim, the study will have the five linked objectives.  At the national level, we will: 1. Conduct a policy and systems analysis on the provision of healthcare, including rehabilitation, for people with disabilities in Brazil. 2. Conduct a rehabilitation health system assessment, using the WHO Rehabilitation 2030 tool. Within three contrasting States in Brazil (Sao Paulo, Distrito Federal (DF), Pernambuco), we will:  3. Analyse the experience of people with disabilities in accessing primary healthcare services provided by SUS (considering: access, continuity, coordination, comprehensiveness, quality, equity and efficiency). 4. Analyse the experience of people with disabilities in accessing rehabilitation services and specialist care provided by SUS (considering: access, continuity, coordination, comprehensiveness, quality, equity and efficiency). Using participatory methods, involving a range of stakeholders, we will: 5. Formulate policy and programme recommendations for the strengthening of the inclusion of people with disabilities, including provision of rehabilitation, within the health system.  This study will therefore help to generate interventions, working together with people with disabilities, that will improve the inclusion of people with disabilities in the health system. These changes will help to ensure that their general healthcare needs are met, as well as their needs in terms of specialist care/rehabilitation. These interventions will target different levels of the healthcare system, including health systems planners, healthcare professionals, and people with disabilities. These changes will have a positive impact in Brazil for people with disabilities specifically, but will also help to improve the health system for other vulnerable groups and the population more generally. Furthermore, we will publish these recommendations and work together with our contacts globally in order to help make international improvements in the inclusion of people with disabilities in the healthcare system around the world.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">96199.68</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">96978.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">73323.44</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-03-07"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-03-07">11637723.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Newton Fund Award to London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_R022755_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">London Sch of Hygiene and Trop Medicine</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FR022755%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
