<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015557_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Resilience or resistance? Negotiated mitigation of landslide risks in informal settlements in Medellin</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Approaches to reducing vulnerability and improving resilience to landslides are often difficult to implement, not only because of the resource implications, but also because of complex social, economic, political and institutional processes that surround the establishment and management of informal settlements. Technical fixes are only part of the solution, with other factors often being far more intractable. Key issues that impact on the capacity to manage risk include differences in perception of risk among different stakeholders (from community to state), lack of opportunity for different types of knowledge (informal/informal, technical/social, etc) to interact in the definition of risk and identification of risk-mitigation strategies, lack of resources, and differences in stakeholder agendas and balances of power.  A case in point is that of Medellin, Colombia, where an estimated 44,600 informal settlement households are at risk of landslides in the Medellin Metropolitan Area, expected to rise by at least 13,000 more by 2030. The threat posed by such informal development practices to their own inhabitants was made starkly clear in 1987 when a landslide killed over 500 people in Villatina, a poor neighbourhood, substantially contributing to the estimated 784 low-income residents&apos; deaths due landslides in Medellin over the last 80 years. However, despite the awareness of risk fostered by this event, and the arguments used by the City Administration to relocate certain parts of informal settlements based on geological studies, the residents of the upper parts of this area of Medellin resist relocation and protest that the local government has other motives. Such confrontations are based on a mixture of factors including fear of removal from proximity to existing social networks and income/livelihood sources; distrust of officialdom, fuelled by a perception of double-standards given that certain &apos;formal&apos; buildings are allowed on the slopes; priority given to other demands for infrastructure and services; and possibly the influence of the armed groups that lie behind much of the informal land allocation.   Building on ongoing research and institutional links that have been developed by the proposed team members under British Council Newton-Caldas funded project Medellin Urban Innovation (MUI), this research will develop a knowledge base that will (i) better understand the perceptions of landslide risk; (ii) provide evidenced on tested community-managed landslide risk monitoring and mitigation; and (iii) support negotiated strategic decision-making to manage landslide risk.  The project therefore aims to explore the scope for, and acceptability of, landslide risk-reducing strategies for informal settlements from the community and state perspectives; to understand the barriers to landslide risk-reducing strategies; and identify politically and practically viable approaches to landslide risk-reducing strategies within a wider and more complex context of social and physical risk. This aim will be met through activities addressing the following interconnected research objectives:  Objective 1: Explore the perceptions of risk and related narratives within the community and among relevant public sector agencies, and the implications of such perceptions and narratives for the adoption of risk-mitigating strategies and actions.  Objective 2: Pilot and test informal settlement community-managed landslide risk monitoring and mitigation techniques at the community and individual household level, with potential to be rolled out on a wider scale through community-based researchers and trainers.  Objective 3: Collaboratively identify mechanisms to develop a sustainable process of risk-mitigation strategy-building and implementation through agreement between informal settlement communities and relevant state agencies at different geographic scales.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Urbanisation continues to drive the growth of informal settlements on land exposed to hazards, increasing risk particularly among low-income populations, and heightening the need to improve the resilience of such communities. Informal settlements growing up steep hillsides and ravines are particularly exposed to landslides, which are a major cause of death in developing countries. In order to reduce disasters, we need to anticipate these through managing risk. Many ways of managing landslide risk are known, ranging from building physical protection barriers to raising awareness to prepare communities. However, in developing countries these measures are often difficult to implement, not only because of lack of resources but also due to complex social, economic, political and institutional reasons.    This project aims to explore the scope for, and acceptability of, landslide risk-reducing strategies for informal settlements from the community and state perspectives; to understand the barriers to landslide risk-reducing strategies; and identify politically and practically viable approaches to landslide risk-reducing strategies within a wider and more complex context of social and physical risk.  We will explore these issues in the city of Medellin, Colombia, which has received many accolades for its urban planning and design and has become a &apos;model&apos; for cities elsewhere. Despite the city&apos;s successes, informal settlement growth on land at risk of landslides continues to be a major problem due to its topography. Lessons learnt about landslide risk management in this city have the potential to be easily disseminated across the developing world.  In Medellin, despite the awareness of risk raised by key tragic landslides in its recent history and the arguments used by the City Administration to relocate parts of informal settlements based on geological studies, the residents of these areas resist relocation and protest that the local government has other motives. The project will work in NE Medellin, where there is a high concentration of &apos;at risk&apos; settlements, and in particular in Comuna 8, where disagreements between community and public agencies are most pronounced.  Using focus groups and semi-structured interviews in Comuna 8, we will explore the perceptions of risk and related narratives within the community and among relevant public sector agencies, and the implications of such perceptions and narratives for the adoption of risk-mitigating strategies and actions. This will help us understand the differences between these perceptions which may hinder agreement over risk-mitigation measures. We will then train community members from selected &apos;at risk&apos; neighbourhoods in order to pilot and test simple landslide risk monitoring and mitigation techniques at the community and individual household level, and the participants will evaluate the experience together with other agencies. The findings from these activities will then be reflected on by workshops bringing together community, public sector and third sector across what has been designated as a &apos;Strategic Intervention Area&apos; (NE Medellin) in order to explore viable ways of achieving joint decision-making around landslide risk mitigation.   The project will provide: (1) a functioning pilot community-managed landslide risk mitigation monitoring scheme, which will serve as a model to be replicated elsewhere after improvements based on the evaluation; (2) pilot individual house risk-mitigating improvements as exemplars in the (informal) community; (3) raised understanding and awareness of perceptions of risk and techniques and strategies that can mitigate landslide risk in informal settlements through collaborative action; (4) and identification of key questions around the interaction between technical, social, cultural and organisational knowledges to address in further research on landslide risk mitigation.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heriot-Watt University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-11-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-11-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CO" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Colombia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-25">105939.48</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-25"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-25">158909.17</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC GCRF Directed - International Award to Heriot-Watt University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE/P015557/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heriot-Watt University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">52969.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015557_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heriot-Watt University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">46077.18</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-NE_P015557_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Heriot-Watt University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FP015557%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-11-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
