<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005015_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Guideline Adherence in Slums Project - Template-based documentation and decision support for primary healthcare clinics in the private sector</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Is the intervention useable: Is the intervention describe above acceptable to providers and managers of primary care clinics in low-resource settings in Nairobi and usable within their work flows? 2. Is the intervention effective: Can we improve evidence based care in private sector primary healthcare clinics by increasing the acceptance, use of, and adherence to CPGs? 3. Is the intervention sustainable: Can the intervention be financially sustainable without significant external funding - i.e. will there be financial support from clinics themselves to continue the effort? 4. Can the intervention scale: Is there wide stakeholder support for the intervention if successful?</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">With large numbers of people in slums seeking care through the private sector, it is important to develop tools to help providers in these clinics improve the quality of their services. For example, documenting the need for an antibiotic helps reduce the number of cases of unnecessary antibiotic prescriptions.  Clinical practice guidelines (CPGs) are tools developed to help doctors and nurses give evidence-based care. These are however not easy to use in a patient-facing scenario (e.g. a doctor looking through a manual when the patient is seated in front of him/her). They also need to be tweaked to be relevant to the local context (e.g. is the first line drug available or affordable?). For CPGs to be relevant in low-resource settings it is important to address multiple, if not all, barriers to using guidelines, but in a manner that does not strain limited resources.  Our intervention involves working with clinical care providers and developing templates (think checklist) that can be used while they are seeing the patient. The templates take the form of rubber stamps that can be printed into the paper case sheet (e.g. if a woman presents with increased frequency of urination, the clinician stamps the Urinary Tract Infection template into her case sheet). This template is both a guide to what questions to ask the patient and how to manage UTIs. Other illnesses get other templates, but a set of 6-8 templates covers the majority of patients walking into primary care clinics.  Importantly these templates are easy to digitise and analyse. They are in the form of a multiple choice exam paper where bubbles need to be shaded. A cell phone image of a filled-in template can quickly give us data on how the case was managed without revealing patient identity. Being rubber stamps we avoid the need to keep track of multiple printed sheets of paper. We also avoid wastage when guidelines change because changing the rubber engraving on the stamp is simple and cheap.  We now have a tool to easily monitor the clinician&apos;s work, check for quality, and work with them if there are reasons to deviate from the guidelines by during regular feedback sessions. The intervention is being used in two slum clinics in Nairobi with great initial responses.   We now want to study this intervention in a set of 10 different private sector clinics in Nairobi&apos;s slums. We would like to test if this intervention is: a) Usable - different clinics have different priorities and attitudes and we need to be sure that the intervention poses no big challenges b) Effective - does the intervention actually improve clinical practice (e.g. by reducing unnecessary antibiotic prescription)? c) Sustainable - how much does it cost for us to support these clinics with tools and feedback? Can the clinics afford to pay us for this service? d) Scalable - is there a realistic chance for us to roll this intervention out at national (or even provincial) level?  If successful the intervention has the potential to change how healthcare is delivered in low-resource settings. More and more people are seeking care in the private sector, but very few regulations, services and tools exist to ensure that care in the private sector is of high quality. We hope to make a significant impact in the quality of care that is delivered to the poor.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-05-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-10-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-12-29" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="KE" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Kenya</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-29">31997.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-29">52219.05</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-07-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-07-29">98972.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to Strathmore University</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/N005015/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">17359.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005015_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-01">17359.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005015_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-10-01">17500.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005015_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">14096.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N005015_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Strathmore University</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN005015%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-09-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
