<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_S01988X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Using host-responses and pathogen genomics to improve diagnostics for tuberculosis in Bandung, Indonesia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Tuberculosis disease (TB) is a major public health issue in Indonesia with over one million cases and 123,000 deaths in 2016 alone. Worldwide, the World Health Organisation estimates that there are nine million new TB cases and nearly two million deaths each year. The increasing prevalence of multi-drug resistance strains is making disease control difficult. Until today, diagnosing active TB, especially in the early stages, is difficult and requires a sputum sample. In addition, current treatment takes more than 6 months of therapy, with diagnostics unable to help identify early treatment failure. An eventual diagnosis of drug resistance may mean extended further treatment for 2 years.  This project seeks to identify a new diagnostic assay that uses a small blood sample to measure the patient&apos;s response to the tuberculosis infection, instead of looking for the tuberculosis bacterium directly. This assay could be able to identify patients earlier and monitor their treatment response. This would allow earlier treatment and more rapid ability to alter therapy to a more appropriate regimen.  This project will link the Dr. Hasan Sadikin Hospital, Faculty of Medicine Universitas Padjadjaran (DHSH-UNPAD), with the Eijkman Institute for Molecular Biology and the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine - three institutions at the forefront of infectious disease research - to enable world class research. The project will also allow for the training of Indonesian researchers in genomic technologies and analysis to allow local capacity building.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-03-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-17" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ID" type="INDONESIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="FAR EAST ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">789</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-18">114012.2</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-18">114935.72</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-12-18">115866.51</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="Tuberculosis (TB), caused by Mycobacterium tuberculosis, is a major infectious disease in Indonesia. The overarching aim of the project is to develop a TB human blood transcriptome response assay risk score that could be used to identify active TB and evaluate treatment response in reducing active disease. We will utilise clinics in the Dr. Hasan Sadikin Hospital, Faculty of Medicine Universitas Padjadjaran (DHSH-UNPAD) to enrol more than 1,000 subjects, and assess the diagnostic developed, across different lineages and strains of M. tuberculosis, drug resistance profiles and patient HIV status. The assay developed will be compared to standard care diagnostic procedures undertaken at the DHSH-UNPAD.  This proposal will focus on four overlapping objectives, to:   (1) Identify a transcriptomic signature of active TB in DHSH-UNPAD patients; (2) Develop the transcriptomic signature into an in-house PCR-based assay;  (3) Convert the PCR transcriptomic signature into a risk score protocol that could be utilised clinically; (4) Evaluate the performance of the risk score in identifying treatment failures;  (5) Capacity-build DHSH-UNPAD staff for performing genomic investigations and analysis.     Success of the research proposal could lead to more informed protocols for treatment change that would be applicable to Indonesia and worldwide. The assays will be of a generic format and should be transferable to nano-scale reactions that could significantly increase the speed of the reaction, with greatly reduced cost, when suitable platform devices for this procedure are developed."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
