<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003389_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF: Pseudo-Panels for Long Period Analysis of African Household Surveys</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">National household surveys have become the standard source of data for analysis of poverty in developing countries. A major limitation of these surveys for Africa, in terms of the potential to analyse poverty dynamics, is that they are not a panel - different households are surveyed in each wave so they constitute repeated cross sections. It is therefore not possible to track the same households over time to investigate the drivers of poverty reduction. This creates challenges for analysis with endogenous variables, such as interactions between household size and poverty or migration, remittances and household income. The absence of a panel also limits analysis of determinants of household welfare over long periods.  The strategy we propose to address this data restriction is to identify representative household types to construct pseudo panels making use of the repeated cross section household surveys (see the Case for Support). Analysis of the pseudo panel allows one to track similar households and complements household-level analysis for each survey. The project will develop methods for constructing pseudo-panels that can be applied, with suitable modifications for specific features of the surveys, in any country with three or more national household surveys. In principle, the methods are also applicable to census and Demographic and Health Survey data. Although the project focuses on Uganda (1992-2012 using eight existing surveys), the methods for constructing and analysing pseudo-panels can be applied to other African countries. Utilising established links with local research partners, hence largely &apos;off-budget&apos;, the pseudo-panel method will be applied to Ghana (1991-2013 using 6 surveys) and Tanzania (1991-2012 using 4 surveys).These three countries all have managed to roughly halve headcount poverty since the early 1990s.  We use the repeated cross-section survey data to form a pseudo panel of &apos;representative&apos; households by grouping individual households (the observational units) into cohorts on the basis of time invariant characteristics (location, gender and birth cohort of household head). The cohorts are then traced over time as they appear in successive surveys, forming a pseudo panel with &apos;lagged values&apos;. As the cohort fixed effect is correlated with cohort (household) characteristics that are unobserved and not constant over time due to the changing membership of the cohorts in each survey, an errors-in-variables estimator is used to correct the cohort means as estimates of the unobservable population means. The lagged dependent variable is constructed from an auxiliary regression with an augmented instrumental variables estimator using time-invariant instruments. The pseudo panel therefore permits a long (20 years or more) analysis of determinants of household welfare and poverty reduction, with the potential to generate internal instruments for endogenous variables and to identify effects of policy changes (such as Universal Primary Education in Uganda).   The project is expected to make a number of contributions. First, methods for constructing and using pseudo-panels will be developed, tried and tested generating a transferable method of potential use for most developing countries, especially in Africa where there are many surveys but few panels. Second, the pseudo-panel will be used to provide new insights on the drivers of poverty reduction in Uganda, with more limited applications (during the life of this project) to Ghana and Tanzania. Third, through training and research collaboration we will support building research capacity in Africa (specifically Uganda). To support these aims, an inception workshop in Kampala will include a variety of stakeholders with focus groups to identify the important research and policy issues; there will be dissemination in country and through AERC; and training will be provided to local researchers.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2017-01-31"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-01-31" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-07-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-09-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">998</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-02">26279.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-02-02">105332.35</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The principal objective is to develop methods to construct reliable pseudo-panels from repeated cross-section household surveys, contributing a new secondary data analysis method to make greater use of existing national household surveys for African countries. The pseudo-panels will be applied to examine the determinants of household welfare over a relatively long (20 years or more) period, using Uganda as the initial case study (extending to Ghana and Tanzania). National household surveys form the basis for most analysis of poverty but a limitation, especially for Africa, is that the surveys are not a panel (do not cover the same households in each wave of the survey), they are repeated cross-sections. This limits the potential for dynamic analysis to track particular households over time and for identifying determinants of changes in household welfare and poverty. By devising methods to construct reliable pseudo-panels the project will contribute to research and policy on poverty reduction and household welfare, especially in Africa.  Pseudo-panels involve grouping individual observations (households) into cohorts and using the cohort means as representative household observations in a genuine panel. The general principle is that if there are sufficient households within each cohort the cohort sample means are a good approximation of the cohort population means. Two issues arise in constructing pseudo-panels: addressing aggregation bias, which depends on how the cohorts are constructed, and measurement error bias (which can be addressed through the estimator used for analysis). For a given survey sample size, the larger is each cohort the fewer the number of cohorts so there is a trade off: a sufficiently large number of cohorts  is required to capture different types of households with sufficient cross-cohort variation for analysis, whereas sufficiently large cohort sizes are required to avoid bias. There is no consensus in the literature on appropriate cohort numbers and sizes, but this is an important issues for African household surveys as the samples are relatively small. The researchers have worked on criteria for cohort construction using four waves of a Uganda panel over 2005-12 to produce consistent estimates from the pseudo-panel and a statistical test to assess that the cohort level data contain sufficient variation for accurate estimates (based on variation across cohort means, over time and within cohort groups). The first objective is to extend this to construct a Ugandan pseudo-panel covering the period 1992 to 2012 and incorporating eight existing surveys.    The second objective is to use the pseudo-panel to identify drivers of household welfare and poverty in Uganda over the 20 year period. This is an issue of major policy relevance given the importance of reducing poverty. Although Uganda has halved headcount poverty since the early 1990s (Ghana and Tanzania have similar achievements), poverty remains high and there is limited understanding of which factors contribute to improving household welfare and poverty reduction. The pseudo-panel will offer new insights into the dynamics of poverty reduction. In particular, it provides an opportunity to address household variables that may be endogenous with respect to welfare (e.g. household size and poverty; migration and poverty).   We will engage with stakeholders in an inception workshop to identify the core questions on determinants of poverty reduction to address in the research, and a Ugandan researcher will be identified to partner in this analysis. Following a dissemination workshop in Kampala towards the end of the project training will be provided to local researchers (mostly Ugandan with some invited from Kenya and Tanzania). While Policy Briefs on specific poverty issues will only be written for and disseminated in Uganda, the methods developed will be disseminated more widely through presentations at meetings of the AERC."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">52559.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q2">26279.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">26279.87</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">26492.74</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">3368.04</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ES_P003389_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000664">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Nottingham</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
