<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_N017269_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leishmania virulence factors and host peptidases associated with visceral leishmaniasis</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. To test if host serine peptidases influence pathogenesis in vitro and in vivo models of infection with L chagasi.  2. To identify the underlying molecular mechanisms and metabolic pathways influenced by neutrophil serine peptidases in experimental visceral leishmaniasis (VL).   3. To investigate if neutrophil serine peptidases are also relevant to the outcome and clinical symptoms of human infections by L chagasi.   4. To investigate if there is a correlation between parasite genotype and clinical presentation for VL in Brazil.  5. To set up a network of researchers in the UK and Brazil working on the pathogenesis of leishmaniasis  Specifically:   a) Create L. donovani and L. chagasi mutants lacking ISP2 or over-expressing ISP2 and mutants expressing red shifted luciferase.   b) In vitro infection of L. chagasi in thioglycolate macrophages isolated from B6, Ela2-/-, CG-/- mice to test the role of different host serine peptidase on infection dynamics. The production of type I Interferons and pro-inflammatory products will be tested to establish a correlation between the requirement of host SPs and innate macrophage responses.   c) Evaluate the kinetics of vesicle fusion with nascent phagosomes containing internalised parasites in infected macrophages using Leishmania transgenic fluorescent lines and organelle-specific fluorescent dyes by time-lapse in live cell microscopy; RNAi or CRISPR/Cas9 knockdown/knockout will be carried out with endosomal markers and subsequent tests carried out on the influence in parasite intracellular development.   d) In vivo infection of L. chagasi in WT B6 and Ela2-/- , CG-/- mice. Parasite burden in the liver will be monitored using red shifted luciferase expressing L. chagasi for longitudinal imaging.   e) Perform RNAseq to identify altered metabolic, immune and haematological pathways in infected Ela-/- and/or CG-/- mice, compare with uninfected mice. Differentially expressed genes will be validated by qRT-PCR and/or protein expression, and the biological significance of observed changes in transcriptome will be probed using in vitro assays of macrophage infectivity or in vivo using pharmacological agents or genetically modified mice.   f) Carry out full pathological characterisation of mice at post mortem, to evaluate signs of immune-protection (granuloma formation), immune pathology (e.g. lymphoid tissue remodelling and coagulopathy (e.g. microthrombus formation, systemic bleeding).   g) Test clinical isolates of L. chagasi for the infection in vitro in macrophages isolated from B6, Ela-/-, CG-/- . Real time PCR will determine the expression levels of ISP2 in each line, in comparison with reference strains. Selected clinical lines with differing phenotypes will be transfected with REH luciferase and the burden of disease monitored in vivo to determine if any pathophysiological characteristics associated with human disease (e.g. bleeding) can be replicated in an animal model. Analysis of blood samples, including by SNP analysis, to identify potential biomarkers of disease and immune response.   h) Genome Analysis of clinical isolates using Illumina paired-end protocols. Sequencing of isolates will allow the identification of any large-scale structural differences (such as chromosome re-arrangements) between the Brazilian L. chagasi strains and the reference L. infantum JPCM5 strain. SNPs will be surveyed across the genome for the identification of potential markers of disease outcome. Perform predictive analysis to classify the samples into disease states using a calculated gene dose (cCNV and gCNV combined) and a principal components regression approach or a variation of the nearest shrunken centroids method. The additional sequencing and more accurate estimates of genomic variance between disease-states will potentially allow the identification of predictive biomarkers for VL disease progression. Analyse polymorphism for specific virulence factors such as ISP2.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Leishmaniasis is a severe disease of humans and one of the world&apos;s most neglected diseases, primarily affecting the poor in developing countries.  350 million people are at risk of contracting the disease and it has severe costs in both health and economic terms and drains resources that could be used to promote growth of developing nations. There is no effective vaccine against the disease and chemotherapy is the prime means for reducing the leishmaniasis burden. Visceral Leishmaniasis (VL) is the most severe form of leishmaniasis with 6,000 cases recorded in Brazil each year.  Unfortunately the drugs available to treat VL have many limitations and new drugs are desperately needed. Our aim in this collaborative project is to characterise key biological processes of Leishmania chagasi, the parasite that causes VL in Brazil, and so identify factors that influence the outcome of disease. We have shown that peptidases, enzymes that digest proteins, and natural inhibitors that block peptidase function, are important in the infectivity and pathogenicity of the parasite. Our work will concentrate on 3 key areas of the biology of the parasite and its interaction with the host. Firstly, we will test if peptidases in the mammalian host are important for the pathogenesis of the disease.  To do this we will use an animal model of infection using the L. chagasi parasite and mice.  A key approach will be to genetically manipulate important Leishmania genes to find out what role the encoded proteins play in the parasite&apos;s infectivity and virulence and to determine whether they might be exploited as novel therapeutics.  Secondly, we shall investigate the genome variation that occurs in different strains of Leishmania.  We will sequence the genomes of L. chagasi parasites isolated from patients in the State of Piaui in Brazil with different clinical VL outcome and identify parasite genes that might influence the presentation of disease.  We will integrate parasitological and immunological studies in animal models and humans and overall, we expect the outcome from this study to be a greatly improved understanding on the roles of these biological processes in Leishmania, and the molecular mechanisms of the processes themselves - which will be relevant to many areas of biology.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">22547.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">140214.29</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">113468.85</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">77253.4</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-01-13"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-01-13">367189.51</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/N017269/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN017269%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-01-14"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
