<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_P015816_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The role of plasma membrane calcium ATPase 4 (PMCA4) in modulating Plasmodium infection and malaria severity</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Malaria is a major public health problem in many parts of the world including Indonesia, causing an estimated 150-300 million clinical cases and killing more than 430 thousand people annually (WHO Report, 2015).  Strategies to control malaria that have demonstrated some success include anti-malaria treatment for infected individuals, application of insecticide to reduce mosquito populations, and reduction of human contact with infected mosquitoes via bednets. However, the rapid spread of parasite resistance to the currently available anti-malarial drugs has hampered large-scale efforts at malaria control within the last few years. Development of new anti-malarial drugs that target novel biochemical pathways is needed to avoid cross resistance.  Recent genetic studies in human populations have identified a calcium pump called PMCA4 that is present in human red blood cells and in cells lining the blood vessels (endothelium) to have a very strong association with resistance against malaria infection and the occurrence of brain malaria. These findings imply that PMCA4 can be used as a possible target for anti-malaria treatment and for the reduction of cerebral malaria, the most deadly complication of this disease.   Pilot observations conducted through a collaboration between scientists at The University of Manchester and Eijkman Institute Indonesia have demonstrated that treatment with drugs that inhibit PMCA4 activity might reduce malaria infection in a mouse model as well as in a cell culture system. Based on this promising preliminary result, in this project we will further investigate whether: 1) Inhibition of PMCA4 genetically in mice will inhibit the growth of malaria parasite (Plasmodium) and reduce the occurrence of experimental brain malaria 2) Inhibition of PMCA4 using a potent and specific pharmacological inhibitor will inhibit the growth of malaria parasite (Plasmodium) in mice and reduce the occurrence of experimental brain malaria 3) In the Indonesian population genetic variations in the PMCA4 gene are associated with resistance against malaria and severity of the disease.  It is expected that this study will provide new information on how malaria infection is regulated at the molecular level. If our hypothesis is correct this project may identify a novel pharmacological target for malaria treatment.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The aims of the proposed project are: 1. To investigate the effects of plasma membrane calcium ATPase 4 (PMCA4) global and cell specific gene ablation on the resistance to murine Plasmodium infection and the development of experimental cerebral malaria (ECM)  2. To investigate whether PMCA4 pharmacological inhibition will reduce parasite infection and the development of experimental cerebral malaria (ECM) in vivo in a mouse model of Plasmodium infection as well as in vitro in human red blood cell culture of P.falciparum.   3. To investigate whether gene polymorphism(s) within the human PMCA4 gene are associated with resistance and/or severity of malaria in the Indonesian population  4. To study the molecular mechanism by which the polymorphism(s) affect PMCA4 expression</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-12-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-07-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ID" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indonesia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">68634.56</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">137825.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">34595.24</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-08-22"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-08-22">275650.11</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Research Grants Award to The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/P015816/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The University of Manchester</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FP015816%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
