<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Evaluating iron and zinc bioavailability from biofortified potatoes to reduce malnutrition in the Andean highlands.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iron and zinc deficiencies are the most common micronutrient deficiencies worldwide and disproportionately affect the poorest and most vulnerable populations in resource-limited settings negatively impacting upon health, child development and economic activity. Significant investment has been made by national programmes and international agencies in the development of staple crops that have been biofortified with iron and zinc as a cost-effective strategy to ameliorate iron and zinc deficiencies. However, there have been relatively few studies to quantify whether the enhanced levels of iron and zinc in these biofortified crops is effectively absorbed by humans following consumption and contributes to improving iron and zinc status - that is whether it is &apos;bioavailable&apos;. A major reason for this is due to the technical challenges involved with accurately quantifying bioavailability with human intervention studies that require the use of stable isotopes of iron and zinc. Iron and zinc deficiencies are widespread amongst low income groups in rural and urban populations in Peru and throughout the Andean Highlands. The diet of these peoples is dominated by potatoes, with little animal products, cereals and vegetables. The International Potato Centre (CIP) in Peru has developed iron and zinc biofortified potatoes, and has worked with small scale farmers and NGOs to select diploid biofortified potatoes that have enhanced levels of iron and zinc and are widely accepted by farmers and consumers. These materials are being used to develop elite biofortified tetraploid potatoes that will be introduced into Africa and Asia. While iron and zinc concentrations in potato are lower than that reported for cereals and legumes, their bioavailability is likely to be significantly higher due to the presence of high levels of vitamin C, which promotes iron absorption in the human body, combined with low levels of phytic acid, an inhibitor of iron and zinc absorption. Studies with cell and rodent models support the hypothesis that iron and zinc from potatoes is highly bioavailable. However, to date there have been no human studies to quantify bioavailability. Thus, to assess the potential impact of the potato biofortification program in reducing iron and zinc deficiencies, human studies are required to gain insight on how much of the iron and zinc from biofortified potatoes are absorbed by the human body and could contribute to an improvement in iron and zinc status.  The primary objective of the proposed research is to determine the human bioavailability of iron and zinc from biofortified potatoes as compared to a non-fortified local variety. Human trials will be undertaken with volunteers in the Huancavelica region of Peru to test the hypotheses that iron and zinc from biofortified potatoes is bioavailable. These trials require incorporation of iron and zinc stable isotopes into the meals of the biofortified and non-fortified potatoes, and the analyses of the isotopes in subsequent blood and urine samples.   The secondary objective is to use the data obtained from the human studies to model the potential impact of the introduction of biofortified potatoes to the alleviation of iron and zinc deficiencies in the Andean Highlands and low and middle-income countries elsewhere. We will apply a Disability Adjusted Life Year (DALY) methodology which is an appropriate approach to estimate nutritional and health impacts of biofortified crops. In addition, we will use data on habitual diet, serum ferritin concentrations and iron bioavailability to adapt a recently developed model to estimate dietary iron requirement in Europe to the Andean highland region and, more generally, to low and middle-income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Iron and zinc deficiency are global problems, with high prevalence in Asia, Sub-Saharan Africa and South America. While iron and zinc supplementation and food fortification programmes have been shown to be efficacious in certain situations, their implementation requires good infrastructure, significant investment and safe delivery systems. The development of crops with enhanced levels of bioavailable iron and zinc - so called biofortification - is a sustainable and cost-effective complementary strategy that has the potential to provide sufficient iron and zinc for resource poor rural and urban communities, such as those in the Andean highlands. There has been significant effort within the international community to breed new varieties of staple crops that have enhanced levels of iron and/or zinc. It is however difficult to predict whether the additional iron and zinc in biofortified crops would be bioavailable - that is effectively absorbed from the diet into the body to improve iron and zinc status. The risk in breeding these biofortified crops is that the investment in crop development will have limited impact if the iron and zinc is not bioavailable.  Iron and zinc biofortified potato are an ideal crop to contribute to a reduction in iron and zinc deficiencies in the Andean highlands for two major reasons. Firstly, unlike cereals and legumes, potatoes have very low levels of phytates which inhibit iron bioavailability, and this is combined with a relatively high concentration of vitamin C which promotes iron absorption - an ideal combination to maximize bioavailability. Secondly, potatoes are the major staple in the diet amongst the iron and zinc-deficient Andean population, and are largely consumed without other foods. Thus, while various strategies including agricultural diversification have potential to alleviate micronutrient deficiencies and should be considered in an integrated approach, biological, cultural and economic factors suggest that the introduction of iron and zinc biofortified potatoes may be an effective approach to have a significant contribution to reducing iron and zinc deficiencies. Quantifying the bioavailability of iron and zinc at this time is critical. The bioavailability of iron and zinc from biofortified crops can only be meaningfully quantified through human dietary intervention studies in which foods made from the biofortified crops are labelled with stable isotopes of iron or zinc, which are subsequently quantified human tissues to provide a measure of bioavailability. These studies are technically challenging, but of the utmost importance for the success of biofortification strategies. To quantify the potential impact of the introduction of biofortified potatoes, data from the human studies will be used within a Disability Adjusted Life Year (DALY) modelling approach. This method has been successfully applied to assess the potential impact of other biofortified crops to alleviate micronutrients deficiencies. Furthermore, we will use data from the proposed research along with that from other studies to develop iron dietary intake guidelines for low and middle-income countries.  If we find compelling evidence through the human intervention studies and the subsequent DALY modeling that iron and zinc biofortified potatoes can contribute to alleviation of iron and zinc deficiencies in low and middle income countries, it will provide the justification for investment from the international donor community and national research programmes for further development and selection of clones of diploid and tetraploid potatoes that have enhanced iron and zinc content, and their transfer to national agricultural research programmes in south America, Asia and Africa. Subsequently, these programmes and their associated extension programmes and NGOs will ensure the introduction of biofortified potatoes to small scale farmers in regions of high iron and zinc deficiencies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-19">503891.43</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-19">372886.17</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-03-19">124295.37</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">123296.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quadram Institute Bioscience</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">134001.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quadram Institute Bioscience</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">123296.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quadram Institute Bioscience</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">123296.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quadram Institute Bioscience</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">124295.39</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quadram Institute Bioscience</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q2">124295.39</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quadram Institute Bioscience</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q3">124295.39</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_S014039_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quadram Institute Bioscience</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
