<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R013853_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">CALOPUS - Computer Assisted LOw-cost Point-of-care UltraSound</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CALOPUS Project brings together an inter-disciplinary UK-India team to address the novel engineering solutions required to provide relatively unskilled healthcare workers in low-middle income countries (LMICs) with a point-of-care ultrasound (POCUS) system to ensure that pregnant women are referred to the appropriate level of care based on automated analysis of ultrasound images of the growing fetus and placenta. The primary research objectives are: 1. To develop a novel simple-to-use automated low-cost ultrasound-based software method that uses deep learning to analyze medical ultrasound video scans acquired to a standardized protocol to give an actionable traffic light system referral recommendation to a healthcare professional.  2. To develop medical image analysis methods for determining 3D fetal position, and orientation from 2D medical ultrasound video as the basis for a communication tool between a healthcare worker and a patient. 3. To develop medical image analysis methods to anonymize gender in fetal ultrasound video. To integrate methods 1-3 together,  4. to perform a pilot study, in an appropriate clinical setting in India, to test performance of the methods, and to conduct a usability assessment. Secondary objectives concerning knowledge exchange, capacity-building and network-building are: 5. (UK-to-India) To train a researcher in the India team in ultrasound image analysis via a visit hosted at Oxford, and on-the-job training with includes mentorship buy UK researchers. 6.  (India-to-UK) To educate the UK-based researchers on healthcare needs in India, and how to map these to healthcare technology research questions and solutions. 7. (Network building) To hold two research workshops in India to encourage scientific debate and discussion of future new collaborations in point-of-care technologies and ultrasound-based technologies for healthcare needs in India and other LMICs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The CALOPUS project is an inter-disciplinary UK-India collaboration that aims to automate the analysis of antenatal ultrasound images to facilitate referral to the appropriate level of pregnancy care in rural settings, an important unmet need in many LMICs. Unlike in the western world, many women in India do not have an antenatal ultrasound check-up scan in the first or second trimester. Without such a check-up, health problems of the fetus and mother can go unnoticed, leading, in the worst case, to a still-birth or preterm birth. India has the highest number of still births and preterm births in the world (Lancet 2O15, 2012).  Thus the ultimate clinical aim motivating this work is to reduce the burden of adverse pregnancy events and improve the health of future generations.  The approach we are taking is to use a low-cost portable imaging technology, ultrasound imaging, as the basis for a novel point-of-care (POC) system that enables a healthcare worker, with limited or no knowledge of ultrasound, to refer a patient to a clinical unit or hospital. Ultrasound scanning normally requires skill to acquire images which is a barrier to use. Our idea is to combine capture of ultrasound videos with machine learning (deep learning) to automatically interpret the content of the ultrasound videos and make the recommendation to the non-expert user. This project explores how we can do this, and will look, as well, at how we can make the technological solution culturally acceptable, and usable in the intended clinical environment.   In addition to the primary scientific endeavour, an important secondary objective will be capacity-building in point-of-care imaging in the India partner team and counter-mentoring of UK investigators in health (particularly in factors related to healthcare technology needs and adoption), and research and cultural issues that are at play in LMICs. This cross-dialogue will strengthen the international team and build mutual respect and complementary expertise.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-01-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-11">73114.87</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-11">341551.28</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-11">346110.71</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-11">252885.45</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-11">10136623.08</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Oxford</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_R013853_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Oxford</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=EP%2FR013853%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2018-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
