<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021355_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">A Pilot Study of Improving Outcomes in Teenage Pregnancy Using a Combined Tailored M- Health Program and Motivational Interviewing Intervention</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mortality among pregnant teenagers in South Africa (SA) is very high: institutional Maternal Mortality Ratio (iMMR) of 67.1 deaths per 100,000 live births in teenagers; with 71.7% of deaths resulting from four causes: hypertension (22.8%); non-pregnancy related infections (21.1%) (HIV/AIDS-related, such as TB or pneumonia); obstetric haemorrhage (14.2%); and medical and surgical disorders (13.6%). Risk factors for these include poor antenatal clinic (ANC) attendance, lack of adherence to antiretroviral therapy, poor compliance to treatment for tuberculosis, inadequate management of preeclampsia, and slow referral of high risk pregnancies to secondary and tertiary centres. Changing the health-related behaviour of pregnant teenagers, using an m-health intervention combined with motivational interviewing (MI), could reduce the prevalence of these risk factors and, thus reduce mortality. This pilot study will test the feasibility, user acceptability and preliminary efficacy of an enhanced version of MomConnect - an m-Health program developed by our partners, the Praekelt Foundation and the SA National Department of Health (NDOH).The enhancements include adding tailored content to the SMS messaging platform; and an MI counselling intervention (4 sessions) delivered face to face by trained healthcare workers. The SMS messages will be tailored by age (13 - 19 years), motivational variables, appointment adherence, language and culture. Messages will be designed, pretested, and refined through formative evaluation procedures, under direction of our health communications expert. The revised program, Teen-MomConnect, will integrate both the enhanced SMS messages and the MI counselling for each pregnant teenager. For example, the MI counsellors will have access to the survey question responses, as well as ANC appointment-keeping status obtained via the cell phone. The MI clinical behavioural counselling training and implementation will be designed by, and pilot tested with health workers, who will deliver the counselling. Starting from week 12 of their pregnancy, the teenagers will receive 4 MI sessions delivered face to face (or via cell phone) at the ANC by a healthcare worker. The study has two phases. Phase 1 aims to develop, test, refine, and then pilot the major program enhancements (SMS and MI) to MomConnect. Phase II is the pilot field test and its aims are:1) to demonstrate whether pregnant teenagers can be recruited and retained in the study; 2) whether the causes of 71.7% of mortality in pregnant teenagers can be measured, 3) to establish uptake rates (both SMS use and completion of MI visit) for the enhanced Teen-MomConnect intervention; 4) evaluate if the integrated motivational behavioural face to face counselling, and the tailored health SMS intervention, impact pregnant teenagers ANC attendance (primary outcome), and the other risk factors for teenage maternal mortality. For the Phase II field pilot study, 200 pregnant teenagers will be recruited through clinics, schools and community organisations - 100 will be randomised to the behavioural intervention of Teen-MomConnect plus MI; and 100 will be given &quot;usual care&quot; with MomConnect alone. The study will take 18 months to complete at a cost of &#xA3;150,000.The results of the pilot will be used to design a randomised controlled trial (RCT) to test the effectiveness of the Teen-MomConnect in a fully powered cohort of pregnant teenagers. The RCT will also include a cost effectiveness analysis. The products from this grant will include the Teen-MomConnect App and SMS messages; an MI training program for health workers; research instruments that have been designed and validated for the larger RCT; recruitment and retention protocols and a partnership between an international collaboration of scientists, Praekelt Foundation and the NDOH. This grant application has received the support of the NDOH who have issued a letter of support.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Primary Aim of the project is to:     Enhance the messaging capacity of MomConnect by adding tailored messaging (by age, motivational variables, appointment adherence, language and culture), and to add an MI training/counselling component, delivered by health workers that is integrated into MomConnect.     The Objectives are to:  - Design and pretest messages for the pregnant teenagers through a formative evaluation and consumer response process. - Integrate the Teen-MomConnect messages into the MomConnect platform.  - Design and pilot an MI training program for nurses, midwives and health educators. - Pilot the enhanced MomConnect program among 200 pregnant SA teenagers - Evaluate if the integrated MI face to face counselling and the tailored health SMS intervention has an impact on pregnant teenagers&apos; ANC    attendance and the risk factors for mortality.  - Establish a mechanism for gathering information from 13 - 19 year olds from the MomConnect system via SMS and electronic surveys    (QUALTRICS) - Design and refine recruitment and retention strategies. - Calculate potential recruitment and retention rates for the future RCT. - Develop and test the qualitative and quantitative measures for the future RCT. - Establish uptake rates for Teen-MomConnect including the SMS and MI components. - Develop a data collection and management plan that will be used in the future RCT. - Develop a cost effectiveness analysis methodology of the intervention for the RCT. - Establish collaboration mechanisms with Praekelt and NDOH</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-09-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-10-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">82528.32</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">45940.08</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-02-12"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-02-12">151527.6</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/N021355/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-07-01">35994.1</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021355_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-01-01">46534.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021355_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-04-01">22880.95</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021355_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">23059.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021355_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-04-01">6101.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N021355_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Human Sciences Research Council</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FN021355%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2016-06-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
