<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE_M021335_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Food Security and Land Use: The Telecoupling Challenge</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Telecoupling Consortium, consists of four focal countries (Brazil, China, U.K. and U.S.), five tentative vulnerable spillover countries in Africa (Kenya, Mozambique, Tanzania, Uganda, and Zambia), two major CGIAR centers (CIAT and IFPRI) and FAO-and stakeholder involvement from all of the above to co-design, co-produce and co-implement the project. We bring together a team of natural and social scientists with an innovative framework, Telecoupling - socioeconomic and environmental interactions among coupled human and natural systems at different scales over great distances - to transform how we think about collateral effects from international trade on food security and land use dynamics. We address Theme 3 (Feedback Loops), focusing on major commodities central to food security: rice, corn, wheat, soybeans, potato, biofuel crops (mainly sugarcane and corn) and livestock. Five interrelated objectives guide the work proposed: Objective 1. Compile and collect socioeconomic and environmental data at local, regional, national, and international scales to quantify feedbacks between food security and land use. Objective 2. Analyze and synthesize multi-scale data to understand relationships and facilitate modeling of feedbacks between food security and land use (Objective 3). Objective 3. Develop and validate an integrated model linking innovative generalized agent-based representations of coupled humans and natural system components across scales. Objective 4. Create a web-based decision-support system (Web-DSS) to enable visualization of the telecouplings and the outcomes under different scenarios. Objective 5. Engage stakeholders across local to international scales throughout the project to co-design, co-produce, and co-implement the jointly defined priorities. To achieve these objectives, we have developed five corresponding tasks. We will collect new complementary data and collate existing data from multiple sources into a common database to facilitate data analysis, integration and modeling. We will leverage existing research that our team and collaborators have already collected and from the substantial portfolio of programs on food security at CIAT, CCAFS, IFPRI, Oxford&apos;s Food Climate Research Network and Future of Food Program, Embrapa, and MSU&apos;s Global Center for Food Systems Innovation (GCFSI) -- many of these in Africa-- which will provide important data across many of the countries with greatest food security challenges. We will assess the dynamics of decision-making in land use in focal countries and with CIAT, IFPRI and other partners, tap into their research in food insecure countries. This will include examining how crop prices and food demands influence land use decisions, how regional and local environmental conditions constrain production, and how policy incentives influence choices. We propose the use of an innovative form of agent-based model (ABM) enabling a representation of the telecoupled agents, flows, causes, effects and systems. Our agent-based modeling approach represents decision-making about land use and food security without the need for detailed and expensive data on individual smallholders or households. Each agent in our model will represent a collection of key agent types, such as policy makers, crop producers, food consumers, and commodity traders. The model will reflect such variations based on empirical data and analysis. This approach facilitates model scaling and providing generality of model outcomes. We will develop and implement a web-based telecoupling decision support system (Web-DSS) with stakeholder participation to enable visualization of the dynamic feedbacks between food security and land use across time and space that will allow for co-production and co-implementation of the results and develop decisions to be used in changing policies.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Telecoupling Consortium, consists of four focal countries (Brazil, China, U.K. and U.S.), vulnerable spillover countries in Africa, two major CGIAR centers (CIAT and IFPRI) , FAO and extensive stakeholder involvement. We apply an innovative integrative framework, Telecoupling - socioeconomic and environmental interactions among coupled human and natural systems at different scales over great distances - that can transform how we think about collateral effects from international trade on food security and land use dynamics. We address Theme 3 (Feedback Loops), focusing on major commodities central to food security: rice, corn, wheat, soybeans, potato, biofuel crops (mainly sugarcane and corn) and livestock. We will examine processes at different scales, from the international trade in major food commodities, to in-depth studies at regional/local scales. The Consortium partners bring to this project a very large portfolio of food security and land use projects, representing four continents, while providing a much needed framework to address how food systems change across large distances, and to account for socioeconomic and environmental consequences of shifting forms of food production, trade and distribution. The team includes leading scholars in social and natural sciences as well as influential stakeholders in relevant sectors. The end result of this project will be enhanced capacity to predict effects from shifts in food flows and land use; tools to facilitate policy changes to improve food security, while ensuring a more sustainable environment; increased cooperation among major research and stakeholder groups in major food production and consuming countries; and training a new generation alert to minimizing negative consequences from changes in land use worldwide. The project will provide a comprehensive framework, a complex systems modeling approach and a Web-based Decision Support System to finding solutions that enhance food security for all, while ensuring a sustainable earth.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-02-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-01-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="IN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">India</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="689" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-29">4262.5</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-29">17084.51</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-29">26255.49</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-29">53566.09</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-29">26608.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-29">8804.58</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-29"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-29">140984.41</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">NERC Newton Directed (RP) - NR1 Award to King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-NE/M021335/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000297">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">King&apos;s College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=NE%2FM021335%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-02-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
