<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T02030X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Affordable Perovskite Solar Irrigation Systems for Small-holder Farmers in Ethiopia (APSISSFE)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Elucidate the surface chemical, structural and electronic changes induced by chemically altering the surfaces with 2D perovskite structures and other additives such as potassium halides 2. Understand how the interfaces perform under operation by depositing ultra-thin interlayers, enabling in-situ surface measurements, allowing dynamic feedback to the specific treatment 3. Investigate the CCS topology of DC-DC converter for the modular Micro DC-DC used in a common DC Bus systems. Design the hardware and software of the common DC Bus systems and its building blocks for irrigation and power supply for Ethiopian farmers.  4. Optimise the system (particularly pump) such that it uses solar-generated electricity efficiently, is affordable for Ethiopian farmers and can be manufactured, operated and maintained locally. 5. Ensure that all aspects of the solar irrigation system withstand Ethiopian environmental and climatic conditions, and are co-designed and iteratively tested with small-holder farmers to ensure they are inclusive, particularly with regard to gender, and are socially, culturally and economically context-appropriate. 6. Ensure that the system can be manufactured locally, and that potential end-of-life concerns about new products and processes are addressed responsibly.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over 85 million Ethiopians depend on rain-fed agriculture. Climate change is increasing vulnerability and poverty amongst small-holder farmers, 21% of whom are female headed. However, women are responsible for about 40% of agricultural activities in Ethiopia. Research by Ethiopian partners in this project shows that the provision of small, solar-powered water pumps to irrigate vegetables and cash crops is a highly effective means of increasing resilience to climate-induced stresses and shocks, enhancing household food security, producing of cash crops, reducing women&apos;s labour, and  ultimately enabling escape from the poverty cycle. Unfortunately, such irrigation systems are presently beyond the means of most farmers.  We propose to drop the cost of solar irrigation systems to a level affordable for Ethiopian small-holder farmers by: (i) advancing the science required to increase the performance and stability potential of halide perovskite photovoltaics (PV) cells; (ii) customizing the engineering required by significantly enhancing the efficiency of power electronic motor drive for pumps to the precise requirements of Ethiopian smallholders; and (iii) taking an Inclusive Innovation approach to co-designing the whole system with end-users to ensure that it is locally-appropriate and effectively reduces women&apos;s work.  We propose that the lead halide perovskites constitute an ideal emerging solar power technology to enable inclusive manufacture in Ethiopia of community-level solar powered irrigation systems because these materials can be printed at relatively low-cost on lightweight, flexible substrates. Here, we focus on solving critical interface loss and stability issues in perovskite solar cells that currently inhibit their commercial deployment. Concomitant with this, we will enhance the engineering of the irrigation system by developing modular and scalable solar inverters using advanced power electronic technologies and precisely designing the pump for small farms with shallow water tables. The solar powered irrigation system will be deployed in Ethiopia to ensure socio-economic and environmental appropriateness and provide a platform for scaled local engineering of the systems.  This proposal represents an innovative and unique programme of leading-edge experimental science and systems engineering studies, which are of direct relevance to enhancing economic development and welfare in Ethiopia. The interdisciplinary project will explore some of the central structure-composition-property issues of halide perovskite interfaces and their integration into systems, which brings together the complementary expertise of the applicants and will exploit techniques in which the UK is internationally competitive and in many aspects internationally leading. The PI, Co-Is and project partners have strong national and international reputations in their fields and an impressive track record in delivering research of the highest quality.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ET" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Ethiopia</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-02-26"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-02-26">809540.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">EPSRC GCRF GCRF (EPSRC) Award to University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP/T02030X/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">100784.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T02030X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">100784.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T02030X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">100784.42</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-EP_T02030X_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cambridge</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=EP%2FT02030X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
