<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003886_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Indicators for informal learning: a mobile heritage network for conflict-affected communities in Uganda</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The overarching aim of this network is to develop understandings about how heritage can be used to inform sustainable peace initiatives and practices, through a critical engagement with networks of innovative heritage work in Uganda. We are interested in the informal learning that occurs at these sites, and how a diversity of actors are enrolled in their construction and use. We will develop research capacity within a range of cultural organisations in Uganda, and bring together interdisciplinary researchers, practitioners and participant groups through participatory, ethical methodologies, to consolidate and build awareness of the work being done in the heritage projects. This will develop academic and policy understanding of how conflict-affected communities negotiate, deliberate and organise narratives of the past in the present to contribute to more sustainable peace in their communities, in Uganda and across East Africa.   This overarching aim will be achieved through the following key objectives: 1. Develop new co-constructed interdisciplinary knowledge about informal heritage learning in conflict-affected communities  a. Design and employ inclusive, participatory and co-constructed methodologies that open up spaces for researchers, practitioners and participant groups (including ex-combatants, refugees, community leaders, women peace club members, abductees and survivors) to co-construct this knowledge. b. Develop ways of understanding, accessing and assessing learning at the informal heritage sites and construct associated indicators for informal heritage learning about peace and reconciliation in Uganda. c. Document this new knowledge and disseminate it among different communities (academic, heritage, policy and local), working to achieve impactful change as a result.  2. Enhance research capacity among heritage organisations working with conflict-affected communities in Uganda a. Work in collaboration with heritage organisations to develop assessments of informal learning at sites of heritage. b. Through the collaborative academic networks and shared collaborative learning, enable the Ugandan Co-I, and members of heritage organisations working in conflict-affected communities, to be well placed to apply for future research projects.  c. Develop the academic dissemination skills of the Ugandan Co-I through leading conference presentations and engaging in academic writing for various audiences.  3. Cultivate an interdisciplinary network which will lead to the development of a large GCRF research project  a. Strengthen international collaboration between Ugandan and UK researchers and practitioners across the humanities and social sciences, which will underpin future grant development. b. Implement a research design which opens up spaces of inclusion and participation; across disciplines, between participants and researchers, and internationally. c. Co-design a GCRF research project which will develop our conceptual framework around informal heritage learning and the ways in which that can be mobilised to bring about positives outcomes for those affected by conflict, violence and displacement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">This network brings together UK and Ugandan researchers and practitioners with expertise in heritage, memory studies and education to critically explore appropriate methods of assessing informal learning in relation to peace and reconciliation in mobile heritage settings. Sites of heritage enrol people into particular practices, engagements with and negotiations of the past, and they are important spaces of informal learning about peace and reconciliation as a result. There is growing expectation that international, national and local heritage agencies and actors have a positive role to play in the prevention of conflict and post-conflict development yet these spaces are often neglected in considerations of education, as they are informal sites where memory work is undertaken but neglected in formal curriculum. This means that there is currently little understanding of the impact of informal heritage learning for sustained peace.  The network will produce interdisciplinary knowledge, build local research capacity within heritage organisations and strengthen an international collaboration for developing future research projects. Through this, it will directly contribute to the Ugandan Peace, Recovery and Development Plan and Refugee and the Host Population Empowerment Strategy. It will also address the global challenges and sustainable development goals of (1) enabling inclusive and equitable quality education and (2) reducing conflict and promoting peace, justice and humanitarian action.  The network focuses on recent and ongoing innovative heritage work by Nelson Abiti (the Ugandan Co-investigator of Uganda Museum) and associated cultural organisations. These mobile exhibitions seek to bring about informal learning about peace and reconciliation and achieve community cohesion amongst a variety of participant groups but tthe impact of which have not been tested. The network activities provide space for academics from the humanities and social sciences, heritage practitioners, government officials and participant groups to (1) reflect on the types of learning that are happening in these informal heritage sites and (2) co-construct meaningful and contextually-appropriate ways to assess this learning. The participant groups will include ex-combatants, refugees, community leaders, women peace club members, abductees and survivors.  Research capacity will be developed among Ugandan cultural organisations to understand and assess learning. We will co-develop informal learning indicators based on participants&apos; reflections on their engagement with informal heritage learning. These will be of significant interest to a range of stakeholders concerned with the role of heritage sites in contributing to peaceful sustainable development in Uganda and across East Africa. The network will develop sustained international relationships that have the potential for longer-term research collaboration leading to significant impact. It is anticipated that this will include the co-design of collaborative academic articles and a large research project about informal heritage learning and the ways in which it can be mobilised to bring about positives outcomes for those affected by conflict, violence and displacement.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-11-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-07-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="UG" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Uganda</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1027" percentage="100" vocabulary="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">35563.19</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-11-09">15358.27</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q4">35563.19</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003886_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">15358.27</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003886_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020/21 FY Q1">-930.55</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-AH_S003886_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Bath</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
