<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ES_R010749_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Territorial planning for peace and statebuilding in the Alto Cauca region of Colombia</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Following the signing of the 2016 peace agreement and the demobilization of the FARC-EP, the Colombian state is trying to re-establish its authority in conflict-affected areas through developing new instruments for territorial planning and decentralization. This process of entails a reconfiguration of the governance structures built during the conflict - which involved a mix of local actors including the FARC-EP, pro-government paramilitaries and local communities - and the construction of a new &apos;social pact&apos; between citizens and the state. In order to facilitate this process, the national government is formulating a series of planning tools to be implemented at the local level, the most important ones being Development Programmes with a Regional Focus (PDET) and the National Programme for the Substitution of Illicit Cultivations (PNIS).   This project will explore the formulation and implementation of territorial planning via the PDET and PNIS, which are both crucial to the success of the Colombian peace process. The location selected for the project is the Alto Cauca region, one of the areas identified by the Colombian government as particularly affected by the armed conflict. Research will be conducted in three rural municipalities in the region, all of which have been targeted as priority areas for the government-led process of territorial planning: Buenos Aires, Miranda, and Corinto. The state has long had only a weak presence in these areas resulting in the ethnically diverse local communities reacting to this absence by developing their own planning instruments and, in some cases, their own governance institutions. The process of territorial planning has thus become a process of negotiation between the state and local communities, and between the local communities, which sometimes have diverging interests. Through engaging the active participation of long marginalized actors, including landless peasants, Afro-descendants and indigenous peoples, this project will bring the voices of these communities into the territorial peacebuilding process in an attempt to ensure that it is truly participatory and long lasting.   The project will primarily use ethnographic and participatory approaches to map the socio-economic actors, production systems, rural transformations and territorial power relations in the three areas under study, and explore the instruments, institutions, and government strategies being used to build peace. An important element of the project is to strengthen the communities&apos; capacities for negotiating with the state and contribute to the [re]construction of the bonds of trust between communities and local government institutions. This will be achieved through an innovative participatory strategy including a series of community exchange workshops and a capacity building training programme. In addition, producing participatory videos with community members will allow for the articulation of alternative, non-academic and non-written narratives on experiences of territorial planning in relation to the peace process. These videos will widen the potential impact of the project, in particular in other communities and municipalities with a similar history and facing similar challenges related to implementing the Peace Agreements.  All partners will participate in all aspects of the research from design, to execution and dissemination.  Through multidisciplinary collaboration between human geographers, political scientists, education and design specialists based both in Colombia and the UK, this project will facilitate the generation of innovative understandings of the process of territorial peacebuilding in Colombia and lead to important new knowledge on how territorial rights and access, social relationships, and state power interact in the transition from war to peace.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-05-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-08-14" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="CO" type="COLOMBIA"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH AMERICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">489</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">150148.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">184103.76</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-06-18">35976.52</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall aim of this project is to understand how the state&apos;s presence is being constructed through territorial planning in three post-conflict zones in the Alto Cauca region, and thereby strengthen the capacities of the local communities to successfully plan and develop their territories in accordance with the Peace Agreement.   The project is built around three key objectives:   1. Map the socio-economic actors, production systems, rural transformations and territorial power relations in the three study areas.   2. Explore the instruments, institutions, and government strategies being used to build peace through territorial planning.   3. Strengthen the communities&apos; capacities for negotiating with the state and contribute to the [re]construction of the bonds of trust between communities and the government."></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
