<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008520_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Mycotoxin exposure, intestinal inflammation and childhood stunting in India</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Childhood stunting is recognised as &apos;one of the most significant impediments to human development&apos; by the World Health Assembly and its aim to reduce global stunting rates by 40% by 2025 is now deemed unachievable. When growth is impaired in children at an early age, later development of cognitive capacity is also impacted and children are thought not to be able to reach their full potential. The first 1000 days of a child&apos;s life are crucial to determining the development in later life. Hence it is imperative that the multiple factors contributing to childhood stunting are identified, their interrelation understood and their route cause treated. Undernutrition is an obvious risk factor for childhood stunting, but simple nutritional interventions have failed to solve the problem. Multiple dietary and environmental risk factors are likely to contribute, and in this study we aim to unpick these complex links. The environment a child grows up in regarding access to clean water and basic sanitation as well as access to nutritious and safe food are likely to contribute to the healthy functioning of the child&apos;s digestive tract which will facilitate the utilisation of foods for the growth and development of the child. Hence the proposed project aims to follow children from birth up to two years of age and from two to five years of age and link multiple measures of child growth, health status and intestinal function with dietary intakes and exposure food contaminants. The study will be conducted in rural areas of southern India where stunting is prevalent. This study will identify the main contributors to stunting in children and will provide the necessary information to guide future intervention programmes aimed at improving the lives of children in affected areas and hence addressing the WHO childhood development targets.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2019-07-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-09-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-02-28" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="IN" type="INDIA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTH &amp; CENTRAL ASIA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">689</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019-07-04">38237.68</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="We hypothesise that exposure to dietary mycotoxins increases the risk of childhood stunting, involving a mechanism whereby mycotoxins act on the gut by decreasing intestinal barrier function, and inducing low-grade intestinal inflammation. This will impair nutrient utilisation and increase the risk of intestinal infections, thereby exacerbating the risk of malnutrition and stunting in a vulnerable group of children.  Aims and objectives of the research To explore this mechanistic link between mycotoxin exposure, intestinal function and childhood stunting in rural and urban regions of South India with high risk of mycotoxin exposure, we propose the following objectives:  Development award 1. Establish mycotoxin contamination of foods frequently consumed by mothers and children; Main study 2. Assess the dietary exposure to mycotoxins in children up to 5 years of age through chemical analysis of food and mycotoxin biomarkers in biological samples (urine, blood); 3. Assess the prevalence of stunting in children up to 5 years of age, and establish its association with mycotoxin exposure and intestinal inflammation as well as assessing nutritional status and microbiome composition in a longitudinal study."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q4">38237.68</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T008520_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Aberdeen</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
