<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002746_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">SA-DISCNet: A collaborative data science training network across southern Africa and southern UK</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">4</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Data intensive science is a major global growth area, as the volume, complexity and rate of digital data within governments and companies continues to rapidly increase. At the same time, powerful analysis techniques continue to evolve for obtaining radical insights into large datasets, including finding clusters and anomalies, as well as detecting and predicting dominant trends and correlations in such data. This data intensive science comes at a crucial time for global development. Major worldwide challenges, as encapsulated in the United Nations&apos; Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), require multidisciplinary solutions, many of which include data science. Moreover, the South African National Development Plan (NDP) for 2030 recognises the need to &quot;sharpen its innovative edge and continue contributing to global scientific and technological advancement&quot; and &quot;shift to a more knowledge-intensive economy&quot;.    We therefore propose to build a training network in data intensive science between universities in southern UK and partners in southern Africa to help address these SDGs and NDP priorities. The cornerstones of this network will be the `Data Intensive Science Centre in SEPnet&apos; (DISCnet) and the African Institute of Mathematical Science (AIMS) South Africa. Together, we will pilot an innovative course of training and internships for the next generation of data analysts, focusing on solving SDG-related questions in South Africa and acting as a driver of the country&apos;s economy in the 21st century.   Our aim with this pilot training programme is to equip and send students to solve data science problems associated with sustainable development goals (SDGs) in SA and beyond. The specific goals of the pilot programme are to: (i) Deliver an initial cohort of at least 10 highly trained African data scientists; (ii) Provide a world-class data science school to African students, leveraging existing DISCnet training material; (iii) Prime-pump a new 8-week hand-on data science training course at AIMS with contributions from DISCnet; (iv) Contribute to the sustainable development goals via 3 month strategic student internships with South African organisations and companies, focusing on economic development and welfare; (v) Understand the details of managing an extended, sustainable training network across southern Africa.  This pilot leverages considerable investment from STFC, our university partners, and the Royal Society (RS). Our long-term ambition is to create a sustainable network of comparable scale to DISCnet, e.g. approximately 25 African STEM students per year receiving our specialist training. These students will become the future data science leaders in Africa.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2018-01-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-03-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ZA" type="SOUTH AFRICA"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1029</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-19">23186.31</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-19">69558.93</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall goals of this proposal are:  a) To found a sustainable data intensive science training network for students in Southern Africa based our DISCnet experience and the successful JEDI workshops at AIMS.   b) Through this programme, to prepare students to solve data science problems associated with economic development and the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in South Africa and beyond.  c) To contribute to SDGs 4, 5, 8, 9, 11 and 17 through student internships at Transport for Cape Town, and other SA companies including Siyavula, Zoona and Ekaya.  These overall goals are achieved through subsidiary goals:  a) To run a one week pilot data intensive science school for a first cohort of graduate students from Southern Africa, with lecturers drawn from the STFC-funded DISCnet data science doctoral training centre and South African academic institutions.   b) To subsequently run a pilot eight week data science workshop for graduate students, with training provided from DISCnet and South African academics. This will provide hands-on training for the students with real-life data science problems, e.g. medical imaging, loan risk assessment, and traffic optimisation. The workshop will be based on the successful hands-on JEDI format.   c) To place our trained students in internships with organisations in South Africa, in each case working on an issue linked to one of the SDGs. The internships will last three months, and will seek to answer a set of specific problems from the partner organisations for new insights into their datasets, with the aim of improving infrastructure, equal opportunities and innovation in South Africa.  d) To foster careers in data science for our student cohort. As the relationship between the student and the internship organisation develops, we have the ambition that some of our students will be able to continue into a career in these organisations. In addition, we will provide advice and help during the workshop and afterwards to our students, through our institutions&apos; career services together with innovation fellows associated with DISCnet institutions, in order to match students with data science jobs particularly answering SDG challenges.  Finally, we have the ambition to extend our programme to include a larger student cohort, more internships, and other nodes across Africa in future years. By demonstrating the value and excitement of our programme through this pilot, we will seek funding from GCRF and other UK and SA opportunities to expand the school and workshop to two cohorts of students in 2019; one delivered in South Africa and one in an AIMS node in another African country (Cameroon, Ghana, Rwanda, Senegal and Tanzania). Further expansion will be possible to give similar courses and internships throughout the whole AIMS network."></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">23186.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002746_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Portsmouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q1">23186.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002746_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Portsmouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q2">23186.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002746_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Portsmouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018/19 FY Q3">23186.31</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-ST_R002746_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Portsmouth</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
