<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="EN" hierarchy="1" humanitarian="4" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_T038594_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="10" type="DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS, ENERGY AND INDUSTRIAL STRATEGY">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Assessment of Point of CaRe creatinine testing In pregnancy: a feasibilty Cohort sTudy in Sierra Leone (APRICOT-SL)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">2</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Background: Every day, approximately 800 women die in pregnancy or childbirth. 99% of all of these deaths occur in the developing world.  Women with limited access to healthcare are at the greatest risk. Many women die in pregnancy because problems are recognised too late. We have experience using a simple, accurate, handheld device (CRADLE VSA) to measure blood pressure and pulse with minimal skill. It uses a &apos;traffic light&apos; system; the device tells the user if the blood pressure and pulse measurements are normal (green), worrying (amber) or severely abnormal (red) thus highlighting those who are unwell;  however, further work is needed to identify women at greatest risk of death.    Our previous work in Africa showed that women with raised creatinine (a marker of kidney function) indicating acute kidney injury (AKI) were more likely to die.  AKI is the sudden loss of kidney function and many cases are preventable. AKI leads to an increase in number of all pregnancy complications. Costs of AKI are high due to longer length of stay and extra treatment costs, especially if life-saving dialysis is needed. Longer term problems for the mother after AKI including chronic kidney disease, heart disease and pre-eclampsia (high blood pressure and urine protein) in future pregnancies.   Early delivery of the baby, if the mother has AKI, also may lead to infant death and short and long term health problems including future chronic kidney disease.  Point of care testing of creatinine (POC-Cr) on finger prick blood is ideal for low income settings as blood taking and laboratory processing are not required.  But POC-Cr testing in pregnancy to identify AKI at early stages, when treatments are likely to be successful, has not been performed. In the future we think that preventing AKI in pregnancy using POC-Cr in low income settings could lead to a reduction in death of mother and baby.  The aim of this study is to work out:  -How easy it is to do POC-Cr testing in pregnant or postpartum women: we will measure number of test failures, time taken for training and time taken for testing -How accurate POC-Cr testing is compared to routine blood creatinine concentration testing  -Whether POC-Cr testing is acceptable to health care providers and women -How many women are at risk of AKI and how many develop AKI -How long it takes to complete a POC-Cr study in pregnancy and analyse the findings  -What increase in POC-Cr testing value from study entry and at 6-8 hours indicates the likely development of AKI at 24 hours?  -An estimate of the reduction in AKI rate if repeat POC-Cr testing and training to treat AKI is used  Method: We will recruit 2000 pregnant women with abnormal CRADLE VSA readings.  All women will have:  i) POC-Cr at admission/at time of AKI event and again after 6-8 hours ii) Blood creatinine test at admission/ at time of AKI event again at 24 hours   Run-in period (6 months): 1000 women - POC-Cr results will not be seen by the clinical team.  We will compare POC-Cr results with blood laboratory tests.  We will calculate the number of women who develop AKI from blood creatinine changes at 24 hours and work out what increase in POC-Cr measured at 6-8 hours is best at predicting which women get AKI at 24 hours.  Intervention period (6 months): 1000 pregnant women - POC-Cr results will be seen by the clinical team.  The clinical team will also have training in AKI care and it will be recommended that this is given to women who have a rise POC-Cr measured at 6-8 hours which predicts that they might develop AKI at 24 hours.  We will compare how many women get AKI in the run-in period and in the intervention period.    Next steps: The results of this study will be used to design a large international study which will work out if POC-Cr testing can reduce the number of cases of AKI, maternal and neonatal death in low income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <other-identifier type="GB-GOV-13"></other-identifier>
  <activity-status code="2020-07-01"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-06-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="ZW" type="ZIMBABWE"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="UK RESEARCH &amp; INNOVATION">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">gcrf@ukri.org</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>https://www.ukri.org/</email>
   <website>Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GBP</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="EASTERN AFRICA, REGIONAL" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1027</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1" percentage="100" vocabulary="RESEARCH/SCIENTIFIC INSTITUTIONS"></recipient-region>
  <sector percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">43082</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="10"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="110"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="D02"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="5" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-30">24879.26</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-06-30">74637.78</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="The overall aim of this proposal is to develop pilot data to inform the design of a future stepped-wedge cluster-randomised controlled trial to assess the role of serial point of care creatinine (POC-Cr) testing in pregnancy to reduce acute kidney injury (AKI) and maternal mortality.  Objectives in order of priority are listed below:  1. To recruit pregnant or postpartum women with abnormal CRADLE VSA readings to a prospective cohort study 2. To assess feasibility (number of strips used, test failure rate, time for training, time for testing) and acceptability of POC-Cr testing for AKI in pregnancy and postpartum 3. To compare accuracy and precision of POC-Cr and venous creatinine concentrations and establish if an adjustment factor is required. 4. To estimate the incidence of AKI at 24 hours after admission/ AKI associated event assessed by serum creatinine (KDIGO criteria) in pregnant and postpartum women 5. To determine threshold changes in POC-Cr (between abnormal CRADLE VSA reading and 6-8 hours later) which are predictive of AKI confirmed by serum creatinine concentration at 24 hours 6. To compare rates of AKI in women with and without  revealed serial POC-Cr testing"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="HTTPS://WWW.UKRI.ORG/FUNDING/INFORMATION-FOR-AWARD-HOLDERS/GRANT-TERMS-AND-CONDITIONS/" url="A04">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">application/pdf</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="0"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="2021-09-24"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
