<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR_M02640X_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton001 Biochemical Investigation of the Enzyme PRMT7 Function in Leishmania spp Parasite Infectivity; Screening Targets for Leishmaniasis Relevance</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">- To biochemically analyse PRMT7 enzymatic function in Leishmania spp. parasites to generate sufficient preliminary data for planned grant applications (BBSRC/FAPESP). - To build upon our successful joint FAPESP student fellowship this year which published in vivo characterisation of PRMT7 (Ferreira et al., Mol Micro, 2014) o created genetic and biochemical tools to pursue biochemical analyses. - To further isolate and validate protein targets of PRMT7 methylation, including RNA binding protein targets. - To determine whether and how target protein function is altered by PRMT7- dependent methylation. - To cross train our laboratories in key specialist techniques including optimised parasite transfection, in vivo imaging, RNA-Seq, iTRAQ LC-MS, and bioinformatic analyses relevant to the molecular cell biology of Leishmania spp. parasites, which cause the Neglected Tropical Disease leishmaniasis in Brazil.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Leishmaniases are the ninth largest disease burden amongst infectious diseases and the second biggest killer of parasitic diseases next to malaria, threatening one tenth of the world&apos;s population. WHO estimates 0.7-1.2 million new cases of cutaneous Leishmaniasis annually while visceral Leishmaniasis infects 200-400,000, killing 10-20% of them. Brazil is stricken by all pathologies of this disease with 30,000 new infections every year. Over 70% of leishmaniasis patients are under 15 years of age. No vaccine exists and there is a growing resistance to available treatments; which are expensive, highly toxic and unsuitable for children. The past decade has seen an increase of epidemics coincident with heightened severity of the disease and an expansion of territory. Despite the urgent need for intervention, leishmaniasis remains a neglected tropical disease. This is largely attributable to its afflicting the poorest of society. Understanding the function and activity of proteins implicated in Leishmania spp. parasite virulence will provide useful insight into new potential ways to combat Leishmaniasis.  Leishmania spp. parasites adapt to drastic changes in environments during transmission between insect vectors and human hosts. Developmental changes require the Leishmania parasite cell to interpret changing environmental cues, and to coordinate a swift response for survival. Lifecycle-specific adaptions enable parasite transmission between hosts and perpetuate parasitic infections and diseases.   Environmental cues trigger signalling cascades to initiate developmental events. Expressed &apos;response&apos; proteins enable cellular adaptation to the given environment. Downstream of these signals, specific RNA binding proteins (RBPs) bind mRNAs essential for the cellular response and target them for protein production, storage or degradation. Precise gene regulation coordinates the expression of stage- specific proteins essential for cell adaptation. In this way gene regulation promotes parasite survival and infectivity.  Molecular regulators that coordinate the adaptation of these parasites to different host cells and promote parasite infection are critically important to our broader understanding of this disease. The enzyme PRMT7 is a novel regulator of Leishmania virulence. We seek to combine our expertise and facilities to biochemically characterise PRMT7 function and explore how it and its target proteins enable parasite infectivity.  The Cruz and Walrad laboratories have complementary expertise and objectives in Leishmania molecular cell biology and transcriptomics. The Cruz lab has an extensive history of molecular characterisation in Leishmania spp. parasites. The Walrad lab has expertise in characterising RNA binding regulatory proteins which enable parasite transmission between hosts.  Our collaboration will biochemically characterise the function of the Protein aRginine Methyl Transferase enzyme, PRMT7, its protein targets and how this pathway participates in Leishmania spp. infectivity. PRMT7 is the first Leishmania methylating enzyme to be implicated in host-parasite interactions. Preliminary evidence suggests it may act via modification of regulatory RNA binding proteins, RBPs. The recent MRC NIRG award to the Walrad lab centres on regulatory RBPs involved in Leishmania spp. parasite differentiation to human infectious forms.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-30" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="BR" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Brazil</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="489" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">8921.69</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">17843.38</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2015-01-05"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-01-05">35686.76</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC Newton Strategic Awards Award to University of York</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-MR/M02640X/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000679">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of York</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FM02640X%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
