<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-BB_N013808_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Enhanced Rice quality for Health (EnRicH)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rice is a staple food for more than half of the world&apos;s population. However, rice is largely consumed as polished grain (white rice) and its consumption, as part of the adoption of a Western diet and increasingly sedentary life style, is associated with increased risk of a range of chronic diseases including type 2 diabetes, obesity, cardio-vascular disease and forms of cancer. Hence it is important to consider the impact of rice on nutrition and health as well as traditional quality attributes. Consequently, the two most important targets for quality improvement of polished white rice are to reduce the rate of digestion in the human gastrointestinal tract (through starch structure manipulation and increasing the percentage of resistant starch) and increase the content of dietary fibre while retaining high yield and good cooking and sensory properties. The research project will carry out detailed analyses of grain composition of a wide range of rice lines to identify lines with increased health benefits combined with good consumer acceptability. Cutting-edge genetics and bioinformatics will then be used to identify molecular markers that can be used to select for quality traits by breeders.  The improved lines and markers will then be delivered to national and international rice breeding programmes to allow them to develop new commercial varieties.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Rice provides the staple food for more than half the world&apos;s population. However, it is mainly consumed after polishing to remove the outer nutritious layer (bran) and germ. Consequently, white rice comprises over 90% starch with only low contents of protein, dietary fibre and micronutrients. It is therefore provides mainly a source of energy in the diet and, because it is rapidly digested in the human GI tract, has a high glycaemic index (GI). The consumption of foods with a high content of rapidly digested carbohydrates and low content of dietary fibre (DF) is associated with increased risks of a range of chronic diseases including type 2 diabetes, CVD and some types of cancer. Furthermore, the incidence of these conditions is increasing dramatically in areas where rice is the staple food, notably SE Asia, India and China. Hence it is necessary to develop new types of rice in which high energy content is combined with low GI and high contents of DF and micronutrients. We aim to address the &apos;improved quality of rice&apos; challenge posed by the Call, through enhancement of rice germplasm with healthier traits. This project aims to identify rice lines with high resistant starch (RS) and DF content combined with good cooking and organoleptic properties and include them in national rice breeding programmes in the Philippines.  The project will therefore: 1. Identify variation in the content and composition of starch and DF in diverse rice genotypes. 2. Identify lines with increased properties of both components. 3. Determine the processing and organoleptic properties of these lines and relate these properties to the amounts, compositions, structures and properties of starch and DF. 4. Determine QTLs and identify molecular markers for improved starch and DF in breeding 5. Disseminate genotypes and markers to national and international breeding programmes.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">40795.73</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">163513.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">164837.84</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-16">82918.6</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
