<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V001388_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">AMAZING- Advancing MAiZe INformation for Ghana</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Reducing rural poverty through the increased productivity of smallholder agriculture has always been a critical national development objective of the governments of both China and Ghana.  To support Chinese and Ghanaian policy makers, extension workers and other stakeholders, this project aims to demonstrate the practical benefits of EO-enabled crop monitoring and yield prediction for sustainable agriculture, to continue, and deepen, our collaborative partnerships between the UK and China and extend its impact, as well as to develop a partnership with Ghana to adapt the approach to meet local needs and conditions. The main objectives (with priority) of the project are:  1. Apply methods developed for EO-enabled crop monitoring and yield prediction for wheat in North China Plain to maize in China; 2. Enhance the system by using other agrometeorological models and investigate multi-model ensembles; 3. Develop an in-season forecasting system for yield for at least North China Plain; 4. Engagement and capacity building in Ghana; 5. Demonstrate application of crop monitoring and yield prediction to maize in Ghana.  Frequent EO observations of the land surface allow us to infer parameters describing crop development at the field scale. The system will use EO-derived biophysical parameters in conjunction with mechanistic crop growth models (CGMs) to monitor yield from grain food crops such as maize. CGMs encode our understanding of the mechanisms affecting crop development, such as photosynthesis, water use, carbon allocation, etc. These models are usually driven by meteorological, as well as soil and crop management inputs, and predict crop development over time. However, due to the inherent variability in agricultural systems, predictions from CGMs are often inaccurate at the plot level. If evidence of crop development in the form of EO-derived parameters becomes available, then data assimilation (DA) techniques can be used to &quot;correct&quot; model predictions so as to be consistent with the observed evidence (including uncertainties), and thus provide a more accurate depiction of crop development and thus grain yield. Such a system would enable stakeholders (e.g. the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs in CHina (MARA), the Ministry of Food and Agriculture in Ghana (MoFA), The United Nations Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO) to obtain timely estimates of crop condition over the whole country and to plan and react to emergency situations like drought or pest outbreaks.   The UCL team has considerable experience both on the interpretation of EO data using physical models, and in developing DA systems for vegetation monitoring, including specific software tools. Pioneering works have gained the UCL team extensive experience in EO data interpretation in the optical domain and enabled the development of a similar wheat monitoring system in China. This proposed project will extend such a system to monitor maize, and translate such capacity to Ghana. Additionally, the system and data will be open to all interested stakeholders, allowing other interested parties to use the EO and meteorological data for additional tasks, and with a view to encouraging in-country use of these resources and ensuring the sustainability of the service.   Our overseas users, CAU and CAAS are closely connected to China&apos;s MARA and GSSTI is to Ghana&apos;s MoFA. The outputs of the proposed work will feed directly to MARA and MoFA for critical decision-making and can be used to assess the current crop situation or the success of government policies such as the Planting For Jobs programme. This project also benefits from having the FAO as a partner, who will help to promote the project outputs to a wider range of stakeholders and to accelerate the migration of such capacity to other countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The agricultural sector is under increasing pressure from population growth, climate change and environmental issues such as soil erosion, drought, flooding and pesticide overuse. In China, which has 20% of the world&apos;s population and only 10% of the arable land and water resources, huge changes have been made in agricultural practice in recent years to maintain food security. In the North China Plain (NCP), 61% of China&apos;s winter wheat and 45% of its maize are grown, but this is dependent on irrigation, causing a 1 m annual drop in the water table. Since 1985, double cropping of winter wheat and maize has been used to increase supply but this exacerbates water issues even further. China is investing heavily in technology at farm, regional and global scales and remote sensing forms a vital part of that strategy, for monitoring crop health and production.  In Ghana, more than half of its labour force is engaged in agriculture, which contributes to 54% of its GDP and provides over 90% of the country&apos;s food needs. At the same time, Ghana&apos;s agriculture predominantly involves smallholders and relies heavily on rain-fed subsistence farming practices, resulting in food production being below its potential. Similar to many other countries in the region, smallholders are widely considered to be the most vulnerable component of Ghana&apos;s rural sector. The project will use earth observation (EO) data and crop modelling techniques to help Ghana to build a national crop monitoring capability, informed by state-of-the-art developments in EO and crop modelling. Among various types of crops, food-crop farming is vital to low-income households and particularly women and children relying on subsistence agriculture. Timely monitoring information will result in better informed farmers and extension workers, as well as government, which will lead to better evidence-based decision-making, more efficient farming management, and more sustainable development in the Ghanaian agricultural industry in the long run.   Field survey and census has been traditionally used in many countries for crop yield estimation, but these have gradually been replaced or supplemented in many countries by EO-based estimates. EO data can provide a frequent measurement of a number of crop relevant biophysical parameters at a high spatial resolution (10-20 m). Using these data to monitor croplands, however, is hampered by the inherent difference between the nature of EO measurements and the agronomic parameters of interest. An alternative but equally compelling line of research is that of physical-based crop growth models (CGMs), which predict the crop development as a function of meteorological drivers, soil properties, specific cultivar parameters and management practices. The predictions from these CGMs, however, are not capable of describing a particular field with detail due to insufficient information on management practices, microclimate and soil variations, pests, etc. One way to account for this local variability is to use satellite observations to &quot;correct&quot; the model trajectory. In these &quot;data assimilation&quot; (DA) systems, the model &quot;learns&quot; about the reality of the crop from the observations.   The UCL team and its collaborators have conducted a series of DA work in China and Ghana in recent years. From these pioneering works, a number of major research challenges have been conquered for implementing a DA-based crop monitoring system. This project will demonstrate the practical benefits of EO-enabled crop monitoring and yield prediction for sustainable agriculture, to continue and deepen our collaborative partnerships between the UK and China and extend its impact, as well as to develop a partnership with Ghana to adapt the approach to meet local needs and conditions. This project will also present an opportunity to train in-country specialists both in EO, physical modelling, data assimilation, as well as in standard geoprocessing techniques.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631" role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-02-13" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-03-31" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2022-03-30" type="3"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Newton</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="CN" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">China</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="789" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="1"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">161631.01</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">189703.37</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">53039.1</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-04-01">187120.78</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V001388_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-07-01">36142.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V001388_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-10-01">36142.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V001388_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-01-01">91928.2</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V001388_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-04-01">2410.33</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V001388_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2021-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2021-07-01">611.82</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST_V001388_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2020-03-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2020-03-11">404373.48</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">STFC Newton Newton Fund Award to University College London</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--Newton-ST/V001388/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org ref="GB-COH-RC000631">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University College London</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=ST%2FV001388%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2020-02-13"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
