<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Implementing comprehensive, integrated, community-based health care for vulnerable communities in South Africa: An evidence-informed model</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">In low and middle income countries across the world many poor communities have little access to health care. Providing health care is a challenge as the available national resources for health care is limited. People in these communities suffer from infectious diseases such as TB and HIV and from long term health conditions such as diabetes and high blood pressure. In poor communities many people with these conditions do not know they have them. Even if aware of their health condition, people may be unable to access the right treatment. Community Health Workers (CHWs) are local people trained to visit households in their community to identify people who are unwell, help them gain access to health care and support them in treatment. Existing CHW programmes have been successful in tackling infectious disease, as well as improving maternal and child health, but programmes usually focus on a limited range of health problems and do not cater for people with multiple problems. This project will design and evaluate a comprehensive integrated CHW programme that aims to identify and support the treatment of all types of ill health experienced in poor communities.  Research has demonstrated that CHW programmes are successful if there is good programme design, management, integration with the health system, and a good &apos;fit&apos; with the community. However, there is insufficient evidence on how to operationalise these attributes for a successful comprehensive, integrated CHW service. Policy makers and service providers want to know how many CHWs are needed and at what cost, how are they best supervised, what is the best balance in terms of training, scope of work and household coverage, and how can they remain responsive to their community yet integrated with the health system? We aim to identify the key features of an evidence-informed CHW service model and the lessons for scale up.  South Africa is a middle income country with poor communities who have limited access to health care. The national Government is committed to strengthening primary care through the provision of community-based care by CHWs for these communities. The project will be undertaken in Sedibeng District, Gauteng Province of South Africa. Our collaborator, the District manager, is currently piloting three designs of comprehensive, integrated CHW programme, with different CHW-to-household ratios and different levels of access to supervision for the CHWs. Our objectives are to:  1) observe and interview existing CHW teams to understand how they work, and undertake a community survey to assess coverage, 2) using what we learn, in consultation with local, provincial and national stakeholders and international experts, to design an evidence informed CHW model then,  3) implement the model in two communities,  4) assess the impact by undertaking a survey of the community before and 15 months after implementation, as well as observation and interviews, and  5) to inform policy, implementation and practice.  The project results will inform the national roll out of these programmes by the South Africa Department of Health. By providing sufficient detail about the intervention, its context and evaluation, we expect governments internationally to be able to assess the applicability of the evidence-informed CHW model for their contexts and any adaptations needed. This will inform the use of resources for the provision of health care for poor communities, and the channeling of donor resources from high income country governments and other donor organisations, to maximise health benefit for poor communities.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Progression towards universal health coverage (UHC; access to quality care for all) requires an affordable service that enables under-served, vulnerable communities to access care. Given the insufficient numbers of staff in the health workforce in low and middle income countries, the provision of such a service requires properly supervised task shifting, so that more expensive, trained staff can concentrate on tasks that depend on their training while others take on the tasks requiring less specialized knowledge.   Community Health Workers (CHWs) (lay people chosen by the community and given minimal training) have been successfully deployed to provide appropriate community-based care. Success depends on the CHW programme being well managed, integrated with the health system and being a good &apos;fit&apos; with the community. However, existing CHW programmes usually focus on specific diseases (e.g. TB, HIV) or population groups (e.g. maternal and child health). Given the growing burden of both infectious and non-infectious disease, and resulting co-morbidities, South Africa is seeking to move towards CHW programmes that provide comprehensive, integrated, community based care.  Innovation within the Sedibeng District of Gauteng Province provides an opportunity to learn from recently established CHW programmes which provide comprehensive care using differing models of CHW supervision and deployment.  Our overall objective is to identify the key features of a practical, evidence-informed CHW service model that can provide effective comprehensive care to vulnerable communities, and identify the lessons for scale up.  To achieve this we will meet the following time-ordered objectives   Obj. 1: To describe, cost, and compare six existing CHW programmes that provide comprehensive care in order to identify the factors that can facilitate or impede success;  Obj. 2: To develop an evidence-informed CHW service model drawing on the lessons from Objective 1, the latest international evidence, and the new South African policy; Obj. 3: To implement the evidence-informed model in two pilot sites that do not yet have a CHW programme; Obj. 4: To evaluate the two pilots to provide evidence on design, implementation, cost, and effect, as well as acceptability to the community;  Obj. 5: To contribute practical recommendations to strengthen policy, implementation and practice in similar settings of sub-Saharan Africa and other low and middle income countries.</narrative>
  </description>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-06-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2016-07-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2019-02-28" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-12-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="SOUTHERN AFRICA, REGIONAL"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-20">182081.04</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-20">193974.47</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2015-12-20">220178.46</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q2">60693.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016/17 FY Q4">121387.4</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q1">60693.7</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q3">60235.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017/18 FY Q4">73045.65</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q1">73392.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q2">73392.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2019-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2019/20 FY Q3">73392.8</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_N015908_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of the Witwatersrand</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
  <iati-activities>
   <iati-activity>
    <title>
     <narrative xml:lang="EN"></narrative>
    </title>
   </iati-activity>
  </iati-activities>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
