<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P027954_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF: One Health Regional Network for the Horn of Africa (HORN)</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">One Health is the concept that the health and well-being of people is linked to the health of their animals and the environment.  It is nowhere more true than in the Horn of Africa (Kenya, Ethiopia, Eritrea and Somalia) where many people&apos;s livelihoods are highly, or in some cases entirely, dependent on livestock. Animals are culturally, socially and economically vital in the region. Livestock provide, for example, over 60% of agricultural GDP in the Horn. Livestock are also a source of human disease. Outbreaks of disease in animals thereby directly affect people&apos;s health but also their wealth and nutrition. Livestock production and human health and wellbeing in the Horn of Africa can be increased through research, leading to improved agricultural systems; more food and less malnutrition; more financial resilience; and better detection, diagnosis, prevention and control of disease. HORN&apos;s mission is to improve the health and wealth of the people of the Horn of Africa by increasing the local capacity to undertake high quality research in the interactions between people and animals - One Health. HORN aims to develop a One Health Regional Network - a network of individuals and organisations across the Horn of Africa that can undertake high quality research into the link between people&apos;s health and wealth and that of livestock and the environment. HORN will strengthen the ability of organisations to undertake research with a 5 step process. (i) First, the current research capacity of the organisations will be assessed, relative to their goals; a plan will then be developed to bridge the gap, implemented, and progress will be monitored. (ii) Following from #1, training will be provided to non-academics in these organisations that have roles that provide the foundations for research: these could be leadership roles, technical roles or other roles, such as in finance or contracts or IT. (iii) Training will also be provided to academic researchers from the region. Workshops and short courses (2-5 days), 4-8 week masterclasses and summer schools will educate researchers  in aspects of One Health, as well as providing the generic skills that underpin high quality research, like research methods, statistics, presentation, grantsmanship.  An e-learning platform will enable a wider body of researchers to access the course material. (iv) Researchers will &apos;learn on the job&apos; by undertaking research projects of 3-12 months duration. These projects will be co-created (by discussion and interaction with expert academics) at group events (&apos;sandpits&apos;), with successful ideas rapidly agreed and funded. Mobility of many researchers between countries is envisaged, with research focused in specific parts of Kenya and Ethiopia. UK researchers will be based in these countries too, following research programmes aligned with the development challenges, and providing supervision and mentoring to the researchers from the Horn countries. (v) By bringing people together, encouraging mobility and increasing the number of organisations who bid in for research projects, we intend to develop the One Health Regional Network for the Horn of Africa - HORN.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Title: One Health Research Network for the Horn of Africa (HORN). HORN&apos;S mission is to improve the health and wealth of the people of the Horn of Africa (Kenya, Ethiopia, Eritrea and Somalia) by increasing the local capacity to undertake high quality research in the interactions between people, animals and the environment - One Health.  HORN&apos;s aim is to build a regional network of individuals and institutions able to deliver high quality research into the linkage of the health and wealth of people to livestock and the environment, in the context of how people interact now and how they interacted in the past. It addresses three development challenges: (i). Disease and disease control: Increasing the health and productivity of livestock to provide better nutrition and reduced zoonotic disease transmission to people in the Horn of Africa (ii) Agriculture, livelihoods and economics: Improving agricultural systems in the Horn to reduce animal and human disease, improve local economies and increase financial resilience (iii) Health in changing world: Human and animal health under conditions of societal, climate and environmental change HORN has the following 5 objectives. 1. Undertaking of research capability assessments (RCAs) of partner institutions in the Horn of Africa. A UK team will assess the current and target research capabilities of partner institutions, propose plans to reach the target, implementing them and monitor progress. A reflective Learning and Evaluation Project will assess the success of the RCAs from a research perspective. 2. Provision of training to non-research staff from these institutions. Depending on the outcome of Objective 1, non-research staff in roles that underpin research will be trained. This includes leadership training, placements/shadowing in research support, and training in laboratory skills. 3. Advancing the knowledge and research skills of researchers from these institutions in generic, laboratory and subject-specific skills. Research staff from partner institutions will take part in 2-5 day workshops/short courses, 4-8 week masterclasses, and attend summer schools in aspects of One Health. An e-learning platform will be developed.  4. Undertaking of basic and applied research in the area of One Health. Researchers from partner institutions will undertake 3-12 month research projects (totalling 50 person-years) in &apos;research clusters&apos; in Kenya and Ethiopia; alongside and mentored by UK researchers and with the supervision by UK and local academic partners. The research projects will be co-created at &apos;sandpit&apos; events, themed according to the development challenges.   5. Creation of the One Health Regional Network - HORN. The proposed partnership, training of non-research and research staff, and research placements with mobility between countries will develop a regional network. This network will grow during the programme, as more institutions join, supported by project partners and NGOs.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-01" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-10-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2021-03-31" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="289" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">499694</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">1942596</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">2008864</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">2026557</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2021-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2022-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">926749.3</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-09-21"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-09-21">7898299.296</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">BBSRC GCRF RCUK Award to University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-BB_P027954_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Liverpool</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=BB%2FP027954%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
