<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021336_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The use of human monoclonal antibodies to inform and enhance influenza vaccine virus selection.</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">1. Use the information derived from the sequences of human monoclonal antibody resistant influenza A viruses to predict antigenic drift, and thus improve the accuracy of influenza vaccine virus selection. 2. Develop a selected panel of human monoclonal antibodies to influenza A viruses for distribution to the WHO collaborating centres world-wide to monitor antigenic drift for comparison to standard primary ferret sera. 3. Select antibodies defined by their binding sites that occur frequently in young adults, and thus show evidence for focusing of the antibody response. 4. Identify the binding sites by selection of resistant viruses and sequencing the vRNA 5. To isolate neutralising human monoclonal antibodies to Influenza A haemagglutinin and neuraminidase</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Influenza infections each year cause a major burden of sickness and death (greater than 250,000 deaths each year world wide). The most effective means of reducing illness caused by influenza is by vaccination. The influenza virus evolves by changing its surface proteins each year in response to selective pressure from the human antibody response. The World Health Organisation coordinates a massive effort to monitor the evolution of influenza around the world to try and identify the viruses that are most likely to cause infections in the coming years, and select the best candidates for manufacture into a vaccine. The methods used to do this are both new, by sequencing virus genes to monitor genetic changes, and old, by testing the antibodies that ferrets make to candidate vaccine viruses for cross-reactivity with circulating strains. Ferret antibodies are traditionally used because these animals are susceptible to influenza infections in a way similar to humans. Overall the effectiveness (reduction in risk of becoming ill with influenza) of the vaccines selected by these methods is quite poor at ~54%, so there is room for improvement. Recent technical developments have provided a new method to analyse the evolution of influenza that uses human monoclonal antibodies. It is these human antibodies that are thought to be driving the evolution of influenza in nature. We have shown that human antibodies isolated from vaccinated or infected individuals can detect changes in the virus that the ferret antibodies miss. In addition the changes that human antibodies detect frequently correlate with the changes that are appearing in the influenza viruses currently circulating in the human population. We propose to develop panels of human monoclonal antibodies that can help predict the future evolution of the virus, which will be distributed to the WHO Collaborating Centres around the world, for comparison to the standard ferret antibodies to see if this new technology can improve vaccine selection.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Francis Crick Institute</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="2"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-04-03" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2017-08-18" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-04-02" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-region code="998" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-27">165832.58</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-27">333008.44</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2019-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2020-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-27">335705.86</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2020-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2021-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-27">168530.09</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-03-27"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-03-27">1003076.968</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Research Grants Award to The Francis Crick Institute</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_P021336_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">The Francis Crick Institute</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.ukri.org/projects?ref=MR%2FP021336%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2017-08-18"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
