<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<iati-activities version="2.03">
 <iati-activity default-currency="GBP" hierarchy="1" iati-activities:version="2.03" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:iati-activities="http://d-portal.org/xmlns/iati-activities">
  <iati-identifier>GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1</iati-identifier>
  <reporting-org ref="GB-GOV-13" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </reporting-org>
  <title>
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Postpartum Adherence Clubs for Antiretroviral Therapy: a randomised controlled trial</narrative>
  </title>
  <description type="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Over the past 20 years there have been major advances in preventing the mother-to-child-transmission (PMTCT) of HIV, and interventions based on this knowledge have resulted in transmission rates &lt;1% in the United Kingdom and Europe, attributable largely to widespread use of combination antiretroviral therapy (ART) in pregnancy. The remarkable effectiveness of these interventions has led many to suggest that the global elimination of paediatric HIV infection may be possible. Towards this, there is particular excitement regarding universal initiation of lifelong ART for all HIV-infected pregnant women following the World Health Organisation&apos;s &quot;Option B+&quot; approach, and this strategy has been implemented in many parts of Africa, including the Western Cape Province of South Africa (SA) from July 2013. But despite considerable optimism, more than 300 000 new paediatric HIV infections occur each year around the globe; almost 10% of these are in SA alone. In turn there is growing recognition that the &quot;Option B+&quot; approach must be accompanied by effective and efficient models of care for delivering ART to unprecedented numbers of HIV-infected pregnant women.   For women starting lifelong ART in pregnancy, there is particular concern about the postpartum period (for the purposes of this proposal, this is from delivery until 24 months postpartum) as a time when HIV-infected women are at a very high risk of not taking their medications (non-adherence) and/or dropping out of care altogether (non-retention). Over the last few years there has been growing evidence that the postpartum period is a difficult time for women on ART, but there are few interventions that aim to support HIV-infected women during this time. One of the few interventions for this purpose is the &apos;Adherence Club&apos; model. In South Africa and most parts of Africa, HIV-infected patients (including pregnant and postpartum women) attend primary care clinics where doctors and nurses focus on the clinical care of individual patients. In contrast to this, the Adherence Club model is operated by community health workers (lay people without clinical training) working from community venues that are located closer to peoples&apos; homes. There is preliminary evidence that the Adherence Club model could lead to better clinical outcomes than standard clinical services, but the observational studies used to generate this evidence have significant methodological flaws.   To help generate robust evidence about the Adherence Club model for managing HIV-infected women on ART during the postpartum period, we plan to enroll 388 HIV-infected pregnant women on ART immediately after delivery. These women will be allocated at random to either attend routine primary health care clinics for their ART during the postpartum period, or to attend an Adherence Club. Women will be followed up by a study measurement team (that operates separately from either of the clinical services) at regular intervals through 24 months postpartum. This measurement team will check the HIV viral loads and administer questionnaires to women who are participating. The primary focus of the study is the retention of women in care, and their adherence to ART, during the 24-month period. There are secondary outcomes related to the acceptability of the Adherence Club model, and also the cost-effectiveness of the model, compared to standard primary care services as the control condition.</narrative>
  </description>
  <description type="2">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">The past few years have witnessed a paradigm shift in the conceptualization of prevention of mother-to-child transmission (PMTCT) services across sub-Saharan Africa, with increasing attention to use of antiretroviral therapy (ART) in all HIV-infected pregnant women. The Western Cape province of South Africa (SA) is implementing the policy of universal initiation of lifelong ART in all HIV-infected pregnant women regardless of CD4 cell count or disease stage (&quot;Option B+&quot;), and given the high antenatal HIV seroprevalence, HIV-infected pregnant women represent the largest group of patients initiating ART in primary care facilities. However there are few well-developed models of service delivery to support implementation of &quot;Option B+&quot; here and in many parts of the continent. In particular, while systems for initiation and follow-up of pregnant women on ART are based within well-established antenatal care clinics, there are major concerns regarding delivery of ART to HIV-infected women during the postpartum period. Multiple studies indicate high levels of non-retention in care, and/or inadequate ART adherence, during the postpartum period, presenting a threat to HIV-infected (HIV+) women and their infants. In turn, there is an urgent need for evidence-based approaches to support the growing number of HIV+ mothers on ART.  The Adherence Club (AC) model is a direct response to the need to deliver ART services to unprecedented numbers of HIV-infected individuals in southern Africa. The AC concept is based on chronic disease management strategies that emphasize social support, adherence to treatment and retention in care, rather than intensive clinical management, as the most important determinant of long-term health outcomes in stable patients in chronic care. There is preliminary evidence that in stable patients on ART, management via ACs results in virologic and programmatic outcomes that could be comparable to those achieved in more intensive clinical services. However there are profound selection biases fundamental to the existing observational data, and a clear need for more rigourous evaluations. Yet there are no randomised studies examining the impact of the Adherence Clubs, and no data on ACs as a model of care for managing HIV-infected women and exposed infants in the postpartum period, presenting a major gap in the evidence base to inform ART and PMTCT services across sub-Saharan Africa.  In this context, the objectives of this research are:  1. To evaluate the impact of antiretroviral therapy (ART) adherence clubs as a model of postpartum care for HIV-infected women initiating lifelong ART during pregnancy on maternal and child health outcomes, including:     a) Retention of HIV-infected mothers in ART services at 24 months postpartum     b) Adherence to therapy and viral suppression among HIV-infected mothers on ART up to 24 months postpartum       c) Retention of HIV-exposed infants in routine child health services, including repeat HIV testing  2. To examine the acceptability of ART adherence clubs as a model of care for HIV-infected women  3. To examine the cost-effectiveness of ART adherence clubs compared to routine ART programmes  To address these, we propose a randomised controlled trial to examine the impact of postpartum adherence clubs on maternal and child health outcomes in Cape Town, South Africa. The trial will randomise 388 HIV-infected women and their HIV-exposed infants within 7 days postpartum to either (a) referral to ART services at local adult ART clinics, following the current standard of care, or (b) referral to a community-based ART adherence club. The primary outcome is the combined endpoint of maternal retention in care (alive and attending ART services) and viral suppression up to 24 months postpartum, which reflects the ultimate goal of PMTCT and ART services: to keep mothers alive and in care and at the same time minimizing the risk of HIV transmission through breastfeeding.</narrative>
  </description>
  <participating-org ref="GB-GOV-13" role="1" type="10">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="3" type="90">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <participating-org role="4" type="80">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
  </participating-org>
  <activity-status code="4"></activity-status>
  <activity-date iso-date="2014-06-02" type="1"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2015-01-01" type="2"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2018-06-01" type="3"></activity-date>
  <activity-date iso-date="2020-05-31" type="4"></activity-date>
  <contact-info type="1">
   <organisation>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </organisation>
   <department>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">International Development</narrative>
   </department>
   <person-name>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">GCRF</narrative>
   </person-name>
   <email>gcrf@ukri.org</email>
   <website>https://www.ukri.org/</website>
   <mailing-address>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Polaris House, Swindon, SN2 1LF</narrative>
   </mailing-address>
  </contact-info>
  <recipient-country code="ZA" percentage="100">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">South Africa</narrative>
  </recipient-country>
  <recipient-region code="1029" percentage="100" vocabulary="1"></recipient-region>
  <sector code="43082" percentage="100" vocabulary="1">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research/scientific institutions</narrative>
  </sector>
  <tag code="RI" vocabulary="99" vocabulary-uri="https://devtracker.fcdo.gov.uk/custom-codes">
   <narrative xml:lang="EN">Research and Innovation</narrative>
  </tag>
  <collaboration-type code="4"></collaboration-type>
  <default-flow-type code="10"></default-flow-type>
  <default-finance-type code="110"></default-finance-type>
  <default-aid-type code="D02" vocabulary="1"></default-aid-type>
  <default-tied-status code="5"></default-tied-status>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2014-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2015-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-11">75492.63</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2015-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2016-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-11">226477.89</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2016-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2017-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-11">76093.27</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2017-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2018-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-11">360801.39</value>
  </budget>
  <budget status="2" type="1">
   <period-start iso-date="2018-04-01"></period-start>
   <period-end iso-date="2019-03-31"></period-end>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-11">337322.63</value>
  </budget>
  <capital-spend percentage="0"></capital-spend>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="2"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2014-12-11"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2014-12-11">1168957.83</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">MRC GCRF Joint Funded Initiatives Full Award to University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR/M007464/1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2016-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2016-04-01">76093.25</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-07-01">120267.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2017-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2017-10-01">120267.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-01-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-01-01">120267.15</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-04-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-04-01">120714.5</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-07-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-07-01">114846.35</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <transaction>
   <transaction-type code="3"></transaction-type>
   <transaction-date iso-date="2018-10-01"></transaction-date>
   <value currency="GBP" value-date="2018-10-01">101761.75</value>
   <description>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Quarterly Payment for the GCRF funded activity</narrative>
   </description>
   <provider-org provider-activity-id="GB-GOV-13-FUND--GCRF-MR_M007464_1" ref="GB-GOV-13">
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK - Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy</narrative>
   </provider-org>
   <receiver-org>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">University of Cape Town</narrative>
   </receiver-org>
  </transaction>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/HTTP" url="http://gtr.rcuk.ac.uk/projects?ref=MR%2FM007464%2F1">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">Abstract/Planned Impact</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A01"></category>
   <language code="EN"></language>
   <document-date iso-date="2015-01-01"></document-date>
  </document-link>
  <document-link format="APPLICATION/PDF" url="https://www.ukri.org/funding/information-for-award-holders/grant-terms-and-conditions/">
   <title>
    <narrative xml:lang="EN">UK Research &amp; Innovation Grant Terms and Conditions</narrative>
   </title>
   <category code="A04"></category>
  </document-link>
  <conditions attached="1"></conditions>
 </iati-activity>
</iati-activities>
